The Legend of Zhen Huan  -Episode 26-
Fucha Guiren has seen such misfortune all because of her baby.
She has now lost her baby...
while you're pregnant on the other hand.
Thank you for the advice, niangniang.
Babies are innocent. Every baby carries the effort of every parent.
I just can't bear to see bad things happen.
Just take it as accumulating good fortune for your baby.
I thank Your Highness for your pity and care for my baby.
What are you doing? Quickly get up.
Since I've said so much, I might as well say something more.
Cao Qinmo is even tougher to tackle than Hua Fei.
She is patient with her cunning schemes
For many a time, I've almost fallen into her traps.
If Hua Fei were to be described as a tiger,
Cao Qinmo would be the claw of the tiger.
But,
as long as you know who wants to harm you, you can be more cautious and avoid it.
I'm just afraid that you'd be harmed
Not knowing who your opponent is... that's the most...
scary part.
Niangniang, why is it that you never seem to recover?
Would Your Highness like to meet an Imperial Doctor that I know?
It's alright.
It's just an old illness.
I'm really tired,
I need to get back right now.
Then let me get someone to escort Your Highness back.
This can't be known by the public.
Does the Emperor know about this?
I've sent someone already. I told him to report it in a proper manner.
To prevent the Emperor from feeling sad,
report it slowly and mention more about Wan Guiren's pregnancy.
I hope that the Emperor would feel better
upon news of Wǎn guìrén's pregnancy.
I was thinking of that too.
No matter how sad the Emperor is,
there's still Wǎn guìrén's baby.
If not, there are still so many concubines that could
bear children for the Emperor.
Never mind that we could not save Fùchá guìrén's baby,
With Wǎn guìrén's baby,
There can be no mistakes!
Understood.
Your Imperial Highness
there's something else I have yet to report.
What is that?
Huá fēi wants to hire an outside doctor for herself.
What makes her bring up this matter?
Huá fēi thinks that her inability to get
pregnant is due to the incapable Imperial Doctors.
So, she wanted to hire a doctor to have a look.
This is what Huá fēi requested.
I heard that is was Nian Gengyao's idea as well.
What do you think, Empress?
If news of this matter is spread outside,
people would view Ministry of Imperial Doctor in a bad light.
It's bad for their reputation.
It's a loss of honor for sure
But if we reject her request,
with her temperament,
she will ask again and again.
Forget it,
let her go ahead with it.
If he is really a good physician,
after examining Huá fēi,
let him take a look at Zhu-Xi.
By my side, she has grown old.
Of course there are times when the old feel unwell.
Yes.
If Sun gugu is not feeling well,
it's convenient for him to examine her as well.
Huá fēi was right,
With these mediocre Imperial Physicians,
illness takes a longer time to recover
I'm exhausted
I need to rest
Madam is weak originally
How could your body take it
after working for such a long time?
If it wasn't due to unsettled matters
I would've thrown this body of mine a long time ago
You still didn't have to meet Wǎn guìrén in the middle of the night and exhaust yourself by speaking for so long.
Babies are innocent.
The mothers are innocent too.
Naturally, I can't
let her be in danger without helping her.
It's just a pity that
I will never be able
to have my own baby in this life.
Your Highness!!
Please, you have to stop. These sour cucumber are bad for stomach.
Madam,
please don't torture yourself
I've just vomitted
Song-Zhi, I've just vomited.
Aren't you happy for me?
Quickly bring the Imperial Doctor!
Your Highness
Fùchá guìrén was pregnant,
so is Wǎn guìrén now.
Seems like everyone could get pregnant
But why can't I get pregnant?
Madam,
you are still young,
it's just a matter of time.
I was pregnant.
It was a baby boy.
It's all because of her.
The medicines are bitter. This barley soup helps in soothing the throat.
You can get to sleep after taking this.
Arrival of Huá fēi!
Huá fēi...
Your Highness, Huá fēi...
Duān fēi is asleep. Please come tomorrow if you'd like to visit.
Move aside!
Yes.
Hold her!
Understood.
Your Highness! Your Highness!
Your Highness!
It's been so many years.
You stormed in with the same posture
every time when you were mad.
It's been many years.
Whenever I think of my unborn baby!
I just can't wait to tear you apart!
Tear me apart?
You've been doing it all these years, haven't you?
I wanted
I hate that I am unable to kill you with my own hands!
Sickness have clung on to me for so long
death seems to be a better choice to me.
Doesn't this make you happier than killing me?
Your misery could never make up for the pain
that I suffered for losing my son.
When the Emperor took the throne,
he granted you rank of consort and kept you alive.
How could I not hate you?
A cruel woman like you should've been
tortured to death.
If I am really such a great sinner,
the Emperor wouldn't have
let me lived til now.
The Emperor protects you because he trusts you.
But I will never believe you even if I die.
It was you who gave me the medicine.
I believed in you then because you were such a peaceful person.
I didn't stop to think that you could be so cruel.
You killed my baby with that medicine!
My poor baby..
It was a formed baby that you killed so cold-heartedly!
Back then you jumped the gun and blamed everything on me.
Forcing me to drink the Saffron in the middle of the night.
You've lost a son. But I've lost the ability to get pregnant!
So what?
How I wish you'd have no descendants forever!
If you have any solid evidence,
you would have had me killed,
why would you still be here?
As long as you are still in this Imperial Palace,
I will never let you go.
Whether you forgive me or not,
I do not care.
I've resigned to my fate.
I've lost myself in your hand.
It's late already.
There is nothing beneficial
in disturbing the Empress Dowager now.
Do you think I'll be afraid of it?
Of course you will.
If the Empress Dowager knew about it,
the Emperor would know about it too once he is back.
You've been favored all these years.
You must be afraid to lose the trust of the Emperor.
You're making a fuss because
of Fùchá guìrén and Wǎn guìrén getting pregnant successively.
You're jealous.
Now that you're making a ruckus,
Aren't you afraid that Emperor would
suspect you for Fùchá guìrén's miscarriage
and Wǎn guìrén's injury?
You could
take a good look by then
If Emperor cares more about you
or the future generation of the Royal Family.
Today's incident has nothing to do with me.
It doesn't matter at all.
The only opinion that matters is the Emperor's
Just like how you insisted that I killed your unborn baby
and wouldn't forgive me.
It's the same theory.
There's still a lot to come
Just wait and see what's going to happen to you.
I'm going to watch you suffer through your life.
Transfer all allowance of Yanqing Hall to Ministry of Imperial Medicine from now onwards.Count it costs for her medicine
Tell the Laundry Department not to wash anything from her palace
No fresh foods are allowed in her palace. Everything is not allowed!
Please calm down. It's been this way all these years.
Those Imperial Doctors are useless. Send a message to my brother tomorrow
Empress Dowager has agreed on hiring an outside doctor
Heard that you are one of the best doctors within the region of Qinghai.
It is rare for a servant to get to meet Madam. It is an honor for me too. For being able to serve you.
Eunuch is being modest. Qinghai is a stretch of barren land. I am just trying to earn a living.
How can I be compared to the Imperial Doctor?
I'm nothing compared to them
I know nothing about medicine. But Empress Dowager is kind and says that
It is tough for Doctor Chen to enter the capital. Of course you would want to exchange ideas with the Imperial Doctors.
So that you could help the others when you leave
-How kind of the Empress Dowager, it's an honor to the nation..
Heard that you are treating Huá fēi. These are the previous medical records of Huá fēi.
ever since she entered the palace. Take it, I hope it helps you.
Thank you Chief Doctor.
Huá fēi has a prestigious status. She was favored by Emperor the most
That is why we put in the extra effort for her.
There has been more than 20 experienced doctors, treating her in the past.  Exactly
General Nian reminded me to treat Huá fēi with my utmost care
before he left.
I'm feeling very uneasy.  Exactly
Good that I get to discuss with Imperial Doctor, or I would stumble my way through  That's right
You've been working under my brother back in Qinghai?
Yes.
How long has it been?  Ever since the day the General came to Qinghai
Qinghai is a barren stretch of land. You have been working hard for my brother's health.
Song-Zhi
Thank you.
These 100 taels seems little, but it's more than enough
to kill a person.
I'd give you 10000 taels if you could take care of my health
I would give you 10000 taels too, if you don't.
That's for the expenses of your funeral
Your servant will do my best, please spare me.
I'm just saying it to let you know
If you sincerely give your best effort,
I will, naturally, not treat you badly.
How's my health? Any possibility for pregnancy?
Your Highness is fine.
Then why can't I get pregnant all this while?
Could it be affected by a previous miscarriage?
It's been years since the miscarriage.
It shouldn't affect that much or else other Imperial Doctors
would've diagnosed it earlier on.
Pregnancy needs good timing
and opportunity. Pardon me for my words. Was Your Hihness eager for kids all this while?
Of course.  Exactly.
Things like this can't be rushed
Urging it will only cause delay. Your Highness needs to lighten up. (be patient)
Perhaps there'd be chances in it.
You mean
Sense of urge in mood will make it tough
You mean there's still a chance for me to get pregnant?
It's just the matter of timing.
Timing is crucial, same goes to you
Bring me some good medicine for pregnancy
Yes
Keep the money. I'll send another 2000 taels of silver to your estate later on
Thank you
Excused  Thank you
What's the matter with you?The weather is good.Why'd you sweat this much after coming from Palace of Supporting Earth?
I'm ashamed. I was intimidated
by the environment of the Imperial Palace.
Please take a look at Empress Dowager's servant if you are not in a hurry.
Of course, please lead the way
How is my illness?
You are fine, there is nothing wrong
The Imperial Doctor said that my illness takes a long effort to recover.
When everyone around said that the person is ill
While you go against it alone
What do you think will happen?
In contrast, a person is ill
But not one dares to say it out loud. However, you notice and tell everything.
What do you think will happen?
Then people will think that I am a crazy man.
Yes, a reputable doctor would be thought of as a maniac then.
But there are other Imperial Doctors besides me. What if it was said by others?
That is impossible...
..ever. Everyone in the Ministry of Imperial Doctor shares the same thought.
I have the exact thought as them then.
Your Majesty. Your Majesty.
You're awake.
When did Your Majesty come back?
I had no idea at all
I was at Hénán when I heard of the incident of you and Fùchá guìrén.
It bothers me a lot.
So I came back once I got things settled.
Your Majesty must be tired, you should've
gone back to the Hall of Mental Cultivation to get some rest.
I wanted to take a look at you.
Fùchá guìrén's baby is gone
I've lost yet another baby. Why?
Why can't my children survive?
Your Majesty you must be tired
Please take some rest here.
You must give birth to the baby.
I will love and care for him
Your Majesty, please don't look at me. I'm injured and look awful.
It's alright, Imperial Doctor will cure you for sure.
How is your arm?  It's fine.
How foolish.
Even if you weren't pregnant, trying to save Fùchá guìrén...
What if you injured yourself?
It wasn't to save her, it was to save Your Majesty's baby.
She can never be compared to you
even if she's pregnant.
I know that both you and your father suffered due to Huá fēi's incident.
Don't worry, I won't make you sad anymore.
Emotions can't be controlled, It's enough for Your Majesty to have such thoughts
Now that your father holds the position of a supervisor, it's more convenient to handle certain affairs.
I've informed the Empress about granting you the rank of Concubine on the same day as Consort Jing.
I will never let you suffer anymore.
I'm not suffering at all
When everything is settled, our baby will be born by then.
I'll grant you the rank of Consort and get you another place to stay by then.
The House of Broken Jade is good enough already. I care nothing about rankings.
I just want to live a normal life with Your Majesty and our baby.
Hui-Chun  Eunuch Su is here.
Did you come here to pass the royal order?
It's not even evening yet
Is the Empress inside?
Yes, I will pass on your words.  Please
Your Highness, Eunuch Su is here
We were talking about how Emperor went to other's palace once coming back.
Now that Emperor wants to accompany Your Highness, Emperor still cares for Your Highness the most.
It is the 15th of the month,the Emperor must've missed Your Highness a lot.That's why he let Eunuch Wu to pass the order
Enough of words, quickly bring him in.
Yes
This way, Eunuch Su
Greetings to your Highness
Excused. What brings you here?
Your servant is here to pass the royal order. Emperor is not coming to the Palace of Great Benevolence tonight.
The Emperor would come to Empress' palace on every 15th of the month.
What's the matter now?
Did Huá fēi invite the Emperor for dinner or is the Emperor not feeling well?
Emperor said that Wǎn guìrén is pregnant. So he went to visit her once the official matters were settled.
Your Highness, please get some rest.
That's normal. Wǎn guìrén is soft and detailed.
Of course His Majestey would love to accompany her.
– Huichun,  – Yes
– Pick up two Nephrite Jade Ruyi from the store room and send them to Wǎn guìrén later on.  – Understood
Your servant takes his leave now then.
Go ahead
It's still early. Your Majesty,
please proceed to the Empress's Palace.
It's alright
Your Majesty shouldn't neglect Empress just because of me.
I want to be with the one I love no matter what.
Empress treats me really well.
I can't bear to let down Empress.
I'll accompany Empress for meals tomorrow then.
Your Majesty
It's sour
I had no idea that it is sour. I'll keep it aside.
It's really sour, don't throw it away. Send it to Wǎn guìrén.
Now that she likes to eat sour stuff
It's an auspicious sign.
Now that Fùchá guìrén had a miscarriage and Wǎn guìrén got pregnant, Empress must take good care of them.
Of course, precautions must be taken since it's Wǎn guìrén's first pregnancy
Be careful so that Chun-Yuan's incident won't reoccur.
That was a tragedy, I will never let such an incident to reoccur.
In my opinion, precaution is necessary
beside that, Lady Fuca's incident
It's my oversight on it.
Be more careful and take precautions
Take note that cats are no longer allowed in the palace.  -Understood
Besides, regarding the granting of Wǎn guìrén, please manage it with care.
I will take care of it
The day of granting ceremony is near. How are things going?
Wǎn guìrén ranks with Hierarchy of Concubines. It's a must to perform a ritual during the ceremony.
Perhaps it's a little bit of a rush, since the time given was limited.
I'll follow the orders given by Empress Dowager and Empress
Be seated. I know that you're being mature
Although it's a bit of a rush. But we can't lack on ritual etiquettes
I've got everything settled, Your Highness
It's just that Wǎn guìrén's formal attire cannot be cone in time,
So I asked the Ministry of Ritual to alter the previous attire of Jìng fēi
It's proper and expedient
You did a good job on this
– Chunmao  – Yes
This hairpin looks familiar
It looks like the one from when Huì guìrén was pregnant,
Your Imperial Highness bestowed it upon her
You have good sights. Back then Emperor smashed it with rage.
Caused the break on this hairpin.
Now that the gemstone has been reattached,
I shall grant this Ruyi  Hairpin of Pure Gold
to you
Come here
It looks really good
Huì guìrén didn't get the chance to put this on
You must keep this virtue of yours and contribute to future generations of the Royal Family.
contribute to the future generation of the Royal Family
Thank you.
What are these?
These are all granted by Emperor
This is Agar Cream
I heard it's good for healing scars
This is Jade Powder that helps
in removing blood condensation
Emperor granted a lot  of medicines like this
The scratches aren't that bad
But it's startling just by looking at it
Miss has to be more careful
from now onwards
Your servant will take care of  of miss' daily meals
Emperor has transferred a royal cook  from the Royal Kitchen
to specially take care of miss' meals. Others have no rights to interrupt.
Doctor Zhang will take care of Miss's medicine from today onwards
Doctor Zhang is reliable  There shouldn't be any error
Noble Consort, Lady An is here  Quickly bring her in
Yes
Sister
Pardon me. With such condition
With such a condition  I really shouldn't have come out
What's wrong with your throat?
Have a seat
The coughing is not getting any better
It affects the throat I guess
Why didn't the imperial Doctor  give you proper treatment?
Doctor dares not use strong prescription since I'm weak
I forced myself to accompany Empress back then.
I got a shock because of Fùchá guìrén's incident
It affected the illness in the end
That's way I haven't visited you these days  to congratulate you
These are small matters  Your health is the only thing that matters
Does the Emperor know about this?
Emperor summoned me to  Hall of Mental Cultivation when he's back
But I can't sing at all
Emperor told me to get some rest
and never summoned me since then
When did this happen? I had no idea at all..
It's not something worth mentioning  Of course others wouldn't know
I've been complaining too much that I  almost forgot the purpose of coming here
How's your wound?
It's getting better
Doctor was here for an examination
Emperor even granted me medicine
it's should be fine after some rest
It's good that Emperor  granted you medicine
But you can't simply use any medicine
since your pregnant
Besides these medicines you were granted are all imported
It might not suit us well  Don't you think so?
Your right
This healing cream is  a tradition of my family
Back in those years,
When wife of Sun He, Lady Deng's face was hurt by a Jade Ruyi  The wound recovers just by using this
This cream contains Plum Blossom and Pearl Powder that helps in improving complexion
Gelatine and honey that nourishes the skin
Jade grits and Amber resin that helps in  healing wounds
The marrow of white otter  that helps in removing
scar is the most precious ingredients
The other ingredients sound good
But marrow of white otter is really rare
Perhaps it could hardly  be seen even in the palace
That's right
White otter only exist within Fuchun River
The marrow can only be
or dead otter in caves
Freshness of the marrow is the crucial point
The effect of stale marrow is nothing  compared to fresh marrow
It smells good
I wanted to use perfume originally
But jiejie, due to your pregnancy, you should avoid using perfume.
So I used flowers to adjust the fragrance
so that jiějie wouldn't feel uncomfortable with it
It's good but it's too precious
I can't accept this
It's alright
I'd feel better once your wound recovers
Besides, jiějie, you have injuries on your neck
Now that there's dust  and pollen everywhere
It's bad if you accidentally got infected
Besides, this healing cream can't be exposed
Please remember to cover up your wound
when your heading outside
Your so detailed. I have no idea how to my appreciation.
Have a try
I heard that sister's mother is allowed to enter the
Palace when it's about time to give birth
Really?
Yes, there'd be orders from Emperor
by the 8th month of pregnancy
You seem carefree all the time.
What's the matter?
It's been a while since I seen my mother
But jiějie could get to meet your mother soon.
How nice!
You're the youngest daughter in the family.
You must miss your family a lot since
you've not meet them since your entering the palace.
It's alright your mother would be happy once
knowing that Miss is living a good life here.
Besides, outside food can't be
compared to those in the palace isn't it?
These are freshly baked corn cakes with milk it tastes best when it's hot
It tastes good!
How admirable, you could get rid of all the problems in the world once there's food.
Your mindset is like a pond of pure water.
I care nothing about pure water. I'll be happy once there's food!
Yu-Er said that you liked corn cakes. So I told the kitchen to per pare some for you.
I even added in some milk, so that it's more crispy.
This taste so much better than these at my place.
I'll get the kitchen to make it for you everyday. If you like?
But only one, nothing more than that
Wang Jie Jie, do you really have a kid in your stomach?
Yes.
But the kid is still very small.
He doesn't even have hands or legs yet.
Wow! That is small!
I'll make him your nephew, if you like?
I could be his auntie for real?
Alright, this is my present.
Not that I can run away after taking your present.
Look how nice your Aunt is. Giving a present before you're born.
Little baby, quickly grow up.
When you've grown up I'll feed you the most delicious foods in the world
Plum Blossom Cake, Glutinous Rice Cake, Bea Paste Roll, and Lychee Dessert.
I will give you everything!
You'll be a chubby baby for sure
Besides, your Aunt will give birth to a lot of babies to accompany you
Are you happy?
Jie Jie is teasing me again
Lady Chun runs really fast. Now you see her, now you don't.
Jie Jie, what about me giving birth to eight kids to accompany your baby?
Enough, it's not like we could take care of it
Niang Niang, both Doctor Jiang's came to examine you earlier on
Knowing that it's not proper timing since Emperor is coming
they'd come again in the evening
Right!
That woman is pregnant and can't serve at night. Yet the Emperor still went over to see her.
I'll tell Doctor Jiang to remind Emperor of it
Although Precious Wan is pregnant
But Lady Chun, is taking all the advantages now.
Such a cheap act, her playing innocent to seduce Emperor
Niang Niang, need not get angry she's just a young brat.
She's usually blunt with her words. You could use that as an excuse to get rid of her in the future
You could use that as an excuse to get rid of her in the future.
Aunt has been serving in the palace for years
It's a blessings to me that maiden is willing to bun my hair for the ceremony.
Your forelock is really high
I've been serving in the palace for years. Your forelock is the highest among all that I've served.
Now that your pregnant
It's a bliss that can't be compared to others
Everyone in the palace knows that high forelock carries sign of good fortune
You look like one that has good fortune
Oh, it's heavy!
Now that you are Wǎn pín, you find this new headpiece heavy,
What will you say when you become a guìfēi?
Don't spread nonsense!
Liuzhu has a point.
If you were to give birth to a baby prince
It would be outrageous if you did not become a guìfēi!
Jing Fei née Feng and Wan Pin née Zhen...
May Heaven guide you in your new positions.
Henceforth, you shall keep the virtue of harmony.
With diligence, may you bear many heirs.
We consorts shall follow Your Highness' guidance with gratitude.