Episode 29
Kneel.
I did not leave anyone here is to help salvage your reputation.
If word gets out
there will be no place for your corpse.
What is it that you speak of your highness?
I do not understand.
You don't understand?
You sent this plate of chestnut sweets to Wan Pin,
what is hidden inside of it?
I did send a plate of this desert to Wan Pin, but it was out of good will.
Good will?
I have already asked the imperial doctor Zhang, the sweets were filled with oleander powder.
Oleander is poisonous.
I did not know.
You dare lie to me?
Who went to check the prescription for post pregnancy from the doctors?
You knew Wan Pin was taking cinnamon tea!
Oleander added with cinnamon
that is a combination for abortion.
You were not careless at all.
You had intentions to kill Wang Pin's child.
Your highness, I only have 3 brothers and a son
I cannot not make plans for his future.
So what? Even if Wan Pin gives birth to a boy,
the child is still young. What are you afraid of?
I must be afraid.
I have already fallen into disfavor
3rd prince is not loved by his majesty
if he does not become the heir to the throne, then he will not have a future.
You're foolish.
Did you really think that you are helping 3rd prince? You're lucky that I found out about this early.
Do you think the emperor will let you off if you really did kill Wan Pin's unborn child?
His majesty will think of his evil mother the moment he sees 3rd prince.
3rd prince is the one who truly has no hope.
Your highness, I was careless. It was really a moment of carelessness!
You were careless of course.
You're lucky that I was told of this earlier.
I have kept it under wraps for you.
Or else, did you think that you can still speak in front of me like this?
Does Wan Pin know about this?
She naturally knows.
She is even in a hurry to speak with his majesty about it.
Luckily, I was there to stop her.
And promised her a punishment for you,
only then did she agreed to hold back.
Thank you your highness.
But.. I did not really cause any harm to her.
She didn't eat it anyway.
You already have the idea of harming her
and you even did it.
The only difference is Wan Pin not consuming it and harming her child.
That's not because her luck, its you.
How could 3rd prince have such a foolish mother to commit such a foolish act.
I will clean this up nicely for you.
But for sake of shutting Wan Pin's mouth,
I have no choice but to implement harsh punishment upon you
Other than studying in Chong Hua palace,
3rd prince is not allowed to go to Chang Chun palace.
Your highness...
There is no doubt that you are 3rd prince's mother, but a punishment is unavoidable.
In the future, I will discipline 3rd prince in your place,
there is no need for you to be at Chang Chun palace.
No.. your highness...
Your highness...
I cannot live without 3rd prince.
Don't worry,
I will not cut off your mother and child ties.
Come to Jing Ren palace if you wish to see him.
If anyone word were to be out in the future,
I at least something to say to the public, or in the least protected you.
Its only natural that you're rejecting,
it would be impossible for you to see 3rd prince if Wan Pin makes a fuss.
Thank you your highness.
Young master has been exposed to shock, its best that you turn in early.
Thank goodness that I have Ling Rong here.
if she did not detect the scent of oleander...
Lin Rong did put her heart into it.
I have shunned away from her in the past thinking that she is over sensitive,
but come to think of it now, it's my fault.
You can't put it that way either.
Only time will reveal one's true character.
Peasant have heard from her highness has already implemented punishment on her.
They say that they will personally take care of 3rd prince.
To a mother
a mother and child separating is the most painful.
Her Highness has dealt with this harshly.
Oh well, as long as it will be left alone.
Hopefully it can really be left alone for the best.
There was already the problem of investigating Fu Precious
I don't want the Emperor to worry anymore
I just believe that if some events were to occur again
with the same cycle
yesterday it was you tomorrow it is her
everyone getting hurt and hurting each other
It's like a strange cycle, it really is terrifying.
The Harem's ”kill or get killed" behavior will never end
so my lady you must take many precautions
I have thought about it for two nights and am still uneasy
So I asked you to come talk with me
yes
You have suffered from Noble Consort Qi's situation
But it can't be helped
The Emperor can focus on the Imperial Court only if his harem is harmonious
Noble Consort Qi's problem has affected everyone
Even 3rd prince will be implicated. 4th prince and 5th prince are still young.
If this is known by people who have hidden agendas
unfortunately it will be another mighty uproar
Thankfully Ling Rong discovered it soon
Otherwise neither I nor my baby would have been lucky
An Chang Zai is meticulous,
so with her by your side I am able to rest assured
This time it will serve as a warning
From now on you must be extremely careful
I will definitely be very cautious
This year has been different from others
I wonder what has disturbed the balance
I hear from the Emperor that some lands are suffering from a drought
It has been two months without a drop of rain
This is devastating for the agricultural plans
Troubled Heavens means human suffering
Both the Imperial Court and the Harem are restless
The Emperor and Empress have worried
The Emperor and I have decided to go to Tian Tan to pray for rain
Then go to Gan Lu temple to pray for good fortune
Noble Consort Hua will be completely in charge of the Harem
Consort Jing will assist
I will rest for my baby
and won't go out unless there is a problem
That is good
You understand Noble Consort Hua's personality
Bear with it if you can
Wait for the Emperor and I to come back to give you justice
But you are pregnant so she won't dare to do anything to you
You can just rest at ease
The trip will only take ten days
we will be back very soon
Thank you for your concern
I will definitely take good care of myself
Good
How is your wound?
An Chang Zai presented a soothing balm.
I have used it since and indeed my wound has healed
If it is helping then you should use it often
A girl should never leave any kind of scar
You must fully recover
Thank you Empress
Jie Jie has returned
You came at the perfect time. I wanted to talk to you
The soothing balm is almost gone, I wanted to ask you for more
What a coincidence, I was thinking the same
See, I brought it with me
Sorry for imposing
I've already used three or four boxes
And I will continue to bother you and ask you to do this
Jie Jie is pregnant, quickly, sit
I have nothing better to do
Doing things I like for Jie Jie is a wonderful thing
You haven't fully recovered from your Laryngeal disease. You must rest and not strain yourself.
The Emperor has arrived
Huan Huan
Good fortune for your majesty
Get up
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I told you not to carelessly move around
Yet you still greet me
What if you fell in a hurry to get up?
I'm not that fragile
Have you been well these few days?
I feel fatigued. My back and legs are sore
But the doctors said that because it is my first pregnancy,  feeling tired is a normal symptom.
Then has imperial doctor Wen come to examine Jie Jie?
No
Doctor Wen is busy with epidemiology and takes care of Mei Jie Jie
My pregnancy is being cared for by imperial doctor Zhang
Then, with the Emperor at Jie Jie's side
I will take my leave first
The Empress and I will go to Tian Alter to pray
The palace will be overseen by Consort Hua
You two don't get along well. If there are conflicts you must give in to her
If you have any grievances tell me when I return
Yes
There is another urgent matter
As you are pregnant, to avoid troubles don't go to Yi Kun Palace
I will be careful. Please don't worry
Because I am worried I keep telling you
Shi Lan is competitive has a quick mouth but she isn't a bad person
You are worrying about this and that
Just take in fewer concubines and it will be fine
Splitting a heart into so many parts
Just watching it seems exhausting
If I wasn't the emperor and a wealthy prince instead, the Empress as the wife
and you with Shi Lan as my consorts, that would be satisfactory
Noble Consort Hua
All of the palace's duties have been given to you
You must take good care of everything
I will follow the Emperor's orders
Lower the sedan chair
Raise the sedan chair
The Emperor and Empress are leaving
Sending the Emperor and Empress away
On this trip to pray Empress it the only one serving the Emperor
Perhaps wishing for rain from the heavens isn't the only goal
Empress will be satisfied only if her wish for a son will come true
Concubine Wan don't you agree?
If the Empress really becomes pregnant, Noble Consort will be happy too right?
Of course
I believe that Concubine Wan will be happy as well
Empress is the mother of the country. If she bears a son that is the nation's fortune,
Naturally no one will be unhappy
Concubine Wan has gotten better at speaking
Concubine Wan is pregnant and shouldn't stand outside for too long. Let's return to the palace.
Consort Jing may share some powers with me
But a consort is a consort, a noble consort is a noble consort
There is only a one word difference yet it differentiates the two ranks
The one of lower status must obey the other
Consort Jing do you understand?
Yes
I served the Emperor before you. When I was his first rank concubine, you were only a Gege
Maybe if you have luck there will be a day in the future when you are my equal
You must remember that you are a person from my palace
In front of me, if I have not spoken, you have no right to speak
Understand?
yes
The weather is hot. Sisters let's disperse
Hurry, help her sit
Zhang Mi greets the two concubines
Rise
Thank you
You came at the right time. Consort Wan doesn't look well. Hurry and look at her
Yes. I was just about to examine her pulse
Niang Niang you only went out for a bit why is your face so pale?
Just now when I was standing in the sun it was a bit hot but not I am better
You have indeed suffered from the heat
but it isn't significant
However, if I may ask, do you frequently feel anxious?
Ever since Precious Chun's death she has been grieving
Her fetus hasn't been affected
But as pregnant woman, feeling depressed will not be good for the fetus
You must have a more open heart
Thank you imperial doctor
During the summer it is hot and your body may be weak
Avoid walking around when the sun is strong and focus on resting
Thank you imperial doctor
Liu Zhu, please see imperial doctor Zhang out
Thank you Niang Niang
Master, even though doctor Zhang knows what he's doing, servant has still according to tradition
should take the prescription and let doctor Wen look at it okay?
Have you forgotten? Doctor Wen went with the Emperor to serve him
Doctor Zhang's medicine had been looked at doctor Wen before, it's fine
Oh
I'm grateful to Jie Jie for just now, thank you
It's nothing really
Living with her before, I've heard everything and suffered through it all
I'm used to it. But you saw what happened just now
Even if I want to protect you
I really am powerless
Thankfully the Emperor will return soon
I believe that nothing significant will occur
I'm grateful for Jie Jie's caring intentions. Thank you
Emperor and Empress left the palace while Empress Dowager is ill
This palace is now your's
Oh yes
What a rare opportunity. It is the perfect time to deal with those who need it
I'm sleepy. Go light my Huan Yi incense.
Yes
Master, the medicine is ready
No matter how long I sleep I'm still tired. My hip is so sore
What is wrong, master?
It's nothing
I'm guessing it's these past few days I've been going to Noble Consort Hua's palace to listen to her talk
and getting tired so I would become like this
Really, she has no reason but keeps asking people to go over to talk to her
In one sitting it is six to eight hours and she doesn't feel tired
Her status is high and powerful. Before we would stay with Empress and talk
Now we have to stay with her
And I don't know what kind of incense she uses
I've always thought it was pungent
Hua Niang Niang loves to use insense
and makes it strong. It can be smelled from far away
Master has been saying these past few days your body feels sore
Maybe you should drink some warm water and rest a bit
Servant will tell Xiao Yun Zi to ask for an imperial doctor
Go quick and return quickly.
Okay
Servant greets Imperial Concubine Wan
Rise
A message from Noble Consort Hua: Please send Wan Niang Niang to Yi Kun palace to talk
It's not that I don't want to but today my body does not feel well
Could you pass this on to Noble Consort?
Noble Consort Hua is acting on Emperor's orders and supervising the Harem
Can't you see my master isn't feeling well?
A few days ago even the Empress said that master is pregnant
and the daily greetings could be waived
compared to now when she isn't feeling good. Even if the Empress was her she wouldn't have to go
Noble Consort Hua understands that Niang Niang's body is weak right now
and especially sent servant to invite you
If you don't go then how is Noble Consort going to handle the Harem?
Supervising the Harem is the Emperor's order. Niang Niang you must not disobey the Emperor
Gong Gong has a point but today I am not feeling well
I really can't go
Consort Duan's body is in that condition so obviously can't attend
But all the other concubines are there. Even An Chang. They are all waiting for you
Master, how about you go after the imperial doctor has looked at you?
Imperial Concubine Wan should just go. Don't be late and make Niang Niang angry which is bad for everyone
You can go outside and wait
I will go after I change
Great, then servant will be outside waiting
Niang Niang has already sent Zhou Ning Hai to invite her, Imperial Consort Wan will definitely come
Even the Empress has to concede to me, I don't believe that she has the nerve to not come
Actually Niang Niang doesn't have to deal with her right now, there is plenty of time
In order to crush someone you must do it at their most satisfactory moment
As of now she is proud because of her pregnancy. I will use this time to deal her a severe blow
I will let her know that in front of me there can only be those who serve him
There cannot be anyone who is doted on by the Emperor
Even more it can't be someone who is fighting me to get his love
Niang Niang everyone has arrived and now are waiting for you
Master, can you not go?
When the Emperor and Empress left the cautioned me to endure it
If I don't go who knows what kind of drama will erupt
Everyone is there, I don't think anything will happen
Then I will go with master
Let's go
Empress Dowager has been ill these few days and has been thinking about Prince and Prince has come
Is Empress Dowager's illness better?
It's still the same. She coughs every night and cannot get a good night's rest
You wait out here, Jin Xi will accompany me.
Yes
Greetings to Noble Consort. I wasn't feeling well so I arrived late.
Please forgive me.
Due to your pregnancy fatigue is unavoidable.
Please rise.
This rose flavored cake is one of the tastiest delicacies
yet after smelling the fragrant incense in your palace the cake seems flavorless
Forgive my boldness, but what scent does Noble Consort use?
An Chang's smelling sense is very strong.
The Emperor had experts specially create it for me.
It's called "Happily Desirable" and in this palace only I can use it
My knowledge is limited
and have not seen as much as Noble Consort.
An sister came to serve the Emperor later than you, naturally she wouldn't know
When the Emperor was only a Lord he only allowed Noble Consort to use the "Happily Desirable" incense
Of which includes the Ambergris scent. It was given passed down from the previous emperor.
The Emperor divided it in half and used it to make Noble Consort's incense.
It's been a long time so why bring it up now?
Yes, I have spoken too much.
Today there were many maids and servants who were fighting.
During this opportunity it is time to clean up and straighten out the palace.
The maids and servants are bickering and fighting
It is all as a result of the young mistresses spoiling them.
If the servants are misbehaving it means that their masters aren't behaving properly.
Pi Ru Fu Cha Consort used her pregnancy to act all high and mighty.
If there is anyone who hasn't learned her lesson and follows the consort's footsteps
That would be such a pity. Imperial Concubine Wan.
Do you admit your crime?
Today all of the concubines came here to listen
You came here late, disrespecting me. Hurry up and kneel before me.
I admit my guilt. Just now I wanted to ask for forgiveness.
Today you've shown disrespect to those above you. Who knows how you will be if you bear a son.
Does everyone have to follow you?
Although Noble Consort is angry, I can't help but say
but when Precious Fu Cha was pregnant the Emperor and Empress to special care of her. This wasn't for Precious Fu Cha.
Rather it was for the ancestors. Today I had no intention to come here late.
Although I may have offended you the Empress Dowager and Empress are still above me. What you just said about the Harem
following me really makes me feel scared.
Noble Consort you've been talking so you must be thirsty. How about you have some tea and rest.
Imperial Concubine may be in the wrong but at least let her rise to talk.
Women should behave like a housewife
You are trying to be clever and flagrantly disobeying rules and offended me. You will kneel outside my palace
as a punishment.
Niang Niang, the sun is strong outside and the ground is hard. Imperial Concubine is pregnant, she can't kneel there!
Noble Consort please forgive sister for the sake of her unborn child.
Niang Niang, punishing her is a small matter, but it harms the child the Emperor and Empress will surely punish you.
The rules aren't strict enough so I will correct it
If the Emperor and Empress were here it would also be this way.
Unless you want to use the Emperor and Empress to threaten me?
Niang Niang please keep the Emperor in your mind.
Imperial Concubine Wan. Will you walk out of here by yourself?
Or should I ask someone to give you a hand?
Imperial Concubine Wan. This way please.
Mother you don't look too well you must not do anything stressful. You must rest.
How can I still do anything that requires my attention?
With the Emperor and Empress gone the Harem has been handed to Noble Consort Hua.
When the Emperor was only a lord she was already helping the Empress
and I'm sure she will do a good job and not have you worry.
Noble Consort Hua's personality is just like her brother's.
Capable of handling big responsibilities but also of doing bad deeds.
Your Highness, Official Long Ke Duo's household sent this thousand year ginseng in hopes that your body will heal.
You may leave it.
Have you heard what Noble Consort Hua's brother has been doing in the official court?
No wonder your body isn't doing well. You didn't listen to the imperial doctor's orders to not stress about anything.
Yet you are even concerning yourself with the political matters.
One you mention them, I have to go around asking for more information.
This time I will let it slide. But if it happens again then I will be afraid of coming inside the palace.
Oh child, you are speaking with that slick mouth of yours.
I accept my punishment.
But I am pregnant and seriously cannot kneel for a long time.
Niang Niang please rethink it.
Do you take me for a fool?
You are doing well with your pregnancy and it has passed the dangerous first trimester.
Your pregnancy has been stable for a while now.
I have already asked the imperial doctors and kneeling for two hours won't be harmful.
Kneel.  you can't!
Young miss!
The reason why I accept this is because the Emperor gave you the responsibility of supervising the harem.
Real justice is known within the hearts of the people and isn't determined
Okay.
We will see if justice is controlled in my hands
or in what you believe to be in people's hearts.
Read it well, until I am satisfied.
Imperial Concubine is pregnant! She really can't take kneeling.
Does being pregnant mean you can disobey the palace rules?
I think that you have forgotten the lesson you already learned.
Why don't you kneel with her instead of pleading for her?
Precious Hui isn't intentionally asking for my forgiveness. Please don't involve her as well.
If I really wanted to include her than what can you really do?
Aren't you two as close as sisters?
Fine then.
Kneel next to her and hold the book. Have her recite it and learn the rules properly.
I'll stay with you.
Oh it's so hot.
Bring the concubine's chairs out here.
So they can all watch
and see what the consequences are for defying me.
Even if it is a gorgeous woman sweating the smell is still pungent.
In short, go put the incense over there.
Add a lot of "Happily Desirable" incense to get rid of the stink.
Noble Consort
If you dare to say another word then you will go kneel with her.
You can't go in.
She has been kneeling for so long.
How come she still isn't allowed to get up?
Don't you know Noble Consort's personality?
She punishes people whenever she wants to.
She is far from being done.
Who's there?
I am with Sui Yu Xuan and have urgent news to tell the Empress Dowager.
Her Highness isn't feeling well and took some medicine before sleeping. How dare you behave so noisily.
This has to do with someone's life! Please let me in.
Even if you can get through here you won't get inside to see her. If you disturb her it will cost more than a few lives.
Empress Dowager!  Get out of here
If you weren't from Sui Yu Xuan I'd already have beaten you do death. Get lost.
Eh? Huan Bi why are you here?
Ah Jin! Why are you here?
Why can't I be here? I came here with the lord.
Ah Jing, where's the lord?
Come here  Yes.
Hit.
If we can't hit the one with a baby then we will hit the one without one.
Yes.
No, you can't hit her!
Young miss be careful! You can't hit her.
Young miss!
Noble Consort
If you are lazy again then your sister will take the punishment in your place.
Niang Niang
My body really isn't feeling well.
Look at her you guys, she really is stupid.
Her acting as a sick person looks exactly like what Precious Fu Cha did
and doesn't even think how this excuse is so overused that everyone finds it annoying.
Why don't you change it?
Niang Niang, sister's body is weak
if she gets heatstroke and faints even you won't be able to endure the punishment.
I want to see if she really will faint.
Zhou Ning Hai. Go get some mint leaves.
Yes.
If she smells this and still faints
Then she will be lying to me.
If I can't punish you
I won't let Precious Hui or An Chang get away with it.
"The second couple"
"The road of the couple matches with Ying and Yang"
Niang Niang please forgive her. Please forgive sister.
Noble Consort. Niang Niang.
Niang Niang, it has already been an hour.
No hurry, have her kneel for another half an hour.
If something happens you won't be able to take the responsibility either.
Niang Niang, Imperial Concubine's face is already pale.
Is her hypocritical acting just for me to see?
I think she looks perfectly fine.
Miss.
Miss!
Miss. Wan Er
Wan Er!  Young miss!
Go away
Get off!
Young Miss. Young Miss
Lord Guo Jun!
Young miss what's wrong?
He dares to invade my palace
Stop! Where are you taking Imperial Concubine Wan?
Don't you know that invading an interior palace is punishable by death?
Whether it's punishable by death or not is determined by my brother.
The reason why I intruded is because I don't want to see the Emperor's royal child be lost.
If someday he punishes me after listening to you talk I will have no regrets.
Stop right there!
Niang Niang, it looks like there's blood on the ground.
Niang Niang
How can this be? Wasn't it just an hour?
How can there be blood?
Quick call for the doctor!
What happened?  The blankets!
Miss.
Imperial Concubine Wan.
Young miss. How can this happen?!
You! Go get some water. Yes
Lord, Emperor and Empress are at Tian Tan praying and I can't leave. Please take care of this in the Emperor's place!
Lord, your presence here may be awkward, I ask that you leave.
Miss.
Thank you lord.
Lord,
Miss
Your highness thank you so much for your help.
Your miss will be in the care of your hands.
When you report to the Emperor may I ask you to tell him word for word what happened in Yi Kong Palace?
I will report everything to him with out forgetting anything.
Miss
The Harem is restless; the people's hearts are drifting.
The Emperor does not have many sons.
So please have mercy and help Imperial Concubine be able to safely deliver a son.
The Heavens will be moved by your generous heart.
I hope that she will be able to successfully give birth to a son.
One, so she can preserve the royal bloodline.
Two, so that 3rd Prince will have someone by his side.
Anyways, even though 3rd Prince has two younger brothers,
but they are being raised in a different place so naturally he would be lonely.
With you as the mother, I am able to rest my worries.
I am incapable.
I am unable to raise 1st Prince for you
and sister died after giving birth to 2nd Prince.
Us two sister have no luck and don't have any sons.
I just hope that the other sisters may be successful for you.
You are so virtuous. My heart is comforted.
Emperor Emperor!
What?
Emperor
Emperor.
Something has happened to Sui Yu Xuan.
What happened to Imperial Concubine Wan?
Your Highness don't be impatient.The 17th lord will be here in a bit to explain everything to you.