~ Episode 25 ~
The Internal Affairs Dept. is pretty good at their work
They made this nail shield so grandiose and glorious
How can they not put their all into their work when they're working for Niang Niang?
know that working hard for me
is being cautious of me
Position and name are not important
what's important is where the emperor's heart is
What if Emperor ordained the Fei of Respect?
he still doesn't favor her
And don't even get me started on the Empress. She's old and ugly.
Emperor's only caring about Empress Dowager's wishes
That's right
Even during Emperor's duke days,
he has been cold to the Empress
it's even more evident now
Report to Niang Niang:
Doctor Jiang is here for regular visit
Send him in
Yes
Ten thousand wishes to Fei of Hua
Get up!
the Imperial Doctor has worked hard
Niang Niang, your precious body is well and everything is all right
If I'm well, when can I get pregnant?
Lady Fucha is already pregnant
Niang Niang's body hasn't fully recovered from your miscarriage four years ago
After careful adjustments and care, you will slowly recover
As for news of pregnancy, it will be only a matter of days
During this time Niang Niang still needs to care for her body
Borrowing your good words, I hope that Heaven will grant my wish
Is everything well at the Imperial Hospital?
Because of Niang Niang's immense fortune, everything has been well
I am able to have everything I have
because of you two brother
Naturally, I won't mistreat you guys
Where the plague cure was found
is a secret between us
Be more cautious of your work now
I understand
I was trying to save my life that day
so I had to use this method
I ask for Niang Niang's forgiveness
As long as the goal is reached
why fuss about what methods and ways were employed?
Milord don't need to be worried
Wen Shichu wasn't suspicious of anything, right?
What if he gets suspicious?
Though his medical skills stand out from the rest
but his experience in the Imperial Hospital is shallow
He has no evidence or proof
so he can only keep his mouth shut about this
That's good. You can leave now
Why is it that your expression is always sour after you visit Fei of Glory Niang Niang?
You don't understand
What don't I understand?
In the Imperial Hospital us brothers have obtained much prestige
and we have Fei of Glory Niang Niang to back us up
It's only a matter of days before we reach our peak
the peak of our success?
That's only for those who know how to be humans and who values life
Guard your mouth and do your tasks well
If it doesn't affect you, pretend you don't know it
This is the way of survival in the palace
Courtier Concubines greet Empress Niang Niang
Ten thousand blessings and golden peace to the Empress
You guys may rise. Grant seats.
Thanks to Empress Niang Niang
Why isn't An Changzai here?
An sister's throat infection hasn't healed yet
The imperial doctor has cautioned her
to stay indoors in case she catches a cold
Thus she can't come greet Empress Niang Niang
An Changzai is weak physically
Right now the plague hasn't been cleared so it's best for her to not move around
Thanks for understanding Empress Niang Niang
Oh right, did the palace distribute the silvers?
They've all been distributed accordingly
The silver the Internal Affairs Department distributed
I've already seen the record book
Is Fei of Glory familiar with some of the listed items?
Each individual in each palace has received the amount of silver ordained to them by the ancients (previous emperors)
there are definitely no loopholes
Did Fei of Respect go over it?
There's no need
Any records I went over never have loopholes
Besides, Fei of Respect is not familiar with financial matters
It would be a waste anyways to have her go over it
and she would delay the silver distribution
causing everyone to complain
Empress Niang Niang
I admiit I am somewhat slow at reading account books
But I will certainly improve
and not delay anyone
Study to improve, how long will that take you?
If you were given time to improve
how many matters would be delayed?
It's hard for the talentless to conquer great tasks
they would only be dragging everyone down
and embarrass themselves in front of servants
that their superiors are stupid and useless
Lady Fucha, are you experiencing the pregnant syndroms?
When I wake up in the morning, I want to vomit
After eating the three meals I want to throw up even more
It really is hard
If it's so hard then you should eat less
If you make the Imperial Kitchen deliver food to you like flowing water
then of course you will eat and throw up, throw up and eat
and vomit endlessly
For which pregnant women is it not hard?
Right now your body's worth gold
even if you have to eat abalone ginseng wing stomach everyday
it would be alright
It's not often that the palace has good news of pregnancy
Everyone's eyes and thoughts
are now resting on your belly
Thanks for Empress Niang Niang's care. I will certainly engrave this in my heart
and not blame Fei of Glory Niang Niang for saying that I eat too much
The bitterness of being pregnant
is something Niang Niang cannot expeience
I have also carried the dragon's seed inside me
even if it's gone, I've seen many pregnancies
Pregnant concubines act like they've gotten the grand prize and show it off to everyone
They really are little girls who haven't seen the world
Alright, all of you should less
Lady Fucha
it would be nice if you have a prince inside
The emperor doesn't have many heirs
If you can have a son
it will be a matter of days before you are promoted to a Pin or a Fei
For the prince and for your own body
you must take care of yourself
Yes
This is the new blue the Internal Affairs Department created
Emperor specifically instructed them before he left
to make it intricately for my use
Yeah
Emperor said that since Mistress Fucha is pregnant
and that An Changzai has throat infection
all the scent powder from Palace of Everlasting Blessings is to used with great caution
It's best to avoid using musk and to use more tranquilizing scent powders
So all these scent powders have been previously examined by the imperial doctors
they definitely will not hurt Mistress's pregnancy
Look at how fortunate you are
Emperor is so caring toward you
I do have good fortune
but that An Changzai nextdoor got throat infection
what a misfortune for her!
she is an unlucky woman who will take away my fortune
Baojuan, what are you so happy about?
Mistress, didn't you go to visit Chun Changzai?
how are you back so quickly?
What did you go do?
Servant really didn't do anything
Reach out your hand, reach it out!
Why is so gray and dusty?
Scent dust?
Servant really cannot stand
to see Lady Fucha mistreat Mistress
Servant heard that scent dust mixed with horse urine
would cause a person misfortune if spilled at the base of their wall
Servant did it only because I couldn't stand her ways
You are crazy!
How can you believe such baseless rumors?
It's all Servant's fault
If Mistress is angry, please punish Servant only
Servant willingly accepts the punishments
If Mistress take Servant to go see Lady Fucha
servant will not involve your, Mistress
Get up
You are my closest servant
From the outsider's point of view, what you do is no different from what I do
Everyday I see her being so arrogant
I also want to see her less aggresive
You are just one step before me
Did what I wanted to do
Mistress
If the servant has been long with the Mistress
Mistress wishes are just servants' wishes
So no matter what you do or say now
You did it only after thinking about what I would do
Jian Qiu to the Empress
Liu Zhu to Lady Wan is also the same
Then mistress, did I do wrong?
How come?
This is what a royal servant is like
Blessings to Lady Wan
Sister why did you get out of bed?
Do you feel better now？
I am better
Precious's health is getting much better
But...heavy disease hurt your body
you still need to rest well
thank you, Imperial doctor Wen
It is really because of you I can still live
Lady, I have something on my mind
that I always question
Speak...
Lady, do you not think
you caught the plague too suddenly
I remember that the plague
was first discovered in the palace of Fei of Glory
followed by you, Lady
however, Lady was grounded then
and did not encounter any servants in the palace of the Fei of Glory
How come suddenly catching the plague?
You are saying. Someone tried to use the plague to murder me
I am only doubtful
Sister, recall carefully
Was there anything unusual?
Internal Affairs specifically ordered me
to send you a new tea set
The tea is already ready. Please have a sip, Mistress
Cai yue
Mistress, what is it?
Have you changed my tea set?
Yes, Mistress has caught the plague
So items you used
especially tea sets and bowls
were all shattered and buried
You can leave
Yes
I remember that the first two days before my illness
Zhou Ning Hai, from Fei of Glory's palace
sent me a tea set
and said Internal Affairs ordered him to replace my old ones
I saw that tea set
wasn't to the standard of Concubines
I thought because I was grounded
It is not good to quarrel with him
The plague transmits fast
to avoid the transmission
the first rule is to not contact the patient
the second rule is to not use any item the patient touched
especially the same tea cup
Then the tea set Zhou Ning Hai delivered
was used by a patient with plague
I'm afraid so
No, it must be!
Fei of Glory wants me dead
this wasn't the first time
It was her.
It must be her!
Sister, don't get angered first. We still need evidence
I'm confused about another thing
Jiang Cheng is good at gynecology
How did he all of a sudden
know out of his own expertise, and was good at treating plagues
If I say that the plague-treating prescription
is from me
Do you believe me, Mistress?
I do. You are able to
But the prescription
how did they get hold of it?
I have already thought of the prescription
But I still needed more time to think over a few ingredients
So I didn't dare to use this prescription
and put it inside my drawer in the Imperial Hospital
I assume that when I was taking care of Lady Hui
they took advantage of it, and stole the prescription
They probably added a few more ingredients too
But because they were not experts on plagues
Prescription is a little too acute
But the medicine I gave to Lady Hui
was mild and good for the body
Since the Emperor already said they made huge contributions
even if you mention it
nobody will believe you
and will say you are too aggressive and just wants to claim your reward
Be assured. I will know how to deal with this issue
What is fun with arranging the silk lines?
You cannot cut it, and arranging it will only make it messier (from ancient Chinese poetry)
Now the days are longer
Arranging this can kill time
You are so young, and you say you want to kill time
Why not take more time to be with the Emperor
It feels lonely in the palace
Being with Niang Niang makes my mind at ease
You come to Jing Ren Palace more and more often recently
But less to Yu Xuan Palace to be with Lady Wan
and Chun Chang Zai
Empress Niang Niang, do you not like me to serve at your side?
You are smart and elegant. Of course I like you
But who does not like crowds?
How can you truly like to come here, the always silent Jing Ren palace?
Because it is usually quiet
it can teach me how to endure loneliness
Empress Niang Niang, you are so graceful like the clouds at the mountain tops
I admire you
And I have chronic illness with my throat
It is not suitable for me to go to crowded places
What you mean by graceful and reserved
is caused by the silence and loneliness
people become so after enduring long silences
Sorry for not minding my own words. I did not mean this
Get up
Of course I know you did not mean this
There is no need for more explanations between you and me
Thank you, Empress Niang Niang
Oh right, I made a fragrant bag
and want to give this to Niang Niang
I wish Niang Niang does not mind that I do not have exquisite hands
This fragrant bag is so special
The smell is also mild and full of grace
The materials I used are peony and flower Lan
with Chen Shui fragrance and pine leaves
It smells mild at first
If only smelled long
can the supreme elegance of Mu Dan (peony)
slowly radiate
The embroidery patterns are also my favorite
Phoenix surrounded by Mu Dan
If Niang Niang likes it, it is my only pleasure
Although the fragrance bag is great, it is a pity that
I usually don't use fragrances
Sorry I have not observed well
Every time I greet Niang Niang at the palace
I only know that your place is full of the sweet smells of flowers and fresh fruits
but have not noticed that Niang Niang doesn't like using fragrances
I am too careless
It is not that I do not like fragrance
but to remind you
that some fragrances, if not used properly, only hurt your health
I thank Niang Niang for your teachings
You know how to make fragrances
then you should know what terrible things can be involved
It is spring now. Even the cats are courting
All the other cats do is to moew to court
But my cat, Song Zi, likes to throw itself at things
Cats are not easy to tame in springs
But cats like smells
Cats will be tamed after they smell certain smells long enough
An Chang Zai knows the most about fragrances
No wonder you know about this trick
After I go back, I will definitely make this fragrance with care
then bring it here so that Song Zi can smell it
A few days of taming will do
That is great
The flowers at Jing Ren palace have all blossomed
I want to invite all the Concubines in the palace
to enjoy the beautiful spring together
Sure
It smells so good
Mistress, there are many flowers over there
It is the warmest in Empress's palace
Flowers bloom the earliest and most vibrantly
Jing Ren Palace has the greatest "soil power" (the unsensible power from soils that nurture plants)
But you get the biggest blessings
It has been 4 months already, right?
Yes, that right
The Imperial Doctor say, pregnancy will be stable after 4 months
When I was pregnant with No.3 A Ge (son of emperor)
I had lots of early pregnancy symptoms
My feet are too swollen to fit in my shoes
I see that you don't have such problems, that's great
I heard that when Fei of Qi was pregnant
No. 3 A Ge was strong and liked to tumble
that is why he is a bit more rushy now
The emperor needs to take extra care of him
Right, what you said is quite reasonable
The rushy temper
can only be tolerated by Fei of Qi
Fei of Glory is too spoiled
to go through the hardships of giving birth to children
Wish you are pregnant with a son
If it is a daughter
what a waste to your arrogance now!
Now you are pregnant, you shouldn't stand for so long
Jian Qiu
Send Lady FuCha to sit down in the sheltered hall
then bring her a swan feathered cushion. Don't let her catch cold
Sure, Niang Niang
Thank you, Empress Niang Niang
Blessings to Fu Cha Sister
The make up of Fu Cha Sister is sweet as the fresh dew
seems not to be what we normally use
Lady Wan, you have a sensitive nose
the Emperor specifically asked Internal Affairs to make this for me
it doesn't hurt the baby, and nurtures the skin
This must be something really good
The Emperor takes so much care of Sister
If Lady Wan really likes it, I will give some to you then
The emperor specifically made it for Sister
how can I be so shameless to take it?
That is true too
This shows the Emperor's kindness to and care for me
Lady Wan, you are so modest
I won't bother you to take the gift reluctantly
Given it is a kindness from the Emperor
it is best Lady you keep it
better to wax it and put it on the shrine
Now you apply it on your skin, and expose it under the sun and wind
if you melted the Emperor's "kindness"
Sister, let's go
Who hasn't been pregnant
I can't stand her arrogance
Lose your anger, Sister
Now she rides the top of the tide
why bother to get angry with her?
Ten thousand blessings and Golden Peace to Empress Niang Niang
Xin Chang Zai, what are you talking about?
Sister was saying that it is a good weather today
Since the weather is so nice today
Why don't we take Song Zi out, Empress?
What Fei of Qi loves most is the cat, Song Zi
Always wants to huddle the cat when you come to my place
Just that Lady Wan is afraid of the cat
But it's a good idea too
Jian Qiu, bring Song Zi out
Servant doesn't dare to take it
That cat is really heavy now
and is annoyed in the spring
I don't know where it went at this time
We were just talking about Song Zi
and here it comes
Empress has cared for it well
it's gotten bigger
People usually have cats or dogs,
but Princess of Respects is different
In her glass bowl,
she kept a huge turtle
I just didn't want to spend too much time
It's quiet and easy to raise
you can feed it anything
I'm clusmy and can't raise anything else
If Princess of Respects say you're clumsy,
then I don't know what to call myself
The Pin of Respects hasn't been formally bestowed the title of Princess yet
Precious Smile are calling her Princess of Respects already
you're too eager
You'll have plenty of time later, what's the hurry?
Princess of Glory, you're too serious
it doesn't matter if it's formal or not
As long as the Emperor agree
she is the Princess of Respects
Don't you agree?
If it is, then it is. If it's not, then it's not.
If you are blessed, you're not afarid to wait
If you're not,
you won't make it even if it was just seconds way
Today's already the 3rd
another ten more days, it'll be the ceremony
Princess of Respects, you should be prepared
Yes
Princess of Respects and Princess of Glory started serving the Emperor on the same day
Not only are you conferred a Princess,
you will also help Princess of Glory with the management of the six palaces
It's your blessing to have someone assist you
I am even more blessed to be able to live so leisurely
Your Majesty has great fortunes
This peony flower has blossomed nicely
but pink is still an inferior colour
it's unqualified for refined places
Unlike this garden peony
it's not the king of flowers, but it's red and captivating
Now this is a grand colour
Pinks are always for concubines
Only bright red and red are for main wives
Truthfully, if you're young
who cares what colour flower you use?
How can she invert the superior and the inferior
I learned a poem when I was young
it suits the situation now
I shall recite for the Empress and all the sisters
Go ahead
The garden peony in the courtyard is bewitching but lack style
The lotus in the pond is clean but lack emotion
Only the peony is the true national beauty
When it blossoms, it moves the capital
What a line, "only the peony is the true national beauty"!
The superior and inferior is in the heart
No matter how red the garden peony is, it still lacks style
It cannot be compared to the national beauty of peony
Princess of Glory, we came here to enjoy the flowers
why do you look so unhappy?
Why ruin your mood by worrying too much?
Precious has enjoyed the flowers for too long, your makeup is coming off
It's indeed the powders bestowed by the Emperor
it smells so nice
What happened?
Young Mistress!
Call the Imperial Physicians!
Young Mistress, are you okay?
Are you okay?
It hurts
Niang Niang, it hurts
Call the Imperial Physicians now!
Help Precious Fucha into the palace
Jie Jie, if you're hurt, I...
Is Fucha Jie Jie okay?
Help her into the palace, hurry
Jie Jie, don't scare me!
How are you feeling?
Empress, it hurts
The Imperial physician will be here soon, don't worry
Your Servant is late, please forgive me
It's good you're here
Imperial physician Zhang, hurry and go see Precious Fucha
Yes
Reply to Your Majesty, after Young Mistress fell
her pulse became unstable, and it shook the fetus
and she was shocked
Your servant suggests
she be transported back to her palace to rest
Then I wiill write some prescriptions
and see if it will restore the fetus's vitals
Then go write the prescriptions now
Yes
Greetings to the Empress dowager
All rise
Thank you Empress dowager
I came as soon as I heard the news
How is Precious Fucha?
The Imperial physician has prescribed medicine to stablize the fetus
It hurts
Empress, Empress dowager
Precious Fucha is bleeding
It's useless now
What happened?
Empress dowager
How pitiful for Precious Fucha
The Empress's cat went crazy
and jumped on Precious
Precious was hit and shocked
that's how it happened
Where is the animal?
I've ordered them to catch it
Whose pet was it?
I am to blame,
that animal is called Song Zi
Princess of Regularity gave it to me
I was keeping it for fun
Song Zi is usually very tamed
But it went crazy today
it is really my fault
All rise
Yes
Hurry and send Precious Fucha back in a soft sedan chair
It's inconvenient to stay in the Empress's palace
Tell the Imperial physician to do his best
and see if he can keep the Imperial child
Everything else, leave it to heaven
Yes
What happened to Precious Smile?
Precious Smile tried saving Precious Fucha
and fell too
Maybe she's hurt somewhere
Imperial physician, take a look at Precious Smile
Yes
Reply to Empress dowager, the wound on Young mistress's neck is superficial
It will heal with some ointment
But this arm
will have to be treated with care
Please take her pulse too
this will ease our worries
Yes, let me take the pulse
Congratulations, Young mistress
What are you talking about?
Wan Jie Jie's arm is hurt, and you are congratulating her?
Congratulations, Young mistress
You are nearly two months pregnant
That's wonderful
Don't move, don't move
Sit down, sit down sit down
Imperial physician Zhang
it is true that Precious Smile is pregnant?
Your Servant has been practicing medicine for several decades
I am confident
Reply to Niang Niang, Precious Smile's body is frail
and she also fell, so the fetus's a little unstable
Let me write a prescription
for the Young mistress to use
If she get some rest, it won't be a problem
Then please take care of her, Imperial physician Zhang
I will put Precious Smile and her baby
in your hands
Your servant will try his best
Imperial physician Zhang is very skilled, don't worry
Please look after at Precious Fucha for now
Hui Chun
Your servant is here
Send more Imperial physicians to come assist Imperial physician Zhang
Yes, Niang Niang
Thank you for your attention, Your Majesty
I can't thank you enough
What a good time for the baby to come
Precious Fucha's baby will probably be gone
And yours came right after
What a fortune
What happened today was surprising
But you're too careless, Precious Smile
how can you not know you're pregnant?
You even tried to save her
Luckily you're not hurt
If something happened
it's a big incident that affects the Royal lineage
It's my mistake
Everyone around you were also too careless
How can they be absent minded about
something as big as a pregnancy
If something had happened today
I will banish them all to the Bureau of Cautious Punishment
Please don't be mad, Your Majesty
It's not their fault
I was careless myself
I thought the fatigue was caused by the spring season
I have always been unbalanced
it's normal for my periods to come late
And I noticed when the sisters were pregnant
they felt sick and nauseous
But I did not
The signs of pregnancy
depends on your physique
When I had Princess Wen Yi
I only started getting morning sickness when I was four or five months pregnant
Empress dowager, the Emperor does not have many offsprings
Now that Precious Smile is pregnant
it's really heaven sending blessings to Qing
You have to be careful in the first three months
You must rest quietly
you're hurt too
Yes, thank you Empress Dowager
Enough, stop looking
The Imperial physician said it's just a superficial wound
I wonder if it'll leave a scar
Even if it did, it's okay
Put some powders on and you won't see it
As long as you're okay
You're right, as long as the baby's okay
Liu Zhu, bring some water
Yes
Huan Bi, bring two good pillows
and let your mistress rest more comfortably
Yes
Jin Xi, go close the doors, don't let the wind in
Xiao Yun Zi, bring a softer cloud silk cover
Yes
No, I'm not that fragile
it's too much trouble
Fine, fine
I forgot how picky you are
You may go now
You sent them all away
who will serve me now?
I will, okay?
You're just getting better
why did you came here in such a hurry
Huan Er, I am really happy for you
But Precious Fucha just had a miscarriage today
and the Emperor's not back yet
I am really worry for you too
I won't let anything happen to my baby
Of course you won't,
but neither did Precious Fucha
Let me tell you,
there are too many miscarriages in this harem
I asked the Imperial physician
he said Lingering Xin had a miscarriage
because she slipped and fell
This time, Precious Fucha had an accident too
Don't you think
these accidents might not be accidents after all?
How is Precious Fucha?
She went back to Palace of Lasting Fortune
I took a look, she's still unconscious
The Imperial physicians are all there waiting
Young mistress, let's go in. This is scary
What's so scary?
It's all a mess
we won't get any sleep tonight
It's really the month of March, the fragrance of flowers and grass
Even late at night, it's not in the least inferior
Young mistress, I did what you told me
and opened the corner door
But, will Princess of Modesty really be here?
Princess of Modesty is someone who keeps her promises
Since she sent words, she probably won't break her promise
Young mistress tried to save Precious Fucha today
It really gave me a fright
It was too dangerous
You're not that close with Precious Fucha anyways,
why bother?
If I say someone pushed me,
will you believe me?
I suspects that person wanted
me to hit Precious Fucha's stomach
Then if Precious Fucha has a miscarriage,
I'll be the main culprit
Two birds with one stone
In the harem,
if you're pregnant, you'll become the target
Today, it's Precious Fucha
Tomorrow, it might be you, Young mistress
There will be many who can't sleep tonight
Yes
Those who couldn't sleep because of Precious Fucha's baby
can now get a good night's rest
But when they think you
they probably can't fall asleep again
I called the Empress here so late
I can't sleep
Neither can I
just in time to keep you company
I heard that when Precious Fucha woke up
and know the baby's gone
she started crying heavily
She is upset, it will pass
You still didn't catch that animal?
I tried my best
I see you still need help for something so trivial
Zhu Xi
Your servant is here
Is it ready?
Yes
Bring it in
Empress, take a close look
Precious Smile, take a look at this
There's no powder in this box
but I can still smell it
This is Precious Fucha's powders
I've also seen Precious Fucha's maid with this box
Did Niang Niang find this in the Empress's courtyard?
That's right
Everyone was busy looking at you and Precious Fucha
and I picked this up
What does Niang Niang suspect?
I heard that Precious Fucha had a miscarriage
because of a cat called Song Zi
suddenly jumped out
Don't you think that's weird?
Of course, cats get a little irritable in Spring
but Song Zi was trained
Why would it suddenly hurt someone?
And only jumped at Precious Fucha?
Maybe it was a coincidence
Look, you said it so hesitantly
you probably don't believe it either
What Niang Niang is trying to say
How much powder can Precious Fucha use by herself?
Empress Dowager
And you blame it on an animal?
I have eye problems
and you all treat me as if I'm blind!
Luckily I am clear in my heart
This animal killed my biological grandson
Please forgive, Empress Dowager
I've never been an Empress in my life
only when the late Emperor died, I became the Empress Dowager
So when the Emperor ascended the throne
I made you the Empress
just so the throne of the Empress
will remain in the hands of our family
Remember
there are some things I can turn the blind eye
but there are some things, I can't
Thank you for watching!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki