Episode 52
Greetings to your highness
and greetings to all sisters.
Rise
You've been in the palace for a while, but I havn't met you once.
So I had to invite you over to hang with your sisters in the palace.
His majesty knows I am a loner and don't enjoy personal visits
So he conveniently exempted me from daily greeting visits
despite his majesty's considerateness, how can you delay your greetings to her highness the Empress.
She is the holder of the harum
Heart felt respect is not necessarily represented by daily greetings
Not to mention that, of all the people sitting here, who knows who is speaking against her heart.
What do you mean by that?
Within the harem, who doesn't truly respect her highness
So what's true in the heart is what's said from the mouth?
You! Look your highness, look at Attendant Ye! You are way out of line!
Can you tell any difference from this and the expelled Concubine Wan!
May you blessed and healthy your highness. If you have no further instructions,,
Let's take it as I have greeted you.
I'll excuse myself.
Look! Look at her! She...
She? She did nothing wrong. What are you so annoyed about?
There, there have never been such an in-obedient person in the harem.
Well there is now.
It's getting late today
You are all dismissed
Excuse me please.
Consort Qi, stay
Of course
Your highness, It used to be Concubine Wan that was spoiled.
And that was understandable. But what is this Attendant Ye?
A mere female slave born inferior
How dare she shoucase any might in front of your highness
She WAS an inferior slave. But now she is his majesty's favourate
Should she gave birth to a prince and became noble because of her son
It would be most probable that
she will be bullying you and me
She? Not worthy enough to give birth to a prince
With the favor she is enjoying now, it's just a matter of time
Concubine Qi said it right.
It would be great if she' was infertile
As favored as she could be, she will have nothing to bank on eventually
Last time you used the pollen of Nerium oleander,
intending for the miscarriage of Concubine Wan
You still remember it?
Your highness, I
I agreed to keep your secret, and I will keep to it
Comparing to killing a fetus with pollen
preventative control would be much easier,
wouldn't it?
Think about what I said. Not for me
It's for your 3rd Prince to not have any risk
All the fabric is newly rewarded to you by his majesty, Why don't you pick what you like to make new cloths? My mistress
Keep the green and blue ones,
You guys can take whatever you like from the rest.
All your outfits are either green or blue, my mistress,
why not make some red or purple ones? They are pretty too.
I don't like them
Greetings, Attendant Ye.
Consort Qi ordered me to bring you some jujube soup
Do I have to drink it?
It's her highness's nice gesture
Go, tell your mistress you've done it
your highness, your highness
U scared me. What are you being so loud for?
Please forgive me, your highness, I didn't mean to.
Didn't I tell you to wait outside Chun Xi Chamber and see what happens？ Why are you back?
Attendant Ye is suffering from severe stomachache, his majesty decided on a thorough investigation
Why would Attendant Ye suffer from such severe stomachache？
Your majesty, I discovered that Attendant Ye had taken something extremely cold (Chinese Medicine concept)
damaging her mothering body,
It's likely, very likely, that
What's the matter?
Your majesty, Attendant Ye is likely to
not be able to have children
Who did it?
Why would she eat this thing so carelessly
That, I am not aware of.
All I know is that
The pain must have started right after she eats it.
Tell me!
What did she eat before the pain started?
Consort Qi ordered Cui Guo to bring some jujube soup, mistress started feeling unwell right after drinking it.
Consort Qi
Take Consort Qi to Chun Xi Chamber for me!
Yes your majesty
Your majesty,
Minister Zhang Tingyu requests to meet you.
- What's the matter? - He said the autumn flood in the south has destroyed dams, hundreds of thousands are homeless
- Where is he? - He is waiting at the Supreme Study Hall
Go to Yang Xin Chamber. Su Peisheng
Yes your majesty
Keep an eye on Consort Qi. I will let her explain
what happened today.
His majesty is going to Yang Xin Chamber
You really did that?
Yes
The physician told me,
Attendant Ye is infertile
That's a very clean cut you did. But his majesty is not stupid.
Your highness
I did it on your instructions
You must save me
On my instructions!
When did I ever instruct you to hurt people?
You made the call, you hurt the woman
If I would like to give you a pull, that's because I am merciful
If I couldn't, you just had asked for it
Your highness
Since your Pollen scheme
I have always protected you, lead you
But a mother like you is really useless.
Your father Governor Li had been expelled by the late emperor for taking bribes
Even since then, you have been unable to protect your son
If it weren't for my protection
You think your 3rd Prince could grow-up uneventfully?
Every time I ask you to do something, it's done stupidly.
When I knew that you were stupid enough to have Cui Guo send the soup, I knew there's no way to keep you.
- Your highness, I, I really... - Everyone knows you did what you did immediately
If I keep protecting you, it's gonna take me with you
And take 3rd Prince with you
It's because he has a mother like you that he is not valued by his majesty
Tell me yourself, with what you have done, can you help 3rd Prince ascend the throne?
I am a useless mother
I am... Useless
With a mother like you, 3rd Prince will never become the Crown Prince.
Now I give you 2 options, one, I report to his majesty that
you intended to hurt Concubine Wan's fetus, and poison Attendant Ye,
Then he will vent his anger on 3rd Prince. By then one of you will be executed,
the other will never touch the throne
No, no
2, you handle this yourself
I will help you fulfill 3rd, let him ascend the throne
What to do, is your pick
Your highness, your highness
I can't die, I can't die
Please help me, help me! I have a child
Help me
You did every stupid thing possible, I cannot help you
Also, you don't need to think about fighting me, slander that I instigated you to do evil.
for one, his majesty won't believe you,
for another, with the Dowager, I will always be the irreplaceable Empress
You can only pray for your blessings
3rd Prince, mother is leaving
make me proud
Consort Qi, why did you do this
An evil bitch like her,
letting her hang herself is too easy on her
Your majesty, Consort Qi was just making a wrong call
Your majesty, her funeral...
She hang herself in fear of guilt, and cannot be awarded better titles.
To avoid gossip, and considering 3rd Prince, I will not dig deeper.
She has served me for over 10 years. How could she be so messed up
It's unvelievable
Your majesty, Consort Qi has served you for 21 years
Now that Qi died, although 3rd has grown up
he needs someone to look after him
I oversee the harem,
so I see any child in the harem as my child
And I have always fostered 3rd
I will take the responsibilities of a mother
I feel much relieved hearing you say this
The Dowager is old, and suffering from illness,
You have always loved 3rd.
It's the most suitable arrangement that you foster him
Yes
Greetings your highness
Take care of your body. Don't catch a cold
Thanks. If you are just here to see me, you have seen me.
you can go back. now
I know you are heart broken
but there are plenty of excellent physicians in the palace.
You will have your own child.
Heart broken? Why would I be heart broken?
The reason you are visiting me, is because I am like your sister Concubine Wan,
We are both schemed. Right?
same, but different
It doesn't matter whether we are alike
just one life
All right, you take some rest. I shall not disturb you.
Even without the soup from Consort Qi, I would not want any kids
I'm just suspecting
The soup came in a strange way
Even my cat smelled the unusual scent.
Since she wants me dead so bad
I shall fulfill her wish
Whether it's infertilization medication or poison,
I don't care
You want to die so bad?
I was alone and free
Who knows I would be kept in this place where I can't see the sun
and live with a man I don't like at all
He took away any chance I might have had
what chance?
It's not important anymore
I'll see it as Qi giving me an end
I don't want his child anyway
Don't say this to anyone
Mistress, Eunice Su is here
Greetings Concubine Hui, greetings Attendant Ye
Imperial Decree.
Second Class Female Attendant Ye has been unfairly treated. I feel for her.
I hereby promote Second Class Female Attendant Ye to Noble Lady, with the title of Ning.
End of Decree
Thank you your majesty
Congratulations Noble Lady Ning
This way please Minister Wen
- Here you are. - This is the new pregnancy medication I prepared for you
Use it for now
Have you not rested well recently? You look tired.
Prince said he would be back in 40 days
It's been 50, and we havn't heard from him
Miss is surely anxious. Last night she had nightmares and didn't sleep well,
So she doesn't look too good
Nightmares are not to believe.
He should be back soon
- He won't. - What do you say? - Prince Guo won't be back.
He's dead
Minister Wen, you...
What are you talking about?
How can you curse him like this?
He's the father of my child
Huan, when have I ever lied to you?
Prince Guo went to Yunnan and Tibet, and hasn't come back in time,
There has been no information about him in the Court
His majesty ordered a search mission
and learnt that the ship he took sank
Not even a body was recovered
Miss
Huan, the Yellow River is so fierce,
It broke the steel ship into fragments
Even the body was recovered
It wouldn't have been recognisable
You are lying, you are lying, you are lying
I'm not lying. I swear with our friendship. I'm not lying
He's dead
I can't even see him for one last time
Huan, clear your mind, dead is dead
dead is dead
Not even his spirit came to my dream
- Huan - What can we do about this, miss, miss
- Huan - Miss
Why would he die, out of no where
why wouldn't even his body be recovereable
Actually they found the wreckage of the ship he took
There is nothing wrong with it, but
but what
but the fuselage isn't mounted by steel nails,
but tied together with glue and robe.
Once the ship travels in the water, the glue and robe would break, and the ship would sink.
The ship was sent by the government
It shouldn't be like that
True. There wasn't a problem with the ship on the way there. According to the ship builders,
Although the ship looked similar to what they built,
the bottom of the ship was different
So it's evident that when the ship was parked, it was replaced.
Who did this? Who did this?
Who did this?
- miss - who did this, who did this - miss, miss
Huan, what happened happened. We don't know who did this
before we find the body, his majesty wants to keep this a secret
- I don't believe it, I don't believe it. He won't die! -Miss - I don't believe it, don'tbelieve it
Minister Wen, please stop. Miss is pregnant, telling her this is killing her.
Aren't you always considerate like her brother? Why are you being silly now?
I don't want to see her wait so miserably for someone never coming back
Huan, I know you are sad, but you have to mqake considerations for things now
If you still decides to have this child, I will give you the relive-after-death pill
And Jin Xi will report your death,
I will take you away from here, and find a quiet place to start a life
Trust me, I will take good care of you. I'll take care of your child like mine own
Whatever Prince Guo can do, I can do it too.
Minister Wen, whatever you say now, she won't hear it.
Why don't you wait until she calms down.
Minister Wen
How could you treat Prince's child like your own?
How could you do what he can?
How can you compare with him!
I just want to see him everyday
I just want to see him smile everyday
No, even occasionally is enough
Even his smile isn't for me
I will be content.
But he has dies now
From now on, in my life
I will never see him again
I don't believe it
It's impossible
Miss, you are up.
you have slept for hours,
you havn't eaten for quite a while
why not drink the porridge while it's warm
Doctor Wen said
Your were to excited, and it had affected your pregnancy
You cannot keep being sad
It's important to keep healthy
Can, can I feed you?
The dream still clear,
things in the past have become less recognizable, in the spring blossoms and autumn moon.
Like looking at a flower through the fog, like watching the moon from the water
It floats back and forth
You came, with your voice; you left, quietly
It's never been predictable
Although in love, although in sync
We got it, and we lost it
There's a poem to be matched with, there's a song to be responded to
There are two hearts to be tied together
Hoping for eternal love, hoping for eternal matrimony
But all I have left is the violin and the flute
We had the connection with our love, we had the commitment with our heart
We leaned on each other with our bodies
Don't forget me, don't betray me
But what about hatred and deceit
What I got, I don't want, What I want, I don't get
Fate is mock using
Destiny is playing us. My heartly love,
finally flew away with falling blossoms.
Looking forward to a bright moon, looking forward to the morning sun,
I look forward to the breeze in the spring.
But the wind is vicious, bringing rain and snow with it
It damaged the plum blossoms, and broke the tree branch
The phoenix is about to fly. It makes sound with it's feather
It left, far, without any trace.
Listening to the rain, dropping on the sycamore tree
My memory sways with the wind
Greetings to my imperial mother from your son Hong Shi
Jian Qiu, help 3rd Prince up.
Yes. 3rd Prince
Now, you should call me mother instead.
Yes
From now on, I am your nother
Although I'm not your birth mother,
the mother-son relationship we have is something worth celebrating
I look forward to it being a great and eternal one.
I promise to be a good son with my full heart , my imperial mother
I mean mother
That's good
Consort Qi has served his majesty for 21 years
I saw her enter the Prince's Mansion as a princess,
become the vice mistress after having you
and got conferred the title of Consort after the coronationa
Now she committed such a big mistake
but in the end, she left heir for the imperial family.
That's a big credit for her
Now she ended up miserablly
Although his majesty isn't happy about it,
I'm going to order guards for her grave palace
as we have been sisters for years,
serving his majesty
and that she also had you
Hope she can rest in peace
I am beyond grateful for your forgiveness, mother,
Your highness, please don't be sad
You have been heart broken for days
for Consort Qi
How that 3rd Prince gets taken care of by you
she will rest in peace
It makes everyone sad
if you keep being so heart broken
That sounds reasonable,
but Qi and I served his majesty for so many years together
There is no way her sudden departure
won't break my heart
She made such a bad call
Mother
My late birth mother had un-erasable guilt when she was alive
I promise to work harder int he future
and help father with his worries
So I won't waste all the time father and you spent on me
Good, good
You are a good kid
you are my good kid
What's the matter? Seems like you have some worries
Is t because you think I havn't
been taking care of Concubine Wan recently?
Not having Fang Ruo visit her
I'm just worried about your health your highness
Once old, you are useless
Always having health problems
Right now, the are people brave enough to
do despicable things under my watch
Once I die
I'll never be able to protect you guys
I am guilty of execution for making your highness feel sad
Take it easy. As long as I am alive
I will protect you
Get up
Thanks your highness
Although Fang Ruo hasn't been out visiting Concubine Wan
But I assme the nuns at the temple
won't dare to do anything obserd
Her highness the Empress has arrived
Listen, what a big presentation
May you all good imperial mother
No
it's good enough that you are all good
The impress need not to worry about whether the old lady is all good
Now that your highness has taken the medicine, I will excuse myself.
Imperial mother, that's harsh, I feel scared and uneasy.
You are scared? I should be scared
You forced Qi to die with such a good scheme
and took 3rd as your own son
What a clean cut
Please, imperial mother
I havn't done that
Dare you say Qi's death wasn't for you?
If you say it like this
I cannot really debate it
Of course not
so you have no witness
You killed Qi's Cui Guo, pushing her into the lotus pool
What you don't know is
that Cui Guo had come to me
and told me everything
in fear of getting involved.
But Cui Guo was indeed not killed by me
Anyway, it's not the first time
that you do evil
The death of your dear sister, Impress Chun Yuan
You know about it better than I do
Now that you are aware of this
you should also be aware that
all I did was for the family of Uranara
You should know better than I that
with a soft temper like my sister's
she could not have ruled the harem at all
Not to mention suppressing concubines and balancing interests
Only I can do that
Good, you can take responsibility for what you did
Counting the miscarriages of
Noble ladies Xin and Fucha
There are quite some lost lives under your belt
Isn't that enough?
Fucha used her pregnancy to get favor in multiple occasions
she didn't deserve to give birth to a prince
If your child was still alive
For the emperor's favor, you will do the same with your child
I am a cursed person, with my 1st Prince died early
But I know
that neither Uya nor Uranara are significant families
It took you so much effort to become the Dowager
and you could make me the Empress to further the glory of the family
I did everything with care
to prolong the power of our family
I did nothing wrong
Of course you did nothing wrong
I've never been an Empress
I only became the Empress Dowager after the late Emperor died
So as soon as the Emperor ascended the throne
I made you the Empress
To ensure the Harem Throne
is in the hands of our own people
So I pretended not to see
many of your wrongdoings
But those in the wombs of the concubines
are my very own grandchildren
I love them more
No matter whose son ascends the throne
you will always be the Noble Empress Dowager
Why did you need to kill the mother and take the child
being so cruel?
How could there be two Empress Dowagers in the harem
If I have to fight and get rid of her at that time,
it's not as convenient as it is now.
Yes I am guilty
But I have the whole Uranara family in my mind
Do you think
there is anyone capable of the Harem Throne?
I am the only candidate
And I am the only
Empress that mothers the whole nation
So as much as you are angry Imperial Mother
You can't not support me
which is supporting yourself
Great, great
Now you are the one and only in the harem.
That I have to pay tribute to the teaching and protection from you, my imperial mother
I am beyond grateful. You have been unwell for a long time. There is really not much need to worry about me.
It's more important to focus on recovering from the illness
So his majesty won't suspect
that your illness
has to do with Long Keduo
Truly, you are more and more like an Empress
I do hope you can hold on to this throne
But I need to tell you
you need to leave some space, either as a person, or in handling youraffairs
Killing everyone will cut your own options
Thanks for your teaching imperial mother
With you leading by example, I will surely be a student better than the teacher
You can just relax
If there's nothing else, I'll excuse myself for now
Zhu Xi
look, this is the kid I taught personally
Chun Yuan was too soft-hearted
Yi Xiu is too hard-hearted
I
Your highness, you need to take care of your health
It's not that I don't look after my health
I'm just afraid that if Yi Xiu keeps doing what she is doing
Uranara and Uya families
will end in her hands
Of course I want the Empress of the Dynasty
is always from my family
But if there is no one to balance her out in the harem,
Her vice will kill herself
and kill all heir of Ashinjero
Where have you been miss
you havn't eaten anything in 3 whole days
even an iron man can't survive this
If you don't want to eat
just drink the medicine
It's what I begged Doctor Wen
to prepare for you
It has blah blah blah blah
blah blah blah blah
They are all good for clearing clots (fetus)
If you drink it, there will no know trouble from your womb
You aren't keeping it anyway
since you aren't eating or drinking anything
Why not drink it so that the poor baby can go earlier
and doesn't have to live through the miseries with you
It's very strong medicine
There's no way back after you take it
It won't hurt too much
you know about Dr Wen's skills
Please take it, miss
Sister, you cannot take this
You need to keep this child
it's the only child of Prince
You can't not have it
Jin Xi
I won't take the medicine
I will keep this child
Not only this child
but my family
Yun Li is dead
There is no one that can protect me like he did
I need to learn to protect myself
and those I need to protect
miss, this is the Zhen Huan I know
I cannot die
For this child
for my parents, my family
for Yun Li who died innocently
I'll live
I'll live well