Fire! Fire!
Hurry! Fire!
Hurry up!
Fire!
Who's there? Why are you acting suspiciously?
This is the person who started the fire. What?
His majesty has arrived.
Precious Hui how are your injuries?
Jie Jie is scared stiff.
It's all my fault.
Why did I have to invite her to play chess with me?
Please don't worry Imperial Concubine Wan
Precious Hui's mental state hasn't been greatly affected.
But her injuries are a bit severe.
It was perfectly fine how could a fire start? Where were the servants?
Please forgive me. I was being negligent in my duties.
However the one who started the fire has been caught and is waiting for judgement.
The fire was intentionally started?
Yes
Bring him up.
Bring him up!
it was this servant who was behaving suspiciously by Sui Yu Xuan.
I have already found flint and oil that he carried.
Which palace are you from?
Emperor,
This person is from Yi Kun Palace and Promise Nian's servant. His name is Su Xi.
I don't know how I offended this servant
to have him wish for my place to burn down and for me to die.
Emperor, both her and my father are heroes for subduing Nian Geng Yao.
Promise Nian and I don't get along, Since her punishment she obviously hates the two of us.
Otherwise how would a lowly servant have the guts to burn down Sui Yu Xuan?
There had to be someone behind this.
Although Promise Nian is unhappy, she only felt hate towards me.
But I've involved Precious Qi and Mei Jie jie.
I originally didn't want to ruthless and kill them all
and wanted to give her a chance to reform.
Who knew that she would become even more devious.
Let it pass.
Tell Empress and Consort Jing to interrogate Su Xi into the night.
If this is really the truth, immediately send her to the cold palace and reward her with suicide.
You don't have to report back to me.
Yes.
My plase is smaller than Sui Yu Xuan
but bear with it and just live here.
I'm very happy to be able to live here.
Do you remember? When we were little we would lie on bed like this and talk.
Yes.
It's almost new years.
Interrogating Nian Shi Lan
should not be pushed into the new year
or it may be inauspicious.
Today is the 25th. The latest is the 29th.
She has to die.
Or I would have burned myself for nothing.
The Empress and Consort Jing
have always been Nian Shi Lan's enemies.
Now that she's in their hands
even if she didn't send someone to commit arson
there is enough evidence.
right now
the evidence is concrete.
And you, really, why would you burn yourself?
Thankfully it's still cold out. If it was in the summer
it would definitely fester.
At worse it will leave a scar.
Exchanging it for Nian Shi's life isn't a bad deal.
If the Emperor sees my wounds
only then he will realize how scary a fire can be.
He will think of
if it had been on your body and how heartbroken he would feel.
Only then he would thoroughly hate Nian Shi Lan.
If she didn't force us to,
I wouldn't realize how ruthless I could be.
When Nian Shi Lan dies
I don't know who to fight with.
Isn't it easy enough to fight with someone in the Harem?
You can fight anyone.
But it's also simple to not fight.
And let it someone kill you silently without a trace.
New people are always coming in.
Are you worried that the rest of your days will be dull?
I'm just concerned about your injury. Does it hurt?
I'm fine.
When your wound heals
I'll give you a soothing balm.
It's the best to remove scars.
Promise Nian is not repentant
and has evil intentions,
she even had the nerve to order her servant Su Xi to burn down Sui Yu Xuan.
Such a cruel act.
I will pass a harsh punishment; suicide.
Otherwise there will be no justice in the Harem.
The Empress is fair in her judgement, we respectfully consent.
Because she served the Emperor for many years,
I will show mercy and allow her to leave a whole corpse.
Jian Qiu. Notify Eunuch Su and prepare poison, a blade, and a white cloth.
And let her choose which way to go.
This will be to remember her for serving the Emperor.
You are merciful. If it was me who saw her do such devious things, I would have
beheaded her to relieve my anger.
You may all sit.
Yes.
Imperial Consort Xiang,
What's wrong?
In your reply, I have not been feeling well.
I've eaten a lot of medicine but it still isn't better. I apologize for my appearance.
Sit down.
Yes.
You must take care of Wen Yi and prepare for the new year.
No wonder you are exhausted. You must care for your health.
Empress you spent the night interrogating Su Xi and must be tired.
You should rest today.
I will take my leave first then.
Okay,
You may all leave.
We take our leave.
Jin Xi,
What time did Enuch Su say that he will send miss Nian on her path?
In the cold palace death sentences are carried out at dusk.
Help me with my hair and makeup . I want to see Madam Hua on her way.
You certainly have the guts.
You even come to the cold palace like this.
I've come to this place more than you.
Back then it was here that I saw Consort Li become crazy.
You are dreaming again.
You have hurt me to this point.
I won't let you get away with it even if I am a ghost.
No one wants to harm you. You reap what you sow.
You drowned Consort Chun, right? You were also the one who put cassava in Princess Wen Yi's food right?
You ordered Consort Yu to poison my food
and pushed Consort Mei into the water.
Wrongly accusing Consort Mei of faking a pregnancy to get favor.
But you did all of it.
I know.
That evil woman Cao Qing Mo would only stab me in the back with you directing her.
With her ability? She doesn't have the guts.
You really don't understand people.
You used Wen Yi to compete for affection
even to the point when you don't care if you are playing with her life.
Imperial Concubine Xiang is her birth mother!
Why wouldn't she hate you?
Did you think that she only recently started to hate you?
Three feet of ice doesn't occur in one night.
You should have known earlier that she became unfaithful to you.
With my status back then,
even the old hag Empress had to back off.
Cao Qing Mo was only a dog by my side.
Why would I care about her?
Too bad but she is a person.
People are more complicated than dogs.
Wrench. You are as crafty as your father.
If it wasn't your dad who set up that plan
the Nian family wouldn't have been burried.
You became allies
just to ensure that I die?
If it wasn't the fact that the Nian family became arrogant and prideful after an accomplishment
This wouldn't have happened.
You forgot that your husband is the Emperor.
How can anyone else sleep on the Emperor's bed?
My brother is a meritorious official. For our kingdom he settled the dispute in the northwest.
A military expliot
No matter how much he contributed he is still the Emperor's official.
How can he behave as though he's above the Emperor?
Unless he intended to throw a coup.
Why would you be here?
I came with my miss.
Imperial Concubine Wan is inside?
With the Empress's order's I need to send miss Nian on her way now.
You send her in your way and the miss will see her off in her way.
Quickly go inside so you don't miss the time.
Good fortunes to you madam.
Eunuch Su please rise.
Under the Empress's orders
Please select one.
The Empress's orders?
Where's the Emperor's imperial order? Bring it.
The Emperor's intentions
are to let the Empress take care of everything.
Without the Emperor's orders I refuse to die.
The Emperor can personally sentence my brother to death.
Why can't he give one to me?
The Emperor said
he doesn't want to hear anything about you.
The Emperor really despises me to this point?
Go ask for his Imperial Order.
I'll wait.
Eunuch Su, just let it go for now
Let me say a few goodbyes to Promise Nian
Yes. Please go ahead.
I will wait outside.
I'm sorry, I got used to calling you Niang Niang
Now to call you Promise
is new to me.
The heater has cooled, go add some more charcoal.
Yes, but staying here by yourself is too dangerous.
Just go, if anything happens
Eunuch Su and them are outside.
The Emperor hates you..
Do you know? The Emperor has never hated me.
He used to spoil me.
No matter what mistakes I made
how angry he was,
he couldn't stay away from me for too long.
The reason why the Emperor likes you, do you know?
It's because of your beauty?
The palace never is in need of beauties.
You are saying that the Emperor spoiled me because I was Niang Geng Yao's sister?
Consort Duan was also a general's daughter. Actually you know very well in your heart.
Why do you need to lie to yourself? You're lying!
Why wouldn't the Emperor have real feelings for me?
Maybe he did. But even if they existed
Nian Geng Yao was domineering for so many years.
These real feelings
would have dissipated until there was nothing left.
How would a wrench like you know anything?
I remember the year I first entered the lord's estate.
and I became a side concubine.
I became the Emperor's most loved woman.
The lord's estate had so many women
but everyone was afraid of him. Only I wasn't.
He brought me to ride horses,
to hunt.
He said he only liked me.
But there were so many women in the lord's estate.
It made me so angry.
Tonight he would stay at one concubine's place.
The next he would stay at a different one's.
Just like that I waited and waited.
I waited until it was morning but he still didn't come.
Have you tasted the feeling of staying up until morning?
I knew he was the Emperor
so I knew that at night he never belonged to just me.
Of course.
You never liked the Emperor like I did.
Then I got pregnant.
The Emperor was really happy.
But then he became unhappy.
although he didn't say it
I could tell
that there would only be 3rd prince who grew up in his estate.
I knew he was worried.
So I said "don't worry"
I will give birth to a prince.
But not long after I drank pregnancy medicine given by Consort Duan
and I lost my child!
The Imperial Doctor told me
that it was already a fetus that became a male.
You lost your kid,
so you had to take my kid to accompany him to death?
He was only 4 months old.
Yet you had to sentence him to death
I didn't kill your child.
It was because you were pathetic and kneeled for only and hour before having a miscarriage.
You couldn't keep your own child.
Why do you blame me?
I hated how the Emperor took special notice of you.
I never saw
the Emperor spoil a woman so much.
With you
The Emperor would not care about me anymore.
I didn't want to keep waiting until morning.
If any women compete with me for the Emperor's favor
they have to die.
I did tell miss Yu to kill you.
But I didn't want to kil your child.
You didn't?
Even if you didn't have that intention
but if it wasn't for your "Happily Desirable" incense
why would my body become so weak?
And kneel for only an hour before having a miscarriage?
"Happily Desirable" incense
Do you know why you never got pregnant after your miscarriage?
Did you know that your incense had large amounts of musk?
How many years did you use it?
Of course you wouldn't ever have children
You are lying. That incense was a gift from the Emperor.
The Emperor.
No, it can't be.
If it wasn't the Emperor's orders
why wouldn't any doctors tell you that you had musk in your system?
Which caused you to become unable to become pregnant. Even your miscarriage
was the Emperor's orders.
Consort Duan's pregnancy medicine only protected the Emperor's reputation.
No matter how much safflower you gave to Consort Duan
you won't be able to get your child back.
Why? Why?
Because you are Nian's daughter.
Niang Geng Yao already had a mutinous intent.
The Emperor wouldn't let you give birth to a child with the Nian bloodline.
Emperor!
You have made me suffer from so much.
Shi Lan's funeral is completed?
She died in a very cruel manner.
When the Emperor found out he became quiet for a while.
In the end he still gave her dignity.
He buried her as a Noble Consort and gave her the posthumous name of Dun Su.
It's a pity that although she will be buried as a Noble Consort
it's almost the new year and there's only grass.
Kind hearted... When was she ever kind hearted?
The people will think it is irony when they hear it.
No matter if it is sarcasm or praise.
Although when she died she was only a "promise"
But the Emperor
still gave her face after her death.
When she was alive she didn't get any.
Dignity given after death is only for the living people to see.
The reason why the Emperor did this was so no one would doubt his reputation.
And save some face for himself.
Jie jie sees this clearly
How can I not? Right now the only ones getting affection
are you and Precious Qi.
You guys are monopolizing the best time.
So what if we are getting affection during this period of time?
If we are like Nian Shi Lan
and lose our ability to see clearly because of our competition for his love
That is scary.
Today you seem to have a mixed feelings toward her.
I thought I hated her guts.
But now she died,
I only feel dreary.
When she entered the estate
She never would have imagined that after so many years,
she would be plotted against by the person closest to her.
And resulted in today's outcome.
Isn't the palace like this?
Plotting to get affection and ranks.
What we can calculate,
why can't the Emperor?
If we don't plot can't we live?
After I woke up this morning I discovered that the wrinkles by my eyes have deepened.
I remembered my age.
Plotting and plotting
for over half my life.
Madam, Imperial Concubine Xiang passed away.
Make preparations, I'll be right over.
Let's go.
A few days ago I saw that she didn't look too good.
How can she suddenly die?
Imperial Doctor secretly told me that the Emperor and Empress Dowager can't keep her.
They told her servants to drug her.
The symptoms of the drug is often sleeptalking
and she was the one who exposed Nian Shi Lan
Now that Nian Shi Lan died
everyone will think that Imperial Concubine died of grief.
The Empress Dowager told the imperial doctors to keep it quiet.
Then can only pretend to be deaf and mute.
Cao Qin Mo was good at scheming.
But no matter how deep it was it could never compare to the Emperor and Empress Dowager.
To forward herself consort Xiang betrayed consort Hua.
It means that someday she may betray someone else.
Princess Wen Yi is a pitiful child.
She lost her mother.
I think
If she were to be under your care
she would become very obedient and intelligent.
I don't think the Emperor would have any objections.
I really like Princess Wen Yi, but this kind of thing
isn't something we can be in charge of.
You love her so much you would treat her as though she is your real child.
I am willing to help you.
If so
I will give her everthing that I can.
The wound has healed,
but from the wound's appearance
it may reoccur.
Please forgive me for my lack of knowledge.
Don't blame yourself. This has always been the reason why my body is weak.
I will have to ask you to come may times.
You spoke too seriously. Then I will come tomorrow.
The medicine is already being prepared.
Please use it on time. I will take my leave.
Imperial Doctor Wen please take care.
Miss, this is a new medicine the Doctor Wen prescribed.
This is too bitter, bring some honey.
Yes.
What's wrong?
Why doesn't the wound seem to be healing?
Thankfully it is winter. If it was hot then it would probably become inflamed.
You are already being very careful with your diet.
You don't eat fish or shrimp. But...
My health has always been weak.
Maybe if I have medicine for a few more days it will become better.
It's late, we should sleep.
I don't know why, but recently I am always feeling tired.
Jiejie should also sleep.
These western expedition essays were found when we were taking things from Nian Geng Yao's estate.
They weren't seen as very valuable
so they were just found.
From what I have seen, the writings are all treasonous.
I brought it here immediately for your Majesty to handle.
I have sentenced Nian Geng Yao to death.
It is not just that.
Inside it refers to history using his name to keep track of years.
It says that your Majesty's name for the year isn't good.
The Emperor is only mediocre and is jealous of Nian Geng Yao's skills
And in the future would definitely dispose of Nian Geng Yao.
Insolent.
Please calm down your Majesty.
Who wrote this book?
Nian Geng Yao's Chief of staff Wang Jing Qi.
It is treacherous and heresy.
If this book is spread through the villages,
My honorable name
will be ruined by this villain.
Please calm down.
Send an order.
Wang's female family members
will be sent to Pi Jia Ren as servants.
The males will be sent to Ning Gu Ta.
As for his relatives, any who are in the government will be removed.
I cannot allow these kind of people
to leave their legacy.
Your official accepts the order.
The Emperor's fury
scared me so much I was sweating.
The Emperor truly cannot accept him.
However,
although Wang Jing Qi is at fault
and deserves death,
Hanging his head
in front of the market for ten years...
Aiya.
Think about how this situation
will make so many peasants tremble.
It seems as though brother Zhen doesn't support his Majesty's punshiment.
Brother E Min don't joke around.
His Majesty is wise how can I not support it?
It's just that Nian Geng Yao's is already dead
but the Emperor still punishes his assistant so harshly.
It feels that the Imperial Court
has an unsettling feeling.
This unsettling feeling
Is as a result of both of our work, right?
Of course. Tang Ke has committed a crime.
But his entire family will be involved.
It's a pity.
Brother Zhen,
I've heard that Qi Pan street has a lot of
nice paintings and books. Shall we go take a look?
I was just thinking about going.
E Min should we go together now?
Today before I left my wife told me to go home earlier.
If you see something good you must tell me
Definitely, definitely.
Greetings to Imperial Concubine Wan and Precious Hui.
Madam, the Emperor has ordered
you to go to the Hall of Mental Cultivation in a bit.
I know.
Then today we should stop.
Tomorrow we can continue playing. You should prepare yourself
So you don't make the Emperor wait.
Okay.
Oh yeah Cai Yue. Why hasn't Doctor Wen come to take my pulse today?
You go take a look and see what's going on.
Doctor Wen always comes before dinner, not this early.
So in the end,
It was because I remembered the wrong time.
The Official's report says
That I use his wife's life to threaten him.
Now that he is arrested no wonder he would blame you.
How do you plan on handling it?
What you do is understandable.
After all, Yun E is a traitor.
Killing him is necessary.
You were mad today,
due to Yun E's treasonous words right?
Huan Huan
I am more concerned with what the public thinks of me.
Then your majesty,
Then I will send an order
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty needs to go.
I know. I will go there in a bit.
Yes.
Then I will take my leave first.
Today marks seven days after consort Hua's death.
She's already dead.
Why do you bring it up?
Since I witnessed Shi Lan's death,
I don't know why
but I feel uneasy.
Sometimes I would be speaking to the Emperor
when suddenly her face would appear in front of me.
I don't know if I will end up like her.
Miss Shi doesn't have a son.
But if you have one,
your status will definitely be stable.
It's not that easy to have one whenever.
Doctor Wen has been prescribing medicine and I've been eating it.
But there is nothing.  How about
we go to the peasants and get some home remedies.
Maybe it would be more effective than the Imperial Doctors'.
When you get married,
I wonder if you will still speak of nonsense.
I am thinking of ideas for you.
If my idea isn't good then that's fine.
But you are making fun of me.
What teasing?
In about a year,
you won't be by my side serving me anymore.
Unless you were going to stay with my forever.
Miss,
Let me be honest.
I don't want to get married.
I only want to stay with you forever.
In here everything is good
but everything isn't good.
Miss suffering it by herself
is too tiring.
You are talking nonsense again.
If you wait until you are an old girl
then you really won't be able to get married.
Miss Wan Bi today is my turn.
Liu Ju is waiting for you to go to sleep.
Madam Mei is already resting,
You should also hurry and rest. I will go now.
Today at the Yang Xin Palace Miss why did you
ask for mercy for Lord Duan's son?
Back when I lost affection and my child
The palace had so many people but
besides Consort Jing and Mei
There was only Lord Dun who came to see me.
Miss your heart is kind.
This is your repayment for the small favor from years ago.
Lord Dun is arrogant and domineering.
But to his wife and kids
he would be willing to lose his life to protect them.
Although he has made many mistakes
he isn't a bad husband.
Good fortunes to your Majesty, good fortunes Empress.
Hurry and rise.  Thank you your Majesty
Jie Jie came late. Your punishment is that after you peel the walnuts
you cannot eat them yourself.
It's cold outside so I used a hand warmer. Halfway here
it became cold so I went back to get another one.
Thus it resulted in my late arrival.
It's indeed cold. Hurry and warm up.
Eat some of the food.  Thank you your Majesty.
Of course.
Otherwise if you eat it cold
your stomach won't feel good.
Thank you Niang Niang.
Your Majesty,
Right now there are many open spots for the Imperial Harem.
Are you going to select some sisters
fill the empty spaces?
Continue speaking.
According to the Harem's guidelines,
there should be one imperial noble consort, two noble consorts, four consorts,
six imperial concubines, and the rest are unlimited.
Right now of the consorts
there are Consort Duan, Consort Jing, and Consort Qi.
Regarding imperial concubines there is only Imperial Concubine Wan.
There aren't enough people.
The imperial noble consort and noble consort are of no worries.
Of the consorts
we could add someone.
Choose a good date
and Imperial Concubine Wan will become a consort.
My qualifications are low.
This isn't a matter of qualifying.
Imperial Concubine Wan has wonderful virtues.
Naturally you should become a consort. But you came in the palace late
and don't have any sons.
In the future if you bear a son
that would be the best time
to become a consort.  -It doesn't matter.
She will become Consort Wan.
The second of the second month is a good date.
Thank you your Majesty, thank you Empress.
Rise.  Congratulations Jie Jie
You are busy congratulating Imperial Concubine Wan, how do you know you don't have good news?
Precious An will become Imperial Concubine An.
Then choose a good date for those two.
So the sisters can have the same good fortune.
In addition, Lingering Xin has been serving me for a long time.
She will become Precious Xin.
Thank your your Majesty.
Thank you Empress.
Thank you jie jei.  - Congratulations mei mei.
Rise.  - Thank you Emperor.
It's still early.
I will go look at some reports.
Imperial Concubine Wan will come with me
to help with my ink.
His Majesty is leaving.
Sending off his Majesty.