~ Episode 21 ~
Precious Smile
Why are you here in the middle of the night?
Because it's the middle of the night,
Lingrong Meimei must not travel alone.
So I came to keep her company
Jiejie is a master instrument player
I was afraid that the song alone would be monotonous
so I specially invited her to come along.
Singing with instrumental accompaniment is of course the best
You've been troubled, Precious Smile
I don't know what Princess of Glory likes to listen to
The flowers are in full bloom and the moon is full
Sing a romantic song then
Yes
the song was lovely
but there were no romance
Lingering An, you're not trying to put me off are you?
Although this song did not mention love directly
but every word is about the joy of the woman
after the couple proclaimed their love for eachother
And the two golden partridges
also meant a pair of lovers
If so,
why didn't Lingering An sing it with affection?
Did you not sing well because you see His Majesty and I together,
and felt unhappy?
Replying to Princess of Glory,
Lingering An caught a cold in the morning,
so her voice is not as usual.
What a coincidence
Several days ago Lingering An was singing for His Majesty
song after song
Her voice was just fine!
Songzhi
Pour Lingering An a cup of sweet rose wine
Fend off the cold, and continue singing
Yes
Niang Niang, when I'm singing,
I can't consume anything too sweet, greasy, or spicy.
You can't sing songs, or drink wine
His Majesty summoned you here
It's fine if you disregard me,
but His Majesty...
Since Princess of Glory granted the wine, just drink it
Yes
Pick a good song to sing
Are you alright?
Your Majesty and Niang Niang,
A song accompanied by music
is definitely the most elegant
But sometimes, a poem accompanied by music
can also be refreshing
May I try?
Yes
Precious Smile is quite the scholar of the inner palace
Alright, His Majesty and I are tired
You've worked hard
Zhou Ning Hai
Yes
Escort them out
We take our leave
Go
Your Majesty
It's late
Go to bed
Young mistresses have worked hard tonight
This is Princess of Glory's reward for young mistresses
Many thanks
If there's nothing else
then servant is leaving.
We're home now
Cry if you want to
Jiejie, we're not musical entertainment for sale!
What right does she have to treat us like that?
This jade pendant from her
what a nuisance!
Does she think I'm a singing geisha? Reward?!
Young mistress!
Young mistress, be angry if you must
but if you really break this,
who knows what further trouble it will bring.
Don't cry
Your voice is not well
Have some water
Jiejie, I let you be humiliated along with me today
If you hadn't been there today,
the emperor to keep up appearance's sake,
I don't know how much more torment I would have to endure from her.
His Majesty values Nian Gengyao right now
Princess of Glory is very pleased with herself
For the sake of the broader situation,
for us
His Majesty cannot rip her face too much.
I just hope Nian Gengyao leaves soon
so Princess of Glory will be less arrogant.
It's not that easy
Leaving aside His Majesty's former feelings for Princess of Glory,
as long as Nian Gengyao is around,
His Majesty will not give her the cold shoulder.
As Niang Niang ordered, servant went to the Palace of Wings
Originally I wanted to say Empress was sick in bed,
so you can't attend the chrysanthemum festival tomorrow
Who knew I'd hear Xiao Xiazi say
that Precious Smile and Lingering An
were performing for Princess of Glory's amusement.
I was nosy and stayed around a bit longer
When Precious Smile and Lingering An came out,
they looked normal and nothing much happened
I know Precious Smile's temperament
She's not easily irritable
But I never thought that Lingering An would be able to bear it too.
it seems that I have been less observant
That's in public
Who knows what she's like when she returns home
If she can bear it, of course that's good
Princess of Glory is overly arrogant and willful
and humilates others at will
In the end, others will humiliate her
But this Lingering An
She's alright
Over here!
I'm over here!
These plum blossoms are the prettiest!
Young mistress be careful!
Can't catch me! Faster!
Faster
Young mistress, be careful!
Can't catch me!
Young mistress, put on another layer of clothes
it is still snowing. please wear a coat. it will be very cold.
Look
I haven't heard this type of laughter for a while
Precious Smile and Lingering An sent over lots of charcoal
Let me burn some for you
Burn or not, that's not important
Even if it warms the body, it can't warm the heart
young mistress returned.
didn't you want to see the flowers in the yard?
why come back so early?
looking at the flowers for too makes me feel dizzy
Dear 4th was kind to have plum blossoms planted in the courtyard
But when it snows, they're all the same color
now all the white flowers and the snow are blended together
That's easy
if you like the red ones,
I'll let the servants,
bring them all to your palace.
Didn't you want me to concentrate on writing?
How come now you are throwing off my concentration by talking about these things?
Shameless
You're the one who's not concentrating, but you blame others
If I hadn't just lost three rounds of chess to you,
I wouldn't be enduring this punishment right now.
Dear 4th's words carry weight
You can't go back on your word
Alright
Huan Huan is also
making a coat for Dear 4th as a gift.
It's fine if I go back on my words.
Simply because you thought of personally making a coat for me,
I would copy three times and not mind.
Dear 4th said it yourself!
To copy all the song lyrics about plum blossoms for Huan Huan
Don't renege!
You applied clear paper onto the windows
The color of snow pours in from outside
It's even brighter than Hall of Resting Soul
I don't like the room to be dark
Besides, once it rains or snows, we use up a lot of candles
Not only does the air smell, it's also too wasteful
You are quite frugal
Not to mention other expenses,
the candle expenses in the inner palace have increased considerably.
Although it's not a huge number,
it is still an expense.
I'm stingy,
it's very kind of Your Majesty to still like me
When I see the Empress,
I also want to tell her this idea.
Cut costs in the inner palace wherever possible
It's almost the end of the year
If some money could be saved to create a rice factory
and give aid to the people, it would be good charity.
Then I'll tell the Empress to do it
Auspicious greetings to young mistress Chun
Where's Wan Jiejie?
Inside
Young mistress, the Emperor is also inside
Young mistress!
Wan Jiejie!
Chun'er is here?
Auspicious greetings, Your Majesty
Jiejie, look
Aren't the plum blossoms Chun'er picked for you pretty?
Yes they're pretty
It's so warm here
It's freezing outside
Quickly sit by the fire
Your Majesty look
Are these plum blossoms I picked for Jiejie pretty?
Your sister was just talking about plum blossoms
and you came.
Of course, I know Jiejie the best
Lingering Chun seems to have grown much taller
Your Majesty, did you forget?
After this year end, I will be 17
Don't just talk
Quickly dust off the snow on you
If you catch a cold, don't cry when you have to take medicine!
Still carrying it
Have it put in a vase
Jinxi
Jiejie, don't you have a white porcelain vase?
That would be best for the red plum blossoms
You picked some good plum blossoms
They're still buds
and will bloom for a while.
I just love that color
Makes the heart warm inside
I did this for Jiejie
What will you reward me with?
I don't have much else
Try some cakes the kitchen just made
Great! Nothing would be better.
Thanks to you,
I also get to eat something.
If you didn't come, your sister would starve me
My sister wouldn't!
My sister loves Your Majesty the most
If sister means to starve your majesty
it must be your majesty was staring at sister
and has no time to eat
Listen, what a sharp tongue. She must have learned that from you.
Keep eating. Even eating can't stop you from talking.
Today, I'm not the emperor
I will just pretend I'm the young master of a common noble family
Can't I be a little talkative?
I dare not order Your Majesty around
but I dare order a common young master around.
If you don't finish copying these verses,
don't think about dinner tonight!
Listen, isn't your sister overbearing?
She's my sister! Of course I don't think she's overbearing!
You grind the ink. If you don't, I won't write.
Originally I couldn't figure out
why the two of you together looked so familiar to me.
My own sister
and brother-in-law back home are also this way.
One grinds the ink, the other writes
You ate too much
Quickly, drink some water to wash it down
Why won't you let her finish?
Keep talking
Your majesty just likes listening to the nonsenses
Before, when my sister and brother-in-law were together,
they were very close despite not saying much.
My mother calls this...
calls this...
she calls it the joy of the lady's chamber!
Chun'er is still young, where did you hear such things?
It's nonsense
And Your Majesty indulges her!
Your Majesty, do you think I'm speaking nonsense?
Of course not
What you said was excellent
Huan Huan and I are like that
Young mistress
Later we will be entering the Hall of Resting Soul
By all means, don't be afraid
Servant has waited on so many young mistresses
It's the first time I've seen one as giggly as you
Slowly, slowly
I saw at Precious Smile's place
that she used translucent paper on the windows.
That can save a lot of lighting expenses in the palace
What does Empress think?
The winters in Jing City are slow and long
Precious Smile's idea is very effective
The New Year's festival is coming, there will be many expenditures
Of course it would be good if money can be saved
I always thought that her intelligence and talent
were limited to books and poetry.
to my surprise, she is also good at managing household
I underestimated her
Precious Smile is a quick learner
She picks things up quickly
Even more precious is her kind heart
She wanted to use the savings to establish a rice factory
someday, she will be a great lady
I heard that last night, Your Majesty called for Lingering Chun
You checked the records in the House of Respectful Affairs?
Lingering Chun has been in the palace for two years now?
She's a big girl now
I remember that she liked to eat sweets
and wear brightly colored clothes.
So this morning, I had some sent over
She has a little girl's disposition, so she likes those things
It is good for a little girl to love those things
but now she's a concubine
She should act more dignified and composed
I like her cute and straightforward personality
Unlike some people who are constantly provoking others. They irritate me.
Reporting to Your Majesty, Sir Zhang Tingyu is here
Tell him to wait a moment
Yes
I should be leaving as well
Is everything alright with Nian Genyao in the city?
He has many visitors, he's very busy entertaining guests
That's normal. He has many old friends in the city.
Your Majesty, forgive me for being direct
Most of his visitors are people who work for him
He doesn't even look at other officials
Go ahead
This time he come to Beijing
On the way, he let the navarch Fan Shijie
and the governor Lee Weijun kneel to send him off
on his arrival, his troops are fulled of momentum
officials must kneel to welcome him
Nian Gengyao continued riding past them without taking a single look
He's so arrogant, it's shocking
This really happened?
I would not lie
Nian Gengyao returns in triumph and glory
It's easy to get carried away with pride. I will remind him.
With Your Majesty's words, I can rest assured
The Board of Revenue has many things to attend to
Nian Gengyao understands the frontier situation
If there's anything, you can discuss it with him
remember, just discuss
If Nian Gengyao's people are not faithful to their duties,
instead using it as an excuse to start trouble and abuse their power,
immediately report it to me.
They will be harshly punished. I will absolutely not tolerate it.
It will be year end in a couple days
Is the palace's annual bonus out?
Yes it is
But the Internal Affairs Authority said
that the emperor wants to cut costs.
So this year's bonus money is only half of last year's
Every New Years, I grant large sums of money
Even twice the original isn't enough, and they want to cut half?
That's a drop in the bucket
Exactly, this year is different
Great general is celebrating New Years in the city
We should grant the servants more money
Getting people in the palace to obey you
prestige is a matter
The emperor's favor is a separate matter
It's most important to keep giving out rewards
so others are willing to dependably work for you.
Actually Niang Niang can ask general for money
All these years brother was away,
he has been financially supporting me both openly and secretly.
Otherwise, these meager monthly salaries
wouldn't last me 10 days!
But to keep asking family for money
is not a solution.
Actually, it's not difficult for you to make some money
You got ideas?
I heard that
After General came back
so many people want to meet him and ask for an official position
but General has no time for them
so they all got into a flap
and don't know what to do
If Niangniang is willing to recommend them to General
they will know how to repay niangniang
This is too good to be true
His majesty organised the national exam to select talented person
Those people introduce themself to General for the sake of their own future
If there are talented persons
and let General recommand to his majesty
it will be Niangniang's credit
His majesty doesn't allowe us to interfere the national affairs
They want to meet my brother
I am able to pass on a message
as to whether they will be used, it's all up to brother
Niangniang is wise
Young mistress, you have been sewing this pajamas and then clearing backward for many times
when can you finish it
I make it for his majesty, I have to be very meticulous
Young mistress, you caught a cold the day before
and then keep coughing all the time
How long hasn't his majesty been here
over a month
if not with Princess of Glory
then his majesty must be with Precious Smile
Princess of Glory is riding high now
I can't compete with her
Right, but since his majesty has visited Precious Smile
young mistress gets along well with Precious Smile
she should have reminded his majesty to come here
His majesty hasn't came
Jiejie may not mention him
I heard that his majesty has slept with Lingering Chun recently
but she is as noisy as usual
after having been favoured
His majesty may not mean to favour her
probably, it is Empress' idea
Empress is good
everyone is under her consideration
but Princess of Glory always bullies you
Empress can't help us though she want
young mistress, you'd better go to bed early
servant will go to send for a doctor tomorrow morning
you may leave
Yes
Oh, right
you needn't tidy my bed today
Yes
Princess of Glory
Go to die
Respects to Empress
Get up and sit
Thank Niangniang
In such cold and windy days
it's very hard of you to come and greet me so early
I wanted to come with sister An
but she's still weak and can't be in a draught
so I came with Lingering Chun
Lingering Chun is becoming more and more beautiful
Is his majesty good to you?
His majesty is very nice to me
he ordered the Imperial Kitchen
to make plenty of tasty dessert for me everyday
That's good
You are his majesty's concubine now
you should concern about his majesty all the time
understand?
Empress
I have a little request
hope you can grant
say it
I want to live with sister Smile
I moved out to get away from her illness before
but sister has already recovered
I want to be with sister
There is only me live in Palace of Shattered Jade, so it's a little deserted
If Lingering Chun accompanies me
I will be very happy
It is good for you to move there
If everyone gets along well with each other just like you two
then I will be relieved
She is moving out?
These are Lingering Chun's things, who dare to break them
Lingering Chun is young
but smart
how long does it take her to learn to to be a social climber
Lingering Chun is not such a person
she just likes lively place
and wants to change a place to liveI like lively place too
and also want to change a place to live
Is it possible
she planed it well, relying on his majesty's favour
asked Empress, and move out herself
Palace of Shattered Jade is small and remote
Sister's place is the the best
Everyone knows they are the most favoured two except for Princess of Glory at the moment
now they live together, it's more convenient for them to invite his majesty
You and Lingering Chun came into the palace at the same time
and you were recommended by Precious Smile
This time, she only invited Lingering Chun to live with her, without you
you don't even think why
Sister An
It's so cold,why are you standing here
It's noisy outside, so I come out and have a look
Right, it is nice here
it's also close to Palace of Shattered Jade
why go through all the troubles to move?
Sister Wan and I both love to be lively
so we get along much better!
Yes, you both came from similar background
you get along much bettter
Sister, you're not well, go back inside
Go back to your business
Yes
Young mistress, the Empress is here
Bring Niang Niang in quickly
Greetings to the Empress
Rise
Thank you Niang Niang
I heard you are coughing these two days
I just visited Princess of Modesty
so I came to see you too
I just have a cold
and coughing a bit
Thank Niang Niang for the trouble
You're so young, you need to take care of your body
You musn't end up like Princess of Modesty
My heart will ache for you
Jian Qiu
Young mistress,
this is the donkey-hide gelatin sent by the Governor of Shandong
Niang Niang didn't want to use it
and specifically asked me to save it for Young mistress
Many thanks to Niang Niang
This house is cold in the winter and hot in the summer,
luckily the charcoals can warm you, so it's fine.
I remember when you first came to the inner palace,
Princess of Glory assigned the residents and took care of things
It's inevitable there be some faults
Don't take it to heart
I have the concern of Niang Niang,
I dare not ask for anything more
I am perfectly satisfied
Look at you, you're the most modest and polite
I like you from the bottom of my heart
I also ache for you
I'm afraid you will sidestep everything and suffer losses
If I have Niang Niang's concern, I will not suffer losses
You still say you won't suffer losses
look at how cold your hands are
Here, lie down
What is this?
Niang Niang!
Leave, don't say anything reckless
Yes
This jade pendant,
I remember Princess of Glory gave this to you
and Precious Smile
Each of you has one
You used this jade pendant to form a curse
Are you cursing Princess of Glory
or cursing Precious Smile?
Niang Niang,
Sister Wan is like a sister to me
I will rather die than curse Sister Wan!
It's Princess of Glory then?
You dare to curse Princess of Glory, how many lives do you think you have?
Why?
Niang Niang, Princess of Glory humiliates me
and treats me like a servant, I really...
Ridiculous!
I thought you were smart and perceptive
I never knew you could be so stupid
How dare you cast a curse in the palace?
I was ignorant, please forgive me
You're not just ignorant but also impossibly stupid
If Princess of Glory saw this,
do you still want to live?
These curses rely on the spirits
but your luck and life is only in your hands
If curses really worked,
no one will need to use their brain to think!
I was stupid
I don't care how much you hate Princess of Glory
I just want to tell you
instead of wasting your time on curses
you should spend you time on the Emperor  it's half the work, twice the effect
I was wrong
You stupid girl
Burn it. I didn't see anything
I am grateful to Niang Niang
You're alone in the palace, it's inevitable to feel desolate
Even if you have a sister like Precious Smile
but she is deep in the Emperor's favor
I'm afraid she can't think about you all the time
If you have any more grievance in the future
tell it to me
You musn't have stupid thoughts again
Niang Niang's concern for me
I will bring it to heart and never forget
Good, get up. It's cold on the floor
Luckily someone told me about this
I'll never have known otherwise
May I be bold
and ask Niang Niang who it was
Of course it was your close sister
but she didn't mean to
She had no choice
I told her already
this incident
ends with me
Was it Sister Wan?
Don't ask anymore
Just take care of your body and everything else will be fine
I respectful send Niang Niang off
Young mistress, it's time for your medicine
Young mistress?
Young mistress!
How dare you bite the hand that feeds you!
I don't know what I did wrong
but please punish me!
But I dare not
bite the hand that feeds me
You're always the one who cleans my chamber
you know exactly what is in my palace
How dare you say you don't know?
Young mistress, please calm down
I do clean young mistress' chamber
but recently you won't let me touch your bed
I don't know if something went missing or what
but I really don't know!
Then again, I'm not the only one who's allowed in this chamber
There's also Ju Qing
If something really went missing
I'm not the only suspect!
Ju Qing
Yes
Few days ago, young mistress said it's cold and wanted a thicker blanket
It was Ju Qing who did it
Luckily I remembered your order
and told her to just leave it there
No one is allowed to touch young mistress's bed
Yes,
there's also Ju Qing
She was originally Sister's servant
Bao Juan, get up quickly, let me see your injury
I dare not
It's all my fault, I was too harsh
But Bao Juan, you are my trusted aide
that's why I was so harsh
I was afraid you were the one who disclosed my information to others
Young mistress, I wouldn't dare
I hoped it wasn't you
but I never thought it would be Ju Qing
Young mistress, you suspect Ju Qing?
She was originally Sister's servant
Aside from her, there's no one else
I thought Sister was doing me a favor
by sending her to serve me
I never thought she wanted to plant a mole
right under my eye
I remember Internal Affairs Authority
sent over two otter fur garments
Remember to give them to Pin of Respects
one for her
and ask her to secretly give the other to Sister Mei
I know
I originally thought with Pin of Respects as the supervisor
I could still go see Sister Mei sometimes
But with Princess of Glory watching so closely
there's no loophole at all
Young mistress, don't worry
Wait until the year passes and spring comes
find a time when His Majesty is happy
and try to persuade him to release Mistress Mei
Also remember to urge them back home,
they must catch Liu Ben
Yes
Young mistress, let's hurry
I heard the Empress Dowager will be there too
even the 17th prince is back
It will be bad if we're late
Let's go
This time I went to the old plank roads of Jiange County and Zitong County,
Li Bing's Dujiangyan,
and Du Fu's residence in Huanhua
Did you see the Thousand Buddha Rock?
I know Imperial Mother care about the Buddhas,
so I prayed to each of them for Imperial Mother
You have quite the filial piety
The Shu Road is harder to climb than the sky
This has been a difficult trip
Princess of Glory, this is a nice outfit
Although I have bad eyesights,
it still dazzles my eyes
Empress Dowager gave me that hair ornament
and I thought I should have some nice clothes  to compliment it
So I had the Embroidery House made me some
The clothes must match the accessories
the silk flowers you wear
must have costed a fortune too
The silk flowers given in the palace are all made of satin
They are pretty but also rot easily
The ones I use are embroided with gold threads
and connected with gemstone beads
They are pretty, but they must cost a lot too?
Thank Empress for the concern,
but I have subsidies from home
I don't have to waste the palace's money
It'll be nice if we all had a family like Princess of Glory
then we won't have to wait on the monthly allowances
and live so stingily
Even if I have a good family
it's because of His Majesty's appreciation
Nian Genyao only has one sister
of course he subsidizes you with
everything I gave him
Empress Dowager, it's time for your medicine
The Imperial Doctor is waiting in the palace
Emperor,
I don't feel well, I will leave now
Imperial Mother must take care of yourself
so I will not worry
Respectfully sends Empress Dowager off
This is the wine made by Precious Smile
everyone have a taste
This is osmanthus flower wine
Precious Smile and I picked the freshely opened osmanthus
from this autumn to make this wine
That's why Imperial Brother is so pleased
and wanted us to treat it
In a family feast, with all the princes,
the osmanthus wine is sweet but also slightly meager
If we treat the guests with fine wines from the palace
wouldn't it demonstrate the style of the Imperial family better?
The war in the northwest just ended
even the Empress Dowager and the Emperor are cutting expenses
of course the inner palace has to follow suit
Replacing the expensive wines
with the osmanthus wine personally made by the Emperor,
it not only shows the intention of cutting expenses
but also shows the closeness of the Imperial family
It's good that Precious Smile wants to cut down expenses
but I heard  Precious has a pair of jade shoes made with Shu silk
the luxury can not be matched
I don't know if I can see them sometimes?
His Majesty gave them to Sister Wan because he likes her!
Of course it should be as luxurious as possible!
If His Majesty wants to, why not?
Isn't that right, Your Majesty?
You always say what's on your mind, that's the thing I like the most about you
Precious Fucha, don't you think so?
That's right, Lingering Chun
Thank you for watching this episodes with us!
Subtitles brought to you by The Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki