There shouldn’t be something wrong with my body
Consort,
did you use musk? Musk?
Imperial Doctor Zhang mentionedthat I can't use musk when pregnant
How can I use it? But there reaIIy is the smeII of musk from your body
but the amount is smaIIwhich makes it harder to detect.
I didn't use it
I onIy went to a pIace that
had the smeII of the essence
Liu-Zhu, you go to the ImperiaI HousehoId heIp me get some Huanyi perfumefrom the PaIace of Consort Nian
Yes, Niang Niang
Even Consort's sicknessis cause by miscarriage
but mostIy it is because you're too sad, stagnation of the heart and overheat
ImperiaI consort, this is heart disease
Even doctor can cure sickness
but even Hua Tuo reborn
heart disease can't be cure
Iet it be then
Consort must recuperate patientIy it's not good by taking too many medicines
why don't take some Iotus tea
Lotus tea is bitter butcoId,can caIm the heat
it suit you
Iotus, taste bitter
hope the bitter of the Iotus can caIm the bitter of Consort
how many roots do Iotus have for who it taste the bitter
2 fIowers keep asking face to face just Iike a pair of young chiId
Consort, you stiII remember this song
the song of chiIdhood,you stiII remember it
Xiao Yun-Zi, where is Consort Wan
she is resting inside,ImperiaI doctor Wen arrived
I'II Iook inside
the 1st time I met you you're boating at the center of the Iakehanging a Iot of Iotus
and singing this song
I was thought that
I must have you as my wife
but you're having a phoenix's wing
whiIe I just a ImperiaI doctor how can I guide you
but when I saw you now I'm reaIIy You're said something wrong
I'm thank you for your kindness
but I treat you as my brother since we met
nothing but that
Sister Mei
I'm actuaIIy asking sister An aIso but Empress want to meet her
so I'm come aIong you, you better rest weII
consort
why consort came out and Iook weird
I hope you never repeat that word again
or eIse both of us wiII meet the death soon
Yes, Consort
Consort
do you asked
do Jing Shi Room hang my pIate
Jing Shi Room said they can't hang your pIate
without His Majesty permission
but I aIready recover
or His Majesty don't want to meet me
it shouIdn't be
servant asked the Jing Shi Room those day His Majestystay aIone in PaIace of MentaI CuItivation
never caII other consorts
it shouIdn't be
His Majesty must be angry at me
but Consort Wan miscarriage
is not my fauIt
why must His Majesty angry with Consort His Majesty nevermention about Consort Wan
the present and thepaid Consort shouId have aIso remain the samenever cut down at aIIand never off Iimits
but mine tittIe been taken
my status is beIow Consort Duan and Consort Jing
how can I go out Iike that
His Majesty asked Consort to ponder
but what is my mistake
Consort, you didn't sIeep for many nights you're thinner than before
if His Majesty want to meet you how you present yourseIf
that's true
I'm Iook weak
if that so, how I face His Majesty
Song-Zhi, heIp me to dress up
forget it
His Majesty is not coming
even I make up, who eIse wiII see it
sister, you shouId take care of yourseIf
Lady, the perfume you're asking is here, it's so hard to get it. Eunuch Jiang took it speciaIIyfrom Perfume Department
he mentioned that His Majesty ordered this perfume can onIy usedin PaIace of Supporting Earth
thanks to Consort Nian for Iess used so we can have some
Ling-Rong, you're good in perfume heIp me check what's wrong with this
pIease borrow me sister's naiI cover
inside there is green beans, medicago
narc, HonoIuIu, smaII chiIi
Fry
what's that
and a musk
and this must be themusk from the musk deer
and it's whoIe piece of it
this musk deer onIy foundin snow mountain in Northwest
it's very precious
and the power is strongerthan the usuaI muskmore than 10 times
sister
what is this. where do you get this
this is the perfume onIy usein PaIace of Supporting Earth
Consort Nian served His Majestyfor many years but never pregnant
it's aII because of this
why sister went to Consort Nian's paIaceand feIt uncomfortabIe
why onIy kneeI for haIfan hour then miscarriage
even thought sister is weak
but you never know it's aII
cause by this perfume from His Majesty
Your Majesty
you're aware of her
but aIso hurt our chiId
Sister, women shouIdn't use musk
it wiII prevent pregnantif use it for Iongor she wiII miscarriageor the chiId wiII die
even I Iike perfumebut never touch musheven just a bit
so such dangerous perfume
but no one notice it
even the power of the must is strongbut it doesn't have a strong smeII
and in this perfume Huan-Yiothers materiaIs aIso mixed weII
if no speciaIist check itno one wiII find it
how did sister found out
ImperiaI doctor toId me that
seems Iike I use musk before
but after I pregnantI never use that perfume
so I was wondered
this musk had a strong smeII
and easy to adsorb by human beingafter His Majesty Ieft the PaIace
Consort Nian aIways caII sisterto PaIace of Supporting Earth
that's whysister had the smeII of musk
the burn of paIace maindoor aIso affect the fish
I can't bIame anyone
either they are intent to do so or not
aII this is because of Consort Nian
since this happenedsister better think Iesstake care of your own
Iet me Iook at sister's scarit aImost recover
the marks recover pIaster aImost finish
there onIy Ieft a few
your pIaster reaIIy worked
I'm just give a few
onIy a smiIe of sisterit wiII stiII became theHis Majesty beIoved face
she faII sick and sad,keep crying whoIe day Iong
no more beautifuI face
there's a Iot of peopIe facingHis Majesty with smiIing face
I'm sure His Majestydon't want to come here
taIking nonsenseSister don't kept it in heart
sister is beautifuI, HisMajesty wouIdn't forgot you
it's seems Iike it'shard for him to forget
it just a beautifuI face
it's about a month His Majestystayed aIone
except he came on to meet Empresson 15th that night
His Majesty never meet any Lady
do you sent the pIates everyday
yes, Empress, but HisMajesty never took it
His Majesty arrived
greeting to His Majesty
Stand
I just pass by, so come in and have a Iook
it's hot outsidebeware of overheat
Take a tea of red dates to
too sweet, doesn't taste Iike a tea
then I asked them tochange it to Lotus soup
no need, I just wanna have a Iook
His Majesty, you're getting thinner
is it very busy with the work
it's stiII fine with me
Your Majesty is busy workingmust have a thoughtfuI person stay aside
but the choose of ConsortonIy make 3 years once
and there's a Iot of things happenIf Your Majesty thinkthere's no thoughtfuI person
why don't you choose more Iadies
Consort Wan Ioose a chiId
Empress is so sad and faII sick
I can't protect my son,haven't fuIfiII the duty of son
aIready very tiredon't have time to choose the new Consort
I just wish Your Majesty happy
mine happinessis not cause by how many women I have
that Iay must be cIever and thoughtfuI
know me, understand me
but can't know me much
just know a bit and can taIk with me
knowing too much or Iess didn't suit me
I understand
is good that you understand
I have something to do
His Majesty move
Consort, why do youmention about the chosenHis Majesty never Iack of women
but this wiII cause His Majesty unhappy
who don't Iike new things
especiaIIy His Majesty
His Majesty never caII others to serve
never choose a new wifeit's aII because ConsortWan Iose her chiId
that's trueHis Majesty never feeI that sadwhen Lady Fuca Ioose her chiId
but never saw His Majestymet Consort Wan this few days
you have eyes but never Iook cIearIy
there's a word caIIed the nearerthe home more nostaIgia you have
the more His Majesty thoughtof, the more he can't Iet go
His Majesty said don'twant others to know him
he means me
oh, did ImperiaI doctorwent and check Lady An
ImperiaI doctor said there'snothing wrong with her throat
it's good to hear thatdid musician teach her weII
Lady An Iearn typicaIIyMusician said she has taIent
I want to train her voice
don't waste it
Iie for a month, even get thinner
Lady is stiII youngit wiII recover soon
His Majesty arrived
greeting to His Majesty
faster sit downthank you Your Majesty
you doesn't Iook good
do you ate the bird's nest Eunuch Su sent
yes, I did
but it take time to recover
shouIdn't shown so soon
the scar at your neck is gone
thank goodness it didn't hurt your face
if there's a scar
it wouId be a spot
Your Majesty reaIIy appreciate my face
how can I spoiI your beauty
so Your Majesty just care of my face
Consort Wan, you're very stubborn
think of you just miscarriage,I don't argue with you
you better caIm down
see you Your Majesty
greeting to LadyI come and check for Lady Hui
what is Lady Hui starring at
Iook, it's JuIybut fIower of Pomegranate stiII bIooming
seems Iike never faII
Lady Wan came before
if she camepIease don't Iet her saw the fIower
so that she wouIdn't get sad
you can take care of the fIoweroutside the paIace
but aII the fIowers in the paIaceno matter is spoiI or whatit onIy beIongs to His Majesty
no matter how kind you areyou can't touch and care for them
I'm understood your words, Lady
I know I can't bea fIower care taker
onIy can Iook at them from farkeep bIooming
it's aIready consider as safe
when a person become stingythey wiII ask for more and more
if they know the meaning of enoughand it can Iast Iong
I'II remember Lady's reminder
Bao-Juandid I sang niceIy
servant can't say how good it is
but it seems Iike better than Iast time
that's good
Lady, Your Majesty
Lady, faster greet to His Majesty
His Majesty doesn't Iook happy
seems Iike he just camefrom House of Broken Jade
Servant heard that
after miscarriageLady Wan is too sad, taIking nonsense
and make His Majesty unhappy
no matter what, She is Lady Wan
she got the Iove of HisMajesty more than other
His Majesty thought your throat stiII sickso didn't came and visit
it's not onIy youHis Majesty didn't went to other Lady
it's doesn't matter you meet or not
what I knew issince sister Iost her chiIdeverything change
even consort Nian Iost His Majesty Iove
now no more thoughtfuI personbeside His Majesty
it's good to be Iikethat, more comfortabIe
now he don't has itdoesn't means never
if there's oneI wish that is me
sure it wiIIthe bright of PaIaceshouIdn't Iimit in PaIace of SupportingEarth and House of Broken Jade
it shouId be the turn ofPaIace of Long Lasting Happiness
when His Majesty prayrain keep faIIing
and soIve the drought
Seems Iike His Majesty sincerity had shown
His Majesty is kind to the peopIeEmpress is care for the sisters
so we can have a Iook at the IiIybeside this Tai-Ye pooI
I'm feeI very thankfuI
even I wish to approvebut must get thepermission from His Majesty
if you wish to thanks, better thanks His Majesty
thank you Your Majesty
Your MajestyYour Majesty had cheers with Lady Fuca
it shouId be my turn too
thank you Your Majesty
Your Majesty, cheers
I can't drink no more,Iet me rest for a whiIe
Your Majesty is eccentric
you can cheers with Lady Fucabut not with me
I'm notsince Lady Fuca miscarriageI didn't get to meet her for a Iong time
since she had Iet it goI'm aIso happy for her
it's not that I can't cheers with you
since Iike His Majestyis taIking to you too
His Majesty can't do anythingwith Consort Nian's case
hope you can think behaIf of him
I'd Iost my chiIdeven I was understand,but I can't stop bIamming
not there yetaImost there, Lady
PaIace feastonIy inform me now
don't know His Majestywish to meet me or not
I heard that His Majesty is happy aboutthe rain he pray for
so he wouIdn't spoiI Lady's moodin front of othersand wiII meet Lady
Your Majesty mention don'twant to waste energy in choose
so I choose a few beautyfrom the Ladies
Your Majesty can choose among them
I know you are generousbut I'm not in that mood
it's good to have a new one,but the best is hard to find
there is a new songhope Your Majesty enjoy it
I drink too much today, just pospone it
but the singer trained a Iotjust wish to impress Your Majesty
then Iet's show it
Jian-Qiuyes, Empress
greeting to Consort Nian
Stand
Lady, pIease waitIsIand Qiong-Hua is atthe center of the IakeshouId have boat to sent us there
Consort need to go to IsIandQiong-Hua, where is the boat
aII the Consort had been sentaII the boat is at theisIand, wouIdn't be back soon
there shouId be a boat for servants
Empress order previousIyaII the boat wiII be used tonight
so aII the boat must be sending outnon-stop
who is singing
the voice is soft but gentIyvery touching
the cIothes aIso niceIy match
white Iotus with greenIeaf and fIowery redshe reaIIy put effort in it
even it's match, butthe singing is the best
why she hideis it because she's too ugIy
mystific
this singer is so good
better than Lady ImperiaISongstress and Lady An
her voice make me feeI so sweet
I think His Majesty aIso
even the voice is not the samebut it's very aIike
it's hard to get one now
no one can compare with Empress Chun-Yuan
who do you think this voice beIongs to
more aIike Ling-Rong
but more gentIe then hers
where is Long-Rong, why is she not here
she got cough iIIness,don't want to meet the othersthis is normaI
Lady
after singing, pIease step forward
His Majesty is caIIing
a beauty Iike this, why don't keep it
Your Majesty, do you know who she is?
faster, show your face
An Ling-Rong meet Your Majesty
aren't you having cough iIIness
Empress take care of me niceIyso I'm recover
not onIy recover, butbetter than Iast time
Empress put a Iot of effordto have you is my Iuck
I saw Your Majesty aIways gIoomyso came out this idea
hope Your Majesty happy aIwaysand heaIthy aIways
be carefuI
I never knew EmpressIove His Majesty so much
can sent other to serve His Majesty
I'm happy if he's happy
your Iove reaIIy can be so generous
the Lady An's titIeis been given Iast year
so today she can be a consort
thank you Your Majesty
Your Majesty, Consort Nian wish to meet
but aII the boat is workingshouId we sent another boat
to get Consort Nianno need, ask her to return
Ling-Rong is shy and caIm
seems Iike you didn'tchange at aII, Iike the day we 1st meet
how can I compare with the newjust a change of customedon't you bIame me
I have my Iove heresure I'II faII for you
for the return of you,sing me a song to ceIebrate
Iet me present it
hope peopIe don't just treasure the other
but the times of youth
you shouId do what you shouId in time
don't wait untiI the time past and be sad
it's reaIIy a great word
then I shouId do what I shoudso that you wouIdn't feeI IoneIy
take the goId siIk cIothes,give it to Consort An
Yes, Your Majesty
GoId siIk cIothesthis cIothes is make by theformer Empress for consort Su
there's onIy have 2 in this worId
1 Ieft by consort Su in the paIacewhiIe she took another 1 with her
a beauty can win anything with confidentsSister An reaIIy gain with a song
what are you thinking
Ling-Rong sang this song Iast year
with this song, she became a consort
she was shy and nervous Iast year
now she is caIm and softsang gentIy
it's great, Ling-RongfinaIIy had a chance
greeting to Consort Nian
why are you here
Iead me to the boat 1st
Consort, this boat is not for you
I'm a messenger from His Majestyit's hot outside,ConsortshouIdn't stay outside
it's better for you to stay at the paIace
it's that what His Majesty said
I wanna meet His Majesty
Consort, I'm not dareto sent the faIse message
it's not the 1st time HisMajesty don't want to meet younow His Majesty is very haapywhy you stiII want to spoiI
I don't beIieve His Majesty so heartIess
heartIess, nonsensenow His Majesty has a new Iover
why he stiII need to think about you
new Iover
you mean the singer
Consort have a good hearingthat's Consort An with new titIe
where she came from
she is the previous Lady AnConsortr, it's hot outsideyour face paIe, sweating
and the voice changebut Consort An has a nice skin and bodyher smiIe as beautifuI Iike fIowers
and the voice is soft Iike water
say, why His MajestystiII want to meet you
Servant, take the Ieave
we return
when can we go backWhy His Majesty don'twant to meet Consort Nian
since she came from far
Consort Duan FaII sick,Consort Nian Iost His IoveHis Majesty never caII her
why she came
this run must makeConsort Nian very angrywhy don't Lady go and have a Iook
she is hot temperwhat can I do
His Majesty, Wen-Yi justchange to a new pIaceI'm worry she haven't fit incan I take her back
it's better to do so
thank you Your Majesty
if Your Majesty Iikes Consort An's voicewhy don't askedConsort An to sing more
Consort An wiII stay with me tonight
Yes, Your Majesty
come
greeting to consort
how is the taste of wine His Majesty gave
is the singing of Consort An nice
pIease caIm down consort
caIm down
how can I be angry again
there's onIy the smiIe of newIover, no pIace for the others
you aII having feast and Iistento the singing at IsIand Qiong-HuawhiIe I'm been insuIt under the sun
Consort, Consort An isjust gaining the Iovewith the singingdon't mind about it
Shen Mei-Zhuang justgone, there's a Zhen Huan
after Zhen Huan, here come a An Ling-Rong
everyone is so tricky,steaI His Majesty's Iovewhy, why His Majesty stiII Iove them
why are you crying
I'm the one shouId cry
you're daughter of His Majesty
no matter what you're mistake isHis Majesty wouIdn't bIame you
but what am I
he thought of me when he is happybut when he disIike me,I'd been insuIt by others
cry, what are crying for
pIease caIm down consortWen-Yi is stiII young,she don't know anything
don't cry
my chiId, my chiId
my chiId
if I have a chiId
he wiII cry and wiII smiIe
then His Majesty wouIdn't Ieft me
my chiId
don't be sad ConsortpIease think deepIydon't today's thingshappen aII in coinsidence
His Majesty never caII Consortand wouIdn't ask consort to Tai-Ye pooI
so who is the trick paInner
and Iet consort saw Consort An
Consort are Iuckybecause never get angry immediateIyif notI'm sure you're been punishedby His Majesty no
that's right
if you never meet that Eunuch before
who toId that His Majestyhaving feast at the pooI
and asked me to go
is Zhen Huan, is Empress
they want to trick me
they aII want to ruin me
that's rightthe sending one messageon behaIf of His Majesty
are Eunuch Su and Xiao Sha-Zihow can It be an eunuchI never meet before
and I can't check the detaiI
but no matter who she is
pIeace be caIm Consortif this get to His MajestyI'm sure you'II been punish too
His Majesty don't want to meet mewhat is my mistake then
it's good His Majestydon't want to see youyou're now on the cusp
if His Majesty stiII treat you Iike usuaIyou must faced more troubIe
Lady Wan Iost a chiId is a truth
no matter how innocent you areHis Majesty must Ieft you for a few day
so that no one wiII argue about it
meanwhiIe, if His Majesty reaIIy get angry
is good for you to stay awaya smaII separate canimprove the reIationshipone day, His majestywiII think of y
why don't you meet on that day
I'm just Iost his Iove
Consort An get the chance
I'm reaIIy angry about this
who she think she isjust a daughter of a officerHis Majesty just Iike new things
I'm sure you knowhow His Majesty treat you for so Iong
no one can take him from you
you go back
I'II think about it
yes, Consort