Episode 60
Mistress, can we trust Consort Duan?
If we use her, I trust her. If I didn't, I wouldn't use her
The Emperor is here!
Greetings Emperor
Hurry, rise
Thank you Emperor
Why are you here at this time?
You surprised me
You're just getting ready
Such a peaceful sight
Why are you doing your hair now?
When you first came in, you looked very happy
Share it with me
So I might share your happiness
Huan Huan is truly meticulous
The officials gave reports at court this morning
That this autumn is very prosperous
The people are also happy and healthy
When I heard it, I was happy
Last night I went to see Consort Duan
She's usually very quiet
But when she does speak, she speaks sense
Consort Duan has been in the palace for a long time
Emperor, you've always been very good to everyone
Treating everyone with mercy
That's why the people are happy and healthy
And the people are at peace
I can see, everything is stable at court
When Empress Chun Yuan was the First Wife
The way she ruled the manor
If she was here today
The harem
Would be even more stable
You've heard of Empress Chun Yuan?
Jin Xi has been in the palace for a long time
When she's serving me
She would mention the good Empress Chun Yuan did
If I may say
If Empress Chun Yuan was still here
Then Jin Xi and Su Pei Sheng's situation
How would it be dealt with?
If Chun Yuan was still here
I think
The current Empress is Chun Yuan's biological sister
Their attitudes must be similar
The Empress said
She wants to make them an example
She musn't really
Want their lives, right?
Besides, the Emperor treats everyone so well
I'm sure the Empress
Wouldn't go against the Emperor
Wouldn't go against Empress Chun Yuan
How can Yi Xiu be compared to Chun Yuan?
You must be tired being pregnant with twins
Yet there's rumours in the palace
That they are not my kids
Other people aside
Even the Empress wants me to be wary
The Empress
Is just ruling the harem
Consort Duan said something correct
There's 2 Consorts pregnant in the palace
Who can't handle seeing heavy punishments
Even if they were to be punished
It should be later
The Emperor was asking
Why the Misstress was only doing her hair now
There's a reason
With Jin Xi gone
Mistress was so angry and upset
She hasn't slept well in 2 days
Dr Wen's idea is good though
Brushing hair can help relax
And can sleep better
Stop talking
Who asked you to speak in front of the Emperor
Emperor
Don't listen to Huan Bi
I'm fine, I sleep well
You still want to hide it?
I can see the dark circles under your eyes
You mustn't be sleeping well
Huan Huan
You wish everything would be well
And prevent Huan Bi from telling the truth
That I can serve again at the Emperor's side
Is my fortune
It doesn't matter if I'm upset
But Jin Xi
She's been beside me for many years
In my heart
I'm always going to find it hard
But it is Jin Xi's fault
The Empress is the master of the harem
If she really wants to play by the rules
There's nothing I can do
I can only obey
Even though the Empress is in charge
Doesn't mean I can't have a say
The Emperor shouldn't quarrel with the Empress over this
You should blame me
I didn't teach my servant well
This kind of matter has been happening for dynasties
It's not the first case
After all they are lonely servants
Even though eunuchs aren't considered men
They still have human emotions
Why should I suppress what is human?
Actually this problem
Is contained within the palace walls
If we just cover it up, it'll be fine
If it was made into a big deal, and the citizens heard it
It'll become a laughingstock
Su Pei Sheng has served the Emperor since young
Surely he's spent much more time
With the emperor, even more than me
He's done a good job
What spend more time?
It sounds like you're jealous of him
I really can't do anything with you women and small people
Huan Huan is a woman
In my tummy are small people
If Emperor thinks it's too difficult
Then you don't have to support us
How could I bare that?
Jin Xi
Niang Niang
As long as you're back
- Is Niang Niang alright?  - As long as you're back
Please forgive me
Get up, get up
The Emperor said
Will only fine you a year's salary
As long as you're ok
Thank you Niang Niang. Thank the Emperor for his grace
Take Jin Xi into her rooms to rest
You don't need to come serve me these couple of days
I'm fine
What about Su Pei Sheng?
Everything's fine, he's back at Yang Xin Hall
Go and rest
Thank you Niang Niang
Huan BI, help Jin Xi go rest
Let's go
Your servant, Su Pei Sheng
Greet the Emperor
Greetings Emperor
You're back
Thank you Emperor
I can never repay such kindness
As long as you're back. Make ink
Yes
Emperor, have this white fungus soup
I'll help you make ink
I know what you want to ask
Yong Shou Hall is fine, Cui Jin Xi is fine
I fined you a year's salary. Quite a small punishment
This kind of embarrassing situation
I can't just ignore the Empress's reasoning
I had to set an example
I understand
Why didn't you tell me earlier
I was afraid if I mentioned it
It'll dirty your ears
Forget it
Don't see her in the future
So that others don't gossip
Emperor
I've known Jin Xi for a long time
And we're from the same town
I'm old
Being castrated, I have no sons or daughters
I don't have anyone to bury me
I only want to be companions with Jin Xi
Emperor
I mean it
Alright
We'll forget I said that
And I didn't hear what you said
You deal with it yourself
Thank you for your grace
Thank you Emperor
Greetings to all mistresses
The Empress just woke up, please wait here
Niang Niang's chrysanthemums are beautiful
We'll just admire them here
There's no hurry
Please feel free
Jie Jie was saying
The servant is a reflection of the master
This situation caused a big ruckus
I want to see how Consort Xi gains back her "face"
How will she gain back her "face"
She's embarrassed the whole palace
If I were her, I'd hide away with the servant
I'll never leave Yong Shou Palace
Cui Jin Xi is her confidante
She might have planned this whole thing to seduce the Emperor
She's just hidden it well
Greetings Consort Xi
I haven't congratulated Precious Qi on your release
Precious Qi must've been so bored during your grounding
Jump right back into the pit once you're out
Who's right and wrong, Niang Niang must know
Why would you blur what's black and white?
The Empress was merciful
So that mid-autumn we may be whole
She begged the Emperor to let Precious Qi out
Thinking she's learnt her lesson
Yet you're still so impudent
The effort's wasted on you
What I did wrong was only about me
Not like Niang Niang's companions, did something so embarrassing
Or is it the servant following the ways of the master?
I was sick the last two days
I'm better now
So I can come and serve Niang Niang
Let me
Huan Bi, it's cold early in the morning
You should've brought a cloak for Niang Niang
What if she caught a cold? The Emperor would be sad
Precious Qi as a concubine
What you just said, was it really appropriate?
"The servant following the ways of the master"
Then, Niang Niang is a Consort
You are just a Precious
You must know the difference in status
Besides
When Young Miss was cruel to the servants
Was it also "the servant, following the master"
Young Miss is being a little ridiculous
You Cui Jin Xi are the ridiculous one. You're the one who broke the rules
Su Pei Sheng and I are good friends
But so what?
Young Miss doens't like
That the Emperor let me go
So "breaking the rules"
Is certainly not something I can admit to
If Young Miss really wants to say I broke the rules
Then are you saying the Emperor covered for me?
Approving of mess within the palace?
And what do you guys think?
The same as Precious Qi
I dare not
The Empress is up, please come in
Jin Xi came today too
Yes, Empress
Serving Consort Xi is my duty
Jin Xi, you're an old hand in the palace
In the future, be careful when serving Consort Xi
Don't cause any trouble for her
Yes, thank you for the reminder
Mid-autumn is almost here
I heard Guo Jun Wang should be returning soon
Plus Consort Xi's due date is coming up
Imperial Concubine Hui is also pregnant  The Emperor wants this to be a grand event
The Empress should decide, we will be happy with everything
Su Pei Sheng greets Niang Niang
You're here
Emperor wanted me to bring this date soup for Niang Niang
Thank the Emperor for this thought
It's been hard on you
Huan Bi, bring a seat
Thank you Niang Niang
You've lost weight in the days I haven't seen you
I had thought that I was quite healthy
Didn't think that doing a few day's labour
Would ruin my body like this
I'm getting old and useless
At least now I returned to the Emperor's side
Other people won't dare to gossip
But... Jin Xi
You must know
Jin Xi would be gossiped about because she's with me
Even though this was caused by your accidentally dropping the purse
I wanted to protect the two of you yet I couldn't do much
At least the Emperor thought of the old times
Yes
I didn't realise my momentary mistake would even disrupt the Empress
I've learnt my lesson
This lesson isn't just learnt by you
But I'll remember too
Yes
Then Jin Xi
Don't worry
As you've said that, I have nothing to worry about
I'll leave first  Alright
Let me Let me
Just sit
You haven't even realised there's a hole in your shirt
Aren't you afraid the Emperor would say something?
I know you can do it, but you're so busy
Are you ok?
Me? I'm great
The more people say about me, the better I will live
We live life for ourselves
If I go hang myself, it'd only give them pleasure
That's right
But I also know, you first approached me
Because of Consort Xi
If you don't really want to be with me
And seeing as the rumours are going wild, why don't we stop meeting?
What are you saying? We're together to keep each other company
Aside from Consort Xi, you're the only one who's close to me
When I thought a lot during my exile
Why should I hurt someone who really cares for me
Because of other people's rumours
It's your auspicious day Miss, why don't you wear something red?
I'd look like a country bumpkin all rouged up
Go get me a green outfit
Miss, you only wear green or aqua
Why don't you change the colour today?
I said I want the green one
If you want it more cheerful, get the one with the silktree flower embroidery
Ok
Miss
Very pretty, come with me to the Chun Hua Palace Autumn's festival tonight
I only wanted to not be ugly, not to compete with you Miss
You should dress pretty while you're young
I'm not dressing pretty for Wang Ye
If you dress up, you'd be even prettier
I am ashamed in front of him
Anything I have to show off can only be for the Emperor
The Emperor has arrived
Greetings Emperor
Sit
Have a seat
Your hands are so cold, are you ill?
It's been a bit cold at night lately
Where's 17th brother?
I'm late
Please forgive me
I'm used to you being late and leaving early at parties
Back then you stubbornly wanted to go to Shen Jin
Nowadays you seem tired
I became ill when I arrived in Shen Jin
Why didn't anyone tell you? What are your servants doing?
I told them not to say anything. It wasn't anything major. I'm better now
You need someone to take care of you
Do you have anyone in mind?
If I favoured anyone, I would tell you
Perhaps all I wish for is a dream
Actually Yun Xi has also grown up
Should also find a wife and settle down
Sister in law is making fun of me. I think the same as 17th Brother
I must find someone who I love
Look, the older one making the younger one dream too
Yun Xi's afraid of getting a wife
Our Great Qing only need descendants from the Emperor's family
We can be lazy
Congratulations Imperial Concubine Hui
Thank you Wang Ye
Consort Xi is well too?
May Wang Ye also be well
Niang Niang is almost due, is your health alright?
Thank you Wang Ye, everything is fine
Emperor, Miss needs to take her medication
You should go
I'll be back soon
Hopefully everyone lives long, including those living far away.
Mistress, are you well?
I thought I could hold it in.
I thought I could forget him.I almost forgot myself.
I understand the heartbreak that Wang Ye and Mistress are going through.
-But...-He must live well.
Mistress is in a bad mood.
Are you well?
I just said in the room,
Just now was just now. Now is now.
Now that I've returned, I just want to know that you are doing well.
That way I don't have to worry.
If you care too much for me
then you won't feel well.
Please don't have too much concern. Huan Bing let's return.
Don't leave.
Let go. Let go.
Let go.
I get the feeling that you aren't living well these days.
Regardless of whether it's a golden house or a hut, it's my willing choice.
Whether or not I can be comfortable depends on myself. It has nothing to do with anyone else.
It's like Precious Ning.
Although her position was low, she had more freedom.
And it's you we are talking about.
You're not her.
Whether or not you are happy you may not know yourself.
The moon has its cycles and people go through many changes.
Don't feel sad for people who aren't worth feeling sad for.
If a person can't live following their own heart
it's worse than the moon. At least on the 15th of every (lunar) month the moon will be round.
So I won't choose to be that persistent.
If I continue to talk to you I'm worried that the Emperor will notice.
Take care of yourself.
To avoid bad luck I will return first.
You can go in after I've gone in for a while.
Who?
Huan Bi, what happened?
I just saw someone's shadow pass by.
Let's hurry back.
During the day time the garden looks nice.
But at night it seems full of negative energy.
We go this way everyday.
What is there to be afraid of.
Where did so many cats come from? Hurry and protect Niangniang.
There's cats. Hurry let's go!
Mistress, how are you?
Niangniang!
It hurts!
What to do?
Use more strength Niangniang
Use your strength.
Come on!
Use your strength!
How is it? Did she give birth?
What to do?
Niangniang, use your strength
Go check the medicine used to speed up the labor. It has to be very dense before Niangniang can drink it.
Okay okay.
Niangniang, the Emperor just received the news and will be here shortly.
There is a question that I must ask Niangniang.
If anything goes wrong, do I save you
or the child?
Wen Shizhu, with the many years of our friendship
I want you to promise me
no matter what happens
you cannot harm my child.
Do you hear me?
I already knew that would be your answer. But I had to ask.
Remember, protecting the three of us is the best thing.
If you can't, then you have to protect the child first.
Can you remember this?
Or else even if you save me
I will definitely commit suicide.
Or other terrible things.
I mean what I say.
Did you hear me?
What kind of situation are you in to say those ill words?
The Emperor has arrived.
Go, tell the Emperor
that if something happens
don't have the Emperor dwell on our many years of love.
Don't hesitate
to protect the child.
Niangniang  Mistress,
how can you say such unlucky things when you are in this situation?
Niangniang, use your strength.
Niangniang
Protect the child over the mother?
I have said that Consort Xi and the child must both be saved.
or else every imperial physician will be buried with her.
The heaven have already punished me enough. My child cannot have an accident.
Mistress woke up.
Child. Where is the child?
Niangniang, the wet nurse has the child and will be here soon.
It's a twin girl and boy. You have given me a phoenix and dragon.
Has Mei jiejie visited? And what about doctor Wen? Why isn't he here anymore?
Imperial Concubine Hui is pregnant so I told her to get some rest.
Doctor Wen didn't leave, he is in the back personally watching the medicine.
Niangniang, I heard that you twin phoenix and dragon bring good luck
to the kingdom. Congratulations Niangniang, Congratulations Emperor!
Well said! Yongshou Palace will receive half a year's wages
as a reward for serving your mistress so well.
Thank you your Majesty.
I came to congratulate the Emperor and Niangniang.
Auntie came.
The Empress Dowager heard that the birth was successful and all three are healthy, and is very elated.
She asked me to see you.
I ask auntie to give Empress Dowager my thanks.
I don't know if I can have the honor
of first seeing the little prince and princess
so I can give a good report back to Empress Dowager.
-Bring the babies here  When the Empress Dowager finds out
She will definitely be very happy
and her health will take a turn for the better.
I haven't even seen them yet.
Little princess and little prince give their greetings to your Majesty.
The prince's forehead and chin looks like Huanhuan's.
The princess's eyebrows look like Huanhuan's.
The children are still young, how can you tell that they look like me?
You just know how to cheer me up.
When the father sees the children more he loves them more.
Huanhuan, I thank you.
Emperor, the children are still young. The nurses should take them.
Yes, hurry hurry.
I have seen them and now I can report back to Empress Dowager.
Okay
I will take my leave.
Huanhuan, do you know how happy I am?
You gave birth to two children for me.
You have made such an accomplishment that I will name you as Noble Consort.
I want you to be my beloved Noble Consort.
If you want to give me the title of Noble Consort
I honestly can't take it.
Besides you, no one else in my heart can have the title of Noble Consort.
You were well just a while ago how can you start coughing?
Feiwen! Niangniang just gave birth how can you open the windows?
Hurry and close it.
Your majesty, just now the midwife said
that the palace smelled strongly of blood so to open the windows.
So I didn't close it.
You caused Niangniang to catch cold air and you talk back? Take her out for 20 slaps.
Yes.
Su Bisheng?
Tell the palaces that Yongshou Palace's Consort Xi is now Noble Consort Xi.
When the children are a month old we shall make it official.
After Consort Xi recovers she will have some power over the harem.
Yes your Majesty.
Huanhuan, do you like it?
It is your gift, of course I cherish it.
The Emperor is inside listening.
You slap yourself. Mine are too hard.
Gongong, this really doesn't have to do with me.
I am just listening to orders.
The Emperor loves Niangniang and is taking some anger out on you.
Don't take it to heart.
The Emperor loves Niangniang so he takes his anger on us servants?
Watch what you say. If the Emperor hears you it won't just be slapping yourself.
Niangniang, I boldly as you for a reward.
Anything that you reward me with
I will gratefully accept and receive some good luck
If I want to reward you it will be a big one.
It takes the Emperor to be here to ask me?
Before, you two suffered a lot.
Today since Noble Consort has asked
I will officially give Jingxi to you to be your wife.
You must treat her well.
Okay.
Thank you your Majesty!
With the Emperor and Niangniang's love
I will definitely, definitely treat Jingxi well.
Go ask them for wine to drink.
Niangniang!
You rest well, I will come see you at night.
I wish you a safe return.
Seeing his Majesty off.
Just now Consort Jing came to see you.
Do you want to see her?
I'm tired now. Go tell her that I'm thankful.
When I feel better I will personally go see her.
Go tell her my words.
Right now I won't see anyone who comes.
Yes.
A small princess and a small prince. Both are adorable.
Empress Dowager is so happy that she look enough at them.
With such a happy occasion even if looking at them caused me to go blind I would be happy.
Bring them further away so they don't get my sick air.
Consort Xi's children are premature so you must care for them very carefully.
No accidents can occur.
Yes.
Did you think of the names?
Sixth prince will be Hong Yan.
Let me look at sixth prince.
Such a good child.
White and chubby,
not like the the Emperor who was very dark.
Consort Xi has fair skin so of course her children will be lighter skinned.
I haven't decided on the Princess's name. I'll have Consort Xi think of a name.
That works well. You name the prince and she names the princess.
When Imperial Concubine Hui gives birth I will name the child.
Since the children have been born I can clear my name.
I will not tolerate and wild rumors about you.
Being able to bring up the children is Heaven's gift.
I don't have anything to be upset about.
You speak carefully. Yet others suspected your pregnancy.
No matter how big the harem is it's between women.
Empress will take care of this, so you don't need to get involved.
That way you won't get a reputation for being biased towards me.
I just want them to know that I dote on you the most.
That way they won't bully you.
The Empress used to be able hold up the title of being virtuous.
But now she's changed. Maybe it has to do with her age.
Empress has arrived.
Greetings, your Majesty.
Sit.
I don't have my manners, forgive me.
You can just lie down. You have accomplished a lot.
Thank you for you care.
After Consort Xi gave birth to these babies
I don't have anything to give them.
But before, a sister gave me some valuable Suet jade.
I asked the workers to work through the night to create jade pieces for the two children.
It can keep them safe.
Her things are of high quality.
You can give it to the children. It must have been difficult to part with it.
Jiejie left me with many items.
I don't usually take it out
as it represents our good relationship.
Naturally.
It's been a while since I've visited you.
I am aging and becoming ugly. I can't compare to the youth of my sisters.
If you have time then visit the young sisters more. Don't coop yourself up and look at reports and see your officials.
Today I came after I sorted through half of jiejie's items, the rest is still there.
As it's still early I will take my leave first.
Mmm, go then.
Credits