Episode 65
I won't treat her poorly because she's your relative
How about Lingering?
Attendant Xi?
I dare not. I could never be good enough your majesty
Please don't
Should a normal maid have this honour
She'd be thanking the budda
whereas you would not
I confess my guilt.
I am in love with someone
you are in love with someone
Is he a guard or a imperial physician? Tell me
You tell me
then...
and I'll consent to a marriage
Huan Bi I need to keep
and arrange her marriage myself some day
Huan Bi
Go bring Hong Yan from Prince Nursery.
Yes
I love watching you being jealous
After Consort Hui passed away, you have been upset.
It's so hard to make you say more than a few words.
If it's just my grief, that would've been fine.
But had Ruofeiguaerjia not been making troubles,
Mei Jiejie would have not died.
You don't have to worry about that.
I will give you an answer soon.
I hope so.
Or else Mei Jiejie wouldn't be able to rest in peace.
During this morning's court sesision,
Emin mentioned that I already have four sons
I can choose the eldest son as the crown prince to strengthen our nation's roots.
Those who say so should immediately be beaten.
Even killing them wouldn't be enough.
You are still at your peak, how can people talk about roots and such?
How ridiculous.
The earlier I appoint a crown prince,
the earlier he will be a target for everyone.
And it will result in all the princes not studying well.
All their thoughts will be occupied on the crown prince's seat.
Besides, our dynasty has always chosen the wisest as the crown prince, not necessarily the eldest.
Why would anyone waste their breath on the matter of seniority?
Right,
recently the Fourth Prince has been diligent in his studies.
Have you asked about his studies?
He's alright. He is fluent in what he has studied.
But,
I still feel our child is the best. Hongyan is the best.
In the end, the Empress really is an honest person.
How else would she have concocted such a plan
to add alum into the paternity-testing water and obscure your vision and hearing.
It's probably because you favor the younger ones.
Even now, I still fear for the future.
So I beg you to favor Hongyan a little less.
The Empress is anxious,
that I know.
Though Hongshi is not the best,
he is still my child. How can I not care for him?
I'll negotiate a marriage for Hongshi soon.
Then the Empress will be at peace.
I have been afraid to tell Empress Mother
that the Empress was also involved in the matter from last time.
She even secretly changed the paternity-testing water
and tried to implicate Noble Consort and the Sixth Prince.
You don't have to tell me.
These days,
you have been unwilling to step inside Jingren Palace.
I knew then.
Ever since the Noble Consort came back pregnant,
not just outsiders,
but even I was suspicious.
The imperial family's bloodline must remain pure.
No accidents can be allowed.
The Empress is in charge of the Six Palaces so she investigated this matter.
She's the only one fit for this duty.
Her method of dealing with this was questionable,
so she snuck in water mixed with alum,
almost wronging the Noble Consort.
As for you, you can blame her for her uselessness.
But you can't accuse her of deliberate implication.
Yes.
It's not because of anything else,
but because she is your most loved one's sister.
You can not believe Yixiu (the Empress),
but you can't not believe Chunyuan.
Yes.
The queen is the mother of the nation.
If the nation's mother is not at peace, then the civilians won't be either.
If an Emperor goes out without his Empress,
but with his favored consort,
then that consort will have a greedy heart.
If one day
the consorts rise above the Empress,
then the harem,
perhaps even the whole country,
will be in great chaos.
Yes.
A dying person,
his words are also just.
I'm almost done here.
Emperor, you should remember that
no matter how good Guifei is,
there is only one queen
Elder sister,
everyday we are in the gardens either looking at flowers or catching butterflies.
It's really boring!
The Forbidden City,
others only see the never-ending luxuries.
But only when they go in
and see the skies from four corners and the walls on the four sides
do they realize this is the most suffocating place.
Right?
What secrets are you sisters sharing?
Greetings to the Emperor.
Sister-in-law is here.
What a coincidence.  Thank you Emperor.
These two days,
the weather has been hot.
Have you gotten used to the palace?
If you have any discomfort, do tell your sister.
Treat here like your house.
Meimei has been in the palace for more than a few days.
Though the palace is different from our home,
she has adjusted well.
They've imported some good after-rain Longjing (a type of tea)
I'll give it to you later.
I don't know if your meimei will like it or not.
Thanks for the Emperor's care.
This palace is luxurious with many beauties. Naturally this is the best place.
But the only inconvenience is that there I have to obey rules everywhere.
It's not like at home where I can do whatever I want.
For example, in a civlian's home,
I would be calling you brother-in-law.
But in this palace, I have to constantly remember
that you are the all-powerful emperor.
So I have to always be cautious.
I can't treat the palace like my home.
Did you hear?
You got quite a sharp mouth.
But compared to your meimei,
you would have to bow down to her.
You are clearly saying that the palace isn't as comfortable as your home,
yet I can't feel angry.
I also fear Yurao's mouth the most.
I've always thought,
what kind of brother-in-law will be able to control Yurao's mouth?
Your meimei just got back from a faraway place,
and you, as a Jiejie,
are already so impatient as to marry her off?
According to my will,
sister-in-law is still young in age and can remain single for two more years.
Then we'll patiently choose a good one and talk about marriage then.
Doesn't sister-in-law feel suppressed in the palace?
I remember now.
Yunxi is here in the palace today.
He told me the weather is good
and that he's going to Yuanmingyuan to practice archery.
Does Noble Consort Xi want to accompany me to see the competition?
Sister-in-law should come too.
Who does he think he is? If his archery skill isn't good,
then I don't want to see it.
She's agreed to go.
Emperor's idea is good.
It's also rare for Prince Shen to enter the palace.
Please allow us to change our clothes first
so that we can escort you.
Alright.
Good!
Yunxi is growing up well.
Excelling in archery and horsemanship.
The seventeenth brother's archery and horsemanship
was taught personally by Emperor Father.
Yet he's forgotten it all now.
He's not as good as he was when he was seven or eight.
Imperial brother,
it's because I drink too often now,
so I've become unfamiliar to it now.
But on the contrary,
you have been diligent in archery and horsemanship.
The seventeeneth brother hasn't married yet.
If he marries,
wouldn't his hands and feet become even lazier?
If I had known this earlier, I wouldn't have drunk the wine.
Before the arrow is shot, I'm already drunk.
Pour it.
I'm worthy of death!  It's fine.
It's just a piece of clothing.
I'll change it at the side palace.
What is that?
Give it to me.
The seventeenth brother must have promised his feelings at some place.
Or else why would we find on his body
such things from women.
This paper art
seems to resemble Noble Consort Xi.
Perhaps some things,
I have experienced too much this year.
It's just a little image.
How can you be sure it's me?
This image does resemble Noble Consort Xi a bit,
but don't you think,
it also looks like Second Lady and Huanbi?
The lady in the image has lively eyes and brows,
The more I look at it, the more I think it's Second Lady.
It will be Qixi (Chinese Valentine's Day) in a month.
Perhaps Emperor should fulfill the lovers' wish.
But this is the first time Second Lady and Seventeenth Brother have ever met!
The edges of this paper art are frayed.
Old seventeen must have held it in his hand and looked at it for many times.
Sister-in-law entered the palace only months ago.
She's never seen Old Seventeen before this.
It can't be her.
Please grant death upon this servant!
This object is my image.
Really?
Seven years ago,
I personally put it into the pouch.
At that time, Niang Niang was punished to kneel in front of Consort Hua's palace.
I met the Seventeenth Prince and asked him for help.
After, I went to Ninghui Palace to express my gratitude.
Really?
At that time, when I went to gave my thanks at Palace Ninghui,
I saw some pieces of colored paper on the Prince's desk.
On an impulse I cut out some window flower decorations
to give to the Prince as a present.
Then the Prince asked me if I knew how to cut out images.
So I cut out one according to my own likeness,
and put that little image into the pouch.
Then there was another time when I met with the Prince,
and the Prince asked me what kind of flower I like.
I said I like irises.
You can check in the pouch
to see if there are iris petals in there.
You are right.
If it's not your image,
how would you know,
what this pouch contains?
Huanhuan, did you know her feelings?
I am a fool.
She's deceived even me.
I remember that you always put a rhododendron in your hair.
What, the flower you like isn't rhododendron
but iris?
That's because the Prince said
I look pretty when I wear rhododendron.
So, so,
A few months ago, I went to Noble Consort Xi's palace
and never saw Huanbi.
I heard that Seventeenth Prince was ill
and Huanbi was the one who took care of him.
I was confused then
so it's because of this story between you two.
No wonder!
No wonder that day,
when I was joking with Noble Consort Xi
that I will make you a Lingering,
you were so shocked that you dropped what you were holding.
And no wonder
Old Seventeen hasn't even married a secondary wife.
I am of a lowly bearing and do not dare to climb to Prince's level.
It's just that,
I heard in the Prince's yard,
there are many jade-colored plum flowers.
I haven't had the chance to see them yet.
I just hope that if one day I can see them,
I would be satisifed.
If you guys keep on waiting,
you guys might have to wait another seven years.
Alright, today I will make a decision for you guys.
I'll give Huanbi to you.
Brother
But my position is lowly,
how can I have the privilege of tending to the Prince?
If it wasn't old Seventeen who personally told you
how would you know that he
has jade-colored plum flowers in his yard?
And your name is Huanbi (bi meaning jade)
Old Seventeen's household needs a mistress to tend to domestic affairs.
You have always been careful and cautious in your service to Noble Consort Xi.
You,
I have no worries.
If you just give Huanbi to the Prince like this,
I don't feel it's appropriate either.
When she enters the Prince's household,
will her position be escort concubine,
secondary wife, or wife?
Huanbi, as a dowry servant of Noble Consort Xi,
it would be too much to make her even an escort concubine.
Back when I left the palace to meditate,
I had only Jinxi and Huanbi by my side.
Huanbi grew up with me and is like a sister to me.
I think, that since the Prince liked Huanbi for seven years,
he must not want to treat her lightly.
Then what do you want?
I want to make Huanbi my godsister,
have her name in the genealogy,
and as Niuhulu clan's second daughter,
marry proudly into Prince Guojun's household as wife.
Noble Consort should know when to stop in sympathizing with Huanbi.
Later when the royal wives enter the palace,
will Huanbi, as the Prince's wife,
be sitting equally with us?
I know that Mistress cares for me,
but I don't care about positions.
Please don't worry for me anymore.
Huanbi,
you don't know how messed-up people can be.
If you marry without a title into the Prince's house,
people will gossip about it.
If well-meaning, they will say that you and the Prince have loved each other for a long time
and that this is fate.
If ill-meaning, they might even say you guys were committing adultery (*palace maids weren't allowed to have romantic affairs)
Both of your reputations would be ruined.
Brother,
forgive me for not marrying Miss Huanbi as my wife.
Many years ago,
I met a lady
whom I had mutual feelings with.
After, even though we were separated by thousands of miles,
and can't become husband and wife,
but in my heart,
she's my only wife.
Though Miss Huanbi is good,
but I will never have her as my wife.
I hope that Noble Consort Xi will understand.
Emperor should make the decision.
Just don't disappoint Huanbi.
I will do as you requested.
I will have Huanbi, as the second daughter of the Niuhulu Clan,
marry Prince Guojun as the secondary wife.
I thank you Emperor.
Congratulations Prince Guojun! Congratulations Miss Huanbi!  Get up!
I salute you.
Mistress is drunk.
I will take Mistress outside for some fresh air.
Huanbi, allow me.
Careful.
This pair of hands,
this person,
will become Huanbi's from now on.
I know you are upset.
But I'm more upset than you.
Today you celebrate with me,
tomorrow you will be my brother-in-law.
Does it have to be this way?
Look,
the moon is destined to set in the west.
You and I have no other roads to take.
If not this,
the dead won't just be you and me.
Just rumors,
Wen Shichu is an example.
I can't involve you anymore.
That matter from that day,
I hate myself for not being able to help you.
If it was you who was accused that day,
I would have gone crazy.
Huanbi has always liked you.
Her feelings toward you
are no less than mine.
I knew from early on.
Don't disappoint her.
You know,
I only want you.
Today will set the boundary between us.
Before there was only me.
After there will only be Huanbi.
To tell you the truth
Huanbi isn't my godsister,
but my blood sister.
Her mother was my father's lover.
But because her father was a criminal,
so father had to hide it
and not let Huanbi be included in the genealogy.
You must treat her well.
The Empress Dowager is very ill.
Your marriage will bring happiness to her.
Though the levels of bearing in this marriage don't match,
but at least you guys have mutual feelings.
I will listen to your arrangements.
On the matter of bearing,
I remember something.
A couple of years ago,
Empress Dowager wanted to arrange a marriage for you.
She was interested in Lord Peiguo's daughter Meng Jingxian.
Meng Jingxian met you once when she was young,
and has liked you ever since.
Yet you still haven't agreed to it.
That Meng Jingxian became obsessed and refused to marry others.
Now she has been delayed and has become an unmarried woman.
The matter of you marrying a secondary wife
has already spread.
Meng Jingxian became very sad
to the extent of being sick in bed.
Lord Peiguo loves his daughter much.
He has already submitted three proposals to me,
asking me to understand his daughter's love for you,
and that he would be willing to marry his daughter off
as an escort concubine to serve you.
So that he won't lose his daughter in his old age.
You know
that I don't want to marry more than I have to.
Besides, I have no feelings for Miss Meng.
I don't want to delay her.
Lord Peiguo has been a court official for two Emperors.
Yet his humble speech reflects his deep love for his daughter.
I can't help but empathize with him.
A man having three or four mistresses
is very normal.
I've made up my mind.
Miss Meng and Huanbi will both become your secondary wives.
But I've already wasted so many of her years
so I don't want to drag her along for the rest of her life.
Marriage between royals.
Being genuine is the least important.
I want you to marry her
to reassure the old official.
If you really don't like her
then just care for her at home.
Why let her become so ill that she dies?
If Lord Peiguo holds a grudge because of this,
the politics will be chaotic.
With this said,
I just need to care for her
and treat her well.
I wanted to hear this.
Then I have something to ask.
Speak.
I ask
to never marry others
and I want Huanbi to be in charge of the household.
You haven't even married, yet you're showing favoritism.
Miss Meng's health isn't well.
Putting Huanbi in charge of the household is natural.
Marrying secondary wife
has clothing obtenance, name choice, marriage fortune report,
dowry obtenance, date choice, and wedding as the six customs.
The rest have been done.
There's only the issue of the name.
As a Niuhulu goddaughter,
my family has the characters "Nu" and "Yu" constituting part of the names for the daughters of this generation.
Huanbi counts as the second miss.
The Internal Affairs Department has prepared
a few names starting with Yu.
Huanbi please choose your name.
Huanbi, look at them and see
which one you like.
They're all good names starting with Yu (jade).
Yuqin, Yuyin, Yuqiao
Why do they have Yu but have no Nu?
The names don't appear to be for a blood-born Niuhulu daughter.
The Customs department said that goddaughters aren't born of the family,
and that there must be a distinction.
So only the character Yu will be included in your name.
The doctor said
father's illness has almost fully recovered.
Your mother's entrance into our family temple is more important.
Then I'll have Yuyin (yin meaning hidden)
WIth Niangniang's opinion
the dowry, besides the Internal Affairs Department's,
Palace Yongshou will prepare three times as much
to give to Miss Yuyin as the dowry?
Consort Jing will oversee the wedding.
Zhen household's former servant girl Bin'er
will accompany Miss Yuyin in her marriage.
I won't let your wedding dowry
be less than Lord Peiguo's
and become inferior to his daughter in the future.
Thank you Mistress.
The wedding is on June fourth.
Niangniang's parents
are being arranged to visit inside the palace.
Huaner.
Greetings to father and mother.
Greetins to Noble Consort.
Noble Consort,
You can't perform the great bow to us!
I am not filial,
Carrying Niuhulu's last name,
I couldn't meet you at Yongshou palace.
As long as we reunite as a family
it is the same wherever we go.
Let's get up.
Get up.
Come, sit.
In all these years
mother has grown many white hairs.
We've endured all these years.
And now we've gotten out of it.
Back when our family was in decline,
I was just afraid that it would trouble you too.
We're a family. Don't speak of troubling each other.
Now it's all better
and Yuying is getting married.
Yuying having this fate
her mother,
can rest in peace now.
Although it's secondary wife,
but Yuying sincerely likes the lord.
Her wish has been granted.
This is all to your trouble.
You have worried much for her.
Parents living at an inn
is not a long term solution.
The Emperor has people fixing up Zhen estate.
Mother and father can live peacefully.
His Majesty allowing us to visit you in the palace
is already a huge gift of kindness.
How can we ask to live in this city for such a long time?
Being able to see you and the grandchild is satisfying.
I am much comforted.
I don't ask for anything else.
Since you've returned,
I won't let you
return to the poor mountains.
Using this return
I will find a way to ask the Emperor
to investigate that year's events.
Originally
Second Miss has always worn jade-colored clothing.
Who would have thought that you wearing red is even prettier?
It's a pity that it's only secondary wife,
and I can't wear true red.
Very beautiful, so pretty.
Thank you, older sister, for arranging all of this.
Tomorrow is the big day.
The lord doesn't have a wife
and there's only Meng Jingxian who ranks the same as you.
You must not endure everything quietly
but you also must not nitpick on everything.
Live a peaceful life.
The lord said
that you will be in charge of everything at his estate.
Balance justice and mercy.
The upper and lower households must be treated appropriately.
Sister, I'm sorry.
This position should have been yours.
I took your position.
My position is the Emperor's Noble Consort Xi.
How did you take mine?
Tomorrow you are to wed.
You need to be very happy.
Don't think too much about other things.
Sister.
I know you are sad.
The bride needs to be happy,
how can you cry?
Sister, do you regret it?
That year
if you waited a few more months
today the person marrying the lord
wouldn't be me.
I chose my own path
so there's no going back.
Living in the palace is too difficult.
I don't have the time, or mood to regret anything.
Your future path has been determined by your choice today.
I hope that
you can always move on with out regretting anything.
Sister I'm afraid.
I am worried that the lord's heart will only have you.
I don't know
how to be this secondary wife.
For your matter, I am an outsider.
Prince Guojun household's husband is you and the prince.
How to accomplish this is all up to you.
I can only tell you to be genuine.
Being genuine is the most important.
Sister
I will use all of my heart to treat the lord well.
I will be filial to his mother.
You just need to remember
that from now on, on our shoulders
we carry the Zhen family's future.
Remember.
You are the lord's secondary wife.
Niuhulu Yuyin bids farewell to Noble Consort Xi.
Take care of yourself.
The lucky time has come, and the lord's estate is ready.
Lord Peiguo's is already on their way.
Second miss may leave now.
Go.
I'd rather it was you.
That way he'd be happy.
Yuying has more fortune than I do.
Marrying two at once.
But both are not the ones he wants.
Raise the sedan.
Time's mistiming has never stopped.
It's normal.
Congratulations!
Congratulations Lord Guojing!
Come, let's drink!
So lucky!
Two secondary wives.
Right, congratulations.
Congratulations!
Happy!
Lord, lord.
Come, get up.
Don't touch me.
I'm fine.
Lord, two secondary wives, you need to say something.
Who's place are you going to sleep tonight?
Lord, it's your big night.
You can't just not go to any of them.
Lord. Lord!
Huan...Huanbi.
Okay. To Changqing Ge!
Lord.
Miss, it's time to sleep.
Changqing Ge's lights have gone out.
Meng Jingxian
I knew what it would be like after I married him.
This is only the first night.
You are sighing already.
From now on there will be more days to sigh.