Episode 36
To the right.
There, go, go.
Left, more left, a bit more.
- Like this?- Good, just like that.
This picture is perfect for our house.
There's no better place for it than here.
It's good that His Majesty writes,
but he keeps writing.
My neck really hurts.
Greetings, Lady Wan.
Why are you so hurried?
I was asked to invite you to the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
What happened?
His Majesty is very upset.
Huan-Bi, prepare to depart.
Down.
Consort has arrived.
His Majesty is very angry.
He chased all the servants away.
Consort, I beg of you,
please try to calm him down.
- We'd be so grateful.- What happened?
I believe it has something to do with a letter from Lord Dun.
Do you know what he wrote?
Seems to be about a request for a promotion.
Lord Dun is too greedy.
Two of his children already received promotions. Now he's asking for another?
Servant has the same thoughts.
His Majesty could deny the request.
He's not a hot-tempered person.
That's true.
Nonsense.
Consort.
Your Majesty, drink some tea. It will help you to calm down.
Why aren't you asking why I'm so upset?
I'm waiting for Your Majesty to calm down.
You will tell me when you want to.
See for yourself.
Yun, how dare he...
He wants Your Majesty to give his mother a title
of Honored Consort,
and receive a burial in the Imperial grave.
Lady Wen is former Lady.
Even though she has passed away,
giving her a title isn't a problem.
But because she died discontented,
the former Emperor denied her being buried there.
If you agree with the promotion,
you will be negating the former Emperor's decision.
What does Your Majesty plan to do?
He wants to destroy me,
even put the former Emperor aside.
Worse than than,
after Lord Dun asked for this promotion,
Nian Gengyao asked for the title of Honored Consort,
and to rebuild the Imperial grave just to calm the Ladies.
Your Majesty is implying
that Lord Dun and Nian Gengyao are conspiring together.
Nonsense.
Your Majesty, calm down.
Don't be angry because of them.
It's a waste to be angry because of them.
There are some things I can tolerate, but some things I can't.
Even if I can't be loyal to my parent,
I can tolerate what they have done,
but Empress can't.
The title of Honored Consort is too much.
Even the mother of the Lord,
did not have the title of Honored Consort.
So how can a woman who betrayed the former Emperor receive it?
If you agree with this promotion,
I'm sure all the Lords and Consorts will be against it.
Both sides will be affected.
If I agree, I lose on both sides.
If I reject it, he will feel a grudge against me.
All this effort will be for nothing.
Your Majesty has been generous for so many years.
Do you wish to continue?
General Nian has many allies.
If I don't tolerate,
I'll only have 40% support.
Nian Gengyao hates the way I treat Consort Nian.
He kept trying to get close to Lord Dun,
in order to gain a win-win situation,
to join forces against me.
Staying in the palace,
seeing the things that bother your Majesty,
I wouldn't dare to touch.
I only knew of my own happiness of being with your Majesty.
I never knew you had so many worries.
Every position
has difficulties that cannot be avoided.
They must run their course.
Then, for the future,
your Majesty must accept this one.
I'm such a coward of an Emperor.
Emperor Jing of Han wanted to calm the seven countries,
so he killed Chao Cuo.
Emperor Guangwu Liu-Xiu wanted to rebuild the Hans,
so he killed his brother, even though he was scared.
In order to stabilize the government,
he withheld the title of Empress from his beloved wife, Yin Lihua.
She was only called Lady.
But in the end,
the country was made harmonious and prosperous.
A true man is broad-minded.
Your Majesty needs to be patient,
so you can setup a greater plan for your government.
Not as a coward, not selfishly.
Huan-Huan.
You really know how to calm my nerves.
It's not to calm you, Your Majesty.
I'm just reciting the facts.
You're right.
I need to be patient.
But how exactly?
Grant Lord Dun his request,
about the title of Honored Consort.
If even Lady Wan cannot advise His Majesty...
What should we do?
How am I to know,
if even Lady Wan does not know?
Your Majesty.
It's fine. Clean it up later.
Your Majesty, please.
Agree to the promotion,
and bestow the title.
Then move her burial to the imperial grave.
Then, for all the Consorts,
elevate each of their titles.
Especially to the consort lead, Honored Consort Sou-Qi.
And give the former Empress a higher title,
to show Your Majesty's loyalty.
That's right. He wants his mother to have the title.
I'll give all the consorts a title,
as a prayer to the former Empress.
That way, none of them will be able to complain.
This shouldn't cause any complaints from the minister.
And the Lords and Consorts will all be glad to hear this news.
But Lord Guo's mother...
Empress Su has already left.
What will Your Majesty do about this?
Lord Seventeenth wouldn't care.
He may not care,
but I'm afraid others will think that
Your Majesty is looking down on him.
Why not extend him a favor?
Why not?
Empress Su is a monk.
I cannot give her a title,
but I can greet her as Lady Chong-Jing.
Yes, that would be the best solution.
You are my solution,
thinking on my behalf.
Your Majesty needs to the rule the country.
I don't know anything about that.
I can only take on small matters,
for Your Majesty.
A thousand mile trip starts with the first step.
Those small matters can lead to solving bigger matters.
Empress has arrived.
Greetings, Empress.
I heard that His Majesty is upset,
so I've come to help.
Yes, that's true.
But right now Lady Wan is in the palace.
Eunuch Su, please inform His Majesty
that I am here.
Yes, Empress.
Empress, it's better to not meet His Majesty right now.
Since Lady Wan is here,
His Majesty has no need of me.
Let's visit Empress Dowager.
I wish for Your Majesty to show generosity,
and return the title of Honored Consort to Consort Nian.
If I return her title, I'll feel guilty towards you.
How will I stop the rumors?
Both brother and sister are alike.
Once they are content, they will make a mistake.
And when she receives the title,
the Nian family will settle down.
Your Majesty must tolerate for the sake of the country.
And I will tolerate for Your Majesty's sake.
This is very unfair for you.
I don't think so.
As long as it helps Your Majesty,
I can be patient with Consort Nian.
Okay.
Huan-Huan, we lost a child.
I'm sorry.
But don't worry,
I'll make up for that.
Lord Dun wants to give Wen-Xi the title of Honored Consort.
And Nian Gengyao supports this idea.
Time flies.
No matter how big the title is,
the dead will never know about it.
Mother, allow this promotion.
Why wouldn't I?
This is just to show the people.
The dead will never know.
As long as your decision is good for the country,
I don't care about the title.
Thank you, Mother.
Time passes and things change.
Look at Consort Nian.
I'm afraid she will become like Wen-Xi.
Thank goodness she doesn't have any children.
Because of this, I have given more care to Lady Wan.
She lost a child.
I feel as if I owe her something.
I know what you are thinking.
The Huanyi perfume we gave to Consort Nian,
it contained muck.
It spoiled Consort Nian.
But I never thought it would affect Lady Wan.
We never wanted that.
But since it happened, don't think too much about it.
You can love Lady Wan more. Everything will be fine.
Just not too much.
I'm not a good father.
You must make decisions when necessary.
Once Consort Nian has a child,
I'm sure Nian Gengyao
will try to make him Emperor.
When that day comes,
you and I
will lose our positions.
You have set Consort Nian aside.
No matter how educated Lord Dun is,
he still cannot compare to General Nian.
But what if they were to work together?
Therefore,
you should spend more time with Consort Nian.
It's not that I don't want to,
to calm her down.
Since she served you for so long,
and so faithfully.
I'm an Emperor, also a father.
When Consort Nian was pregnant,
you were forced to kill the child.
How could this not hurt you?
These things were done by Consort Duan.
Consort Duan admitted to it,
so don't think about it anymore.
So many children lost.
All this might be returned to me.
I'm the one who prepared
the medicine for Consort Nian.
If someone's to pay, it shouldn't be you.
Every time His Majesty has gotten angry.
I've been by his side.
And this is only the first time for Lady Wan.
Empress knows that
she is sure to advise His Majesty.
Empress.
Lady Wan will start going to
the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
But Consorts shouldn't involve themselves in ruling.
Lady Wan should avoid it.
Nothing will happen to her,
if that's what His Majesty wants.
Your servant doesn't think so.
It all depends on His Majesty's mood.
That's true.
If His Majesty is happy, he'll allow her to talk.
If he is not, she'll be overstepping her bounds.
Empress.
His Majesty is moving to the Palace of Supporting Earth.
I knew it. This day has finally come.
Madam.
Madam, His Majesty is coming to the Palace of Supporting Earth.
Madam, quick, greet His Majesty.
Stand.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I'm here. Are you unhappy?
I'm happy.
It's been a long time.
I thought
Your Majesty would never come.
I was so mad at you
that I did not want to see you.
But tomorrow,
I remembered that tomorrow
is the day you came to the palace.
Your Majesty.
Huan-Bi, listen -- the snow is melting.
Yes it is, Lady's hearing is good.
Spring is here.
All the snow will melt.
His Majesty went to the Palace of Supporting Earth. Are you not angry?
I'm aware now that
being the Emperor is difficult and complicated.
Since we each have our own difficulties,
we will end up troubling each other.
I'm just afraid that once His Majesty meets with Consort Nian
she will become your enemy again.
If she becomes my enemy,
then yes, I'll have no choice.
But if His Majesty and I are together,
my enemy will become the Emperor's enemy.
Empress, please have some tea.
Did you sleep well last night?
Yes, I'm fine.
I heard the snow melting last night,
dropping all night.
Empress didn't sleep well.
I'm afraid that all the consorts did not sleep well.
Consort Nian has arrived.
Greetings Empress.
Please, sit down.
Greetings Consort Nian.
Stand.
Thank you Consort.
Lady Wan, long time no see.
I think so.
But I'm always thinking of you.
Even though it's been a long time,
it seems just like the opposite.
I met with His Majesty yesterday.
His Majesty seemed to miss you very much.
You really know His Majesty well.
You can read everything.
I dare not.
But everyone knows that
His Majesty misses Consort.
Thanks to you.
Consort Nian, His Majesty chose some imported items and had them sent to your palace.
Are they to your liking?
Yes, as long as they were chosen by His Majesty.
It's good that you like them.
It's been so long since I've seen you, you've become a stranger.
Please visit me more often.
Yes, I will.
As long as you don't think of me as a meddler.
Emperor has arrived.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty visits so often,
aren't you getting tired of the dishes?
You've never asked that before.
I'm afraid...
Then I'll leave, so you won't have to ask.
Your Majesty.
You're thinking rubbish.
Tell me what you have prepared.
You'll know once you see it.
Zhen Yuan-Dao greets His Majesty.
Zhen Yuan-Dao, stand.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Outsides these walls, you're my minister,
but here, you're my father-in law.
So there's no need to be so formal.
Su Pei-Seng, prepare a seat.
Zhen, please sit.
Thank you, Eunuch.
May I ask why Your Majesty
has called for me?
I promoted you as Left Deputy Censor.
Are you getting used to the work?
Thank you, Your Majesty, for caring.
Sit down. I'll feel strange if you keep standing.
I wasn't so polite with Lady Wan.
Lady Wan is a mischievous and playful girl,
because she is young.
I hope Your Majesty does not mind that.
I like her the way she is.
Thank you for Your Majesty's kindness.
Such a lucky star to my family,
and to Lady Wan.
I called you here
to tell you to keep in contact with useful people in the Censorate,
and to find out what's happening at the Censorate.
Your Majesty.
I will follow your order.
In the Censorate, Left Deputy Censor, Lady Guwalgiya E-Min,
Lady Xue Chong-Jian, Lady Luo Ping, and I
have gathered evidence that proves the disloyalty of Nian Gengyao.
But without Your Majesty's command,
we dared not make a move.
Since Nian Gengyao's return,
complaints keep coming in.
I didn't look into it before,
because I didn't have a suitable plan
to gain success with one strike.
I understand what Your Majesty means.
I will do whatever Your Majesty requires.
Good.
When the time comes, I'll tell Zhang Ting-Yu to inform you.
I'll do whatever I can.
Oh.
Lady Wan is in the palace. Since you are here,
why not pay her a visit?
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Since Lady Wan miscarried
my wife and I have been so worried.
We cannot come and go as we please to the palace.
We will wait for Your Majesty's call,
and then come and visit Lady Wan.
Don't worry. I'll take good care of Lady Wan.
Lady Wan and I, thank Your Majesty for taking care of us.
It's late.
I'll let you go home now.
Su Pei-Seng, escort him.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, I'll take my leave of you now.
Consort.
What happened?
His Majesty is good to Consort these days.
All the servants are happy about it.
By the old rules,
there must be many people waiting to meet you, and give you gifts.
Times are different now.
It's not easy for me to gain His Majesty's love.
So, don't be careless.
But His Majesty still shows Consort favor.
I can't tell what is different,
but His Majesty does not treat me the way he did in the past.
Even though His Majesty visits here often,
he hasn't returned either my title
or my status to me.
I still feel unstable.
As long as His Majesty continues to come here, all those things will soon be yours.
I heard that His Majesty rewarded the General again.
That's good for him.
Even though I behave badly,
I'm still better than Brother.
What I'm most afraid of is, once Brother becomes too happy, he might cause trouble carelessly.
But since Brother is trustworthy,
I, also, can settle down here.
Go and check whether the medicine is ready.
Then send it to His Majesty.
Yes, Consort.
You really have good technique.
I served my mom like this when I was at home.
You're a dutiful daughter.
I have this body because of my parents,
so I should be a dutiful daughter.
I wish to know,
why you treat me so well.
Empress Dowager is the mother of His Majesty.
Therefore, also my mother-in-law.
My owner.
So, I should treat you nicely.
You are so loyal to me.
But you should spend more time with His Majesty.
You are young, but you are always by my side.
You need to plan for yourself.
Your make it sound like I do it on purpose.
It's not that I don't want to get close to His Majesty.
It's just that,
His Majesty cares about Empress Dowager's health.
So I should serve and take care of you.
Secondly, His Majesty has many wives.
I'm not very good with makeup.
I can't compare to you.
I hope that when Empress Dowager has time, you will give me a lesson.
I've gained so much from Empress Dowager,
it's hard for me to leave.
You've become very good with words.
I have you by my side,
and the skill of Imperial Doctor Wen.
I'm sure to stay healthy.
This is all because of Imperial Doctor Wen.
I just stay by your side.
I cannot really help very much.
I know Empress didn't use perfume,
but I don't understand why.
Who doesn't like perfume?
But I wished to follow His Majesty's will.
It was to save money.
But no matter how I save,
once the others saw the precious perfume used by Consort Nian,
they complained about it, and said I was being stingy.
So that resulted with me not using perfume.
Empress is very kind.
His Majesty must appreciate your view.
It is just a small matter.
Greetings Empress.
Greetings Lady Wan.
Stand.
His Majesty has declared to all the consorts,
that the title of Noble Consort has been restored to Consort Nian.
I'm already aware of that. You may leave.
Look, it's just a change.
Empress doesn't feel weird about it?
Things like this can happen anytime.
Just like a flower that blooms in spring,
but only shows for a short time,
turns out to be meaningless.
Congratulations Consort! Congratulations Consort!
Stand.
I've waited so long for this. Finally it is here.
Consort missed His Majesty so much.
Now the world will know that His Majesty sensed it,
and treat Consort nicely now.
I'll never know the truth.
But might I dare to ask
does His Majesty treats you nicely again?
Yes.
Consort kept up with the proposals.
Not just His Majesty,
but also I was touched by that.
Consort is loyal to His Majesty.
I'm sure His Majesty knows this.
There were so many rumors at that time. So in order to stop the rumors,
His Majesty had to avoid Consort.
Consort has finally gained success.
I'm not sure why,
but I feel a bit at a loss.
I've been with His Majesty for so many years,
but feel like I don't really know him.
I don't understand.
His Majesty treats you so well.
Clearly this shows that.
Keep safe the Imperial edict.
I don't care about the title,
as long as His Majesty keeps me in his mind.
This is the new tea for the year.
Sister, what do you think?
It has a nice flavor. Thank you for thinking of me.
Sister seldom walks in front of His Majesty.
Therefore, I miss Sister, and have come to visit.
Sleepy in spring, and lazy in autumn. I don't really like celebrations.
I heard that Empress Dowager likes Sister very much.
Isn't it hard for you, to always be by her side?
No, as long as she doesn't complain about me.
Sister has the Empress Dowager's support,
so you should have nothing to worry about.
Unlike me, who is always facing trouble.
It could be
that His Majesty will plan for you.
But His Majesty restored the title to Consort Hua.
When I think about the way Consort Hua intimidated everybody,
I'm so scared I can't sleep.
The return of Consort Hua.
Sadly, it appears that His Majesty has forgotten all about
the miscarriage of Huan.
All her effort gone, just like that.
I would not dare to talk in front of His Majesty,
but Sister is different.
As long as you gain His Majesty's love,
His Majesty will love to hear what you have to say.
Is Sister angry with me?
Honored Lady Hui has misunderstood.
Lady did not advise His Majesty.
It was Lady Wan who asked His Majesty to restore Consort Hua's title.
What is this rubbish?
Servant wouldn't dare. I heard it from Xiao Sha-Zi.
- Are you sure there was no mistake?- Xiao Sha-Zi works at the palace.
It wouldn't be a mistake.
Sister, why would Sister Huan do that?
Rumors cannot be trusted.
Huan hates Consort Hua. She wouldn't do that.
But last time, Sister Huan advised His Majesty to meet Consort Hua.
Enough.
If Huan did that, she would have told me.
If she didn't, that means she didn't.
We shouldn't listen to rumors.
It's late.
I need to go and visit Empress Dowager. You should leave too.
I'll go first.
Lady, Honored Lady An's words seem to be true.
It might not be a rumor.
I know. Huan must make it clear.
If she asked His Majesty to restore the title,
then she shouldn't be my good sister.
But I don't think she is like that.
Greetings Empress Dowager. Auspicious wishes for the Empress Dowager.
- Stand and talk.- Thank you, Empress Dowager.
Sit down and talk.
It's been a long time that I haven't talked to you.
What keeps you so busy?
Nothing in particular.
Just spending time doing things.
Then tell me how you are spending it.
Listening might bring me some news.
The Imperial Household bred two cranes in the garden.
They look nice.
With two deer in the garden, they really reflect the scene of spring.
This medicine is very bitter.
Even my tongue became woody.
Empress Dowager.
Empress Dowager, this is the newly made hawthorn.
It is sweet and sour. It will be good with your medicine. It will suit you the best.
You are so thoughtful.
- It has a nice flavor.- It's good that Empress Dowager likes it.
I was thinking that since your medicine is bitter,
if you had it with something sweet, it might taste worse.
But if you had it with something sweet and sour, it might taste better.
Lady Wan, do you know your mistake?
I'm afraid I don't. Empress Dowager, please tell me.
How dare you, as a Lady, interfere with the government.
- Empress Dowager, she...- I'm asking her. What are you worried about?
I don't understand Empress Dowager.
But I do not dare to make a mistake.
I'll allow you to talk
about the restoration of the title, and how much you are involved.
Empress Dowager, please check clearly. Even when I was young and mischievous,
I understood that I shouldn't be involved in ruling.
His Majesty is a good Emperor.
He had to make a decision about the title being restored.
I can't move him to change his mind.
I was foolish.
I thought the title return was about all the consorts.
So, I dared to say a few words.
About ruling, I really would not dare to interfere.
Even if you never meant to do so,
you dare to say you didn't try to gain something?
I wouldn't lie to Empress Dowager.
His Majesty is an Emperor,
always worrying about the country -- forgetting to eat and sleep.
I am thankful for His Majesty's love, and that I can serve him.
If I wish for anything,
it is for His Majesty to have a long and peaceful life.
And from that, I would benefit, and be at peace until the end.
All the consorts have this same wish.
Fine then, stand.
Thank you, Empress Dowager.
Your wish. It is the same for all of us.
You're here because the Emperor is here.
As long as His Majesty is here, no matter who is in the palace,
you still have hope, a goal.
If His Majesty is gone,
not to say Empress,
as the Empress Dowager
just like Honored Lady Cao,
she can rely upon her daughter.
but you and Mei don't have any children.
You might have a beautiful life, but you may have a sad end.
In a word, waiting for the time to pass.
The only person you can depend upon
is His Majesty.
I heard it from His Majesty
that the title return was your idea.
Yes, Empress Dowager.
Now you dare to say.
Clever, Empress Dowager.
Try to disobey His Majesty.
Even though I'm stupid,
I understand what Empress Dowager means.
I hope Empress Dowager can check clearly,
that in this situation, the government needed to be settled down,
as well as all the consorts.
I wouldn't cause trouble to the country,
just for myself.
Someone had to suffer.
And I wished to be that person.
Nice girl.
I didn't realize you had such thoughts.
That's why His Majesty loves you so much.
And allows you to enter the Imperial Study Room.
Empress Dowager shouldn't say so. I'm not as good as that.
Empress told me that
your accompanying His Majesty would be no problem.
I didn't feel that way.
How can a consort enter the Imperial Study Room?
But you are so clever.
If you use your cleverness in a bad way,
or encourage His Majesty blindly,
ruling the world by threatening others to follow you,
you'll become a problem for this country.
Then I can't have you in this palace.
I would not dare.
Serve His Majesty well,
so that you may have a child soon.
Thank you, Empress Dowager.
Mei is calm and steady,
while you are clever and smart.
After Empress Chun-Yuan passed away, His Majesty never had
a helpful and understanding person beside him.
If you two serve him with full attention,
I'm sure he'll have nothing to worry about.
Empress Dowager just gave me a big responsibility.
It's my napping time.
You can go and walk around.
I take my leave.
Lady Wan.
There's a saying, that a girl without talent is the best.
But I don't think so.
But if a girl is too clever, she might pay for it with her life.
It's wasted.
A talented girl who knows how to retrieve becomes smart and lucky.
That's the best way to do it.
Even though you are all just consorts in the palace,
with your actions,
you can make a great change.
Beware of your talk and movements.
Yes, Empress Dowager.
Where is Sister Mei?
She took the servants and went to the kitchen.
Seems she's making dessert for Empress Dowager.
She might not come back early.
Let's go home.
Lady.
Speak.
This afternoon, I saw Lady Hui.
She was very angry, rushing from Palace of Long and Healthy Life.
Then I saw Lady Wan leaving as well.
Not sure, but maybe Lady Hui disturbed the Empress Dowager.
If she disturbed the Empress Dowager, why would she be angry?
If Lady Hui was seen angry, she probably found out
that it was Lady Wan who asked for the title return.
But Lady Hui last told you, she didn't believe it.
She wouldn't believe my words.
But later, she discovered the truth.
Because she had doubted it, that's why she's so angry.
I really wish to know.
Since she is so close to Lady Wan,
will she really trust her
to where she never doubts her.