~ Episode 22 ~
Niang Niang definitely got honored today
When the empress was next to Niang Niang
she seemed so shabby compared to you
Even though the emperor said to be frugal
you can't be too uncaring about your own face and appearance
Who doesn't want the woman sitting to them
to be eye-catching and attractive?
I was thinking that since the Empress Dowager is still sick
I should give something to show my filial heart
and gain favor from this old person
Isn't that easy?
As long as silver (money) is spent
there will be good things
The people I recommended to my brother last time
how much of the silver they gave is left?
Servant just went to see
besides rewarding servants
and buying jewelry and clothing
there are still four or five thousand ounces left
How is that enough?
You have to give the very best to the Empress Dowager
or you might as well not give at all
If only at this time
I can get some silver, it would be nice
Servant heard from Zhou Ning Hai
that someone had wanted to go through Niang Niang's backdoor
for a long time
Who?
Last month, the Chief General impeached Zhao Zhi Yuan
and he lost his job as the Zhili Governor
No way!
Gege (older brother) personally asked the Emperor to fire him
how can I let him meet Gege again?
Zhao Zhi Yuan said that
if he can meet the Chief General
and say at least a sentence to him
he would send fifty thousand ounces of silver to Yi Kun Palace
If he is successful
he would double the amount!
Ok then
then tell Zhou Ning Hai to accept the silver
and tell Gege about Zhao Zhi Yuan
Let me see
how much skills he has to persuade Gege
Greetings to the Chief General
The Emperor and Prince Guojun are inside playing Chinese chess
Then I'll be here waiting
Yes
then I am sorry that the Chief General will have to wait here long
Can Chief General please move to the side slightly
Courtiers cannot stand at the very middle
I'll just wait here for a little bit
Ah, yes.
Go get a chair and allow Nian Chief General to sit while he waits
Yes
Chief General, please sit
Move it to the front a little
Move it closer
Chief General, please sit
Was your journey to Chuan Shu all good this time?
The scenery was good, but the people were cold
I (courtier brother) was heading west
especially at the Shan Gan region
the people only respected Nian Chief General and none disobeyed the law
Occassionally there are a couple who don't obey
but they were pressed down quickly
there wasn't any disagreement
Emperor Brother has won
I won quite dangerously
I was fighting hard for a long time
but I still lost the whole game
wouldn't have tried so hard if I had known earlier
If you victory can be achieved easily, what's the point?
You must strategize carefully and then you can win
It was fun playing
I'm not as good at chess as Emperor Brother
Playing chess is like managing an empire, emphasizing on the art of balancing
I only know advancing/backing down, not balancing
No wonder I always lose to Emperor Brother
This game will end here for now
I'll come here next time to learn from Emperor Brother
Leave peacefully, Prince Guojun
Nian Chief General
Courtier greets Prince Guojun
Courtier was in the Northwest for many years
when it's cold my foot illness would start
so I can't get up to greet the Prince
I hope the Prince won't get angry at me
It's fine
as long as you don't lose your manners in front of the Emperor
What?
Prince has a good temper
but servant's (my) heart is made of flesh
I can't stand the Prince being humiliated like this
This time when he, Nian Gengyao, arrived in Jing City,
all the courtiers had to kneel down to welcome him from afar
Such power and honor is definitely a first
Besides, he and Long Ke Duo are like the Emperor's arms
I'm only one of the deceased Emperor's sons
not really worth much
but the Prince is still the Prince
He's just a servant
when a prince loses power, he is not on par with a servant
when a servant gains power, he will humiliate his master
Ever since Emperor Brother stepped onto throne
he's been suspicious about the deceased Emperor's sons
with me, he's already nice enough
but Nian Gengyao being such a tyrant
I (servant) can't stand it!
Indifferent to self-suppression
is the key to surviving besides the Emperor
But...
no need to speak further
Prince
Do we visit Tai Fei (royal concubine dowager) at the end of this month?
Everything's been arranged already
as usual, the Prince doesn't need to worry
I'm enduring all this for Mother
and Mother is enduring everything for me
A Jin, no need for more words
Yes
Courtier has sin
Courtier didn't know the right person and almost delayed military matters
Please forgive me, Emperor
What? Get up and talk
Yes
The last time Courtier reported
that Zhili Governor Zhao Zhi Yuan was useless and unintelligent
was because I believed others' rumors
and caused Zhao Zhi Yuan to lose his job
This time Courtier has investigated Zhao Zhi Yuan again more carefully
and found out that he is a loyal, capable person
Zhao Zhi Yuan's job loss was caused by Courtier's words
it is Courtier's big mistake
Courtier has thought about it day and night and was anxious and ashamed
so I've come to apologize to the Emperor
You were working for me
The matter has a lot of inner details
so it's hard to have everything done perfectly
Since Zhao Zhi Yuan's already been dismissed
Loyal, righteous men like Zhao Zhi Yuan
not being used by the imperial court makes me anxious and worried
I've already dismissed him because of your words
If he is used so suddenly again
the imperial order being changed so quickly
My orders in the future would not be trusted by others
Courtier has misinvestigated
If it's because of my mistake
that the imperial court had to lose righteous courtiers
I would be ashamed of myself
Since the emperor already gave the imperial order
to dismiss Zhao Zhi Yuan from being a Zhili Governor
Then please give him some other job
it would save the Emperor's face on one hand
and be fair to righteous courtiers on the other hand
Are you really gonna be so insistent?
Courtier has already made a mistake, I can't make it again
please let Courtier to correct his mistake
Since you've so insitently recommended him
then I'll use him again, though it's out of order
You say what kind of job he should get
Courtier is scared, Emperor's royal decision will be it
You understand what kind of job he should get
you should his talent
can Zhao Zhi Yuan be the Industry Political Commissioner?
I'll listen to you
Thank the Emperor
You are loyal toward the Empire and puts it first
I, naturally, views you as an important courtier
Courtier bows to thank Emperor
Don't know it's which master of the Harem Palace
that Courtier Nian Gengyao has seen before
Our master is Lady Wan
Lady Wan
Greetings to Nian Chief General
Thank the Lady for her fortunate words
Hua Fei (Fei is 3rd to highest ranked title) Niang Niang is Courtier's younger sister
If Niang Niang is good, then I am good
Niang Niang is favored by the Emperor
how can she not be good?
Though the Emperor favors her
I only fear that some don't know their places
and use their imperial favors to displease Niang Niang
Nobody would dare to create conflicts
I should hope so
Or else even if the Emperor doesn't interfere
I will not just let it go either
Siblings have deep relationships, it's the norm
Since the lady understands, courtier shall go for now
What was the expression on Nian Geng Yao's face when he went out?
Chief General was happier when he went out than when he came in
How can he not be happy when the Emperor called him?
He is happy
When the Chief General arrived
Emperor was still playing chess with Seventeenth Prince
so he waited outside for a while sitting on a chair
He was sitting while he was waiting?
Yes
Even when the Seventeen Prince went out, the Chief General did not get up
said he had foot illness
Fortunately Seventeen Prince's personality is good
so he didn't argue with him
But now that you think abou it,
Chief General has so many achievements
who would dare to argue with him?
Servant was wrong in his words
You said the truth, not necessarily wrong
Lady Wan is here
Servant was just about to come get you
I don't dare to
Is the emperor inside?
He is
Nian General was just here
Emperor is not very happy
Lady should be careful in dealing with him
Thanks Gong Gong
Courtier Concubine greets the Emperor
May the Emperor receive ten thousand blessings and golden peace
Get up then
Yes
Sit
Did the Courtier Concubine arrive at the wrong time?
Emperor just finished discussing matters with Nian Chief General
and must feel tired
I am a little tired
Huan Huan, you are learned in poetry
What are your thoughts on cliques?
Courtier Concubine does not dare to interfere with political matters
No worries
I only discuss historical works with you
Courtier Concubine has long lived in the Back Palace, so how can I know these things?
But when Courtier Concubine read Ouyang Xiu's clique theory
there was a section that quite made sense
Tell me about it
Sir Ouyang said
when villains seek the same goal
acquaintances will become part of the clique
but when only one can attain that benefit and they have to fight amongst themselves
or when both parties have attained the benefit and the goal is already achieved, they will harm each other
To come together for benefits will result in disbandment because of the fight for benefits
therefore any worrying matters
shouldn't amount to be the Emperor's worries
You usually know how to say things that will make me happy
Just talks don't count
You have to write Ouyang Xiu's clique theory
so that when I'm worried
I'll look at your writing and not be worried
After so much fuss
it seems like Emperor only wanted to make Courtier Concubine write
Courtier Concubine's writing most resembles a devil's writing
If the Emperor wants to look at writings
then find a famous calligrapher to write
Emperor
A man's best calligraphy still has a rough prideful air to it
it can't compare to a woman's finely written calligraphy
when worried it has a calming effect
Then Courtier Concubine will respectfully obey the order
Write then
Niang Niang
Niang Niang, besides the promised ten thousand ounces of silver checks
these are all additional items Zhao Daren honored you with
He surprisingly convinced Gege
Isn't that right, Niang Niang?
Zhao Daren has decided to follow Niang Chief General now
Chief General even personally talked to the Emperor
and got a job for Zhao Daren
He really only said one sentence
Reply to Niang Niang, Yes
I am curious then
What kind of sentence was it?
Servant heard that
when Zhao Daren met Niang Chief General
he only said this one sentence
Three hundred thousand ounces of silver delivered to Niang Chief General's household
Ten thousand silver checks delivered to Yi Kun Palace
I'll count him as capable
Lady put a lot of thought into this nightgown
this garment really is flawless
If it had Lin Rong's embroideries
the garment would be ten times better than me
If discussing embroideries
of course there will always be someone better
but if discussing thoughtfulness
this piece would be the very best
Emperor treats me so well
so I naturally have to serve him with my whole heart and my whole mind
Only a few stitches are left to bring the Dragon to life
with the embroidery of the Dragon's eyes
Isn't it right? I embroidered for so many days
Lady's embroidery is so good
the best embroideress in the whole embroidery department
would not compare to Lady
And then there's Lady's thoughtfulness
Sleeping gown is closest to the body
If Emperor really wore this sleeping gown
he would definitely feel Lady's affection
Emperor, Empress Niang Niang has arrived
Courtier Concubine greets the Emperor
You've came, rise then
Thanks to the Emperor
The bill of Back Palace's spendings are paid for
Courtier Concubine especially brought it for the Emperor to see
How did Yi Kun Palace spend eight thousand this month?
that's more than triple the spending of Empress Palace
After one month would be the New Year
Hua Fei has always liked luxuries
so it's hard not to spend so much
Even in that case
you are the Empress, she's only a Fei
Her spendings
shouldn't exceed that of the Empress Palace
Hua Fei cares about the face and the appearance
most of her accessories are foiled with gold
and she ordered the Imperial Household Department clothing
to make a new batch of jewelry and clothing
add to the fact that Niang General came to Jing City this year
Hua Fei has to give something
so her spending was a little more
Women cares for their appearance to show status
so Hua Fei is taking care of the Nian Family's
and the Imperial Family's face
If it were for her own family
I wouldn't mind
From now on, report to me however much her palace spends
Yes
But these silver
are only for Yi Kun Palace's daily spendings
Courtier Concubine asked just in general
and Hua Fei's silver for awarding people exceeds this number
Niang Geng Yao must have given Hua Fei quite a lot also
A sheep's hair grows on a sheep (reap what is sown), let her
Courtier Concubine dares to ask
if these silver came from Nian Geng Yao's household
then did the Emperor award Nian Geng Yao that much?
If it wasn't from the Emperor
and Hua Fei spends so much in one month
where did these silver come from?
I roughly know so no need to say more
Yes
Emperor, Cui Yu Pavilion and Yan Xi Palace
each sent in one sleeping gown. Emperor please look it over
Cui Yu Pavilion and Yan Xi Palace really has interlocked hearts
how about Emperor just take a look?
Take it here
This golden dragon was embroidered so lively
just one look and you know it must be An Changzai's embroidery
In the back palace, there are none that can compare to her embroidery
it really is quite fine
Even though it's a sleeping gown
to be able to take care of minor details so carefully and thoughtfully
shows that An Changzai (changzai is second lowest of concubine titles) has Emperor in her heart
Chun Er is already an adult
and yet still plays with these scented powder
begging us to see them
How can I not show you guys?
Mo Mo always says I'm not white enough
and applies so much of these powder on me everyday
Now that I got good ones
I have to show to Jie Jie (older sister or an older female friend)
This is Jasmine powder from Yangzhou
said they grinded white jasmine flower and blended it in
this powder is smooth and scented, and whiter than snow
this scented powder really is high class
I have a box of sunflower powder
it's white, but not as scented as this powder
I originally thought that applying powder everyday was troublesome enough
but now I have to apply this thing everyday
and can't even miss a spot
Only by applying powder often can you keep your skin white, soft, and fine
it isn't just a day's work
you must apply every day, every night
to get a skin color as white as peeled boiled eggs
Come, I'll put it on for you. You'll guaranteed to be white and smell good!
the Emperor will like it so much!
I'm telling you guys
last night when I went to serve Emperor's sleep
I got curious
wondering if the Emperor's body was white or not
I really wanted to look
You guys have to know
before I always closed my eyes and didn't dare to look
This girl, always telling lies
Jie Jie, don't stop her
Let her say it, let her say it
She's not mature and you still let her
I looked and looked hard
and the Emperor just looked at me and said
"Why do you keep on staring at me today?"
is it because you liked the pattern of a golden dragon coming out of a cloud on my night gown?
If you like it
I'll tell people to cut it off and give it to you
And then?
And then the Emperor really did take it off
and put on a night gown with the pattern of two dragons fighting for a pearl
The Emperor told me
"Stop staring at me and sleep now"
And then the Emperor really did change his sleeping gown
Yeah, why would I lie to you about that?
The emperor also said
he really likes the material of the Two Dragon Fighting for Pearl
and that only like this would it be comfortable
So I asked
who gave you this nightgown?
The Emperor smiled and said
then go ask your Wan Jie Jie
So it was embroidered by Wan Jie Jie
Don't tell lies, who believed you?
I didn't lie to you
I asked the Emperor, did Wan Jie Jie make this?
Emperor (you) really seem to like it
The Emperor then said
"I know in my heart what kind of person makes what kind of clothes"
And then I laughed
I asked the Emperor
"Then was that Golden Dragon Coming Out of a Cloud
too modest so the Emperor didn't like it?"
"It must be made by Embroideresses from the Embroidery Department"
Don't say those things
Though the Emperor likes you,
you can't always be so blunt and careless when you talk
I only thought that
just one lonely dragon twined on a cloud
doesn't have much use
Why doesn't it get a friend?
Ok ok, don't talk about it anymore.
You don't even have limits and manners.
I told the kitchen to make plum flower cake
you go see if it's done yet
If it's ready, take it here for your An Jie Jie to try some
Ok sure!
Jin Xi, go with her
Let's go
The Imperial Doctor came here today
and said that my liver and intestines are not good so I should avoid pastries
It's almost time for me to take my medicine
so I'll leave now
alright, be careful on your way back
Lady what happened?
why did you start crying when you are fine?
Get out
Lady misses her family and can't suppress her sadness
Don't take it to the heart, go out and serve
Yes
Did Chun Er go back?
She took two bags of pastries with her
and looked very happy
Chun Er is innocent so she's always happy
Among Lady's sisters
Shen Daying (lowest of concubine rank) is kind and easygoing
Lady Chun is innocent
Lady An is thoughtful in everything
It's because she is so thoughtful and sensitive
that sometimes
I don't dare to say some things in front of her
Like today, Chun Er was carelessly speaking
I fear that Lin Rong will worry more now
Among these ladies
only Chun Changzai is the least crafty and has a pure heart
It's because she's so innocent that makes me worry
Sometimes she offends others and doesn't even know
Then Lady will just have to care for Lady Chun more
and help her at times
This He Tian jade pin
has a durable fine quality and is a rare find
Later go to Yan Xi Palace and give it to Lin Rong
But
Servant remembered that this jade pin
was personally given to the Lady by the Emperor
Just to comfort An Changzai
Lady really put in a lot of efforts
There are few sincere sisters in the Palace
I can't let her be sad
Then servant will take care
to deliver this jade pin to An Changzai
Lady's heart will surely be understood by An Changzai
Then, servant will go now
Go then
Fortunes to Lady
Aunty, why did you come here now?
Lady Wan got a new pair of jade pins
since among the sisters of the palace
she is best friends with Lady
she especially ordered me to deliver this to Lady
Thanks to my sister
Whenever she gets good stuff she always thinks of me
Our Lady said
back in the Jin Household, whenever there are some pretty accessories
it's always two people taking turns wearing it
Now in the palace, we should all the more share our fortunes
Bao Juan, help keep it safe for me
Yes
I am so happy right now
Please give my thanks to Jie Jie
Oh and, today I heard Jie Jie cough once
Please when you return,
boil a pack of sugar loquat leaf
Thanks Lady for caring
Servant shall do it accordingly
Servant has another word of advice to give to to Lady
Chun Changzai is young and innocent
If she said anything inappropriate
please tolerate her, Lady An
Of course, we are all sisters
what is there to not tolerate?
Besides, Chun Er's personality
it's not like I don't know it
Lady's tolerance really is Chun Changzai's fortune
Then, servant shall leave now
Please wait
Bao Juan, go send out Aunty
Yes
Please leave carefully
Ju Qing?
What are you doing standing here in such a cold day?
Jin Xi aunty
You've been wronged?
Lady came back crying
I just asked her what's wrong
and Lady broke stuff and ran me out
I've never seen Lady been so angry before
Which master doesn't take their temper out on their servant?
Lady Lin Rong is already one of the good-tempered ones
Don't cry anymore
If your face gets frostbites, it won't be pretty anymore
This jade becomes warm when you touch it - it's definitely rare
But now that Lady you have it, aren't you happy?
If I give it to you, would you be happy?
Of course servant would be happy
Yeah
when others give to you, you are of course happy
But I'm equal to her
we're both concubines of the Emperor
this kind of fine stuff I've never even seen before
but she has everything
when she knows that I'm not happy
she would give me this, give me that
Lady don't think so much
I don't want to think so much either
She has good material
when she's happy she would give me two yards
The sleeping gown she made for the emperor
was praised by the Emperor for its comfort
But mine can be cut and given to others
Nowadays, even Chun Changzai dares to be in my face
and laughs at how cheap my embroidery is
making me lose all my face
and even cursing to me forever alone
Chun Changzai only gains favor because of her youth
so it's hard not to be prideful
Lady don't mind her
at least Lady Wan cares for you
or else why would she give you this jade pin?
How is this for me?
She's only worried that I would be angry at Chun Changzai
so she gave me this jade pin
Chun Changzai said
their families are around the same status,
so they're closer
What am I?
Lady Wan is only protecting Chun Changzai
so she gave me this
otherwise
when did she,
under normal circumstances, gave me such expensive stuff?
According to you, then,
Lady Wan only cares about Chun Changzai?
but of course
when Shen Daying was favored
Lady Wan didn't care about us either
I finally understand
If Shen Daying didn't lose power
why would she have helped me?
Now that she has Chun Changzai
she doesn't need me anymore
If Lady is angry
I'll put this jade pin away
to spare Lady the anguish
since she's given me such good stuff
I'll wear it
Or else,
it really would be a waste
Oh right, you saw Jin Xi and Ju Qing talk
They were very close to each other
Now I know
If it wasn't for her (Ju Qing) secret messages
how could Lady Wan have so coincidentally,
like me,
made a night gown and given it to the emperor, trying to fight with me for favor?
from now on, Lady will have to more cautious around Ju Qing
Why is Emperor wearing this old sleeping gown today?
Didn't Lady Wan and An Changzai a few days before
made new sleeping gowns for Emperor?
Undergarments that are worn longer are still the best
Comfortable, durable
This nightgown was made by Empress Chun Yuan when she was still here
At that time, she made many clothes for me
There are only two garments left
Jie Jie's sewing skills are among the best
It's late now, let's sleep
Alright
Tomorrow Hua Fei has a date with the Six Palaces to watch an opera at the Qing Yin Pavilion
Empress Niang Niang arrives
Hua Fei Niang Niang arrives
To Empress Niang Niang be ten thousand fortunes and golden peace
To Hua Fei Niang Niang be ten thousand peace
All rise
Thanks be to Empress Niang Niang
What kind fo operas are prepared today?
Reply to Empress Niang Niang's words:
It's Nanfu Opera's Liu Jinding to the Rescue
The rest are what each Lady has selected
Let them start then
I and the Empress shall select first
Yes
Niang Niang please select first
I remember there was a well-performed version of Ding Zhi Chun Qiu
which talked about the Three Kingdoms
What does Empress think of it?
Since you want to watch it, then select first
Jie Jie
Hua Fei Niang Niang is ahead of Empress Niang Niang?
This opera is fun, you will like it
Then Courtier Concubine will also select Xue Dingshan Conquer the West
Hua Fei Niang Niang's older brother has made quite a few accomplishments in war
just like the General Xue Dingshan of the Tang Dynasty
who succeeded in conquering the west and left his name in history
Lady Cao really knows how to talk
Niang Niang select now
I only like Advising Jin Ke
just select another Yao Tai would be fine
Niang Niang has a good heart and does good deeds
just like the kind mother Yao Tai, who brought fortune to the world
Advising Jin Ke talks about Mu Lian saving mother
just like how Third Ah-ge (Emperor's son) has a filial heart towards you
I remember that the golden hand-warmer in Qi Fei's hand
was given by Third Ah-ge
Hua Fei has a good memory
Third Ah-ge has too much of a filial heart
if he spent more time on reading and studying
Emperor would not lose his temper as much
Mei Mei (younger sister)'s clothing today is really pretty
Gold and ruby jewelries
make you look luxurious and generous
it catces one's eyes
I fear that since Jiang Zhongmin hasn't managed Imperial Household Dept. for a long time, he won't make good stuff
so I especially asked Gege
to get me jewelry from outside the Palace
Few days ago I looked it over
The golden threads are still not bound together tightly enough
said it was ten and something masters that made it
but it was only a bit better than Imperial Household Dept.'s
so I decided to just wear it
Such luxuries must have cost much
In reality, if the stuff is good
what does silver or money matter?
Empress Niang Niang is way too calculating
Since the family and business is big, I can't but not ask
In reality, if it can show Mei Mei's beauty and air
Silver and money really doesn't matter
Courtier Concubine is very glad to hear
such words from the Empress
I heard that a few days ago Empress tattled on me
for my large spendings
Actually even if my spendings are big,
Empress Niang Niang doesn't need to feel such pain
It's Courtier Concubine's own business
it doesn't matter how much I exceed the monthly limit
I'll tell my family to make up for it exactly
I'm also very glad that
Mei Mei has the heart to care for me
I hope that with Hua Fei as an example
all the sisters can understand that every stitch every thread doesn't come easily
if you can't make it open source, then at least be conservative about it
Thanks Empress Niang Niang for her instructions, Courtier Niang Niang accepts them
Alright, get up now
Thanks Empress Niang Niang
Talking about Xue Dingshan Conquering the West,
you cannot but also mention Fan Lihua
Look at this Fan Lihua
always finding ways to make her husband like her
but her husband only likes other people
and divorced Fan Lihua three times
If I were Fan Lihua
I would rather go down from my position and leave
than see my husband with his body here and his heart somewhere else
If you are the wife, you must have tolerance
Doesn't matter how much the husband loves the concubines
The wife is the wife
Even if Xue Dingshan divorced Fan Lihua three times
didn't he also have to beg Fan Lihua three times to return to him?
At least that Fan Lihua came from a good family
she is the daughter of the wife of a Xiliang General
If it were the daughter of a concubine,
she wouldn't have this kind of ability
and death would be her only path
Don't you think it's right, Niang Niang?
Empress Niang Niang
Can we select a Nan Ke Opera?
Jie Jie
your opera in the end turned out to be just a dream
that's no fun
Watching operas are not for fun, but for warning people
You see Nanke's rise and you also see his fall
the higher you climb, the harder you'll fall
in the end his riches are gone, who would still care about wife vs concubine and high-class vs low-class?
and money and power?
it was just Nanke's Dream
Though we all watch the same opera, Lady Wan gets more out of it
no wonder the emperor likes to talk to you so much
Courtier Concubine only discusses the matter as it is
Courtier Concubine also thinks that waiting for the clouds to part to see the moon
the most important part is both hearts are willing
An Changzai is also a royal concubine
how can you say words like "two willing hearts" in the public
without shame and embarrasment?
Having a thick face
is a rare ability
In the opera script for Peony Pavilion
Feelings, don't know from where do they arise, that they become such devoted feelings.
The live one can die, the dead one can live
An Mei Mei was only discussing the opera as it was
Lady Wan is very educated in literary works
Even opera script she can recite from nowhere
If she was only discussing opera, then let's just watch the opera
Today is the eighth day of the twelveth lunar month
the Back Palace all has to go greet the Empress Dowager
Lady should also prepare something
The fur on this garment is very fine
shiny as oil, smooth as water
people in the Imperial Household Dept. is careful in their work
they know that Lady is scared of the cold
so they picked high quality fur
to help Lady guard against the cold
See, these few days the snow has stopped
those were the coldest days
Lady, this fur coat has a bright color
it's pretty and warm
the Imperial Household Dept. especially gifted it to honor Lady
Do you think it's fitting?
When meeting the Empress Dowager
there's no need to wear clothes that especially stand out
gentle and modest like this is most appropriate
Empress Dowager gives order to meet royal concubines of the Back Palace
Lady Wan
Lady Fucha
Lady Cao
give greetings to the Empress Dowager
We wish the Empress Dowager's phoenix body to be healthy and have fortunes for ten thousand years
I haven't seen Lady Wan for a while
Raise your head and let me see your face
Thank you for watching this episodes with us!
Subtitles brought to you by The Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki