Episode 35
Both of you, please have a seat.
The birds disappear in the winter.
Although it's not as lively as spring,
winter has its own atmosphere.
Indeed.
What's your opinion, Sister?
Consort Wan invited me to appreciate the beauty of the snow.
I only know how to watch the snow.
Are you saying that I'm forcing you?
Actually, it's good for us to meet regularly, and talk.
So we'll become closer, and avoid any misunderstandings.
We're both Imperial concubines of the Emperor.
We shouldn't have any misunderstandings or rifts.
I remember a story that happened during wintertime.
Imperial Consort Wan is learned and educated. I'm glad if you can share it with me.
It's the story of homunculus.
I'm neither learned nor educated,
as I cannot remember the story well.
It happened during the reign of Emperor Han.
Madam Qi offended Empress Lu as she was pampered by the Emperor.
After Empress Lu became Empress Dowager,
she cut off Madam Qi's hands and legs,
gouged her eyes, cut her ears, and gave her drugs to keep her mute.
Then she was locked in the toilet. This is called "Homunculus".
Madam Qi was a beautiful lady.
Unfortunately she ended up that way.
Even though Empress Lu was very cruel,
Madam Qi insulted the Empress because she was pampered.
She could only blame herself.
As a Lady, Empress Lu tended to hold deep grudges.
Sister Fuca, am I right?
- Jin-Xi.- Young Master.
- Quick, help Lady Fuca to her chair.- Yes.
That is an interesting story.
What happened to you, Sister?
Perhaps Lady Fuca didn't think I told the story very well.
I was telling the story indiscriminately. Perhaps that made you more confused.
What is the purpose of you telling me this story of homunculus?
Although Consort Nian is arbitrary and despotic, there is one thing that impresses me about her.
She is very decisive and shows no mercy.
Someone who insulted Consort Nian was transferred to another palace.
I'm wondering what she will do if she is bullied at Long Street.
If what you say is true, given Consort Nian's temperament,
she would administer the homunculus punishment,
or some other agonizing punishment.
Yes, if I were as cruel as Consort Nian,
I wouldn't allow myself to be bullied after I become the Imperial Consort.
Sister, you are pampered by the Emperor.
You can do anything you like.
Consort Wan, I was wrong. Please forgive me. I promise never to do that again.
Sister, you used to have great confidence in yourself. What is your mistake?
I was just telling you a story.
- I was instructed by Consort Qi. Please forgive me.- Really?
Whatever it is, let's talk about it later.
I'm curious. Although Sima Qian is good in writing,
he doesn't know what homunculus looks like.
As far as I know, homunculus is not the worst way.
During the Tang Dynasty, concubines were made into homunculus.
Then they were soaked in the wine jar.
This is called Bone in Wine.
Even though it was cruel,
everything happened for a reason. They should have expected it.
Young Master. What has happened to you? Young Master, please wake up.
I thought she was brave,
but all along, she was a coward, pretending to be brave.
Jin-Xi, Lady Fuca is not feeling well. Carry her home.
- Young Master.- Someone, please?
Come here, over here.
- Carry her home.- Yes.
Aunt, do we need to ask for the Imperial doctor to come?
Ask the Imperial doctor to come, but no need to pay too much attention.
Yes.
Kill the chicken to warn the monkey.
The chicken is dead now. What do you want to tell us?
It's good to talk with a smart person like yourself, Sister Cao. I don't need to waste my time.
You are not a cruel, tricky person.
If Lady Fuca really offended you, you could have sent her to the Ministry of Justice.
You don't need to trouble yourself.
The purpose of the things you did, was it to scare me?
Therefore, please be straight-forward.
Sister Cao thinks too much, and likes to speak in a roundabout way.
I feel uneasy for myself,
to be straight-forward with you.
You've had a cold for the past few days.
I made a suggestion to the Emperor to visit you. How are you feeling now?
I appreciate what you did.
But when the Emperor is with me, his heart is with you.
He looked restless.
Sister Cai is a smart person. You don't need to care about that.
The relationship will improve if you meet each other on a regular basis.
As long as the Emperor visits you,
he will come to like you more, due to your intelligence.
Consort Nian fell from grace, and got you into trouble.
The Emperor hasn't visited you for half a year. Am I right?
I don't have good fortune. It makes sense that the Emperor isn't concerned about me.
Actually, it's not a big deal for me to be treated wrongly.
The important thing is the Princess.
If she isn't cherished by her father from a young age,
what's going to happen to her in the future?
I've been so short-sighted.
I didn't make the right choice,
and that has caused this current situation.
I don't blame anyone for that.
You shouldn't repent or redress your errors.
You need to fight for the Princess' future.
As for what happened in the past,
you shouldn't consider yourself short-sighted for choosing to follow Consort Nian.
It's not easy to follow her.
But people think you still follow Consort Nian.
What should we do?
I also worry about what's going to happen in the future.
I hope that Consort Nian doesn't involve me.
Consort Nian is impatient and cruel.
You're not happy with her, right?
Regarding the cassava flour matter the other day,
you knew that I was innocent.
You should know who took advantage of the Princess to create trouble.
Princess Wen-Yi is to be pitied, suffering at such a young age.
I feel sorry for her.
As a mother, you are forced to watch the sufferings of your own child.
I believe you are more miserable.
Without Consort Nian's help,
I wouldn't have been able to deliver a princess.
You showed your gratitude towards her.
But what happened next? She took advantage of your daughter
to attract the Emperor's attention.
Actually, you are just as smart as Consort Nian.
You chose to follow her in order to protect yourself.
I knew Consort Nian was despotic, but there wasn't anything I could do about it.
I wanted to tell you that day,
so you would rescue Lady Chun, when she fell into the pool,
but it was too late.
You are very intelligent and understanding.
You knew that Consort Nian is not reliable.
So you were willing to secretly help me.
I appreciate what you did.
I was just following orders.
Even with all my efforts, I can't fight against Consort Nian.
Unfortunately, I still couldn't save Lady Chun.
I want to ask you a question.
How did Lady Chun slip and fall down that day?
If you in
Consort Nian was jealous of Lady Chun being pampered.
Also, Lady Chun was very close to you.
Consort Nian wanted to cut your wings.
She is so impatient.
She wasn't afraid the Emperor would investigate?
Consort Nian is arrogant.
It's not a big deal for her to kill a concubine.
She was able kill her without a trace.
That day, Lady Chun went to pick up a kite,
and accidentally discovered the relationship between Consort Nian and General Nian's subordinate.
That's why Consort Nian killed her.
It is acceptable if Consort Nian wants to meet with General Nian's subordinate.
She didn't need to meet him in secret.
Consort Nian has always been lavish.
So she has a difficult time when she is short of money.
When she needs money, she will write down the name of the officer who bribes
and ask someone to pass it to General Nian secretly.
The reason Zhao Zhi-Yuan is re-established in an important position is because he bribed Consort Nian.
She dares to collude with Nian Gengyao?
And influence Imperial's personnel decisions?
Yes, Nian Gengyao's subordinates are colluding with each other and formed a gang.
You used to be against because you had no other choice.
I understand that.
You're contributed a lot as you delivered and raised the Princess.
Unfortunately, you have stayed with Consort Nian for many years,
but still are not as important as Consort Li,
who doesn't have any children at all.
The status of the mother is going to influence the future of her children.
You may not know, but the Emperor told me something about Princess Zhao Gui yesterday.
She was married to Dzungaria for about two weeks,
when Inge Khan died suddenly.
Her husband died? That means she's coming back soon, right?
She'll be lucky if she's allowed to come back.
She might have to follow the traditional customs of Dzungaria, and marry the new leader,
who is the new khan, who has ascended the throne.
That can't be.
A woman's duty is to carry on the ancestral line.
Even if Princess does not want to, she must follow the customs.
She can be downgraded from Empress to Concubine.
I'm willing to do anything for you,
provided that you protect me and my daughter.
I would really appreciate your help.
I have admired you for a long time.
Finally, we're able to know each other better today.
Of course I'm willing to protect you.
If you feel cold, lie on the bed and rest.
I will make you a hot-water bottle for warmth.
Bao-Juan, do you think that everyone is laughing at me now?
Young Master, don't think about it too much.
Previously, I was so impressive.
Many people were jealous of me.
Now Consort Wan has won the favor secretly.
She doesn't treat as well as she did before.
Everyone must be laughing at me now.
The Emperor visits Consort Wan more often these last few days.
But I believe he hasn't forgotten about you.
Really? The Emperor always I'm good at singing.
But ever since Consort Wan, he has forgotten everything.
My nose, my ears.
My hands and legs disappeared.
Sister Fuca, what happened to you?
I don't want to be Homunculus. (Homunculus?) I don't want to be Homunculus.
Who wants you to be Homunculus?
She wants me to be Homunculus.
- No.- Help me.
- No, no one will make you into Homunculus.- I don't want to be Homunculus.
That will never happen.
Come here. What happened to Master Fuca?
Nothing special. A few days ago, she met Consort Wan and Lady Cao. She fainted there.
She became like this after she woke up.
Consort Wan? She became like this because of Consort Wan?
That's not possible. Lady Cao was there too.
She didn't have any fear of her.
I don't want to be Homunculus. I don't want to be Homunculus.
I don't want to be Homunculus.
Young Master, Lady Fuca is insane.
I heard that after Lady Fuca left us,
she became insane, and talked incoherently.
She stayed in bed and refused to go out.
- Does the Emperor know about this?- Yes.
The palace is in confusion because of Lady Fuca.
The Emperor has instructed that she needs to stay in the palace, and is not allowed to go out.
An Imperial doctor is attending to her.
I thought she was brave.
But she's become like this because of a few words?
She did something wrong, and became insane by her own fault.
Since the Emperor wants to treat her, just let it be.
Just let it be.
- Go knock on the door.- Yes.
Young Master, Consort Qi is here. She wants to meet with you.
It's strange. Consort Qi isn't very close with us. Why would she come here?
I don't have time to meet with her. Go tell her that.
She won't be involved in what happened to Lady Fuca.
Regarding the bamboo matter, I won't blame her.
Ask her to behave herself.
Yes.
The way you're dealing with problems,
seems different from before.
Before, I was too kind.
Always being generous.
That makes them dare to bully me
when I'm having a difficult time.
Now that Lady Fuca has become insane,
this can be a warning to them,
that they can't bully me.
But you still forgave Consort Qi.
She is as cruel as she is loving towards her son.
Lady Fuca has become insane.
I shouldn't force her anymore.
I just need to give her a warning.
Everyone says that Consort Nian is aggressive and ruthless.
People are afraid of her iron fist.
Those characteristics are effective when dealing with
people with certain agendas.
That's why Consort Nian has been pampered all these years. It is not without its reasons.
I should learn something from this method used by Consort Nian.
Before I was always bullied by others.
It's time for that to change.
These lucky bags made by Sister are small.
Grab them on New Year's eve.
If you can catch many of them by one hand,
you will have good luck in the New Year.
I don't know anything about that.
Are you praising my lucky bags, or teasing me about my big hands?
I'm just praising you. You think too much.
I don't want to praise you anymore.
Consort, there is your yarn.
Aunt Jin-Xi.
Prince Dun beat Zhang-Lin.
What?
What are you talking about?
Something has happened.
What happened?
Prince Dun came back to the capital three days ago.
He was late for the morning assembly, and arrived at the hall in a military uniform.
The morning hall is not a battlefield.
Also, he came back without a victory.
But arriving late and wearing a military uniform,
wasn't it to swagger around?
Before His Majesty could say anything,
Zhang Lin, the censor, reprimanded him, and rebuked him for his impoliteness.
Prince Dun is always reckless.
He has always despised the civil officers and scholars.
A censor always gives advice to the Emperor,
and points out the wrong-doings of officers.
Only they would dare to accuse Prince Dun without mercy.
Yes, you're right. Prince Dun didn't do anything then.
But on the way back,
he stopped Zhang-Lin, and punched and knocked him out.
What?
Yes, the ancient laws say no one can beat up a censor.
Moreover, it was his fault from the beginning.
This time Prince Dun has made everyone angry.
All the censors are calling for him to be punished severely,
per the laws of the Imperial Court.
But Prince Dun does not admit any fault.
He hasn't been to assembly for two days, saying he is sick.
This is ridiculous.
When His Majesty ascended the throne,
everyone knows how he dealt with 8th Prince and 7th Prince.
Prince Dun is being disrespectful.
I don't this this will be hard for His Majesty to settle.
If His Majesty is truly angry,
this is going to become complicated.
Prince Dun just made a contribution in the battlefield.
If His Majesty punishes him,
I'm afraid it will affect His Majesty's reputation.
If this doesn't settle out well,
it will harm the Imperial Court.
You're right.
Because of this,
His Majesty is at the Hall of Mental Cultivation, and hasn't come out all day.
It's getting late. You should go check.
Let me think first.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Wishes for Your Majesty's health and peace.
Stand.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
You already heard
about what has happened in the palace these last few days?
Yes, this news has spread everywhere.
Even as a concubine, I have heard something of it.
Even though there are many matters of state,
Your Majesty, you must take care your health.
I stewed this donkey-hide gelatin with codonopsis.
It's good for Your Majesty, to regulate and reinforce qi.
You already know the details
regarding Prince Dun beating up the censor.
What do you think I should do?
Do I need to follow the laws and punish Prince Dun?
Your Majesty is the Emperor.
Of course, Your Majesty needs to follow the laws.
But Your Majesty doesn't need to punish him.
I thought you would suggest punishing him.
Tell me what you think.
Your Majesty won't blame me, if I comment on matters of the state?
It's fine. This is just a normal conversation.
I won't blame you.
I think
the most important thing right now is to appease the people.
And solve the conflict between Prince Dun and the officers.
If there's a fight, one side will surely be harmed.
But both sides are important assets of the Qing Dynasty.
Prince Dun just made a contribution in the battlefield.
If Your Majesty punishes him at this time,
I'm afraid the other generals will become disgruntled.
Actually Your Majesty doesn't need to punish Prince Dun to settle this issue.
The officers are angry because
they want a settlement.
Your Majesty just needs to give them a statement.
The best way is ask Prince Dun to pay a visit and apologize.
Ask him to apologize?
He is so arrogant,
it'd be easier just to kill him.
Not really.
He fought for this country in wars.
He's a hero.
What is the most difficult obstacle for a hero?
It is a beauty.
You clever girl.
Only you can think of a trick like this.
Your Majesty also knows that a beauty is the most difficult obstacle for a hero.
I don't know anything about big matters.
I only know this little trick.
Prince is most afraid of Princess.
If Princess helps with this, everything can be settled.
I've met the Princess several times.
She is not someone without understanding.
Who do you think should go, and ask for help from the Princess?
If Your Majesty doesn't mind,
I'd like to take care of this.
Among the concubines, you're the one who can help me solve problems.
All those officers who take a salary,
just make noise all day,
but can't decide whether to punish him or not.
They are all useless.
I am just one of your concubines.
This is not my idea.
It is from Your Majesty.
I just guessed correctly, with some luck.
The officers understand books and theories.
But I understand Your Majesty.
His Majesty's thoughts,
I think I can guess at some of them.
Huan Huan, only you know what I'm thinking.
But look at the behavior of Prince Dun.
I can't let him keep doing this.
If Prince Dun continues to be domineering,
Your Majesty will have this for later.
It is really good news for our people.
But now is not the time to eliminate Prince Dun.
That's right.
After all these things are settled,
I'm going to let your father take charge of the Censorate.
He can help me impeach all the officers.
But your father alone will not be enough.
The talented officers, not associated with Prince Dun and Nian Gengyao,
I want to promote them all.
I don't want to act rashly, which will only alert the enemy,
so I'm hesitating.
To appease them...
Prince Dun and his princess already have a lot of wealth.
They are parents now.
It seems
we need to do something for their children.
They have a son and a daughter.
Their daughter is Princess of Qingcheng.
I plan to promote her as He Shuo Princess.
Her position is equal to the the daughter of a concubine.
Then I'll promote his son to Bei Zi, to follow in the footsteps of his father.
Your Majesty is considering everything.
But I think Your Majesty must do more than just promote Princess.
Her name must be changed as well.
The name should be Gong Ding.
This will remind her father to be respectful and peaceful.
To be sure,
Your Majesty wouldn't want to start a fight to solve a conflict between brothers.
It depends on Prince Dun,
whether he understands the effort of Your Majesty or not.
Moreover, Princess should stay in the palace,
and be cared for by the Empress.
Then if something were to happen in the future,
we could use the Princess to threaten Prince Dun.
That's right. Do it as you've said.
I will issue an Imperial edict later.
About what you just said.
A beauty is the most difficult obstacle for a hero?
Your Majesty likes to tease me.
I am not a beauty.
- Your Majesty.- Yes.
Your Majesty asked Lady An to sleep with you tonight.
Lady An sent people here to ask about it.
Tell her she doesn't need to come.
Take a rest.
Sister An felt patronized by Your Majesty recently.
Now would be the best time to pamper her.
Don't keep her waiting.
I will go now.
Don't go.
I think Sister An
is still waiting for Your Majesty.
Your Majesty must keep your promise,
and not break it for a girl.
But I want you to be by my side.
I just want Your Majesty to keep me in your heart.
I won't steal you away from Sister An.
Take care on your way back.
I will go.
Young Master, Master An is going that way.
Whoever she is,
the only thing that matters is whether I can catch the heart of His Majesty.
Jin-Xi.
You, Liu-Zhu and Huan-Bi.
Go make preparations for Prince Dun and Princess' arrival to the palace day after tomorrow.
Alright.
Greetings, Empress.
Stand.
Thank you, Empress.
Greetings, Consort Wan.
Give the seat, and serve the tea.
Yes.
Hui-Chun, serve the tea.
Consort Wan is recovered now.
I'm glad to see that.
A few months ago Princess came to the palace.
I wanted to talk with the Princess,
but unfortunately, I was busy at the time.
I regretted that.
Consort is precious. How dare I come and disturb Consort?
According to virtue, yes.
But from a family perspective, I should call Princess, Tenth Sister.
We're all family. We should be close to each other.
It is my pleasure to hear that from Consort.
Empress looks healthy recently.
Princess really has a way with words.
Princess looks better since giving birth to Xuan Hong Bei-Zi.
Bei-Zi? Empress must be joking.
Xuan Hong is only six years old. How can be become Bei-Zi?
That's the good will of His Majesty.
His Majesty likes Xuan Hong the most of all his nephews.
Although Xuan Hong is small, he is smart and cute.
So His Majesty wants to promote him as Bei-Zi, earlier than usual.
To educate him properly, so in the future, he can become like his father.
And pacify the nations, and contribute to our country.
On behalf of Xuan Hong, I thank His Majesty first.
That's not all.
His Majesty wants to add to the good news.
His Majesty wants to promote Princess of Qingcheng
as He Shuo Gong Ding Princess.
And after this, be taken care of by the Empress.
Thank you for His Majesty's kind intention.
But she is only twelve years old, and still innocent.
I'm afraid if Empress takes care of her,
there will be no peace for the Empress.
Would the Empress ask His Majesty to take back his will?
His Majesty doesn't have many children.
It's good news that His Majesty wants Princess to come to the palace.
Since the Dynasty was established,
although there was a daughter of a Prince promoted as He Shuo Princess,
it was because of a marriage situation that the Princess was promoted.
This promotion will be the first of its kind in history?
Alright. I'm a bit tired.
I'll be leaving first.
The Imperial edict will be sent to your house tonight.
Let me send Empress.
It's late. I'll go back first.
Consort Wan.
It's still early.
I would like to visit Consort's palace.
Would I be disturbing Consort?
Of course not.
I prefer you come without an invitation.
Otherwise, it would be as if we're strangers.
Please.
This tea is called Xue Ding Han Cui.
It was sent here from 500 miles away.
Give it a try. Do you like it?
Recently, Consort is the one who takes care of His Majesty the most.
Of course, Consort acquires the best of everything.
I was neglected when I had my miscarriage.
Only you came to visit me.
I have long kept this in my heart.
And I hope there is a day, when I can repay that kindness.
Would Consort be willing to help me convince His Majesty?
If I think of it from your perspective,
I think it better for you to obey the Imperial edict.
To let the Empress take care of your daughter.
Why do you say so?
As a wife and mother,
you need to plan for your husband and children,
and put them first. Don't you agree?
A few days ago, the Prince beat the censor and made everyone angry.
We wish the Prince would pay a visit to Zhang Lin and apologize.
The Prince is a bad tempered person. Only others go to ask for his favour.
If you care about the Prince, you should give him your advice on this case.
Although his Majesty wants to protect the Prince,
it is he who beat others first.
And Zhang Lin is still lying in bed and still wont wake up.
His Majesty is upset also.
And the Prince is very straight-forward, so it's easy for him to make enemies.
If your daughter is there, she can always give some advice to His Majesty.
Isn't it better?
I will tell His Majesty that so you can always go into the palace to visit your daughter.
This is good.
Since His Majesty puts in a lot of effort, the Prince adn I should take this without any choice.
Thank you Consort.
Have a drink.
I finally now what wistfully is called.
Don't say that..
I don't know,,,, if I look like this
...will His Majesty come?
Don't worry.
General Nian already sent someone to come pass a message that they know Consort is being neglected.
He will cooperate with Prince Dun to probe the intentions of His Majesty.
I told you don't tell my brother about the things between His Majesty and I.
Don't tell brother about the things between His majesty and I
Neither of us mention it, because everyone already knows.
His Majesty neglects you, Consort.
We can't hide it from General Nian
We cant hide it from General Nian.
Anyway. why bother dealing with Prince Dun again.
Even if Prince Dun helped him before..
It's not good for him to be close to Prince Dun.
Now the daugther of Prince Dun became He Shou Princess and his son becomes Bei Zi too
He is very Happy
It's normal for General
to hang out with Prince Dun
Prince Dun is reckless
And too rebellious
tell Consort not to worry
When he gets one thing from Prince Dun
Then the Prince will help.
Consort to get the heart and mind from His majesty again
Really?
General and prince Dun are always there
Nothing to be afraid of
I wish so
Song Zhi
Hurry
and light up the Huan Yi perfume.
It will make me feel better.
Yes His majesty has arrived.
Greetings.  At ease.
Prince Dun personally visited Zhang Lin to apologize yesterday.
Although he was not sincere,
at least it has been settled. Huan-Huan,
you really helped me alot  Its my duty
to help his majesty share his burdens.
There's nothing much that I can help in terms of state matters.
Xuan Ding Han Cui is needed good tea.
I know you like it, so I sent you the best. Do you like it?
Of course I do. Before this, I made this tea for Prince Dun.
I made it for Princess too.
But Princess seems to have gotten used to drinking this kind of tea.
I thought
the tea was not familar to her.
Luckily, she didn't mind.
For the tributes,
if the palace has it, General Nian
would have it too, or even a better one.
Even Prince Dun has it now.
I never did give it to him
Where did he get it from?
Don't be angry.
The incident of Prince Dun's violence
was a great disturbance. If any rumors surface
after it has settled, then his contributions will be eliminated.
Don't you think so?
Have some water, your majesty.
Your majesty,
I've just sewed a new sachet and would like to give
it to you. Would you like to take a look
and see if you like it?
Huan-Huan just gave me a sachet a few days ago.
I already have it with me.
Adding another one would be a burden.
My sewing skills are no better than sister's.
No
Sister's sewing skills far surpasses mine.
Look at those
sachets and other things. It shows how great sister's skills are.
Its because his majesty doesn't mind.
This is good too. I like it too.
Give it to Fang-nuo and put in my bed room.
I am satisfied.
The sachet made by sister,
mine is not as good.
Please
forgive me , your majesty.
No its not.
I understand your sincerity.
There is nothing to blame you for.
Sister's sewing skills
are improving.
It would be great to sew a pair of mandarin ducks on a sachet to express her love for his majesty.
Maybe his majesty will like it.  Mandarin ducks are nice too. But its not good if his majesty wears it
around everywhere. Its better to sew a dragon.
About the mandarin ducks, if your majesty likes it,
I can make another one
and put it under the pillow, ok?
What are you writing?
It sounds good, but sad.
Holding onto each other hands with teary eyes,
yet no words could express their feelings. Its not appropriate for the current situation.
Flower blooms and the moon shines brightly in the night sky, may couples stay in love forever.
Take it and hang it in front of your bed.
Thank you, your majesty.
Your majesty and sister are so loving. What a great sight to see.
Sister is blessed,,
no one else could have asked for more.  Your majesty, you better console Sister An.
She's feeling jealous. You're teasing me again, sister.
How can I be jealous of sister and your majesty?Rong-er has a modest nature,
even if she's jealous, it will only be for a month.