Episode 37
How does it smell?
Sister Cao.
Greetings, Lady Wan.
Sister, please, stand.
Sister is in a really good mood.
Wen-Yi wants to go out and play everyday.
This little child is giving me such a headache.
Not everyone can be as happy as you.
Let me hold her for a while.
My goodness, Princess Wen-Yi.
Stop it, Wen-Yi. Greet Consort Wan.
- Consort.- It's okay. She is so adorable.
Give Consort Wan a kiss.
Here.
Good. Careful of your clothes.
Consort Bin has something to say to you.
The sunshine is very good today.
I think I'll take a walk in the spring garden.
I'll leave first.
Farewell, Consort Wan.
Sister Cao.
Do you have something to tell me?
Consort Hua's position has been restored.
Yesterday, Consort Hua invited me to the Palace of Supporting Earth.
That's good.
Sister Cao has had a constant relationship with Consort Hua all this time.
Now that she has been restored, you should go and congratulate her.
Yes, I have already sent presents.
It's just that, Consort Hua has asked some questions
about your actions during her captivity.
You are a smart person.
You will be able to handle it well.
No matter what,
it's still in your control.
Nothing is in my control.
It all depends on you.
No matter what, Consort Hua is still your previous master.
Although she has mistreated you and the Princess,
she has also helped you.
Her family status is far above my own.
It's natural you would want to maintain
your close relationship with Consort Hua.
There is no need for you to deny me.
Although I am not that smart, I know that the restoration of Consort Hua is just temporary.
No matter what, her end will come soon.
I will not take that risk, for the sake of the Princess and myself.
Your observation skill is better than anybody else.
Actually, I wish for you and Consort Hua to maintain a close relationship.
Princess and I have surrendered ourselves to you.
We only listen to your orders.
How can I serve her as well?
I understand your meaning.
I will not disappoint you.
You are very smart.
I won't have to worry.
Since Consort Hua wants to spy on my actions,
I will return it to her by her own means.
What does she think of her restoration?
Consort Hua is delighted with it.
But she is always in fear that she may be neglected again.
She is cautious of you
because she has been neglected before,
and she heard about the incident between Consort Qi and Lady Fuca.
She has treated me like an enemy for a long time.
Of course, the same goes for me.
You will have your own method of dealing with her.
I'm just providing some assistance to you.
There is one thing.
I have no direct, mutual relationship with you.
If we stand together, it's because of some certain mutual benefit.
We may even separate one day.
I know my own status.
I know I'm no match for you.
I only worry that I won't be of much help to you.
Good, Sister.
Then your problem will be my problem.
I don't have a child yet.
Princess Wen-Yi is very adorable.
I wish to keep her as my step-daughter after everything is finished.
Then, both of us can rely upon each other.
What do you think?
If that's the case, both of us will feel better.
You have a bright future.
Wen-Yi will be blessed to have such a person as her step-mother.
Sister, this looks familiar.
I think I've seen it before in His Majesty's chamber.
It is a gift from His Majesty?
Yes, it is just a small novelty.
Sister, you have a beautiful hand.
It's a pity you only used jasmine lacquer.
His Majesty will like it better,
if you put some interesting decoration on it.
Thank you for the advice.
Officer Wen is in a hurry today.
No time, even for tea.
There's no need to show me out.
Consort Wan's medicine is still cooking.
I'm worried the eunuchs will not properly tend to the medicine,
and miss the time when the medicine is most effective.
Consort Wan is ill?
No, it's just the special face power used by Consort Wan.
Those eunuchs are careless, so I have to supervise them.
It's just a small matter.
His Majesty now favors Consort Wan a lot.
Now that she has His Majesty's attention, she doesn't care about the special medicine.
Consort Wan has grown to be very important.
Everybody is moving to her side.
I think I should have to avoid her for a while.
Doctor Wen, I think you are rushing to help her as well.
Master, why would you say something like that?
My mood is not good, and I have offended you.
But I have to give you a piece of advice.
No one remembers those who rise in times of glory.
People remember those who help in times of need.
Sir, I trust you understand what I'm saying.
It's my responsibility to formulate new medicines.
Just as it is to serve you when you are ill.
I don't dislike helping during times of glory.
I sincerely hope that neither Consort Wan
nor you would need my help during a time of need.
I wish that Doctor Wen would treat
me and my sister equally.
Both you and your sister are people I tend to.
I have no other intentions.
Cai-Yue, show Doctor Wen to the door.
Yes.
Farewell, Doctor Wen.
Master.
Sister, why do you stand in front of the door?
You will catch a cold.
Sister, why are you here today?
Don't you need to accompany His Majesty in visiting Consort Hua?
Sister, don't be angry.
I've come here today,
to explain this matter to you.
I'm tired. I want to take a nap.
I'll be going to the Empress' palace later. Please return.
I know you are angry.
But please, listen to me for a moment.
Do you not care about our past relationship?
Come in.
Why is nobody here?
Where are the servants? Why is there no one here to serve you?
The palace officials are distributing summer clothes today.
I told them to get it from the Imperial Household.
It's different from your court.
where everybody wants to go.
Eunuch Lee from the Imperial Household,
will personally send the summer uniform to your servants.
I know.
You don't care about being neglected by His Majesty.
Sister only cares about
the restoration of Consort Hua.
Fine, let me ask you then.
Are you the one who suggested to restore Consort Hua to His Majesty?
Yes.
But Sister, I was forced to do it.
Who would be willing to help the person who killed her own son?
Please Sister, think of it from my point of view.
Why would I do that,
if I wasn't forced to?
My sufferings were no less than yours.
Then why did you do it?
Sister, think about it. It was to calm down Nian Gengyao.
His Majesty has to restore Nian Shi-Lan's position sooner or later.
The lowest rank being the position of Consort.
If the situation were to worsen,
we'd have to promote her to Imperial Consort.
Although you have captured the heart of Empress Dowager,
you wouldn't have been able to prevent this matter from happening.
Since the situation was like that, I was willing to be the one who suggested it.
His Majesty would feel regret because of what happened to me.
And my position in the court would become more stable.
Although you have explained everything so clearly,
I really still don't understand.
Now she is a Consort,
it only becomes easier for her to become an Imperial Consort.
Even if you think of everything, she may not fall into your trap.
Yes, I don't know when I
became so calculating and selfish.
I know
that I am no longer a naive person with a pure heart.
But I have a strong reason
for what I doing.
Fine, fine. You have your reasons, and I have mine.
It's hard for me to talk to you right now.
I think you wanted to side with Nian Gengyao because he is more powerful.
You used the position of Consort Hua to build up your relationship with him.
Sister,
am I this kind of dishonorable person in your eyes?
Did you forget
how I lost my son?
Huan, we have been together since we were children.
I know I am not as smart nor as beautiful as you.
So I try to improve myself as much as possible to find a good man.
You are good at dancing, while I am good at playing the zither.
I never did anything better than you.
After that, we entered the palace together.
We helped each other.
Although His Majesty neglected me,
I never hated you.
But for some reason I don't know,
whenever I see you,
I feel faraway from you.
You have an admirer like Doctor Wen.
You are adored by His Majesty.
Your father is His Majesty's favorite officer.
You have the whole world with you.
But I don't have anything.
I still remember the paper boats
we put into the water when we were little.
Grandmother said the further apart the boats went,
the further apart we'd be married.
But you said
that our boats should float together,
so that we'd be married to a pair of brothers.
Then we could be together forever.
Now it seems we are together
but actually we are very far apart.
Sister, do you want us to separate?
Yes. Every relationship must come to an end.
There is nothing that lasts forever.
Return now. You need not come here again unless there is a matter that concerns you.
You will understand me one day.
Perhaps.
If you don't want me to visit you anymore,
then I will only visit you, once I have succeeded.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Greetings, to all.
- Stand.- Thank you, Empress.
Lady Hui is here as well.
It's been a long since I've had all of you here gathered together.
I'm busy accompanying Empress Dowager, so I am unable to come here often.
It is almost time
for Empress Dowager to take her medicine.
I have to go now.
It's good that the Empress Dowager likes you.
You should go then.
Consort Wan, come take a seat.
Lady Hui likes to act like this lately,
you don't take it seriously.
Sister Mei is feeling weak lately
Maybe its because of the weather.
Its normal to get a flu when the weather is bad.
But no matter what, girls should always take care of their health.
Don't be like Consort Duan. Now she's having a terrible illness.
Yes.
His Majesty told me that you never met your parents since you entered into the palace.
So I have arranged for your mother to enter into the palace today.
You go and wait for her at the House of Broken Jade.
Thank you, Empress.
Go and prepare now.
Your mother and sister will enter into the palace in the late afternoon.
Yes.
You are all dismissed.
Consort On, Please stay here.
Yes.
Farewell, Your Highness.
Empress.
Just now you saw it.
Lady Hui Dan and Consort Wan are like complete strangers.
Both of their family status is very high in the court.
There will be a lot of trouble if both of them formed an alliance.
I also think so.
It will be trouble if Lady Hui Dan and Consort Wan formed an alliance together, similar to those of Consort Hua.
You are right.
His Majesty can pamper anyone.
But he cannot pamper anyone with the the likes of Consort Hua.
Mother, why are we not there yet?
Shut up. This is the Forbidden Palace.
There is no place larger than this.
Of course it may take some time.
Watch your mouth when you see your sister later.
Understand?
Yes.
Madam Zhen and your sister wish to meet you.
Summon them quickly.
Mother.
Greetings, Lady Consort Wan.
Stand up, quickly.
Thank you.
Mother, you must tired from the long journey. Please sit.
Huan-Bi, prepare some tea.
Sit.
Come.
Huan-Bi has become more beautiful
after you have changed your status.
Thank you, madam.
Its hard for you to come here mother, why don't you give me some praise?
Of course my lady, you are the most beautiful one.
Sister, your shoes are so beautiful.
Everything in this house is so beautiful.
Yu-Rao
This is just a pair of normal shoes worn by master.
His Majesty has given another pair of shoes to master.
It was made from a special cloth with many pearls on it.
Those shoes are very beautiful.
On my way here, I have heard that His Majesty has treated my lady very well.
Madam, please have some tea.
This is the precious tea leaf of this year's tribute.
I can't drink this precious tea.
Mother, Its just a tea leaf.
I know you like to drink tea. Come, drink it.
You still remember, thank you.
This is the favourite dessert for you and miss.
Master had prepared it before you came here.
Master was very happy when she heard you were both coming.
Master, just now, Lady An sent Ju-Qing to bring something.
She said it is for you. I have to keep it for you first.
You are all dismissed now.
I want to have a nice chat with my mother and sister.
Yes.
Let me have a look at you.
Master.
Have you sent it over there?
Good
That is a precious medicine sent by the Governor of Shandong.
I think Lady Zhen will like it.
Good. Dismissed.
Yes.
Who she think she is?
Everything in the palace is good.
I still remember when i first enter into the Zhen's chamber.
Everything I saw is beautiful.
I never saw anything like it before.
Now it's also the time for me to send a gift to them.
Master is really very kind.
Not that I'm kind.
Its just that today I am on the higher rank,
I don't need other people to pity me anymore.
Congratulations, master.
I don't know
when my parents can come to visit me.
There will be such a day, don't worry master.
Maybe after you get pregnant
your mother can come in too.
But Her Majesty will not allow me to get pregnant.
Her Majesty will allow you to have a baby soon.
I am willing to draw His Majesty's attention rather than waiting for a baby.
By that time, I will be at the same level with Consort Wan.
Then my parents can come to visit me in the palace proudly.
Sister, are you happy in the palace?
Does brother-in-law treat you well?
His Majesty has treated me very well.
It's just that sometimes I have to think of something to make him happy.
It's quite tiring.
That's why you've become slim.
Yes, that why I'm thin.
And you must have eaten too much food. You have grown taller and fatter.
My lady has become thin. You had a miscarriage last time.
Is your body well?
Doctor Wen is looking after me.
Now I feel much better.
Good, you are still young.
You can have a baby after you recover.
Besides, His Majesty ha treated you so well.
Everybody think I have all the glory.
But in here, It's more easier to get a precious jewellery than a lover.
My lady, it's not good to say all of those things in the palace.
Not even in front of a parrot.
Mother is so cautious.
Love between a pair of lover is protected by nothing but cautiousness.
Not to mention, this is the royal family.
My lady still has a gap between His Majesty and you.
I will always remember your teaching.
Besides from His Majesty,
you should be cautious in everything you are doing.
One consort has caused enough trouble for you.
Not to mention there is still many people in the palace.
I know you treat Huan-Bi very well,
But its just not good for a servant to
make herself up too well.
Huan-Bi and Liu-Zhu are my good friends since we were small.
We are just friends.
No matter what, do not have any ties with her.
That is your own blood sister.
I don't care once I enter into this confused palace.
I just wish to find a good husband for Yu-Rao.
Yu-Rao is also the same with you. I think it's hard.
That's why i have to give all my effort.
For you and father and also for Yu-Rao.
We know your effort.
Your father is also worried about you.
He felt regret for not being able to help you.
My lady, the time has come.
Madam and miss have to go now.
My lady, we have to go now.
Why do you leave in such a rush?
Mother, why don't you stay for a bit longer.
It's not convenient here.
I'm worried people may say something bad about you.
Actually, your father also didn't let me visit you.
He's scared others may say something bad about it.
I don't know
when i can meet you again next time.
You have to depend on yourself now.
Don't worry, mother.
Let's go.
Consort Wan's relatives have left so early.
Pity her. It's hard for her mother to enter into the palace.
Last time, my parents always enter into the palace.
Consort Wan can also have the same privilege in the matter.
His Majesty has promoted Consort Wan's father just for the sake of her.
No matter what, he is just an ordinary officer.
His Majesty has arrived.
What is so funny?
Greetings, Your Majesty.
I was just joking with Song-Zhi.
Saying that the weather is getting hotter and plan to take a vacation with you at the summer palace.
If not, we may become baked potatoes here.
I always bring you to the Summer Palace.
Your Majesty, dinner is served.
I have asked the imperial chef to prepare many of your favourite dishes.
Good.
This herbs was mixed with what kind of spices?
Last time the soap was made by wrapping the nard, angelica root, guizhi, and bamboo leaf together with animal pancreas,
then placing it in the sun.
My lady doesn't like the smell of guizhi.
so we changed it into magnolia and added some santalaceae.
It will smell better and it is good for the hand.
I didn't know you knew all these things before.
My lady is very cautious when she is using this kind of things.
I'm just testing it for my lady.
I'm impressed you know all these things.
Your hands are so white and soft.
That's why Consort Hua used things that you have tried.
I still remember that your name is Song-Zhi.
Your Majesty, my surname is Qiao.
Song-Zhi is the name given to me by my lady.
What a good name.
It;s time to have dinner.
Yes.
You can just ask the servants to do it.
You don't need to do it personally.
Song-Zhi, take the food to His Majesty.
You just do as His Majesty told you.
Yes.
Your kitchen prepared some delicious food.
If you don't like it then its no use
no matter how nice the food was.
You are trying to tell me something.
I don't know how to speak very well.
But you have people that know how to speak.
That means you are very good in teaching them.
You're right.
I didn't see sister and sister Wan together for a long time.
Did something happen?
His majesty is always there, its inconvenient for me to go there.
Besides, I'm busy serving dowager,
thus we were not able to meet.
That's good. I was thinking too much.
I've not seen you and sister together for quite a while.
I thought the both of you quarreled.
What makes you think so?
If our relationship is close,
nothing can separate us.
I was worried, so I asked.
Please forgive me Sister.
Its not the first day I've known you.
If not you will not come here to tell me
about Consort Wan advising his majesty to restore Consort Hua's position.
I'm just worried about the both of you.
Worried? If you truly are,
you would not have used Bao-Jun's to tell me.
You are as cunning as Consort Wan.
Are you blaming me?
We both have a common enemy, Consort Hua.
That's why I'm worried that Sister Wan will make a mistake.
You can tell her directly if you're worried
that she'll make a mistake.
Sister, don't be angry.
Its all Ling Rong's fault
causing sister to be angry.
No need.
You don't need to spend energy explaining it to me.
You can save your breath for his majesty.
And advice his majesty to punish Consort Hua.
I'm useless.
Being useless is just a small problem,
it will be a big problem if you act immorally and instigate people.
Yes sister, you're right.
Its not that I want to speak ill of you, we are friends after all.
Its okay to speak frankly to each other.
There is no need to have any secrets between us.
It will be difficult to lead such a life.
If you are like this again in the future,
you can just tell her directly.
There is no need to let me know.
Lady Hui is really direct.
I think she's changed alot after his majesty neglected her.
She's been like this all this while, she has never changed.
What are they holding in their hands?
This road leads to the house of broken jade.
Maybe its medicine for health.
Is Consort Wan still taking any medication?
I heard that Consort Wan's body is still weak after the miscarriage.
That's why his majesty has ordered this.
Consort Wan is indeed his majesty's favorite among the 3 of us.
Her majesty is right. After Consort Wan has gained his majesty's favor,
all those around her will naturally benefit.
But it seems that Lady Wan has stayed
away from master after she recovered.
I'll visit her if she doesn't come see me.
Go and get a pack of health medication from the pharmacy.
Yes.
You sure spoke well just now.
Why did you speak of a word now?
Please forgive me, my lady.
Forgive you? What have you done wrong?
Don't you just like to show your claws in front of his majesty?
My lady, my lady.
You can give the comb to me if its not to your liking.
Its a waste to throw such a beautiful comb.
Miss Song Zhi, the medicine for my lady is still brewing outside,
go and monitor the fire.
Don't be angry my lady.
His majesty is only giving her a small praise.
What harm can it do?
It will be trouble if his majesty knows that you're angry.
Even seducer has appeared around me.
Sweet talk and showing off her claws.
My lady, every girl in the palace is for his majesty's picking.
Its normal for you to be concerned about his majesty.
But my lady now is pregnant,
you have to pretend to be tolerant even if his majesty likes Lady Song Shi.
Don't let his majesty think that you're a narrow minded person with no tolerance.
My lady, your main objective now is making his majesty happy.
I will ask her to leave the palace tomorrow.
So that she can't meet his majesty.
My lady, please do not show your anger on your face.
You even have to praise Lady Song Zhi.
Then will he feel your tolerance
and can use that as an excuse to shut people up.
I have nothing to hide anyway.
My lady, be careful of gossips.
I'm not afraid of gossips.
I'm just worried that his majesty will believe in those gossip.
I know.
My lady cares about his majesty the most.
Give this to Song Zhi.
Brilliant my lady, I will do it right away.
Hand me the medicine Bao-Juan.
Is it done?  Yes.
I've did it as you instructed.
Did you use the best medicine?
Yes.
Good, Sister Wan is weak now.
She has to take some tonic.
Master, what are you doing?
How can there be no medicine usher accompanying such a good brew?
The best medicine usher is human blood.
How can you hurt yourself?
Let me do it No need.
Master let me do it. No need.
Huan-Bi, what time is it?
Sister has awaken.
You're here.
I've cooked some medicine for you.
I've cooked it according to Doctor Wen's prescription.
I've also added some useful herbs.
You'll recover soon once you've drank it.
But Doctor Wen
didn't prescribe any new prescription for me.
Sister, its best that you drink it while its hot.
What is this? Why is it so smelly?
Come.
Sister, don't be worried.
I've tried it, its ok.
Don't you trust me anymore?
What happened?
Nothing, its just some small injury.
What happened to your hand?
What happened?
Although you have recovered from your miscarriage, your body is still weak.
I read in an ancient prescription that said human blood is the most effective.
That's why I gave it a try.
I wish you to have a healthy body soon
and help his majesty have babies.
You're crazy. How can you take an ancient remedy seriously?
Besides, I'm not suffering from any serious illness.
I will recover from taking some medicine.
I don't care. I just want you to have a healthy body
and be able to give birth again.
I've noticed that we've distanced from each other
ever since his majesty is giving you his attention again.
I didn't know if it was because His Majesty loves me as well,
or if you blamed me for not being able to rescue you
from the Palace of Supporting Earth,
which caused you to lose your baby.
Don't think too much, Sister.
I have nobody in this palace
besides you and his majesty.
If you distance yourself from me because of the attention that his majesty has given you,
I'd rather only have you.
Ling-Rong, that was not what I meant.
Sister, Sister Mei has stayed away from me.
Are you leaving me too?
3 of us entered the palace together.
Although my relationship with you is nothing compared to Sister Mei,
But I will never forget the times
that we went through together in Zhen's house.
Yes, even with my good intentions in mind,
why do you need to hurt yourself?
Because you are the only one willing to help me.
If you don't trust me,
then who will?
Yes, we will age quickly.
But its pity to lose our friendship before we are old.
Only you and Sister Mei
will keep me company when I'm old.
No. His majesty will not neglect you.
I will always be by your side.
Ok, don't be sad anymore.
If you really want,
you can copy some Buddha scriptures for my child.
Hope that he can reach heaven soon.
I have copied a lot.
Great!
I've been feeling tired these days,
why don't you send the scriptures
to Bao Hua temple and burn it to my child.
Its the least that I can do for my baby.
Pass me your copied scriptures to me then.
I will go there now.
Huan-Bi, go and take the scriptures and accompany Lady An to Bao Hua temple.
Yes.
Sister, take a good rest.
I will go there immediately.
Master, do you want to drink this medicine?
I will not drink any medicine that is not prescribed by Doctor Wen.
Throw it away.
Lady An treated you well.
I don't need her to do this.
I just wish that she still has a truthful heart for our sisterhood.