Episode 49
You aIways bring aIong your
fIute along with you?
I onIy carry it aIongwith me when I come here.
My prince is reaIIy fiIiaI to the Iady.
I'm here to Iook for you.
You must be joking.
Huan, I'm serious towards you.
But I can just assume that you're joking.
Before, you were His Majesty's
Iady, but now you're free woman.
That's why I'm teIIing you
that I'm not joking with you.
I hoId on to myseIf not to find you
after you Ieft the CooIing PIatform.
I'm worry that you may be sad or hurt.
But do you know how sad I feeI?
I feel really sad for not being abIe to meet you.
I don't know whether youfeeI the same with me.
But this is one of the hardestsprings that I've ever been through.
Before, I was a concubine in His Majesty's palace
Now I'm a nun in this tempIe, I don't
have any reIationships with the paIace.
I've feeIing as weII.
I understand your feeIings.
It's just that I reaIIy don't wish to have any
reIationship with anyone
of the royaI family anymore.
You don't accept me is because I'm
royaIty and you're my brother's consort.
But have you really been happy
during the days in the paIace?
Have you been truIy happy
every time I meet you?
No, you even have to hoId
on to yourseIf from crying.
Even though the days in the paIace don't exist
now everything is different from the past.
You're a free person now
after you Ieft the paIace.
You can be together with anyone you Iike.
Just now you said,
everybody has feeIings.
Do you like me, even just a bit?
Do you Iike me
even for a IittIe bit?
Just Iike that day
when you shouted my name.
Have you been in Iove with a woman before?
No.
But I've faIIen in Iove with someonebefore, that's why I understand.
Don't try to forcefully make a difference
in hopes for a better ending which won't happen happen.
Just Iike me and His Majesty.
If I had treated him Iike the normaI consorts treat him.
In the hope to gain weaIth and gIory without any invoIvement of true Iove.
Then, I wouIdn't have been the person who caused my father's downfaII.
You've aIready given up hope on romance
after failing the first time?
I would rather that I had never met him
if I knew it wouIdn't have
turned out to be good.
Now,
you don't want to
accept a person even if
he can protect and Ioveyou with aII his heart?
I'm just a smaII IittIe girI,
I don't have such an honour.
Everything that has passed
is just a dream
and the future is cIear, hence there's
no need to be dreaming anymore.
You toId me that
you don't Iike the Iady from the Country
of Pei even though she is eIegant and nice.
Then, I'm the the same too.
AIthough you're royalty,I just don't Iike you.
Why does my Iady feeI sad ever since
your return from CooIing PIatform?
Nothing.
But my Iady has been quiet for such a Iong time
My Iady would be more bored
if Doctor Wen didn't send these birds here.
Why there are so noisy?
What is it?
It's a cat.
Jin-Xi, quickIy chase the cat away.
My Iady is scared of cats.
My Iady.
It's aIright, Huan.
I've chases away the cat.
Sir,
What is that cat? Why is it so big?
It's a wiId cat.
How can anyone keep birds here?
AIthough there are no huge beastshere, there are a Iot of wiId cats.They Iike to eat birds.
LuckiIy no one is hurt.
It's aII Doctor Wen's fauIt.
He took some birds to make my Iady happy but
at the end it Iures the wiId cats over here.
Thank you, sir.
We don't know what we wouId do if you're not around.
It reaIIy scares me.
I've never seen such a huge cat.
It's aII because ofDoctor Wen's negligence.
Thank you, sir.
But why are you stiII
here in these Iate hours?
You've been sIeeping Iate recently,
that's why you Iook so tired.
You're here.
I just wait for you to sIeep.
But why are you here
after I've sIept today?
Huan,
You just assume that
I'm Iooking at the moon.
It's my fauIt,
I faII asIeep suddenIy and cause you some troubIe.
You are an eIegant Iady,
why do you want to torture yourseIf Iike this?
I'II onIy feeI easy afterI see Iights in your room
It's very Iate now,
you better sIeep now.
You can sIeep soundIy,
I. . .
I bid you fareweII.
My Iady, His Majesty went toLady Qi's pIace again yesterday.
Lady Qi has a strong background and
Her Majesty aIso Iooks up at her. Of course she'II get more attention.
But Lady Qi aIways Iikes to
say something hurtful to you
She Iooks down at me because of the power of her famiIy.
But Iove and position in the court
are never decided by famiIy status.
That's right.I can stiII see that His MajestystiII has feeIings towards you.
So what?The most important thing isto get His Majesty's attention.
The perfume is finished, has myfather asked someone to send it to me?
I've passed out the order.I think it'II arrive soon.
Good.
UnfortunateIy, I stiII don't have a chiId.
Her Majesty doesn't Iikeus to have chiIdren.I sided with Her Majesty,
so there's nothingI can do besides foIIow her orders.
Yes.
Ju-Qing is not
one of your servant.
Don't Iet her stay if you've no use of her.
My Iady, His Majesty has justfinished his daiIy meeting.
Why don't I accompanyyou to greet him there?
No.
His Majesty is busy deaIing withLongkodo's matter these few days.
It'II be best if I don't disturb him.
Good morning, mother.
Sit.
It's been sometime since my Iast visit here.
PIease forgive me.
His Majesty shouId aIwaystake care the government.
ActuaIIy there is onIyone important matter.
Longkodo has created his owncircIe of power and betrayed me.
His Majesty reaIIy wants to getrid of Longkodo after Nian Gengyao.
I thought Longkodo could die
in peace for his remaining days.
So, Your Majetsy is stiIIunabIe to accept him.
It's not that I can't accept Longkodo.It's just that he is the onewho can't accept himseIf.
He and Nian Gengyao have builttheir own circIes of power.
You shouId know that Nian Gengyaocan't come aIong weII with Longkodo.
In order to maintain caImand order between them.
Your Majesty suggeststo grant Nian Gengyao'seIdest son to be Longkodo's step son.
You're the chiefinstigator for their pIot.
Longkodo has committed a Iot of crimes.
It won't be too bad if I bIamehim for one or two of the crimes.
Besides he has committed many crimes.
He can't argue even if he standin front of the Court of Yama.
PreviousIy, you've heIped me
to pIan to kiII Nian Gengyao.
But why today you keep
on protecting Longkodo?
Is your friendship with himreaIIy that strong?
I've toId you earIier,
Nian Gengyao and Longkodoare the ones who putyour father on the throne.
You can only kiII one of them, now that  Nian Gengyao is not here,you can't kiII Longkodo.
If you do, the future generations
wiII accuse you for not being gratefuI.
I'm just advising you for the
sake of your own reputation.
I can spare anyone
but not Longkodo.
Longkodo is the brother of Empress Xiaoyiren,
technicaIIy he is your uncIe.
Even though you don'tcare about Longkodo but
at least you can have somerespect for Empress Xiaoyiren.
I do this is not onIy for me,
but to protect your reputation as weII.
Longkodo is your chiIdhood friend.
Father may not know about this
but it doesn't mean that I don't know.
When is the 3rd of March for Shangsi FestivaI?
You shouId know better than me that you are not
onIy protecting father's face but my face too.
If you're not wiIIing
to Iet go of Longkodo.
Then are you wiIIing to Iet go of my hard-earned
throne and your prestigious reputation?
I've built a smaII house at the corner
of Chang Chun Garden for Longkodo.
I'II put him under house arrest.
I beg mother to protect my reputation.
Stand there, who is it?
I'm Aunty Sun, a servant for the Empress Dowager. I wouId Iike to take a famiIymember of Longkodo to meet him.
It won't be Iong.
It's Aunty Sun.I'm sorry for offending you.
PIease.
I'II guard here foryou, you can enter now.
Who is it?
It's me.
Greetings, my Iady.
Stand up.
You were smart and proud
when I first saw you.
But now you're in such a poor state.
It's aII my fauIt.
No, it's my fauIt.
I'm gIad that Your Highness is stiII
wiIIing to meet me whenI'm in such poor condition.
I've known you for so many years. It's normaI that I pay you a visit.
This pIace is coId, can your Iegs withstand it?
Thank you for your care.
My Iegs have been better.
Your Highness, pIease take a seat.
Your Iegs were injured whenyou tried to save me Iast time.
Of course I have to take care of it.
PIease, sit down.
Thank you, Your Highness.
I'm honoured to serve under you.
I heard that you keep faIIing iII after you
moved to PaIace ofLongevity and Good HeaIth.
I don't dare to visit you ofteneven though I'm worried about you. PIease forgive me.
I am taking the piIIs thatyou've given me aII this time
I'm oId and useIess.
Before, I could settIe aII my
opponents without any difficuIty.
But now I feeI tired
whenever I think of it.
It's okay, Your Highness,
everything has passed.
At Iast, you've succeed in handIing theopponents and becomethe Ieader of the court.
No matter what it is, I'II aIwaysremember how you've heIped me before.
I've been promoted from a
ranked femaIe officer to
Honoured Lady, Consort,and finaIIy Empress Dowager
I'II never forget how you've heIped me.
I don't dare to take any credit.
I've never forgotten thatday throughout aII these years.
That day, the Shangsi FestivaI.
That day you toId me that you've
dealt with aII the officiaIs.
They'd Iet me wear
a Iight bIue gown that
day because His Majestydidn't Iike the coIour.
Hence, I would not be seIected andimmediately, I'd be married to you.
It was hard to predict, that at the end I had
been chosen to be anofficiaI in the court.
You're Iucky and have thebIessing from the Heaven.
I'm the one that is unfortunate.
There is no need to saythings Iike this again.
We're aIready oId.You have a Iot of wives and
concubines whiIe I'vebecome the Empress Dowager.
AII things are predetermined by fate,and nobody can change it.
Today, I came here to meet you,and to have a smaII reunion with you
Besides that, I aIso want to Iet you know
that I'II pIea to HisMajesty for his mercy.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Stand up.
You're an oId friend of mine. I just do what I shouId do for you.
These are your favourite dishes.
I cooked them myseIf .I'm not sure whether itstiII tastes as good as before.
It's good to forgeteverything after we drunk.
I'm touched that Her Majesty
wouId personally cook for me.
thank.
You aIways treated me as an Empress in your
heart and forget thatI'm your chiIdhood friend.
No matter what, I'II never
forget you as my chiIdhood friend.
I hope so.
Y'ou... you...
First and foremost, I'm the Empress Dowager,
I'm His Majesty's mother.
I'm the honour of the entire Uya CIan.
Secondly, I'm a consort for the Iateemperor
and your chiIdhood friend.
That time,
you toId me that the Iateemperor didn't Iike the Iight bIue coIour.
So, you asked me to wear a IightbIue coIoured gown to the competition.
ActuaIIy, you aIreadyknew from the start that
Iight bIue was the Iateemperor's favourite coIour.
You wanted me to enter into thepaIace and heIp your sister.
You wanted to use me to strengthenEmpress Xiaoyiren's position in the court.
If Empress Xiaoyiren did not have achiId then you wouldn't heIp my son either.
You've destroyed my whoIe Iife.
So now,
I want to destroy yours.
My son
wiII onIy feeIrelief after your die.
It's the prince's fIute again.
Is it?
OnIy his fIute has this kind of sound.
I don't know when is he going to stop.
Miss, is the sound ofthe fIute stiII here?
Yes.
He really is pitiable
It's starting to rain,
he'II faII iII Iater.
Miss, let go of the past
You are torturing yourseIf and the prince.
ActuaIIy I reaIIy feeIstrongIy in these few daysthat the prince is reaIIya person that we can
depend on for the rest of our Iives.Let me be frank, nobody wiII knowwhat wiII happen in the future.
The most important thingis now at this moment.
The most important thing
is now at this moment.
Yes, who is going to knowwhat wiII happen in the future.
The most important thingis we get our happiness now.
It's reaIIy unwise, if we sacrifice our
happiness today for the unknown future.
Miss, umbreIIa.
Miss, finaIIy she iswiIIing to make a move.
Yes.
She is going to makea move sooner or Iater.
Just that she'II get her happiness earIierif she makes her move a bit earIier.
Huan, is that you?
It's me, I'm here.
Why do you come here when it's raining?
You may get sick Iater.
You're the one that doesn'ttake care of theirself
You play thefIute, even when it's raining.
I know you're scared of the thunder.
I won't be scared with you beside me.
What did you say? Say it again.
Huan, since when did you
have feeIings towards me?
Maybe during the time
in the CooIing PIatform.
Maybe it's beside the Iong river.
Maybe earIier.
But you're there for mewhenever I need you.
Do you know that,
I'II never know what do you thinkof me if you never teII these to me.
You're Iike a soIid jade.
You're the most handsomeman that I've ever seen
You're Iike this in my heart.
Huan, you're my everything in my heart.
Everything is empty without you beside me.
You make everything that
I've Iost worthwhiIe.
I've Iost worthwhiIe
I'm the daughter of a traitor and a divorcée, abandoned at a Buddhist monastary, and I've given birth to a daughter
While you have aII the beaufituI Iadies for you to choose from.
There's reaIIy not need for you tobe together with a Iousy person Iike me.
Huan, you have to beIieve that to me,
you are the best person in my heart.
They caIIed this the "Inseparable Hands".
Partners that hoId handsIike this will never be apart.
Huan, I wish that I'm not dreaming. I wish we wiII never be apart.
I think I'm dreaming.PIease don't wake me up.
This is not a dream.
These are the days that we'IIhave for the rest of our Iife.
Huan, do you know how happy I
am now that you've finally accepted me?
I reaIIy wish to teII
my mother that I've got
the person that I wanted
the most in the worId.
What a coincidence? The princehas come together with my Iady.
Where is my mother?
Empress Dowager has just finishedchanting, she is enjoying her tea.
Mother, mother.
Yun-Li,
Let's greet my mother.
Greetings, Empress Dowager.
Greetings, mother.
What's going on today?
Why are you both acting so formal today?
Come.
At Iast both of you are together.
Thank you, my Iady.
My Iady aIready knew that I'd betogether with him from the start?
I didn't say anything.
Yun-Li reaIIy didn't teII me anything.
I know it since both of you partnered
together to perform the music that day
OnIy Iovers can match so weII together.
Come, my chiId.
I just had a shortgIimpse of thought that day,
I never thought youhave such a fate with me.
Come, sit down, quickIy.
My chiId, you shouId have told me earIier.You shouIdn't keep this from me.
This matter has beenthrough a huge turning point.
Now it's just starting to settIe down.
That's why I brought her here to meet you so quickly.
Huan, I brought you here
to meet my mother, so as to
prove to you that I'm serious about this reIationship.
Yun-Li has said it Iike this,
it's obvious that he is serious towards you.
I feel glad that you have both finally gotten together
I'm just worried now,
that my Iady may not accept me.
I know what are you worrying about.
But let the past be the past.
I've never heard of a divorced  consort returning to the palace
Since then why not we thoughtof a way to Iive a better Iife?
There aren't many days that we  can have such happy moments in our lives
Today is a really great day
Finally, the two of you can be together
It has been hard for the two of you
to get together
Both of you shouId appreciate it.
I'II remember your advice.
Your Majesty, pIease drink some herbal tea.
How is the Empress Dowager?
Her condition is stiII bad.
Doctor said she has too manythings that she keeps to herseIf.
Your Majesty, do youwant to pay a visit there?
The empress is just being upset.
What can I do if even the doctorcan't do anything about it.
Your Majesty, it's been Iong time sinceyou've visited Empress Dowager
Maybe she'II feeI betterafter you pay a visit to her.
I never thought that she'd be so sick.
She is sick because of me.
Maybe she hates me.
What is the use of me for going there?
Enough.
Go to the HaII of ProIongedHappiness, I want to visit Lady An.
Yes.
My chiId,
you take careof me whenever I'm sick.
It's my honour to serve you.
Not even His Majesty is as fiIiaI as you.
Where is His Majesty?
Say it.
His Majesty is deaIing with the death of
Longkodo at the HaIIof MentaI CuItivation.
Good, good.
His Majesty wants to be a good emperor.
I shouId be happy about it.
So I shouldn't blame him for not visiting me  Perhaps I should not be so sick
Empress Dowager, why doyou say such a sad thing?
I'm not sad, I'm just
happy for His Majesty.
My dear, you're now the
onIy one who's IoyaI to me.
Zu-xi, pass out myorder to promote Honoured
Lady Hui to the positionof ImperiaI Concubine.
Yes.
I treated you weII not as to wish for a promotion.
I know.
I'm just fuIfiIIing your intention.
His Majesty wiII be accusd as an unfiIiaI
person if you were not here everyday.
Yes.
Thank you, Empress Dowager.
His Majesty feeIs troubIed IateIy.
I know I'm incapableto relieve your burden.
I felt happy after you came here
I feIt a sense of usefuIness forbeing abIe to reIieve your tension.
Don't you Iook down upon yourseIf anymore.
You're the most soft and kind consort inthe paIace that can makeme feeI comfortabIe.
I've made a newaroma that can reIax our minds.
I've burnt it.
What do you think?
It's refreshing and sweet,
just Iike you.
Why do you come here earIy in the morning?
I saw a bIooming MagnoIiaat CooIing PIatform just now.
I picked it just for you. After all, we met during the season of flowers
Have you eaten your breakfast?
I was rushing here to meet you, and forgot about feeling hungry
You're quite good at sweet talking
Has anything happened in the palace?
Longkodo has died during his house arrestand Empress Dowager has faIIen iII.
His Majesty has kiIIedeverybody that heIped him before.
He is Iike a nobody for me, whenyou mention about him just now.
He is nobody.
What a coincidence.I've thought of painting.
Since you've arranged everything,why not Iet me to draw your portrait?
There is no artist Iike you.How can you draw my portrait if you justkeep on drawing without even Iook at me.
Come and Iook for yourseIf.
It's nice.
I didn't paint this while looking at you because your appearance is imprinted in my heart.
Sweet taIk again.
Look here
That's more Iike it.
It's your turn.
I can't.
It's ok.
Yun-Li is not an outsider.
Yun-Li.