Episode 58
No need to follow. I will serve her.
Understood.
Speak your mind.
She was only pretending to be nice just now,
don't tell me you are willing to trust her again!
Why shouldn't I believe her?
I saw clearly just now
insider her satchel was--
If you know what's in her satchel
then you must also know what she intends to do.
What she said today may not have all been false,
there is a semblance of truth.
Jin Xi,
Niang niang.
You saw Su Peisheng, what did he say?
What did he say?
He said,
Qi Pin and An Pin
are now in the Empress's camp.
But they have only ever been friends for show.
Lately the Empress favours Qi Pin,
An Pin can't help but feel neglected.
Qi Pin is shallow and loves to flaunt
If I was the Empress,
I would also view her as the more controllable one.
An Ling-Rong is vicious and skilled at manipulation
She and the Empress are of the same persuasion.
Most likely not even the Empress
can fully control her.
These infidels are in league with each other(Lit. A den of snakes and mice)
but still can't keep away from internal strife.
Serves them right.
Young Mistress, what do you plan to do?
Since An Ling Rong came specifically to inform
I may as well accept her gift.
Huan Bi,
Go tell Pei Er
let Xin Guiren know.
Understood.
Consort,  His majesty is coming tonight
Should we start preparing?
Prepare for what?
Xiao Yun-Zi told me earlier that
the Princess was very unaccustomed to you.
It's understandable that you are angry with His Majesty.
He is the culprit.
Your Majesty, please have some lotus seed soup
it's especially good for the summer heat.
Have you sent someone to Consort Xi?
Is she feeling better?
Still the same,
melancholic as always.
Your Majesty, even if Xi Fei Niangniang can take it
bear it,
the child in her can't.
I am not settled either.
Arrange for some entertaining performances
to cheer her up.
But Your Majesty, that's not what Niangniang desires the most
It won't be effective.
She will not be happy.
Then, what do you suggest I do?
Niangniang is alone in the palace and must miss her family,
but the Princess won't be close with her,
Your Majesty, why not arrange for a meeting with her other family members?
Perhaps seeing them will cheer her and disperse her unhappiness
then she may get better.
I know what to do.
Zhen Yuan-Dao hasn't yet fully recovered from his illness,
I am afraid he might infect Xi Fei if they meet.
I will naturally allow them a meeting
when Zhen Yuan-Dao has recovered.
Yes, Your Majesty.
His Majesty has arrived.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Rise.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
You are finally feeling better today?
Su Gonggong said
Your Majesty has permitted my father to visit me after he recovers.
I feel much better hearing that.
Right now I have no other wish than
for my family to be safe and sound
and to give Your Majesty a son.
Niangniang's family is also His Majesty's family,
they are important to Him too.
Niangniang can rest assured.
Your Majesty, Jing Shi Fang inquired earlier
whether you would like to flip a card tonight.
No need, I will stay here.
Yes.
You Majesty, have you forgotten the imperial doctor's advice again?
It is good just to be in your company.
I wouldn't want Your Majesty to feel denied,
and ask that Your Majesty not tease me either.
It's probably best to go elsewhere.
Then...
Chun Xi Dian.
Yes.
I will go and inform Ning Guiren to prepare.
But Qi Pin will be muttering again
when I pass by Chu Xiu Gong.
Oh? Do they often gossip about my attentiveness to Ning Guiren?
That I love Lady Ning too much?
I can't say often,
I just happened to overhear a few times.
You can't really blame Qi Pin.
The Empress Dowager isn't fond of Ning Guiren,
much less the others.
The Empress Dowager is the Empress Dowager.
Who does she think she is?
Qi Pin is only jealous.
It's such a hot day, please do not let anger affect your health.
Your Majesty,
Chu Xiu Gong sent someone to say that Qi Pin feels unwell
will Your Majesty visit her?
If she's unwell then send for a doctor, do I know how to cure her?
Foolish thing!
Tell her I'm busy.
Understood.
I didn't know Your Majesty had such a penchant for bluffing.
She loves to whine, I don't want to deal with her right now.
If you don't want to see her then don't,
why tell me about it?
As if I'm to blame.
Of course you're to blame.
If you were a bit more foolish,
more ugly,
less gentle, understanding
then I might like her more.
Everybody says to treat new affections and old loves equally,
Why is Your Majesty alone so partial?
Qi Pin can be a little difficult as times
but she is not one to claim illness without reason.
Why not check on her?
I will accompany you,  Think of it as a stroll.
Who says His Majesty won't come see me?
It's all because of you grovelling mongrels
trying to degrade me to suck up to Yong Shou Gong.
Audacious!Your Majesty, be careful!
His Majesty is here!
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Didn't you say you were ill?
You look very well to me.
Thank you for your concern Your Majesty,
I was just disciplining the servants,
I really am ill.
Ill? Instead of resting, you're hitting your servant.
What wrong has she committed for you to punish her so severely?
She disrespected me and defied my authority,
I only hit her a little because she made me excessively angry.
You speak.
Qi Pin was hitting my maid, Pei Er.
Just now, she sent someone to invite Your Majesty, but the answer was no.
Therefore,
So she took her anger out on Pei Er.
Pei Er,
I am here.
Was it you who went to Yang Xin Dian to ask for me?
Your Majesty,
it was not me.
It was Niangniang's servant Jing Tai who went.
She wasn't the one who asked for me,
why did you take your anger out on her?
I was-
It's because Pei Er used to serve Xi Fei
Qi Pin has been resentful ever since
Xi Fei's pregnancy was announced.
Therefore, she would always hit me to vent her anger.
How dare you slander me!
You. Raise your head.
Hm. You really did serve Xi Fei.
No wonder you were cursing Yong Shou Gong earlier.
I would not dare!
Flogging a servant innocent of crime,
absolutely no compassion.
Your jealousy over Xi Fei's pregnancy made you disrespect your superior.
Moreover, the anger you vented on servants over my absence
is really directed at me.
Forgive me Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, please look.
Qi Pin takes every little thing out on Pei Er.
Look what she's done,
there's not one spot on Pei Er devoid of scars.
I am useless.
She always uses her higher position to rebuke me.
I can't even protect my own servants.
Pin? (Imperial Consort, 5th rank.)
Is this how the mistress of a palace should act?
Gua Er Jia (Qi Pin's family name),
insolent and contemptuous of authority,
She will be degraded to Lady.
Your Majesty.
To be moved to Jiao Hu Guan (Lagoon Palace?).
Starting today, you are grounded.
You are not to step one foot outside without my order.
Xin Gui Ren will take charge of Chu Xiu Gong.
Thank you, Your majesty.
Your majesty, I'm begging you!
Don't do this to me.
Greetings, Empress Dowager
Rise.
Thank you, Empress Dowager
Quickly
Your complexion looks better, Your Highness.
Everyday I have to drink so much bitter medicine,
so much that my face turns red.
So my complexion seems healthy even though I am not.
It's simply a façade.
Emperor,
Look at Xi Fei, she's too well behaved.
I've told her countless times
to dispense with palace etiquette during her pregnancy,
but she won't listen.
Xi Fei is as filial to you as I am.
It's inconvenient for a pregnant woman to travel, why did you come here?
Xi Fei's stomach looks
a little bigger than what one would expect for the fifth month.
The Imperial Doctor said
I have twins.
That's why it's bigger.
Huan Huan, truly?
Doctor Wen said so. I would not dare to deceive you.
Surely with Doctor Wen's skill a misdiagnosis is not likely.
Such a felicitous event,
I should proclaim it to the whole world!
I am already blessed with the opportunity to serve you once more.
I would not dare receive
the honour of a national proclamation, for the children in me.
I am not worthy of such grace.
Xi Fei is very sensible.
I have only just returned to the Palace.
I would not provoke any disputes if possible,
and desire only to carry my children peacefully to term.
I wish to be undisturbed by those who seek to congratulate me.
Therefore, I hope that the news about twins
will remain confidential
until they are born.
The Harem's knowledge about this matter could indeed disturb Xi Fei's pregnancy.
They will find out
there is no hurry.
Mother, I have no objections since you and Xi Fei both feel this way.
Only,
it is such a pity
that no one can celebrate with us over so joyous a matter.
Your Majesty need not feel regret. If the Imperial Doctor is indeed right, celebrations are inevitable.
Xi Fei is right.
But being pregnant with twins
will only inconvenience her more to serve you.
There are many consorts of good character
among Xi Fei's friends.
Why not let Xi Fei have a leisurely rest,
and let the other consorts serve you?
I personally feel
Hui Pin to be dignified and proper. She is a good choice.
Yes.
I defer to your wisdom, Mother.
Also, the Empress may not be severely sick,
but the ailment refuses to leave her.
Why not task the Bureau of Astronomy to take a look
if anything is seriously wrong.
Then call on Baohua Temple to chant scriptures and pray for blessings.
Yes.
Your Majesty, the Vice Minister of the Bureau of Astronomy is here.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Why did you come in the Minister's stead? Where is he?
The Minister has fallen sick and can't attend Your Majesty.
Therefore, I have been sent in his stead.
Fine. Just as well.
I called you here today to inquire about
the conflict between Wei Yue Yan* and the moon.(*: a constellation in Aquarius.)
Some months have passed, has there been any change?
The conflict between those two celestial bodies is from months ago.
Much has changed in the celestial sphere since then,
Wei Yue Yan* is steadily showing an auspicious purple light, a sign of great fortune.(The Empress formerly used this
The conflict with the moon has passed.to delay Zhen Huan's return to the Palace.)
If that's true,
why haven't the Empress Dowager and Empress recovered?
And why hasn't the Minister
informed me of this earlier?
Has Your Majesty ever heard of the saying
"We do as our position requires us to do,"
But I, your humble servant, believe
we do what is required to be deserving of our position.
Your Majesty consults the Bureau of Astronomy precisely because a conflict existed,
consequently the Minister gains wages and prestige.
If the celestial sphere is forever peaceful,
what use would Your Majesty have for the Bureau of Astronomy?
You seem to understand well the corruption of government officials.
I understand it,
but do not agree with its principles.
There is one thing...
Speak.
The Dowager Empress's misfortune may have lessened, but by my nightly observations
Well before the Suzaku Seven wood in jail
It is blinking with two other stars.
These stars indicate bad things, and will bring bad luck to other people.
The Suzaku Seven is at the south facing the southern part of the Imperial Garden.
May I ask if
any of the consorts or consorts' parents
have "wood" in their name?
The Imperial Garden has...
Many
palaces.
Hall of Prolonged Happiness.
Palace of Great Benevolence.
Palace of Eternal Longevity.
They are there.
It's just names with "wood".
Su Pei-Shung.
Your Majesty.
According to what I know,
only the mother of Consort An has the surname Lim.
Please let me investigate it.
Fine.
Just tell me what I need to do.
It doesn't really matter.
It would be better
for the Consort to stay away from there.
Staying away from there is enough?
Your Majesty,
the Empress hasn't yet recovered.
I heard that Consort An is the one who has been serving her.
I wonder if
this is the reason why
she can't recover from the illness.
Since she serves the Empress the most,
then
tell her that she is not allowed to enter the palace of the Empress.
Ask her to stay away from there for a few days.
Yes.
Since somebody is sick,
you will be
the president of Bureau of Astronomy.
But I still don't know your name.
I am Ji Wei-Sheng.
Greetings to you both Niangniang.
Su Gonggong.
Niangniang,
His Majesty will rest in Sui Yu Xuan tonight.
Truly?
Originally His Majesty intended to visit Ning Guiren,
but changed his mind when he was almost there.
His Majesty is having dinner with Hui Pin at Sui Yu Xuan right now.
It's rare enough for His Majesty to visit Sui Yu Xuan,
but even rarer that Mei Jiejie is willing to serve him.
The Empress Dowager summoned Hui Pin to Shou Kang Gong for a long talk
before His Majesty went to Sui Yu Xuan.
Survival in the Harem is impossible without His Majesty's regard,
perhaps the Empress Dowager's words has finally made Hui Pin realize this.
Your Majesty, why do you look at me so?
A long time has passed since I last saw you,
Looking at you carefully now,
I can't help but think something has changed since you first entered the Palace.
I am ageing, my looks will naturally change.
I used to think you were entirely generous and amiable.
Only the experience of these incidents
taught me that you are not beyond haughtiness and disdain.
I know,
you have resented me all these years.
I do not dare.
You say you do not dare.
Tell me frankly,
After Xi Fei's departure,
you insisted on living here.
Did you not do so to avoid my presence?
I know,
you have suffered through many injustices during these years
But I am the Emperor,
there are times when I need to sacrifice justice to preserve the overall peace.
Moreover, there are times when I, too, am aggrieved by injustices.
You are the Emperor, I dare not be aggrieved.
Your Majesty,
you have your difficulties too.
Fortunately, Huan Er is back now.
I...
Today I have told you my truest, innermost thoughts.
You have been cold to me these many years,
I have neglected you these many years.
In retrospect,
if not for what happened with Hua Fei all those years ago,
perhaps now
I would regard you
as I do Xi Fei.
Dowager Empress, His Majesty is finally staying with Hui Pin tonight.
Hui Pin is a sensible child.
His Majesty has neglected her in the past.
Send them some warming* wine (with aphrodisiac)
tell them it's from me.
Yes.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Greetings, Hui Pin.
Sun Gugu, why have you come?
The Empress Dowager heard that Your Majesty is visiting Hui Pin,
and so sends this wine out of elation.
The Empress Dowager,
still thinks of sending wine this late at night.
What kind of wine is it?
Your Majesty and Consort Hui love each other,
so this wine will make everything perfect.
Give her my thanks.
I will leave now.
We won't need this wine,
if we really love each other.
We still a long time to spend together.
I will come and visit you,
when you are convinced.
Let's go back to Hall of Mental Cultivation.
His Majesty is going back.
Your Majesty.
Goodbye, Your Majesty.
All of you leave first.
Young Master.
Don't worry about me. Leave.
Yes.
I had given up on you.
Why did you have to tell me so much.
Your Majesty, although Consort Hua framed me,
you were the one who disappointed me.
Look,
even the Empress Dowager
knows that we need
this wine.
She thinks that I
will definitely serve you as long as this wine is here.
But what about how I feel?
Just who am I?
Does he even know about
my feelings?
He doesn't care about me.
Even if he knew...
Wen Shi-Chu.
Shi-Chu.
Young Master, did you call for me?
Wen Shi-Chu.
Young Master, you are drunk.
Don't drink so much.
What's the point of being clear all the day.
Can't I get drunk once?
Wen Shi-Chu.
I will call Doctor Wen here to help you.
What's the point of being clear all the day?
Can't I get drunk once?
Paracetamol.
Bird nest.
Master, it's late now, yet you pick the medicine for Consort Xi?
This is not for Consort Xi.
Consort Hui didn't have an appetite all summer.
These medicines are to stimulate her appetite.
Have you memorized them?
Yes.
Wei-Len.
Given your skills, you can work alone.
I let you do these small tasks,
because you are neat, and always assure me.
Doctor Wen.
Aunt Cai-Yue is calling you to House of Broken Jade. Consort Hui is drunk.
Please bring some medicine.
Yes, I will go now.
Are you rushing on time?
I will record your time to enter the palace on the board.
Alright, I will back within an hour.
Master Wen is here.
Miss Cai-Yue, go and boil this medicine.
Yes.
Consort.
Why are you so drunk?
You are here.
A person who never drinks, just drank.
Am I worrying you?
Getting drunk is painful.
Why do you want to hurt yourself?
Consort Hui.
Don't I have a name?
Or to you
am I only a consort,
who is no different from the women in the harem?
I just need to
do things according to His Majesty's mood.
Consort, I...
please don't say that.
Have a seat.
Yes.
I have a bottle of wine.
Join me.
Consort, I do not dare to drink it.
Since I have given the medicine to Cai-Yue,
I will leave now.
Please understand me.
So, I can't find anyone
to chat with me.
Consort.
I... I will drink it.
Everybody says drinking wine makes you feel cheerful.
But after drinking it, I feel so alone.
Everybody in the palace
is putting on an act.
Except for Zhen-Huan,
I am always alone.
Consort.
Please don't be like this.
I know you are sad. I will listen.
This wine is good.
I feel warm after drinking it.
My heart is feeling the same.
But it will hurt you too.
Why do you hurt yourself for the excitement?
Aren't we the same type of person?
We hurt ourselves,
in order to protect our beloved.
Aren't we both
this type of person?
We are close friends.
Close friends.
Consort.
What's wrong with you?
Stop.
Young Master, the rain is getting heavier. Let's go in and seek shelter.
The road is slippery. It will be bad is you fall down.
Alright.
Stop the carriage.
This albizia flower is pretty.
Now matter how pretty it is now,
in the end, it will fade.
Let's go in further.
It's cold here.
Who is she?
Ask her to come in.
I will go take a look. Come.
It's Lady Ning.
Our Consort is seeking shelter from the rain.
Hurry.
Consort. It's Lady Ning.
Greetings, Consort Xi.
She is wet. Jin-Xi, give her a cloth.
Lady,
don't catch a cold.
Do you like Albizia flowers?
Why don't we ask the servant to cover the flowers?
They can send the flowers to you when the rain stops.
Then you won't have to do this in the rain.
Thank you.
Spring is coming soon.
The albizia flowers are beginning to fade.
Among all the albizia flowers in the imperial garden, these are the prettiest.
That's not true.
The albizia flowers in House of Concentraing Glow are the best.
You can smell the fragrance
every summer.
I have never seen it.
I am of low birth,
that I can't even be compared to a servant.
But I can wander where I like.
You shouldn't
look down on yourself.
I am the daughter of a guilty officer too.
The rain is subsiding.
When you are out,
do you want my servant to send you back when the rain stops?
No, Consort wants to go to Hall of Autumn Happiness.
Why would you go there?
Is it that you don't welcome me?
Greetings, Consort.
Have a seat.
Your cat is pretty.
What's so special about it?
Where is the cat?
This cat is quiet.
It is the most clever as well.
Normally it doesn't meow.
When it meows,
the other cats come near here.
Are you afraid of cats?
No.
I am just curious.
How did you manage to train it?
I was an animal trainer, before I went to train horses.
It was very easy to train it.
Consort, it's time to take your medicine.
It will not taste good if it gets cold.
I have to go back to take my medicine.
I was not able to stay long.
Since you were in the rain,
it would be good for you to have hot soup.
Goodbye, Consort.
Keep the albizia flowers.
Yes.
That was bizzare.
I was reminded of the night on Ling-Yun mountain, when I saw that huge cat.
It was really scary.
Are you okay?
Yes. She was just using the cat to play with us.
I think
the soy bean is delicious.
They make it regularly.
I don't find anything special in it.
You like special things.
That's why you went to House of Broken Jade?
Are you jealous?
I am happy for you.
I was not looking for something special.
I hadn't been visitng Consort Hui.
Therefore, I felt sorry towards her.
Moreover, Mother always urged me
to visit her.
But in the end, she still has prejudices against me,
so I just left.
How could you do that?
You have to apologize to her.
I had the same thought.
But she chased me away, saying she had a cold,
when I went to see her today.
Then,
you should go visit Consort An.
I wonder why
I couldn't bear to leave her
when I went there.
Now I don't care about her, even when I haven't gone for a long time.
Consort An has her own specialties.
Bureau of Astronomy said that Consort An is not auspicious.
Although you are not afraid of it,
you have a shadow in your heart.
Go and visit her after some time.
Oh.
I am here to tell you something.
What is it?
The people in the palace are malevolent.
I can't tolerate them.
Why do you say so?
You will be angry as well, if I tell you about it.
I have heard
worse things than what you have heard.
Since I am not angry about it, there's no need for you to be.
I am just afraid you might feel bad.
Since you know about it now,
I no longer feel bad about it.
Since you said it is intolerable to you,
you don't have to care about it.
Zhen-Huan, I only thought you were tender.
Now I see you are also calm and deliberate.
Many people
will be involved.
I have a request.
No matter what you hear from anyone,
Don't be angry.
Don't punish them for it.
Alright.
Today is the 15th of the month.
You have to go have dinner with the Empress.
Go early. Don't keep her waiting.
These are the new dishes I ordered the kitchen to prepare.
Have a try.
Well,
They hold a candle to the dishes at Consort Xi's.
She is pregnant now.
Of course she needs to pay more attention to what she eats.
It is tiring for her to be pregnant.
Therefore, she has no appetite.
She won't eat the food unless it looks good.
Everybody says the baby
of Consort Xi is different.
Her stomach is bigger.
It is right that we be careful with the baby.
Why do you say that?
Although I am sick,
I hear many rumors.
Are you worrying about the rumors
in the palace that never stop?
It is useless to waste your energy
to think about them.
Your body was never healthy.
Consort Duan and Consort Jing will host the harem for you.
Why do you care about the rumors,
when they don't care about them?
Alright. I am full.
Where are you going?
I am going back to Hall of Mental Cultivation,
to mark documents.