~ Episode 11 ~
But this matter started with you
Ling Rong was never implicated in it
But now she's actually gone to the Cold Palace
to ask that someone be strangled alive
This is completely unlike her
usual gentle and warm self
A frightened rabbit can bite people
But this is a matter that even Su Pei Sheng didn't think to interfere with
yet Ling Rong was able to deal with it so efficiently
I'm too surprised
Although it's surprising,
Ling Rong did it because of us
Though that is true, but I still feel that
it's too unlike the Ling Rong that we know
She's dead?
Utterly and completely so
When she was dragged to the burial site,
someone personally witnessed it
It was done very viciously,
her neck was practically severed. It was frightening!
Those things without their genitals
are still rather efficient in their work
But that's not surprising
She even dared to offend those close to the Emperor
She deserves her ending
Did she reveal anything?
Not one word
At least she was smart enough not to
In the past, I underestimated the sickly Zhen Huan
Now, we'll see
After these stuffy past couple of days,
it's about time that it rains
Jinxi
Mistress, why aren't you sleeping?
I'm quite scared
Those myths and ghost stories
are mere folk tales
Don't take them to heart
I'm not scared of ghost stories
I'm afraid
that although Yushi has passed on
that this matter hasn't been completely resolved
Mistress suspects
that someone was giving Yushi the orders?
Think about it carefully
Yushi isn't a calculative person with deep motives
She was merely a palace maid
how would she know about poisons?
How would she know how much to put in my medicine?
And how would she know how to carry out the deed
by planting people both inside and outside of Palace of Shattered Jade?
Furthermore, where did she get the poison?
You're right
Mistress should have kept her alive
and interrogated her carefully
She hated me to the core
and thus wouldn't have revealed the actual perpetrator
She might even have maligned someone else
But with her death
the person instructing her would relax
and we may use such an opportunity
So we should use Yushi's death
to put up a good performance?
Ghost!
How much longer?
We're almost there
Mistress was at Precious Flower Hall praying for half the night
It's been hard on you
The Empress hasn't been feeling well lately
Praying for her is my duty
Who is crying?
It sounds creepy. Let's go, hurry!
Ghost!
There's a ghost! A ghost!
Did you really see it?
Precious sister was praying for half the night
Maybe you were seeing things?
If you don't believe me, ask Sang'er
She saw it too!
It's true. It had a woman's hair
and was cold and creepy
There was the smell of decay; the smell of a dead person
See? Even Sang'er was scared witless
She's the sharpest maid in my palace
Yes
I heard that a eunuch saw it too
and was scared to the point of sickness
I really saw it
She was in white and had a ghostly pale face
with a tongue this long. She was even bloodied.
Her eyes had blood too
Her hair was a mess and she was crying and crying
She was crying so terribly
Perhaps she was a woman who died grievously
You usually don't say much
but now you've hit the nail on the head
If it weren't a woman who died grievously, would she be crying at night?
A woman who died grievously?
It must be Yushi who died in the Cold Palace
It must be Yushi's ghost who has come to seek vengeance
Don't talk rubbish. She was properly convicted.
What grievances could she have?
What do you know?
At that time she didn't want to die
so Eunuch Su couldn't complete his job
She ended up being strangled to death
That back palace is so chaoticWhy don't we
wait for His Majesty to return and inform him then?
His Majesty hates ghost stories and superstitions
If you dare to, then you go and tell him
A person's grievance must go to the person who caused it I didn't do anything to her!
Why would she come and look for me?
That's why she didn't harm you
Didn't she leave immediately?
Otherwise, would you still be sitting here alive?
Then who would she look for?
Anyway, it has nothing to do with Sister Smiles
I heard that after Yushi's death
Precious Smiles hasn't slept well
so the physician has gone to check on her
Thank you for your concern
Physician Wen is looking after her
But she hasn't seen improvement
The palace has been running rampant with ghosts these past couple of days
More than ten people have seen it
It's hard to get a good night's rest
I heard so too. Some eunuchs have even fallen ill
Precious Fucha doesn't even dare to leave her rooms
The Emperor has said
that ghost stories stem from people's overactive imagination
Furthermore, so many people have seen it
they're merely adding their own dimensions to the tale
It looks like Princess of Regularity hasn't seen His Majesty in so long
that she's even forgotten his words
Niang niang often hears the Emperor's words of wisdom and is therefore unafraid
unlike us who seldom see His Majesty
If all of us have His Majesty's wisdom with us,
then the palace would naturally have less of these rumours
Unfortunately, we're not so blessed
Since you're not blessed, then you should pray for more blessings
Otherwise, when the grieving ghost comes upon you
it'll be too late to pray to the gods
All of you talk about such ugly things in private,
talking about nonsensical ghosts and supernatural demons
I don't believe it
Yushi will naturally look for
whoever she hated while she was alive
Why is everyone else even feeling worried?
Niang niang's teachings are right
Yushi was not receiving orders from anyone
of course she was acting out of her own evil thoughts
If someone were instructing her behind the scenes,
she'd definitely go and haunt that person whom caused her death
and ask that person why she had to be the scapegoat
Your Highness looks much better now
Today is the first day of the month
it is my duty to make offerings to the gods
and obtain their protection. Naturally, I feel better.
Your Highness was sick for two days and may not know
but rumours are running amok in the back palace about ghosts and the supernatural
Rumours should not be believed in
The Forbidden City has stood for hundreds of years
what kinds of supernatural tales have not been heard before?
If there is really a problem, then an exorcism should be arranged
Once the exorcism is performed,
wouldn't the back palace strengthen their belief in the supernatural?
Performing an exorcism is not about belief
but to put everyone's minds at ease
Then get the Precious Flower Temple's priest to perform the rites
Performing an big exorcism
The Cold Place is so spooky
I'll ask the priest
to release souls from purgatory in the Cold Place
I was in a trance the days before
I thank Niangniang's kindness
for exempting me giving respects in those days.
You look much better now
Several days ago when I looked at your face
it was so pale
Thank you for Empress's concern
I should have payed respects to Niang Niang
please forgive me
Sit down
Thank you Niang Niang
You were not so well
if you came here everyday
I'll be worried
Right, it's ok for you to come in the daytime
but if at night
and see some ghosts
that's too bad
Your Highness, the thunder is so loud
I'm afraid that there will be a thunderstorm later
It has indeed been raining for the past two days, making it inconvenient to go out
It's not early, all of you should return
We take our leave
Why isn't Precious Cao here today?
Princess Wen Yi caught a cold and she had to accompany her
thus she wasn't able to come out
Respectfully send off Princess of Glory
Respectfully send off Pin of Beauty
Even though Precious Smiles is feeling better,
but I think you look very frail
The feeling of having nightmares keep you up must be horrible
Niang niang, please stop
That thing is heinous, it will haunt people
You've really been scared witless
You even dare to spout nonsense before me
Please forgive her Princess of Glory
Jiejie is indeed frightened by the incident
It really is...
There've just been too many people who have seen it
so it's best to be careful
Yes, exactly! I saw it myself!
If there really isn't a ghost with grievances
then why is the Empress arranging an exorcism?
That ghost is full of such anger and grief,
I wonder if the priest handling the rites will be powerful enough to exorcise her
Can a priest be unable to do so?
She died so horribly. Her grievances must be deep.
It is said while the priest climbs a foot, the devil climbs ten
I heard that His Majesty granted Yushi death by sucide
but the concubines that were close to her
didn't do a single thing to plead for her
that's why she died so horribly in the Cold Palace
These words from the servants' mouths
can be left alone
But from the mouths of you ladies
is a show of lack of dignity and grace
These words should indeed not be uttered
But everyone is scared and uneasy now
I heard Precious Cao has never been a timid one
if she were here we would feel better
But why is it that Precious Cao isn't here today?
Princess Wen Yi caught a cold
Precious Cao has to look after her
That's why she isn't here to pay her respects to the Empress
Precious Smiles has always been a thoughtful person
I'm sure you're thinking too much right now
Let's go
That's true, as long as our conscience is clear
we shouldn't be scared of having ghosts on our doorsteps
Hurry up, let's go
It's already so dark outside
Any later and the unclean things will start coming out
Yes, it's almost night
we should leave quickly
What is that?
What's the matter?
- What is that?  - What happened?
Ghost!
She came. The ghost came to get me!
That's Li Pin's voice
Yes
Jin Xi, quickly report this to the Empress
Hurry, let's go take a look
- Ghost!  - It's the middle of the night
What are you crying madly about?
Quickly shut your mouth
Ghost!
She came. She came, didn't she?
She came, didn't she?
Whoever keeps talking nonsense will be immediately sent to the Cold Palace!
What are you waiting for? Help her up.
It wasn't me!
The medicine...I provided the medicine
but I didn't tell her to poison Precious Smile! It wasn't me!
Pin of Beauty has lost her mind!
Quickly silence her
and take her back to the Palace of Wings!
Wait!
Princess of Glory please reconsider
I'm still not sure what just happened
I think that
Pin of Beauty should be returned to her own palace first
and the imperial physicians summoned.
Why would she go to the Palace of Wings first?
Pin of Beaulty lost her mind, shouldn't be in the public
It's more convenient to bring her back to Palace of Wings
Niang Niang is absolutely right
But things happened so suddenly
I think someone should be sent to inform the Empress first
This must be handled expediently
In such a condition, Pin of Beauty
will pollute the Empress's ears.
It won't be too late to tell the Empress a bit later
I have always helped the Empress manage the six palaces
Don't tell me I can't take this small matter into my own hands
Pin of Beaulty is a host of a palace,so it is important
Niang Niang should really inform the Empress
to avoid His Majesty placing blame in the future.
Although it is true, you're most favoured
you don't need to pressure me with the Emperor
You are all blocking me like this...
are you purposely giving me a hard time?
I am not trying to give Niang Niang a hard time
It's just that Pin of Beauty's words
touched upon the subject of my recent poisoning.
I have to intervene
What are you hesitating for? Take her back!
Empress arrives!
Respects to the Empress
Greetings Empress
Everyone rise
Thanks Empress
Making such a huge commotion in the inner palace...
I can't even rest!
What happened to Li Pin?
Zhou Ning Hai! You're a servant,
how dare you cover Li Pin's mouth!
really offensive
Empress, you don't know
Pin of Beaulty suddenly lost her mind, and talked nonsense
So I ask the servant cover her mouth
In case her words cause troubles
But you should let go of her first
Will you take her back to Palace of Qi Xiang
with her mouth covered
- Niang Niang save me! - What are you doing?
Niang Niang Yu Shi came
I didn't let her do that
Let go of Niang Niang
Right, it's none of everyone's business
she did it herself
Don't be afraid, Yu Shi didn't come
go back with me
Niang Niang
Yu Shi is coming, she is coming
She is coming for us to revenge
What are you talking about
Empress save me, ghost ghost
Nonsense, where's your manner
I can't be assured seeing you act like this
Jiang Fuhai,
Yes
Take Pin of Beaulty back to Palace of Benevolent Hope
Empress
Pin of Beaulty probably got insane
How can you take her to Palace of Benevolent Hope, and disturb you
how about I take her back with me
and take care of her
Palace of Benevolent Hope is big enough to settle her down
besides, Pin of Beauty's lost her mind
but her words
involved Yu Shi's poisioning
This is a matter of grave importance. I have to investigate it.
Do you think it is inappropriate
if I take her with me
No, I don't think it is inappropriate
if Empress takes care of her
But his majesty commanded me to assist in managing the inner palaces himself.
His majesty must believe that
I can share Empress' burdens
I'm afraid his majesty will blame me
for lacking show of concern.
Empress is the master of the inner palaces, if you deal with this yourself
his majesty must be more assured
Respectly send Empress
Jiang Fuhai, take Pin of Beaulty
Yes
Young mistress! Two young mistresses are back.
It took you so long
We were so worried
Xiao Yunzi
We made you dress up like a ghost. We've troubled you.
There's no need to say such things to your servant
But I took a quick look at myself in the mirror
I even scared myself!
Of course
You really scared Pin of Beauty. She became so disoriented
and revealed quite a bit of information!
I didn't think that my trivial skill
would come in so handy here.
I should really thank Huanbi Jiejie
for preparing this white clothing for me
and Promise An
for painting this big white face on me!
That's nothing
The two Jiejies came up with this good idea
You thought of it first
Huan'er and I
just refined the idea a bit and executed it.
Jiejie won't blame me for being vicious?
Everything I'm doing
is for the goal of our peaceful existence in this palace.
How could we?
We're all sisters. Who would say that?
Mei Jiejie won't blame me either?
You're the most meticulous
Finding out ghosts were Pin of Beauty's greatest fear was all thanks to you
Alright, let's not talk about this for now
Xiao Yunzi, burn these costumes
If we leave traces behind things will be ruined
Yes, servant knows
Niang Niang, sit for a while
You must be tired from walking back and forth
I asked you here for half a day. You haven't said a word!
Cry cry cry! You only know to cry!
What did you bring her for?!
Niang Niang, please calm down
The princess is sick. She can't be apart from me.
Now that something big has happened,
you're out of ideas!
Niang Niang, do you believe in this talk of ghosts?
It's precisely because Niang Niang doesn't believe it
that ghosts dare not attack you
But Pin of Beauty is very superstitious
so she believes ghostly stunts pulled off by other people
ghostly stunts pulled off by other people?
You're saying that someone is behind all of this?
Otherwise, how do you explain that the ghost spirit
only dares to frighten Pin of Beauty,
but doesn't dare approach Niang Niang?
It's Zhen Huan! It must be her!
Shen Mei Zhuang doesn't have that many sinister ideas!
She dares to pull such tricks
I will turn her Palace of Shattered Jade upside down!
and find all of the props she used to pull the stunts off
Don't
Niang Niang, you must not
You've already been implicated in the matter
If you pull such a big move, it will backfire
Besides, Zhen Huan must have already destroyed the evidence
It would be useless to search
Then should I just be a sitting duck?
Fortunately though, isn't Pin of Beauty already crazy?
The crazy will say anything!
Crazy?
Their words are not credible
Respects to Empress
Everyone rise
Thanks Empress
I called everyone here this early
to discuss what happened last night.
I want all the details
Empress Dowager arrives
Respects to Empress Dowager
Everyone rise
Thanks Empress
Princess of Glory came to pay her respects early in the morning. She said Pin of Beauty was not feeling well.
I came to take a look
Why was Empress Dowager alerted?
I think it's probably because Princess of Glory is afraid of being suspected
so she told Empress Dowager first to clear herself of involvement.
She is bold
Empress Dowager is the Empress's close relative
Of course she'll side with the Empress
If she's bold enough to do this, she must have some degree of confidence
Any degree of confidence is not enough compared to blood ties
The Empress has been suppressed by Princess of Glory for a long time
Empress Dowager must not be happy about that
Last night's affair caused such a huge commotion
Everyone's eyes must be on the Palace of Benevolent Hope
but there seems no action
When I was young, I heard people say
before the storm comes,
The surface of the sea is always extremely peaceful
Empress Dowager listened to nonsense for a day
and must be annoyed.
First drink some water and rest
This novel kind of nonsense
I rarely get to hear.
If the Empress Dowager has heard it then forget it
I will have the imperial physicians treat Pin of Beauty
No need
If her deranged words are so offensive,
don't mention when she's sober.
Have her leave the Palace of Benevolent Hope, and go to the Cold Palace
so she doesn't desecrate your place.
Yes, I'll assign tomorrow
Pin of Beauty is really useless,
unable to take such a fright.
Clearly,
she has a guilty conscience.
But Pin of Beauty said she took directions from Princess of Glory
So what if Princess of Glory told her to?
Pin of Beauty's words can only be treated as rantings of an insane person
Empress Dowager
I know that Princess of Glory has held you down all these years
She doesn't know to exercise restraint
She's been arrogant ever since she entered the Duke's abode
But the Emperor likes her
Her older brother is also Nian Gengyao
Now Pin of Beauty is insane
Everyone knows not to believe the words of the insane
Yes
So, a little punishment is enough, don't be too rigorous
As to the external, you just need to say the rumors got around in the palaces
As the Empress you must be firm
only then can the rumours be put at ease
Then His Majesty...
When he returns, I will tell him
It was you who handled the six palaces, and quelled the rumors
As for Precious Smile, she's very intelligent
Precious Shen is also steady and calm
Some things
you can let Precious Shen practice handling.
Yes, they're all picked up by his majesty and Empress Dowager
Then deliver my order
Princess of Glory should have a rest
and not assist in managing the Inner Places
Yes
Huan Bi
Why are you here?
Respect to mistress An
My young mistress ask me to bring some joss sticks and candles
and burn the drawn buddhist sutras by the way
Why does Jiejie suddenly want to burn the buddhist sutras
Young mistress say there are too many bad things in the palaces recently
so she asked me to burn the Buddhist sutras to pray for peace
Besides, Yushi died
she was only bad when she was alive
young mistress also asked to burn some for her, wishing she'll be excused from death earlier
It's late
servant will go
Sure
Young mistress
what's wrong, young mistress
Jiejie asked Huan Bi to burn the Buddhist sutras for Yushi
she may blame me for what I've done to Yushi
No
Precious Wan is involved
she can't blame you
Young mistress, don't think too much
Let's go
Emperor arrives
Your Majesty
Quickly get up
Your Majesty, you're finally back
Sit
Miss me?
I miss Your Majesty
You must be very tired for your inspection tour?
I just went to see the Empress Dowager
The poisoning incident has ended
You can now rest assured. I can also sigh in relief.
Since the incident is already over, Your Majesty need not be angry about it anymore
Pin of Beauty only resents me
because she cares about Your Majesty.
Cares about me?
Does she care about me or her own glory?
Only she really knows
Even if she really cares about me,
doing something so sinister
is absolutely unforgiveable.
Pin of Beauty made a mistake. She has already been punished.
Although Princess of Glory
usually hangs around Pin of Beauty,
she wouldn't be so stupid
as to be complicit in this matter.
Princess of Glory is blessed and has a resolute mind
Resolute? What do you mean by resolute?
Doing things with resolve and firmness, knows how to handle matters and people
That is what being resolute means
Princess of Glory assists in managing the inner palace
She should be worthy of these two words
Everything has two sides
Empress Dowager has always used proper judgment in handling affairs
She never meddles in matters of the inner palace
But if she gets involved,
it must be something major that she cannot tolerate.
This time around, it is a warning to the back palace
not to cause such pandemonium again
I just hope that from now on, everyone in the inner palace
can be more considerate of each other, and not so resentful.
Only that way can Your Majesty concentrate on affairs of state
without fear of trouble back home.
This morning at court I saw your father cough a bit
He seems to have caught a cold
Father has always had laryngitis
I'm also very worried
So after court,
I had Su Pei Sheng
get two bottles of honey loquat syrup for your father.
Many thanks Your Majesty
He's your father. I should show care for him.
Father's laryngitis
is something that mother worries about everyday.
She cooks almond lily in the spring
and Sichuan fritillary bulb and pears in the Autumn
she has taken care of him for many years
Your parents care deeply for each other
which is why their daughter is so gentle and affectionate.
Your Majesty jokes with me
Mother, today is your death anniversary
I don't know whether dad still remembers this or not
whether just as me
I can only burn the ghost money for you secretly
Mother
daughter is unfilial
I don't know
when I can stand out among people
and burn the ghost money for you aboveboard
So late, who is still there
How dare you
how dare you burn the ghost money in the Royal Palaces
Precious Cao
You, you are Precious Smile's maid?
You know
the ominous thing is forbiden in the palaces
Burning ghost money is even more serious
Precious Smile couldn't save you even if she knows
Forgive me Precious Cao, servant will never do it again
please don't tell young mistress
Alright, stand up
Please forgive me
You're lucky that I was the one who found you.
if it was anyone else
they would take you to Bureau of Cautious Punishment already
tell me the truth
why you burned it here
Today is my mother's death anniversary
You are filial
but since you are doing it for your mother
Why did you burn it here
instead of in Palace of Shattered Jade
Servant dare not
You are most loved
by your Precious Smile
even your food and clothes are different from others
why didn't she help you with your filial piety
Servant was afraid of offending young mistress
please don't tell young mistress
about what happened today
I know
sweep away all the ashes quickly
they will catch you if they find the ashes
Thank Precious
Precious Flower Hall's priest has done four rites
total expenses on joss sticks and candles is 1800 taels
It's getting hot
Every maid and eunuch in the palaces
have been given green bean soup at lunch to clear their heat
This costs 32 taels per day
Wait
One day's green bean soup is 32 taels?
Then what about a month's worth?
960 taels
Wealth comes from the simple places. Although it's just one bowl of green bean soup
but carried out over a long period of time,
it's no small sum
Empress is right
But this has been going on since the previous Emperor's reign
If it was suddenly discontinued,
I'm afraid that there will be grumblings
His Majesty is right
Acts of benevolence from the masters
encourage the servants to do their jobs to the best of their abilities
So this sum of money is not something we should scrimp on
Precious Smiles, what do you think?
I don't understand these things
Mei Jiejie is doing the accounts
So I can only drink my tea
That is the most fortunate lifestyle to have
Your Majesty, I was thinking
that the daily stipend of each palace is never used up
For example, for Precious ladies
they are given 1 sheng and 2 he of rice evey day
6 jin of pork, and 6 jin of fresh vegetables
2 jin of white noodles, 1 jin and 8 liang of tofu...
No matter how they eat, they will never finish eating such large amounts
Not to mention the amount of food delivered to the Pin ladies and the Princesses
I was thinking, why don't we
cut down on the amount of food in exchange for silver for each palace
Then the green bean and ice candy cases
can also be stopped in exchange for money given to the servants
On one hand, we save on money spent,
on the other, everyone gets a share
So that there won't be any cases of
quibbles over someone eating someone else's share and breeding discontent
Jiejie is bright and intelligent
If it were me,
I would never be able to calculate all of that
I have a headache now
Thank goodness Precious Shen is around to do the calculations
What do I know?
If it weren't for the Empress' pointers and teachings,
I would have become the laughingstock of many by now
You're still young, you should practice more
But even practicing will be useless without some kind of natural talent
You must be referring to me then, as someone naturally stupid
Look at her mouth
She still calls herself stupid
Then everyone else must be worse off
In my opinion, Your Majesty cannot blame Meimei
Your Majesty should blame yourself
for having spoilt Meimei's mouth
to the point that it will say whatever it wishes to say
Your servant respectfully greets Princess of Glory
Rise
Thank you, Niang Niang
Go and inform the Empress that I am here to pay my respects
What's wrong? You aren't even going to listen to Niang niang's orders?
Then you don't have to inform her. I'll just go in myself.
Niang Niang. The Empress' illness is acting up
She's ill-disposed to entertain guests
It's precisely because her illness is acting up
that I am here to pay my respects
Niang Niang's illness is acting up, but her spirits seem to be high
His Majesty has come to visit Niang Niang
That's good. Then I'll pay my respects to the Emperor at the same time
That will save me a trip to the Palace of Resting Soul
Niang Niang be at peace,
whether or not the Empress is ill-disposed,
is inconsequential
The important point is whether the Emperor, upon seeing Niang Niang
will get angry and affect his health
Niang Niang is an intelligent person
and thus naturally knows how important the Emperor's regard is
Why do you want to anger the Emperor?
Respectfully sends off Niang Niang
Reporting to Niang Niang, Precious Cao is here
Greetings, Niang Niang
In this summer's heat, it's unsurprising that Niang Niang has fire in her heart
As long as that fire can be dispelled,
I am willing to accept all consequences
Back then you were merely a
poor concubine candidate
Your nameplate was saved and sent to the Duke's abode
You never even got to see the Emperor
If it weren't for me who suggested that you serve the Emperor,
would you have the opportunity to give birth to the princess and become a Precious?
Now that Pin of Beauty and myself are in trouble,
you come up with foul ideas and mess up everything
Yet you have the cheek to say such things before me?
I am not sure what I did wrong
Please tell me
I will make amends for it
I listened to you
and informed the Empress Dowager about Pin of Beauty's madness
so that I will not be implicated
It's fine if Pin of Beauty is sent to the Cold Palace
but I've lost the power to manage the six palaces
All because you thought you were all that
and came up with that plan
Congratulations, Niang Niang
Tell me why I should be congratulated
No matter what Pin of Beauty says, it is only a madwoman's words
No matter how suspicious the Empress Dowager and Emperor are,
they have no evidence to back it up
Although you appear to have lost power,
Niang Niang is able to be safe
Furthermore, the Emperor is a sentimental man
gaining and losing power is entirely within a single thought
You certainly make it sound easy
Now Precious Smiles has wormed her way into the Emperor's heart
The Empress' manipulations are also at work
Now it's so difficult for me to even see the Emperor!
Niang Niang is virtuous
I am willing to do anything for Niang Niang
and provide any advice
What makes you fit?
The Emperor is an affectionate and sentimental man
He dotes on Wen Yi very much
Get up  Get her a seat
Thank you, Niang Niang
Pin of Beauty is like an embroidered flower - Good to look at, but not very useful
It looks like you're a lot better
You have a daughter to rely on
Unlike me who has no children
I am useless, without Niang Niang's protection,
how can my Princess grow up peacefully?
Niang Niang has always doted on Wen Yi
When Wen Yi is older,
she will look to you as her mother and be filial to you
Look at you
your hair is a mess yet you're still talking to me
It's been hard on you
Song Zhi
Yes
Bring Precious Cao to the back to comb her hair and change her clothes
Thank you, Niang Niang
The Emperor hasn't seen Wen Yi for a couple of days, right?
Bring Wen Yi to Palace of Benevolent Hope to pay her respects to the Emperor
Yes Except that I am not good with words
and I'm afraid that I'll annoy the Emperor
It's all right if you're not good with words
It's enough that Wen Yi knows how to garner his attention
At my dressing table,
there is a phoenix wears herbaceous peony of step-shake
(Step-shake: Dangling ornament worn by women)
Wear it
Thank you for watching! Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki