Episode 59
Why don't you come in?
though I might devour you.
Your servant would not dare.
Look at you,
looking as if you were my enemy.
May I ask why Consort called?
I cannot fathom why.
I have a question,
I hope you can answer, once you've diagnosed my condition.
Yes, Consort.
Consort.
It appears my dreams were correct.
It couldn't be...
that night.
Don't try to tell me this is a crime.
This is my child.
I will use my life,
to protect it.
Shi-Chu, you must help me,
to not let this become a nightmare.
Is His Majesty's meeting suppose to end by now?
When I asked, it ends at this time.
Then let's begin to look around,
to look for my bracelet.
What are you searching for, this early in the morning?
Greetings, Your Majesty.
I lost my bracelet.
It's not a problem,
but it's a gift from Your Majesty,
when I first came to the palace.
- Su Pei-Seng.- Yes, Your Majesty.
- Help her find the bracelet.- Yes, Your Majesty.
You seldom wear such bright colors.
The colors are beautiful and it suits you. You look nice.
Your Majesty, we found it.
There's no need to find it, should you lose it again.
We have thousands of them in the store.
I can lose the bracelet, but never the relationship.
I prepared tea at the House of Broken Jade.
Would Your Majesty care to try some?
Since you offered, how can I refuse?
You're here.
Have a seat.
Cai-Yue, prepare some fruit.
Yes, Consort.
These clothes were made when I left.
I chose some nice fabrics,
for you to use.
You keep sending this and that.
This House of Broken Jade,
is full of your gifts since you've been back.
They're just things I prepared for you.
Consort Xi is here.
Greetings Consort Xi, greetings Imperial Concubine Hui.
Imperial Concubine Hui,
these are gifts from His Majesty.
Please accept them.
Cai-Yue, receive them.
Thank you, Eunuch, for bringing the gifts.
This is a present for you.
Thank you, thank you.
It's very precious.
Thank you, Imperial Concubine Hui.
His Majesty relays that those gifts
are for fun.
And asks that Imperial Concubine serve His Majesty tonight.
The palanquin will be prepared for you tonight.
Please thank His Majesty for me.
Your servant will take his leave.
Congratulations.
Have you had a change in luck,
or in temper?
Nothing good or bad,
I just need to survive.
And the time will pass.
Su Pei-Seng.
Your servant is here, Your Majesty.
Consort Xi is pregnant. Get her some plum soup.
Your Majesty, your servant already asked them to prepare it.
Your Majesty, the plum soup looks nice.
May I ask for one from Consort Xi?
You may have wine.
Su Pei-Seng, prepare a cup for Imperial Concubine Hui.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I am pregnant.
Therefore, I cannot have alcohol.
Since when?
A few months?
I did not feel well,
so I saw Imperial Doctor Wen.
He said I was pregnant, two months along.
Good.
It would be about two months.
Congratulations, Imperial Concubine Hui.
Since she is pregnant.
- Su Pei-Seng.- Yes, Your Majesty.
Quick, change the dishes of Imperial Concubine Hui to be the same as Consort Xi.
Yes, Your Majesty.
The chrysanthemum in the palace
bloomed earlier than expected this summer.
I wondered if this might be a bad sign.
So, this news is a big surprise to me.
Huan-Huan and Mei-Er are pregnant.
This has never happened in the palace before.
Your child is arriving just in time.
Empress even asked Jian-Qiu
to come visit everyday.
That worries me.
I know she's not sincere,
but still I have to serve her.
It tires me out.
True.
Then two powerful Consorts become pregnant at the same time.
She really can't relax.
No matter how strong she is,
she might not be able to handle all this.
Don't let it bother you too much.
Remember, eat mild foods and drinks,
drink less tea, and avoid spicy foods.
Never use perfume.
Appears you are already a mother.
Mumbling at me,
repeating things to me so many times,
I can memorize all you say.
Thank goodness, Empress Dowager sends Wen Shi-Chu to take care of you.
I really don't trust anyone else.
Me too.
I don't want anyone else to care for me.
He's the one who took care of me all those years.
Your child due in eight months.
While mine just near three months old,
is at the most vulnerable time.
True.
I'll protect this child with everything I have.
You still haven't forgiven His Majesty?
The child is innocent.
There's no connection at all.
Should we invite Consort Jin
to visit Consort Duan with us?
Okay.
This servant should be punished for falling asleep while on duty.
Greeting to all the Consorts.
Is His Majesty inside?
Yes.
His Majesty is inside.
We shouldn't interrupt.
Eunuch Su.
You've served His Majesty for such a long time,
you should be allowed to take a rest.
Or else you'll be overworked.
Thank you Consorts for understanding.
Eunuch has dropped something.
Let's see.
This sewing skill is excellent.
It reminds me of...
Imperial Concubine who is good at knitting.
But her skill is not as good as this.
It looks more like yours.
Consort, your praise is too generous...
Take good care of it.
Thank you Consort.
Master, Master Ling-Rong is here.
It's late. Am I interrupting you, Sister?
Why, you are always welcome.
I heard that you were pregnant, so I came to congratulate you.
Am I being presumptuous?
Not at all. You came just in time.
I want to make a tiger hat for my child.
So he'll be warm when he's delivered.
But the tiger's mustache is difficult to embroider.
Let me try.
Is this better?
With your help,
it really does look better.
Later, place a pearl on both sides of the mustache.
It'll look beautiful when you wear it.
Good idea. Can you teach me more?
Master, it's time to take your medicine.
Too much embroidering will hurt your eyes.
Thank you, Master Wen.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Your appetite seems worse than that of Consort Xi.
You haven't slept well these last two days.
You look pale.
Master had a headache last night.
So, it was difficult for her to rest.
Why? What does Imperial Doctor say?
He said it was nothing.
But you don't look well.
Maybe it's because I spent too much energy
talking to Imperial Concubine An last night
that I couldn't sleep.
Imperial Concubine An?
Isn't she still in meditation?
It's difficult for her to come,
so I shouldn't turn her away,
as we are still sisters.
Master also said,
every time Imperial Concubine An visits,
she feels uncomfortable.
Is that true?
Your servant would not dare to lie.
I know.
Let Su Pei-Seng tell Imperial Concubine An
not to visit the House of Broken Jade,
so there will be nothing inauspicious to affect Imperial Concubine Hui.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Have some porridge.
Yes, thank you, Your Majesty.
Can you read this word?
Da (big)
Long-Yu is so clever.
Then what about this one, when we add a dash underneath?
Tai (over)
Very good, my Long-Yue.
Consort, Fourth Prince is here.
Quick, show him in.
Greetings, Consort Jin.
Brother.
You've come so early.
I wanted to greet Mother,
and pass by the Hall of Complete Happiness.
I've come to pick up Sister to go to the Hall of Long Life.
Fourth Prince is very polite.
Will you come to pick up the Princess to greet every two days?
You should come with me to greet Mother.
Fine, be sure to come back early.
I'll send Long-Yue back
after we have breakfast at the Palace of Eternal Longevity.
Okay.
Go with them.
Yes, Consort.
I'll be leaving then.
Ru-Yi.
Do you think...
Consort Xi taught Fourth Prince to do this?
She might want
to take Long-Yue from me.
Consort, don't be bothered by this.
Master, your servant has brought Consort Jin.
Show her in.
Yes, Empress.
How is the Empress doing?
She's been having headaches these days,
but is feeling better lately.
Once she's fully recovered,
I'm sure she'll be a source of many troubles for me.
I'm eight months pregnant,
but must be careful.
I need to make some preparations.
There is no need to worry.
I have prepared everything.
I'm near to giving birth.
But Imperial Concubine Hui hasn't yet reached three months.
How are you?
You look tired these days.
Nothing to worry about.
I and Imperial Concubine Hui,
have relied upon you for our lives.
I'm sure you're feeling tired.
But if you don't take care of yourself,
how can we be safe?
I thought I was just a doctor
that can save people.
But I was wrong.
Why are you so discouraged, and saying such things all of a sudden?
It's not that I feel discouraged.
Everyone is the same.
Everyone has their difficulties.
Just keep going.
But I never imagined
that something would happen to me too.
What of that?
As a man, you must carry your burden.
Don't give up no matter what you're facing.
Not only for your sake,
but for the sake of others.
The burden of a man.
Consort.
No, I mean Little Sister Huan.
If I were to make a huge mistake,
would you forgive me?
No matter what mistake you might make,
there will be no need to plead for my forgiveness.
The most important thing is to obey your heart.
Little Sister is right.
The thing you asked about before.
I'll do my best.
No matter how hard it is to complete it.
Your servant will take your leave.
What is Master staring at?
The Imperial Household sent two boxes of oranges.
I just received them.
Jin-Xi loves oranges. Set aside two for her.
Where is Jin-Xi?
Master thinks she's not in the palace.
Where else would she be?
We need to keep something in mind.
Don't speak of it.
Empress has arrived.
Consort Duan has arrived.
Consort Jin has arrived.
Greetings, Empress.
Arise.
Thank you, Empress.
Consort Xi, when you're in the palace,
I shouldn't have to come here.
But because you're Long-Yue's mother,
and is now pregnant,
I still need to take care of you.
I asked Consort Jin and Consort Duan
to come together here with me.
Thank you for your kindness, Empress.
But I'm still unaware of what has happened.
Would the Empress please tell me?
I haven't felt well these last few months,
and haven't had the energy to care for anything but my health.
So, I've left the cares of the palace
to Consort Duan and Consort Jin.
But Consort Duan is not in the best of health.
And Consort Jin is busy taking care of Long-Yue.
Therefore, mistakes were made.
Empress, please forgive us.
Arise.
Thank you, Empress.
Peace among the Consorts affects the government.
So, I must be very careful.
But today,
there is an unpardonable crime before us
that has come from your palace.
So, I am very angry.
Empress, please tell me.
During the Ming Dynasty,
there were cases concerning court eunuchs and maidens
becoming involved in relationship.
This problem persisted and worsened.
And as a result, the Ming government was tarnished.
Therefore, since then, the rules have been tightened.
And rarely have we had to deal with such a matter.
Today, however, we discovered that...
Jian Qui.
Consort Xi, do you recognize this?
Yes, it looks familiar.
I think I've seen it before.
From the sewing skill,
it appears to be the work of Jin-Xi.
You are very observant. It indeed belongs to Jin-Xi.
Jin-Xi is so careless.
Even at her age, she is unable to take care of her belongings.
Thank you, Empress.
I'll teach her a lesson
once she returns.
It is not an offense to misplace one's belongings.
The essential point is
that this was in the possession of Su Pei-Seng.
Jin-Xi has been sent to jail.
So there is no need for Consort Xi to rebuke her again.
Consort Jin, speak.
Yes, Empress. What happened is...
a few days ago, Consort Xi, Imperial Concubine Hui and I
happened to meet Eunuch Su.
When he greeted us, the purse in question fell out of his sleeve.
Eunuchs are not allowed to keep such things.
Having possession of the purse alone does not prove anything.
Jin-Xi may have dropped it.
Su Pei-Seng might have picked it up
in order to return it to her.
A purse alone cannot prove anything.
But I'm sure Consort Xi understands
I can't ignore this occurrence, and just do nothing.
I'm here so we can avoid rumors.
And therefore,
I must search Jin-Xi's room.
Jin-Xi is my servant.
Empress shouldn't involve herself in this matter.
I'll conduct the search.
You're pregnant and need to avoid arduous work.
Consort Xi is better served to avoid this matter.
Hui-Chun, Jian Qiu.
Go and search Jin-Xi's room.
Be thorough, and don't be careless.
Yes, Empress.
Consort Xi, you are pregnant.
Please, sit down,
and anticipate what they might find.
Search carefully. Search every corner.
Yes.
Aunt Jian Qiu.
Such disgrace. See for yourself.
Both are veterans of the palace.
How can they do this?
I must make an example of them,
so no one else will dare repeat this crime.
I beg of you, Empress.
Jin-Xi is my servant.
Allow me to administer the punishment.
The servant of Consort Xi also belongs to the palace.
As a servant of the palace,
I cannot let her go.
A servant must be polite,
kind, and have no personal wishes,
so they will be loyal in their service.
Otherwise, they will cause trouble.
Consort Xi thinks generously.
To the Empress Dowager and His Majesty,
and all others, Empress is a good queen.
I trust that Empress will be fair and just,
in order to protect the Royal Family and law of the palace.
Of course.
As head of the Consorts,
I must be fair, so all will remain loyal.
Consort Xi, be sure to take care of yourself.
Farewell, Empress.
Empress is really impatient.
Master, don't be afraid.
Afraid.
If I'm afraid, then after Jin-Xi
you'll be her next target.
Then me.
No one can escape her.
Jin-Xi has been captured.
What happens if things worsen?
In that case,
Jin-Xi won't be only one facing trouble.
Even Master's reputation will be in doubt.
What's more important right now?
My reputation or Jin-Xi's life?
No matter what, I must protect Jin-Xi.
Your Majesty, Consort Xi is here.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Quick, quick, arise. Sit.
This is not the first time serving your master.
But when it comes to you...
I prefer tea to be 80% hot,
but this tea is too cold and therefore is less fragrant.
It's your servant's fault, your servant's fault.
Your Majesty, Xiao Sha-Zi is still young.
Don't be angry with him.
What he needs is more practice.
Xiao Sha-Zi, bring some hot water.
Yes, Consort.
Su Pei-Seng is not here.
They could not control themselves.
They haven't done anything good.
A team of good horses need a leader,
so they can travel well together.
They are team of people
who follow orders.
With Su Pei-Seng being imprisoned,
it's like they've lost their direction.
Empress has already informed me
about the case concerning Su Pei-Seng and Cui Jin-Xi.
Actually, I was planning to visit you
after reading these proposals.
But you came to see me first.
It's my fault
that I didn't teach my servant properly.
As you have said,
I'm worse than you.
Su Pei-Seng has served me since my youth.
They made a mistake.
There's nothing we can do.
Since this occurrence,
I've never felt such emptiness.
Even though Jin-Xi made this mistake,
she has served me for so many years.
I feel both sad and angry.
You're being pregnant now,
it's of utmost importance that you to take care of your health.
Empress' health is improving.
Let her take care of the matters of the palace.
If you're that sad about Jin-Xi,
I will ask Imperial Household to find a better maid for you.
Why didn't Master ask for His Majesty's help?
His Majesty is the only one who can influence the Empress.
The Empress was prepared.
She already has evidence.
She's using the rules
His Majesty is powerless to do anything.
If ask him for help,
I'd be falling into her trap.
She would punish me under the rules of being unfair.
What can we do?
If Master is affected,
no one can save Jin-Xi.
Let's go to the Ministry of Justice.
That place is very hot.
Being pregnant, Consort shouldn't go there.
Surely, you're aware of this.
I've endured cold in the palace many times.
It's nothing to be scared of.
The pregnancy has already been difficult.
If not yourself, think of the Prince.
Please avoid the negative effects of the Imperial Criminal Division.
If he can't endure such a small matter,
he's not my child.
Let's go.
(Work harder, don't be lazy.)
It's warm in here.
Why are the blankets so thick?
They use thick blankets and dry grass
for punishment here.
They make it hot
to bring about malaria.
But when the coldest day of winter comes,
they are given only a light blanket.
Prisoners are known then to freeze to death.
Aunt must be undergoing the punishment of rice beating.
The prisoners only get
two hours of sleep everyday.
And they receive rice beating when they're awake.
(Work harder, don't be lazy.)
(What are you doing? Work faster.)
(Keep working, lazy bitch.)
Why are you slowing down? Work faster.
Do you want to live?
Work harder.
(Bitch, work harder.)
(What are you looking at? Where are you looking?)
Work faster, bitch.
(Still don't want to work? Do you want to die?)
(I'm talking to you.)
Servant didn't know Consort Xi was here.
Greetings, Consort Xi.
Is there a person named Cui Jin-Xi here?
Yes, she just arrived.
She's beating rice over there.
Can Aunt help me out?
Let me have a few words with her.
Sure, sure.
Please wait. I'll call her over.
Cui Jin-Xi, come!
Consort, take your time.
I'll be going.
Thank you.
Why is Consort here?(Too slow, work faster.)
Consort is pregnant. Why would you come to such a place?
(I'll beat you to death. Do it right.)
It's my fault that
Consort would have to come to such a place.
There must be a lot of rumors, ridiculing Consort.
Servant feels so guilty to face Consort.
If you caused me trouble,
how could I come visit you?
You have been loyal to me from the beginning.
But to see you like this,
I feel so sorry.
No need to rush.
I will find a way to save you.
Better not to. Master is pregnant now.
Please don't bother.
What if something happens to the baby?
Actually, servant knew,
once all this started,
I would have to face a bad ending.
The worst is that
the Empress has evidence.
Add to that,
even if Master saves me
your servant
wouldn't know how to face the rumors in the palace.
It's better just to leave me here.
Jin-Xi.
Master.
It'll be hard for us to go back.
Master must think ahead.
i won't be disappointed if Master leaves me.
You must take care of yourself.
And give birth to your baby.
I'd really be glad with that.
It's easy to die.
Hang yourself and end it all?
But what those around you? Would they be happy and glad?
It's a loss.
Trust me in this relationship.
I'm going to save you.
This place...
Master, please don't come to this place again.
Servant will take care of herself.
Do you know where Su Pei-Seng is?
Must be something similar,
being punished somewhere.
He's facing all this because of me.
If not for me,
he'd be enjoying his life as Head Eunuch.
Actually, I've never really thought of others...
About Su Pei-Seng...
Both of us,
just used each other, and relied on each other,
to gain a better life.
But that day at the Ministry of Justice,
even as they beat him, he never mentioned my name.
I was really touched by his actions.
A true relationship is built in difficulty,
It is very precious.
When I saw Master and him.
The two of you
looked like perfect match.
Now that I've experienced it,
I understand its meaning.
Don't worry.
I'll take care of Su Pei-Seng.
So, you take care of yourself.
Don't worry about me.
Consort Xi is here.
Sister.
Little Sister.
Sister is reading poetry?
I'm afraid I'm interrupting you.
There's a big problem at your palace.
I rushed over to see you.
Never thought you wouldn't listen.
Tell me everything. Have a seat.
I...
I really want to save Jin-Xi and Su Pei-Seng.
It's to help His Majesty as well.
Su Pei-Seng served His Majesty for so long.
He understands His Majesty very well.
His sudden capture,
has affected His Majesty's reputation.
In addition to that, no one serves His Majesty
as well as he does.
Little Sister is right.
Honored Lady Qi, please stop there.
Empress has arrived.
Greetings, Empress.
Arise.
Thank you, Empress.
Empress, finally you've come.
This place truly is worse than the Palace of Gathered Elegance.
I don't know when I'll be able to leave.
Has His Majesty forgotten all about me?
Do you really want to get out of here?
Empress, please save me.
It's almost Mid-Autumn Festival.
I'll advise His Majesty to allow you to leave this place then.
You should know what to do to thank me.
I will do my best.
His Majesty has arrived.
His Majesty has come.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Arise, arise.
You look well today.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
You have a weak disposition. Be sure to take care of yourself.
Mencius' teaching is deep and meaningful.
I like it very much.
Indeed, you seem to like it very much.
What do you gain from it?
Reading Mencius,
you realize the limited thinking of Zhu-Xi.
Zhu-Xi called himself a teacher,
and the people call his philosophy an authority.
but in actuality, he misunderstood Kong-Zi and Mencius' teaching.
Why do you say that?
Mencius said, a man and woman living together is a normal way of life.
But Zhu Xi said, we must kill personal desires to maintain justice.
That's not really realistic.
Zhu Xi made a mistake.
But it happens in the palace.
If we follow Zhu Xi's teaching,
how can the consorts
serve Your Majesty and bear children?
So, I think the person who says such things
must be a cold-blooded person.
Contrary?
Did you meet with anyone recently?
Or hear any rumors?
Your Majesty, my weak disposition prevents me from going out a lot.
And even when I do,
I'm sure Your Majesty already knows,
I do not like to involve myself in other people's concerns,
or repeat rumors that I hear.
Yes, that's right.
I think that's your strong point.
That's why I want to ask for your opinion.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Nowadays, everybody in the palace
is talking about Cui Jin-Xi and Su Pei-Seng.
Empress calls for punishment.
Consort Jin remains silent.
Consort Xi is not
What do you think?
There are many beauties in the palace.
But no one can decide who is the most beautiful.
Take a blossom, for example.
Its admirers will say it is suitable anywhere.
while others will just let it fly away.
Everybody is different.
It all depends on the heart.
What happened today,
Empress believes it's about to the rules and discipline of the palace.
But I do not agree.
They did not bring any harm to the palace.
It's just about a maiden and an eunuch
wishing to connect with each other.
Servants come to the palace and work here until they die.
It's sad.
They just wanted to find someone to be with.
I feel heavyhearted thinking about this.
Then what do you think?
Your Majesty, have you ever heard the phrase?
If you don't pretend to be silly or deaf, you won't have a daughter-in-law.
Even in the case of a relationship
If Your Majesty doesn't trust me,
you can check for yourself.
It probably happens in the palace all the time.
Do you really want to kill all of them?
Your Majesty is the Emperor of a kingdom -- the king.
Your burden is heavier than others.
You should show your generosity
to lessen the impact of this case.
Consider Consort Xi and Imperial Concubine Hui.
They shouldn't be exposed to such severe cases.
Right.
The Consorts are pregnant.
I should
All right. You should get some rest now.
I'm going to return to the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
Farewell, Your Majesty.
By the way, Your Majesty.
It's windy lately. Ask the servant
to put chrysanthemum in your tea.
Your lips are chapped.
Okay.