Greetings, Young Mistresses.
This is...?
This is the side door forthe Gate of Obeisance and Chastity.
(Gate north of the Imperial Garden)
Side door?
Consorts are only allowed to enter the Forbidden City through side doors .
The Main Gate is reserved for the Empress.
Mei Jiejie.
Young Mistress, there will be plenty of time to talk later,
the eunuchs will show you to your residences.
It's getting late.
your luggage have already been delivered to your palace
by Internal Affairs Authority.
Please enter the Forbidden City right away.
Which palace has been assigned to Wan Changzai?
Sui Yu Xuan (Palace of Jade Fragments).
Please go Young Mistress, there is nothing for you to worry about.
Wan Changzai, this way please.
An Daying, this way please.
Shen Guiren, please walk this way.
How splendid, no wonder people dream about coming to the Forbidden City.
The wild geese are flying. It's an auspicious sign.
Young Mistress, let's hurry. There is still a long way to go.
Greetings, Young Mistress.
Rise.
Thanks, young mistress.
Guiren, this is your Chang Xi Tang (Hall of Perpetual Luminance).
It's quite regal.
Many thanks, Gonggong
Gonggong, from our Young Mistress, please treat yourself to a cup of tea.
My thanks Guiren, this way please.
Isn't it getting more and more deserted?
It's not deserted, only peaceful.
Yes, our Young Mistress likes peace.
Young Mistress, there is your residence.
-Thank you, Gonggong.
-Excuse us.
Someone like you got selected?!
It's as they say, the road is narrow for enemies.
(Idiom: enemies will clash inevitably)
Although...you're just a Daying aren't you?
An Daying, everything is ready for you.
The House of Respectful Affairs has already delivered your luggage.
Greetings, Xia Jiejie.
Don't call me that, I can't afford to be your "jiejie,"
I'd rather not catch your poor person germs thanks.
Greetings, Xia Changzai.
That's more like it.
Young Mistress, let's step inside.
Young Mistress, we are here.
- It looks like it's been renovated.
- It's pretty.
Indeed.
This was where Fang Guiren lived when His Majesty first became the Emperor.
His Majesty specifically commissioned for it to be renovated.
So Fang Guiren also lives here?
...this way please, Young Mistress.
Wan Changzai arrives!
Your servants welcome Young Mistress. Greetings, young mistress.
All rise.
Please feel free to relax now that you have arrived Young Mistress.
We will take our leave of you.
Thank you Gonggong.
We have cleaned the whole day in preparation for your arrival Changzai,
are things to your expectations?
"Palace （Pavilion) of Jade Fragments," an exquisite name.
If I may,
the East and West Halls are to the sides of the Main Hall,
the bedchamber is in the back,
and behind that is a small garden.
To the south is Yin Lu Xuan (Lodge of Flowing Green),
it's a place to be away from the heat on hot summer days.
The pear flower trees in the back are exquisite during flowering season,
it's where the name Jade Fragments comes from.
Oh, the Crabapple Trees' red blossoms are very festive during bloom
Why there is a stage here?
The consorts customarily enjoy watching operas,
so there are stages almost everywhere.
The stage here was a little too out of the way
so people gradually stopped coming.
Which was why it was eventually converted into a place of residence.
But it's a pleasant place don't you think?
It's indeed a place of tranquility.
Young Mistress, this is a new tribute, a gold osmanthus tree.
The Empress had it specifically prepared for you.
Osmanthus signifies nobility;
the newly planted osmanthus in Sui Yu Xuan
signifies the arrival of someone distinguished,
a cause for celebration all over the Harem.
Yes yes yes.
How kind and thoughtful of Her Highness the Empress.
Please step into the Main Hall now Wan Changzai.
Your servant, Sui Yu Xuan's Leading Eunuch, Kang Luhai,
respectfully at your service, Wan Changzai.
May your every wish come true, and many blessings grace you.
I am your humble servant, Leading Maid, Cui Jinxi.
My respects to Wan Changzai,
May you be blessed.
Rise, both of you.
- Yes
- Thank you Changzai.
I heard that a Fang Guiren also lives here?
I would like to pay my respects to her first.
Young Mistress has not been informed,
Fang Guiren no longer lives at Sui Yu Xuan.
The West Hall is currently vacant.
Chun Changzai (Pure/Genuine) of the East Hall arrived four days ago.
You will have a chance to be introduced soon.
Young Mistress, this is Xiao Yunzi.
These two are Kang Luhai's disciples.
Xiao Hezi and Xiao Yinzi.
These are the maids Pei Er and Ju Qing.
They are all appointed specifically to care for your needs.
Greetings, Wan Changzai.
From now on you will all be mine.
I do value cleverness and aptitude in a servant,
but nothing is more important than loyalty.
Yes. yes. yes
Do you understand?
We dedicate our allegiance to you and only you.
Rewards.
We await for your orders.
Mistress must be tired from such a long day, please rest.
You may all go for now.
Yes. Yes.
Cui GuGu, you must have served in the Palace for quite some time already?
I am undeserving Mistress, please call me by my (humble) name.
Gugu, please be at ease.
I've never been a huge fan of formalities.
We are mistress and servant in name,
but you are my elder, and much more experienced than I,
I have much respect for you.
I am not deserving, Mistress.
I used to serve the Consort Dowager.
The Consort Dowager enjoyed peace and solitude,
so I was moved here instead.
The Consort Dowager's servants must be very steady.
You flatter me.
Then I shall trouble you to manage all household affairs
together with Kang Gonggong.
Please rest assured that I will devote all of my effort to serving you, Young Mistress.
Gugu, please rest now,
Liuzhu and Huanbi can help me change.
Then I will take my leave.
Phew, let's sit!
We've been restraining ourselves the whole day.
The Palace is so full of all sorts of rules, it's enough to scare me witless!
But everything is all so fancy-looking too!
Stop being so enraptured by your surroundings! Don't forget, rules, rules, rules!
You two came with me from outside the Palace,
we all need to be extra cautious with what we say and do,
so that nothing bad befall us.
I know
We'll all be fine as long as Liuzhu keeps her quick tongue in check!
- Shut up!
- Her quick tongue is not necessarily a bad thing,
she knows what should and shouldn't be said.
We were together growing up,
now we are together in this Forbidden City.
Without trustworthy people by your side, life in the Palace is like
the experience of a blind person walking at the edge of a cliff,
with the looming threat of a horrible death overhead.
Our fates are irreversibly entwined now.
I know you treat us as if we were your real sisters,
Huanbi and I will always do our utmost to protect you.
You will protect me,
and I will do my best to protect you.
Rest assured. Young mistress..
NIangniang has been reading all morning
won't you have some mandarin oranges? They are a fresh tribute.
The newly selected concubines will have all settled down by now?
Yes, they should all be resting at their respective palaces by now.
What a rare moment of respite for me,
for Hua Fei to administer to everything by herself.
Even the mention of Hua Fei makes me angry.
These mandarin oranges here...
there were originally some high quality pomelos (grapefruit variant) available,
but Songzhi from Hua Fei's palace took them instead,
all the while saying that since His Majesty will be having supper in their palace,
it's only right that they take the best ingredients.
The same thing happened last time.
They had the first pick for the new tribute silks from Suzhou.
These are only trivialities, why not let her do as she likes?
It's hardly a big deal.
The peony flowers outside are looking a little askew,
tell the gardeners to take care of it,
they will bloom again come spring.
Niangniang!
Niangniang's grace nurtures the whole realm,
do you expect her to squabble with Hua Fei over something like that?
Where did Liuzhu go?
Have you forgotten, Young Mistress?
You asked our kitchen to make some pastries this morning,
and for Liuzhu to deliver them to Shen Guiren and An Daying.
She left not too long ago.
Young Mistress,
Jianqiu Gugu has made a delivery for you by the Empress's orders.
She has also invited you to an audience at the Empress's palace in three day's time,
at the hour of Mao (5:00-7:00AM).
I understand.
Also, the Leading Eunuch from Yi Kun Gong (Palace of Wings), Zhou Gonggong,
is outside, waiting to see you.
Yi Kun Gong?
He comes on Hua Fei Niangniang's behalf.
I'll be right there.
Understood.
Young Mistress, Hua Fei's authority is not less than that of the Empress's,
you must take care to tread delicately.
Ah.
It's been such a long time since your last visit.
Hm.
This way please.
Your humble servant greets you, Wan Changzai.
Thank you for waiting, Zhou Gonggong.
Hua Fei Niangniang has instructed me to deliver some gifts for you.
I appreciate Niangniang's generosity.
Please convey to Niangniang my gratitude for her.
Will Gonggong not have a cup of tea?
Apologies for declining Wan Changzai's kind invitation,
Our Niangniang is very strict with rules,
I still need to deliver the other Young Mistresses' gifts,
so I must not tarry.
I thank you for your trouble, Gonggong.
If Young Mistress does not require anything else,
I shall excuse myself
Congratulations, Young Mistress,
Hua Fei Niangniang believes that you have much potential.
I have no use for these right now,
make a record of the gifts and store them in the warehouse for now.
Yes.
So Shen Guiren has received as many gifts as you, Young Mistress.
Only Fucha Guiren and Xia Changzai have received things in Yan Xi Gong
(Palace of Lasting Fortune) where An Daying lives
Hua Fei Niangniang is most likely bestowing her extravagant gifts
according to the Young Mistresses' family backgrounds,
is she intending to recruit people for her camp?
Your servant, Jianqiu salutes the Young Mistress.
You came all this way personally?
Please do come in!
Empress Niangniang figured
the new Young Mistresses must still be unfamiliar with the forbidden city,
so she sent me to see if you needed anything.
She also ask me to bring some tributary cloths from Jiangnan's Textile Manufactures
for you, Xia Changzai.
The Empress flatters me by sending Gugu personally.
I am so honored.
You are very welcome, I will excuse myself then.
Please take care! Gugu.
Here will be fine, Young Mistress.
You shouldn't blame people for passing you over,
since it is your own origin that is humble.
So few rewards? How very pitiful!
However extravagant Hua Fei Niangniang's gifts are,
they can't compare with the Empress Niangniang's!
Tell them to hurry and make a dress with the cloths from the Empress,
I will wear it to the first official audience with the Empress as a symbol of my gratitude for Niangniang.
Yes Mistress.
Young Mistress, don't take her words to heart.
I am insignificant.
Xia Changzai only spoke the truth.
Don't lose hope, Young Mistress.
A hero is a hero, regardless of how humble his origins.
Young Mistress. Chun Changzai is here.
Show her in quick!
(Cap: Chun Changzai)
Wan Jiejie has been busy the whole day,
I hope I didn't catch you at a bad time?
Not at all.
I was planning to visit MeiMei,
but MeiMei beat me to it.
Have a seat.
Tea. Huanbi
Yes.
Today we are serving Puer tea,
I hope you are ok with it?
- Here.
- You have so many delicious pastries!
I didn't eat enough at dinner,
why don't we put the tea aside
until I have my fill of the sweets,
the tea can neutralize the flavor?
Go ahead.
- Liuzhu, bring more pastries.
- ok!
It tastes so good.
Meimei seems rather young still?
No. I am already fourteen!
I don't think Meimei likes Puer tea,
Huanbi, bring a cup of milk tea instead.
Yes
Thank you, Jiejie. I love everything sweet!
Take it slowly. Don't choke.
Please call me Chuner,
My parents both call me Chuner.
- Ok
Why didn't you eat enough at dinner?
I was missing my parents,
The Royal Kitchen served marinated goose for dinner tonight,
it made me think of my mother's marinated goose, the best in the world!
...I lost my appetite after that.
From now on if you don't eat enough for dinner,
You can always come to Jiejie's place for pastries.
Is that okay?
Wan Jiejie, you are so good to me!
I heard His Majesty likes Jiejie a lot.
I saw how many servants were here this afternoon delivering gifts
and knew that it must be true!
I just received some fresh flowers.
They are pretty.
If you like them,
you can take a few home to decorate your hair.
No thanks you...
I think I like the pastries more.
Eat up if you like them!
Huanbi. Pack some pastries up
so Chun Changzai can bring them back with her.
Thank you! Jie Jie.
Jiangnan's lotus flowers are ripe for the picking.
(based on traditional, lotus picking poetry from the Han dynasty)
The Royal Garden is as beautiful as expected.
Every detail is exquisite.
Commoners are indeed common,
can't even be quiet when embroidering.
(suggesting that singing is an art used for seduction, indecency)
During the first three days
we are not allowed to serve His Majesty at night,
but just imagine when we will be allowed,
she'll be jumping into His Majesty's bed.
I was humming subconciously
If Changzai does not like it, I will stop.
Stop acting like a victim,
who are you trying to show?
I am not.
You haven't had the chance to meet His Majesty yet,
but take care when you do,
I won't let you off easy if you use the coquette act to tempt His majesty!
She is always like that
Who does she think she is.
Young Mistress, don't get upset over what she says.
Forget about it. If she is here, then I will go elsewhere.
Accompany me to see two Jiejies.
-Yes.
It smells really good.
Doesn't it?
Let me pick another.
Here you are. Quick, come inside.
Why didn't you announce Young Mistress An's arrival?
keeping her standing there in the sun.
If she gets sunburns or a heatstroke you'd better watch your hide!
Don't blame him, Jiejie.
I asked him to not announce me.
I meant to give you a surprise,
but instead I've irritated you.
It's all Lingrong's fault.
Your intentions were good,
what fault could u have?
It's all your fault for scaring An Meimei.
Hurry up, show her in
and serve her a cup of tea to ask for her forgiveness.
Exactly. Come on in!
I went to Xian Fu Gong to see Mei Jiejie just now,
in the hopes that we could come visit Zhen Jiejie together,
but Jiejie beat me here first.
I ended up being one step behind after all.
You are not late at all,
We can all chat for a while.
The mistress of the palace I live in now, Jin (Respect) Pin Niangniang,
is tremendously easy to get along with.
How about you?
I'm...fine, more or less.
Fucha Guiren does not seem the sort who likes looking for trouble,
but Xia Changzai...
I'll just ignore her.
I will only talk to Jiejies.
Then Young Mistress An, please visit here more often.
I know Young mistress does not like Liuan Tea,
So I switched your tea to XIang Pian tea.
I have troubled Huanbi to remember the little details about me
from the time that I stayed at your manor.
The two Young Mistresses are like family to my Young Mistress,
it's only right that I pay attention to your preferences.
I thought LIuzhu was the quick one,
turns out Huanbi has an even sweeter mouth
and an even better eye for detail.
Huanbi has served me for a long time
she naturally remembers many details.
Of course. Those who have been with us since youth are naturally better,
I also brought Caiyue and Caixing with me.
Speaking of which, you didn't bring any servants with you into the Palace.
Are the palace servants appointed to you to your liking?
Baojuan is smart, she is quite reliable.
The other two are still young, not more older than fifteen years of age.
I don't expect them to do too much.
But it's alright, I have never been one for too much trouble,
so there is nothing to worry about.
Jinxi!
- Here.
- Go inform Empress Niangniang.
I would like to have Juqing moved to Yan Xi Gong to serve Young Mistress An.
Yes, I understand.
Juqing may be young, but she is quite reliable.
Take her with you when you leave.
If you need anything else,
don't hesitate to let me or Mei Jiejie know.
Thanks you very much. Jie jie
I received some new silk today,
I think they will suit you.
I will ask Caiyue to deliver them to Yan Xi Gong.
The two of you are so kind to me,
I can never repay my debt to you.
I am endless grateful for everything you have done for me.
The three of us came together to the Palace,
we are most acquainted with each other out of everyone here,
we should look out for each other, no thanks needed.
Today is Young Mistress's first official audience with the Empress,
you should dress up so that you can stand out.
Fetch some warm water for me outside,
Huanbi can help me here.
Understood.
Do an ordinary bun.
Yes
Niangniang, it's time to go to Jing Ren Gong (Palace of Benelovent Hope).
It won't do to be late today...
No hurry.
Niangniang is always so original,
this hairstyle is especially pleasing to the eye,
artful but natural.
Let's go
Meimei, you are all so early today.
Have you adapted to life in the Palace?
Thanks to your care and concern,
we are doing well.
I'm not late, am I?
Greetings, Hua Fei Niangniang
Greetings, Empress.
- Please rise, Meimei
Hua Fei meimei came so late,
are you feeling unwell?
His Majesty was going over the official reports til late last night,
so I stayed up also to keep him company.
Then this morning His Majesty refused to let me rise early.
So I came late.
I hope Empress Niangniang is not mad?
His Majesty has been busy with state affairs lately
so He may have neglected you for a while.
Naturally He would want to make it up to you.
Today we are meeting the new Meimei,
from now on, we will have new companions.
Who does Hua Fei think she is showing off to?
The Young Mistresses will perform the formal salutation to Empress Niangniang.
(Cap: Jiang Fu Hai)
(Consisting of three kneels and nine kowtow.)
(For the women the handkerchief over shoulder movement
represents the kowtow.)
Blessings, Empress niangniang.
All rise.
Thank you. Empress Niangniang.
Meet the other consorts as well.
Duan （Regularity/Modesty) Fei is unwell,
Young Mistresses will not be seeing her today.
Duan Fei has been unwell for a very long time,
Do visit her on my behalf, Jianqiu, when the ceremony is over.
Yes. Niangniang
All Mistresses salute Hua Fei Niangniang.
Blessings, Hua Fei Niangniang.
The jadeite that the Internal Affairs Authority sent me this year is not as pure,
not at all clear and transparent.
Quality jadeite is getting harder to come by nowadays.
Meimei is still young, jadeite's color is too dark at your age,
so the Internal Affairs Authority selected some lighter colored ones for you.
But then again, if you don't have high quality jadeite Meimei,
how can anyone else have anything better?
I suppose so, I do feel that jadeite is a little too old for me.
I don't deserve to wear them yet,
If Niangniang likes them,
I can give Niangniang the pair of earrings I'm wearing right now.
I recently received a pair of eastern pearls and
have just asked the craftsmen to make a pair of earrings with them.
It would be too wasteful if I accept your pair as well.
His Majesty would disapprove if he hears of it.
Empress Niangniang is truly frugal.
Why don't we let the Meimei rise first?
Oh no, I was so absorbed talking to Empress Niangniang.
I almost forgot you were all still kneeling.
Rise
Thank you Hua Fei Niangniang.
I heard there was a very talented Xia Changzai.
Blessings, Hua Fei Niangniang.
I am the Changzai of the family name Xia.
Xia Changzai sure is well attired,
that material you are wearing looks expensive?
This was a gift from Empress Niangniang.
I picked it specifically for today's occasion.
You understand the concept of gratitude,
not bad.
Rise
Thank you, Hua Fei Niangniang.
And which of you is Shen Guiren and Wan Changzai?
I am Guiren Shen Meizhuang from Xian Fu Gong (Palace of Whole Blessings).
My respectful regards for Hua Fei Niangniang.
I am Changzai Zhen Huan from Sui Yu Xuan (Pavilion of Jade Fragments),
my respectful regards for Hua Fei Niangniang.
How elegant you are, Shen Guiren.
And Wan Changzai, your beauty is still visible, though you are dressed plainly.
His Majesty truly has good taste.
Everyone of you is outstanding.
Alright, rise.
Thank you, Hua Fei Niangniang.
Niangniang's beauty is the true beauty of an empire,
you are the truly eye-catching one.
We are but like dim fireflies in the glowing light of your pearl-like beauty,
we would not dare to compete.
Shen Meimei has a very sweet mouth.
Although...the beauty of an empire...
isn't that a phrase for describing the Empress Niangniang?
Empress Niangniang's brilliant grace nurtures the land,
like the bright moon overhead.
Hua Fei Niangniang's glorious beauty overwhelms
like a pearl shining.
We are but dust compared to you.
More and more clever tongues are joining the Harem.
Naturally, all of the Meimei are smart and capable.
From now on, we will all live together in the Harem.
Your first duty is to serve His Majesty wholeheartedly,
and add children to the Imperial Family.
Then of course, you must live harmoniously with each other,
and never be tempted into jealousy,
for it would trouble His Majesty.
Understood.
Jiang Fuhai, what did the Empress Dowager say?
Empress Dowager Niangniang said it's a joyful thing
to have the new Young Mistresses.
And that she is conscious of your kind intentions,
but as she is preoccupied with meditating on the Buddha's teachings,
it will not be necessary for Niangniang and the Young Mistresses
to pay their formal respects at Shou Kang Gong.
I see.
You all must be tired, you may take your leave now.
Yes. Excuse us.
Jiejies, you have such smooth tongues!
Fawning over Hua Fei after flattering the Empress,
such a splendid performance!
Quite admirable. Bravo!
Greetings, Xia Changzai.
Jiejie, your servants have their hands full with your rewards,
do you even have enough room in your palaces for them?
We are all sisters,
we all share equally in the Imperial blessings.
I was just thinking of selecting some choice pieces
to deliver to each of you after I return to my residence.
But since you are already here,
please, pick something you like.
Please pick something Xia Changzai.
There's no shortage of these toys in my family,
But Shen Guiren sure seems an expert at purchasing favors with small gifts like these.
How did someone like HER get into the Harem?
What an insipid girl.
The Xia family are lower than the servants at Nian manor.
I heard that she has been pestering Fucha Guiren everyday
in their own palace these past few days,
and bullying An Daying at every chance besides.
There is absolutely no peace to be had there because of her.
Look at her dress.
She thinks that she can strut around like she owns the place
just because she has the Empress's support?
I heard Xia jiejie comes from a family of warriors,
I admire you very much.
My family has served in the military generation after generation,
Loyal to the country
How can a county magistrate even hope to compare with us?
What happened on the day of the audition was purely an accident,
I had no intention of offending you.
I have not stopped thinking about it ever since,
I regret my mistake endlessly.
It's just... since you come from a military family,
You must excel in both mental and physical strength.
As expected Jiejie, you are fearless and bold,
you truly live up to your family's name.
I'm only a product of my family's good principles.
Such stupidity actually exists in the world.
And she is a Changzai (lingering)...
I guess she's the lingering laughing stock.
Yes
She is a concubine just as you are!
You can't hit her!
Let me go!
Greetings, Hua Fei Niangniang.
Hua Fei Niangniang...
- Zhou Ninghai Let her go.
- Yes
The Royal Garden during fall is as beautiful as a painting,
but such splendid scenery is ruined by imbeciles.
How disappointing
An Daying insulted me,
I only wanted to teach her a lesson.
A lesson...
Are the Empress and I no longer present in the Harem?
I hadn't heard that the Harem is now Xia Changza's possession...
or that we must trouble you to teach other concubine "lessons"...
I fear that you can't shoulder such a difficult burden...
The maples this year do not quite look red enough.
I have heard that maple dyed in blood is an exquisite shade of red.
Is that so?
Then reward Xia Changzai with "A Zhang of Redness"
(Zhang is a measure of length, =3.33 meters)
Let her blood add some hue to the maples
A Zhang of Redness?
Replying to your question, young mistress
A Zhang of Redness is a kind of punishment in the Harem.
The subject is beaten with a wooden board that is
2 cun thick and 6 chi long, (Cun=3.33cm Chi=33.3cm)
below the waist, until bone and tendon are broken
and the flesh severely mutilated.
It will look like a patch of pure red from a distance,
a dazzling sight.
That is why it's called A Zhang of Redness.
Young Mistress. This way please.
Hua Fei Niangniang, please have mercy!
Hua Fei Niangniang I will never do it again!
Please forgive me!
Young Mistress, it would be a huge honor if your blood really
color the maples as the rumors say!
Hua Fei Niangniang, have mercy!
Guards, take her to the Shen Xing Si (Bureau of Caution and Punishment).
Please forgive me,
Hua Fei Niangniang...Hua Fei Niangniang!
Please forgive me, Hua Fei Niangniang!
Xia disrespected her superiors and caused disorder in the Harem.
Meimeis must be startled.
Although it is said...punish by example, not by number,
but the whole affair still originated with the three of you.
Xia dug her own grave,
but you three are not the guileless type either.
Reflect on your own actions in solitude.
I almost died of fright!
Xia was stupid and arrogant,
but that sentence was too much!
I'd always heard that Hua Fei was harsh,
but I never imagined her to be this perverse.
Hua Fei told us to go and reflect...
This...
It's only reflecting, don't be afraid.
Jiejie, let's return to our palaces. I'm scared!
Let's go back.
What's going on?
What happened?
There's a... a...
Calm down, speak properly! Don't go around frightening people!
Yes
Young Mistress, I am with the Office in charge of maintaining the Royal Garden.
I came to check if the wells in the garden all had water, as according to my duty,
But as soon as I got here...
I never thought...!
In the well...there was...!
I will check it out.
No, don't go! There might be something inauspicious.
Relax. I will come right back.
What's wrong? What's wrong?!
Don't go there. There is a dead person.
What...?
Replying to your inquiry, the dead girl is Fuzi
She was found in a well.
Fuzi?
How did she end up in a well for no reason?
I do not know.
It was a remote place, people seldom passed by.
Of course you wouldn't know,
Fuzi was the servant I appointed to serve Hua Fei.
You may rise.
Then I will make some inquiries at Hua Fei's palace.
I have one more thing to report,
Speak.
Hua Fei Niangniang has punished Xia Changzai...
with A Zhang of Redness.
Xia habitually overstepped her bounds, leave her be.
But Fuzi was pitifully innocent...
she died for nothing.
She was still a child.
I didn't find her on Long Street either!
Alright, go go go.
Young Mistress, where did you go off to?
We couldn't find you anywhere!
Why do you look so pale?
Sit down, sit down!
Young Mistress, Jiang Fuhai was just here to deliver the Empress's indictment;
starting tomorrow,
the new mistresses are to get ready to serve His Majesty.
Congratulations, Young mistress,
Our Young Mistress will surely be His Majesty's favorite.
Young Mistress won't necessarily be called on to serve tomorrow,
but you should still start preparing for when the time comes.
Young Mistress, you haven't eaten anything yet, have you?
You must be hungry. Hurry, tell them to bring in the meal.
No...that won't be necessary.
I have no appetite.
Then bring the meal later. We will help her in first.
Niangniang, Jiang Fuhai is here.
He said he has some questions for you from the Empress.
Let him in.
Yes.
Greetings, Niangniang.
You may rise.
It's good that you're here,
I have something to ask you.
Yes
What's that Fuzi's background?
I can't even scold her?
She is nothing more than a servant, she has no background.
Niangniang you are joking with me.
A joke you say?
All right, then I will tell you a joke.
Did Fuzi make it her mission to antagonize me,
thinking that she had the Empress's support?
Fuzi is newly selected by Internal Affairs Authority
Empress Niangniang had only had her for a few days
before she came to serve you Niangniang.
There is no talk of her having the Empress's support.
The other day her clumsiness hurt me while she was brushing my hair.
I only scolded her a little bit
before she ran out in a noisy, crying flurry.
She hasn't returned even now!
I thought
that's how the Empress disciplines her servants...
Niang niang. Fuzi is dead.
Dead?
Thank you for watching!
Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team