Episode 50
You told me before,  you've gave up on relationship between men and women
You also said,  you will forget everyone who are related to the palace
but what's with Duke Guo?  How are you going to explain this?
yes
I admit I said these before
you promised and why it doesn't count anymore?
It's hard to predict changes in this world  you can't take 'once' as 'forever'
just like how my family once prospered  and just like how I was once naive ZhenHuan
but those are in the past  regardless of whether I don't want it to pass or not
but it still becomes history
I don't want to hear you saying these  just tell me..
what happened between you and Duke Guo?
I like him , and he likes me too
just like this
ok..
only now you tell me the truth
but why must it be him?
you want to know why?
because I have already gave up on relationship
because I'm despaired towards my life
its Yun Li
He started to give me hope
He gave me reason to move on
but if you choose to be with him
you might have to suffer a lot in the future
I have to suffer
so does him
Since I'm willing to follow him
it means I have thought about what I might encounter
Those hardship and unjust that you were afraid of me enduring..
are all out of my will
Willingly?  What determination
but my devotion to you are also out of my will too
That's not the same
I'm grateful for your kindness
but he and I are attracted to each other
Even if choosing Yun Li might be a mistake
I rather be wrong till the end
with no regret
frankly speaking
Do you think your will to be with me is more important?
or my sincere happiness is more important?
To be honest
all the while
I have been hoping to be with you officially
but I knew it even in my dreams that
you don't like me at all
You will never be happy sincerely if you were to be with me
so
you sincere happiness is more important
Thank you, Brother Shi Chu
for treating me nicely
he gets to have your will
you'll never know how envious I am
In the future you'll get to meet a girl who is sincere to you
Its obvious that Dr Wen really likes you
Master, Dr Wen is here
Please come in
You're here
you knew that I don't care about those status addressing
faster get up
Thank you master
What happened? You're getting thinner
Nothing much
What really happened?
Did something happened to Huan er?
Huan er is ok
it's just that she doesn't need me anymore
Huan er knows what she wants
but do you understand what you need most?
Its because I truly understand
that I know that I could never get it
since you can't get it
then you don't have to be sad for no reason
its easy to say
but its hard to do that
You're a man
why are you so long-winded?
if you like her it doesn't matter whether she likes you or not
you just need to be yourself
if you don't like her anymore
just let it go calmly!
why do you have to make yourself so difficult and sallow?
you're asking for it for no reason!
I never know that the dignified and discreet Hui Bin Niangniang spoke
so intensely
That's not intense
it's just that advising others and advising ourselves..
are the same kind of sayings
Looking at this water
I will think of when I met you accidentally  in YuanMing Palace
I never thought that there'll be today
yes
You were really daring that day
you dare to go to visit sisters who were grounded
Don't know how is Mei Jiejie now
She is very good, just got promoted as Hui Bin
other than visiting Longyue
she still doesn't like to social
Based on her temperament
she'll rather grow old lonely in the palace
than begging for sympathy from the King
It's just that she is still young and beautiful
yet have to live a depressed life forever
that's too pitiful
You think that she's pitful
With the Great Empress's protection
despite her being disgraced by the King
no one will ever harm her
just like my LongYue
she's not as striking as the crown prince
I just hope that my LongYue could be safe
The King and the Great Empress both love her very much
not to mention that LongYue herself is very likable
you don't have to worry
Everyone has their own good
all you need now is just
to love yourself nicely
Yes
We have to love ourselves nicely
For you, and for those who worried me
It is becoming an antique
you're still bringing it with you
Even though it is an antique
but if I don't have it all these years
I'll never feel so calm
Sometimes I thought
that all I could leave behind in my life
will only be this small drawings
Actually when I was in the palace  I have already see you as my best friend
just that I'm afraid of my heart
So are you still afraid now?
As long as you're around
I'm not afraid of anything
Your majesty,
people from the House of Affairs has arrived
Your majesty, its time to pick the namecard
go to YanXi Palace
Your majesty, other than reading reports these few days
you have been going to AnPing Niangniang's place only  Today... should you change to other mistress's place?
You're becoming more daring
I'm sorry!
I'm just saying it
or Your Majesty, do you want to go to ShouKang Palace to visit the Great Empress?
You have been busy at work recently  its been long since you last visited her
I will go tomorrow!
Prepare to go to YanXi Palace
Roger
The Great Empress is ill
yet Your Majesty always come to my place
I'm going to be scolded dead soon
What they scolded you for? Tell me
Deceptive Vixen
Roots of troubles
From my perspective
those are words of praise
Your majesty doesn't feel sorry for me
How that I'm not feeling sorry for you?
If Your majesty truly feel sorry for me,
just tell me one truth
what?
These days when the Great Empress is ill
why Your Majesty doesn't go to visit her?
Is it really because of me?
If so, my sins deserve me to be dead
The reason for the Great Empress's illness ..
is of her own acknowledgement
Your majesty, don't be angry
Look at you after all these days, busying approving projects in YangXin Palace
your face is getting greenish!
You must take care of your health
I know it myself
This morning, LongYue came to greet me
I kinda heard that today is some important day
Today is April 17
its not really an important day
Indeed, its not an important day
I kinda remember its someone's birthday
Your Majesty, let me treat you to your sleep
Come, Yue er
Eat it
You're really obedient
Meimei, whats with you?
Why must you ask me to bring LongYue over?without any reasons
JingFei Jiejie, today is Huan Er's birthday
HuiPing, this shouldn't be said
I know the King had ruled that nobody should talk about HuanEr
no mention about LongYue's birth mother
but Huan Er is still LongYue's birth mother
Can't I ask Jiejie to bring LongYue over for me to show my sincerity?
I know you're still missing WanPing
but I'm missing her too
I knew it early
The King looks like he had let go of WanPin
but he still misses her in her heart
you see, ever since WanPin left the palace
Other than AnPin and QiPin's place,
he never visited our palace at all
I don't care whether the King visted our place or not
I'm only missing HuanEr,  don't know if she's living well outside
Ever since last winter, the Great Empress have been sick often
Even Aunt FangRu doesn't have time to go out
Nothing bad will happened for sure
WanPin is blessed  no one will bully her again
No worries
Your majesty
Your Majesty! What happened to you?
Your Majesty!
Eunuch Su! Eunuch Su!
Brat! Something's wrong!
Your Majesty! Your Majesty! What happened to you?
Your Majesty! Your Majesty
What's wrong? What's wrong to the King?
Faster!
The King gets fever suddenly
Faster go and call for the doctor!
Your Majesty!
Faster go!!
Yes! Yes! Doctor!
Summon the doctor! Fast!
BaoQue
Faster pour away the herbs inside
The thing inside shouldn't been seen by anyone!
Remember! Don't let anyone know!
If the content of this incense burner were known
You and I will be dead!
Faster go!
Have the King been moved to YangXin Palace?
Yes
We have already arranged for the Mistresses and the Dukes to take turn attend upon
Don't allow too many mistresses to stand by
especially those who are seductive
Just let the Queen, Qi-Fei, Jing-Fei
and Hui-Pin, that's all
Yes
What did the doctor said after treating the King?
The Doctor said
The King's pulse condition is weak, he's been overworked too much
Where have the King been recently?
Other than meeting the ministers he have been approving reports only
but don't know why, he's been unhappy these few days
Who have been serving his sleep?
Its usually An-Pin Niangniang, or Qi-Pin
but the days he got served during sleep weren't much
If your Majesty doesn't believe, you could check for the record by House of Affairs
This happened in YanXi Palace, there must be something to do with An-Pin
But why is His Majesty unhappy recently?
Especially these few days
What was yesterday's date?
Yesterday was April 17
Is there anything wrong?
Yesterday was the abandoned imperial concubine - Wan-Pin's birthday
Then, it's not An-Pin's fault
I thought he has already let that go
So that's how it is
Su Pei Sheng!
Yes
Go tell An-Pin, to feel relief
and accompany me to visit the King
Your Majesty, you should rest
You don't feel good recently too
If the King knows this after he wakes up
He'll blame us for not serving you well
You fool
Am I more important than the King?
ZhuXi, please help me up
Yes
Miss
Ah Jin just came.
there's a news from the palace, saying that the King is not feeling well
they've called the Lord to go to the palace quickly
I heard that its really serious
Did they said what sickness was that?
This.. I don't really know toojust heard from the King's close servant that..
seems like the King got fever when he stayed overnight in An-Pin's place
after all, the palace is keeping it secretive
The King is very attentive
its hard to avoid being overly worried and become sick now
This time when the Lord left for the palace, will he gets to stay in NingHui Hall?
Yes
The Lord gets called by the Great Empress to go to the palace along with Duke Heng and Knight Shen
It seems that the King is seriously ill this time
So he can't leave the palace these few days?
The Lord has to serve upon the King in the palace so he can't come outbut I'm ok
The Lord knows that he can't visit you these few days
So he requested me to send this to you
when madam you have a free time, please reply to him on this
I will come here everyday
to deliver what madam writes for the Lord
~The poem~Trying the new shirt on the mountain
The cozy weather is making me Iazy
The birds are singing on the tree, I am not abIe to come back
He can't Ieave the paIace as hehas to take care of His Majesty
Yet he says that he doesn't want to comeBecause of the birds
He's the only one who wrote in such elegant yet wild way
~Second poem~
My beIoved is Ieaving
But I am not dare to make a confession
I can just turn back
And waIk away
Send this to the Lord  tell him not to reply everyday
first its going to be really obvious,  secondly, he'll be pretty tired serving upon in the palace
Madam you're very thoughtful  I'll definitely keep this tight
The Lord can't leave the palace these few days  so these are his babies
The Lord definitely reads it day and night  and miss you so much
The Great Empress has arrived
Greeting, Empress dowager
just stand up
Has the King woke up yet?
Not yetThe imperiaI doctor said thatHis Majesty is having fever
It needs some times forhim to come to his sense
These days
His Majesty was beingToo fickIe
I know that he is sad
And know that he is aII heart
But he spoiIed his body
Take good care of himSend someone to report to me
Just Iet His Majesty to restDon't disturb him
Yes
We wiII handIe the domestic affair
Don't worry
Then I wiII go back first
Do keep him company
Yes
Huan-Huan
What
Brother is missing Zhen Huan
Is she the one
Whom brother can't Iet go in these years
He is a man of aII heart
This shouId appear in royaI
His Majesty can't hoIda candIe to you in this
Miss
Fourth poem
The sound of the weaving machine is Ioud
I can't heIp
Missing you
I miss you so badIy
Fifth poem
Nobody understands
What I am trying to teII
I don't want to taIkabout my current situation
What I am doing is using this poemto teII you how badIy I miss you
Drink some ginseng tea
I don't want to drink
AIthough you are worrying about His Majesty. But you have to take care of yourseIf
How am I going to be at easeBy seeing that His Majestyhasn't come to his sense
You have the chance to see His Majesty
Me and consort AnHave no the chance at aII
We can just worry about him
We are useIess
We can onIy care about your heaIth. You have to do So many things at once
Yet we don't know when wiIIHis Majesty come to his sense
Look at you You Iook paIe
You might faII sick too
If you don't take care of your body
Just drink some ginseng tea
Anyway, His Majesty feII sick inHaII of ProIonged Happiness
Consort An must be invoIved
LuckiIy the empress dowagerdidn't bIame it on meOr I wiII be in troubIe
It is my fauItThat I didn't serve His Majesty niceIy
Why wouId His Majesty go to youIf you don't know to serve him niceIy
His Majesty seIdom Iooked for the consorts
Just Iike consort Qi
She hasn't been seeing His Majesty aIoneYou have to appreciate it
Thank you
Stand up
Yes
The Empress Dowager doesn'taIIow you to go there now
You might go to pray for His Majesty in the tempIe
Yes
The empress was born inoId and weII-known famiIy
Therefore she Iikes the womenfrom the same type of famiIy
PeopIe Iike you who have bad originIs Iucky enough
To be aIIowed to serve her
You shouId appreciate itDo you stiII want to fight with me
Yes
Set off
You haven't been having rest
Why don't you take a nap first
No
I haven't beenSeeing His Majesty
For so Iong time
Your Majesty
You are awake
Get some water for His Majesty
A mountain wiII be weII known when there is immortaI Iiving on it
A river wiII be weII known wherethere is dragon Iiving in it
This is a crude house
But
the resident is having good behaviour Hong-Shi
Mother
Hong-Shi
Mother YouWhy are you here
His Majesty has justrecovered from the fever
He is stiII in coma
Then Why didn't you go to serve himI come to visit youWhen the empress went to find him
Hong-Shi Mother hasn't beenTaIking with you for two months
MotherI miss you too
Hong-Shi
Don't be too hardworking
You Iook Thinner now
Mother wants me to study everyday
Then onIy father wiII Iike me
The empress is not your bioIogicaI mother
She won't Iove you whoIeheartedIy
You are the onIy
Son in the paIace
You have to be the ruIer when you grow up
How couId your father not Ioving you
Hong-Shi
Good boy
Be carefuI
Take care of yourseIf
I wiII be sad if you faII sick
Mother
I have begged the empress for many times
But
she didn't aIIowed me to visit youAs I have many homework
Mother
I even went to the entrance ofPaIace of EternaI Spring to find you
But I saw nobody
The empress aIways didn't
AIIow me to visit you too
She didn't want me to disturb you
She didn't even aIIow me
To send you a shirt
And
food
I reaIIy regret it
Mother
What did you regret
It's my fauIt
That I can't breed you
You are my hope
I won't have
To Iive in fears anymore
When you become the ruIer
I want to fight for mother
I wiII honor you as the empress dowagerAnd make up to you
Good boy
Did consort Qi reaIIyteII third prince Iike this
I heard it It's reaI
You treated third prince
So niceIy
But he is not your own son
I feIt hurt to hear it
Third prince has grown up
He is the same Iike other chiIdren
But fourth prince is shy
Fifth prince is weak
They are sunIess
It's fine that thirdprince is not mature enough
Consort Qi is more muddIeheaded
But third prince stiII obeys your order
He has become more hardworking
But you reaIIy
Wasted your effort to protect consort Qi
Consort Qi doesn't know
To repay me
No matter how I
Teach him
It is a bad thing for third
prince to have such mother
Even she wants to be the empress dowager.
Who does she think she is
She can be
She is the mother of third prince
After third prince's accession
She wiII Surpass meAnd become the empress dowager
Look at consort QiShe can't wait to teachthese to third prince
Those are her true feeIing
Why can't she teach him
I thought that
She wiII be contented
To be a consort
I reaIIy underestimated her
Lady
We can't have two tigers on a mountain
She is not a tiger
But a cat
Just a weak cat
Lord
Lan-Yi
Why are you entering the paIace
I am Ieaving
Why
His Majesty has justrecovered from the fever
The empress dowager said tha tWe don't have to perform in this year. Therefore we are going back first
His Majesty
has just recovered
He must be amazed to see you
The empress dowager is reaIIydoing that for His Majesty's good
Lord,
Since when you became so gIib
I am not gIib
You Iook good
In this attire
You haven't been coming to Summer PaIace
I wiII go visit you
when I am free
Bear it in your mind
Sure
Let's go
I am
So exhausted
Your Majesty
You have just recovered from the sickness
Take care of your heaIth
Where shouId I go to have a waIk
Do you want to go to find consort Hui
She did the most thing to take care of you
When you feII sick
Consort Hui is good
But I am weary of Iooking at her
It's because you aIways met Very pretty women in the past
Therefore you are weary of seeing her
You are so mean
You saw the main point
Say something aboout consort An
She isn't educated
But she can comfort you
by singing
AIthough consort Qi
is gentIe too
But you feeI as if
there are something Iess
The baIanced consort is consort Wan
Don't mention about her
Why don't you go to
Consort An
or consort Qi
Forget it
I wiII go to Summer PaIace
Yes
Seventh poem
We are afraid of being together
As we don't want to be apart
How are we going
To be together again
If we are forced to part
Why did you write so pessimistic poem
I haven't been seeing for days
I was afraid
Don't mention this again
No matter what
I kept Iooking at the stars
And missing you
But it is too bad that
You can't aIways see me Iike this
Su Pei-Sheng
Why do I feeI
So weary of the women in the paIace
I can't find anything speciaI
By Iooking at anyone of them
Your Majesty I have no idea
Why don't we choose new girIs
It is useIess
They onIy knowTo fIatter me
They are aII the same
But I think they are different
They have their own speciaIity
Here reaIIy has a variety of horses
What nonsense are you uttering
What is this pIace
Your Majesty It's Hundred-Horse Park here
Here trains the horse that are imported from other pIaces
Go and take a Iook
His Majesty is here
Greeting, Your Majesty
Eunuch Duan
Eunuch Su
Who is the girI on the horse
She
She is the horse trainer Ye Lan-Yi
Horse trainer
You are Iucky
What did you seeOr why did you hear
It seems IikeYou are not happy
Huan-Huan
My brother caIIed your name
When he was in coma
I stayed in the paIace for days
AIthough I just heard him caIIing you for once
But stiII, I am afraid
Huan-Huan
I am afraid
that I might Iose you
Then the person that His Majesty caIIedIs empress Chun-Yuan,
Huan-Huan, am I right
Yes
He aIways stayed aIoneAnd saw the remnant ofEmpress Chun-Yuan
He is thinking ofEmpress Chun-Yuan when he cIear
He caIIed me in his dream
As I Iook aIike empress Chun-Yuan
Sometimes he thinks of
Me when he is
Thinking of empress Chun-Yuan
Moreover I was chased out from the paIace
How couId I go back again
Huan-Huan
I actuaIIy found
MyseIf so timid
I am afraid
that something might happen
No
It wiII never
The meaI is ready
PIease go back together
Let's go back
Huan-Bi Iikes
aqua-mist coIor shirt
She Iooks good with a hairpin Of red cuckoo
Thank you
It is Iate now Let's go back together
HeIp
Huan-Huan What sound is that
Here
HeIp
HeIp HeIp HeIp
HeIp HeIp
Huan-Huan Don't come over here
He is bitten by snake
What shouId we do
Save him
AppIy the paste for him
Huan-Bi HoId his Iegs
HoId them
Where is the wound
We can onIy see his hands
The wound shouId be on his hands
It's here
Huan-Bi Give me the toweI
HeIp
Here
Open the paste
Huan-Bi Water
Hurry up
He is awake
Come
Are you feeIing better
Thank you
Thank you for saving me
LuckiIy Dzungarian are strong
Or
you might have died
How do you know that I am Dzungarian
Your shirt does not have probIem
But you were saying the Ianguage of Dzungarian just now
Huan-Huan toId me that
There are probIems with your hands
The caIIus on your hands
Is caused by archery
Dzungarian is good in horsemanship and archery
This mark wiII be IeftOnIy when you shoot arrow for many years
What a smart woman