~ Episode 12 ~
Reporting to Your Majesties,
Precious Cao has brought Princess Wen Yi here to pay her respects
She's brought the princess out on such a hot day?
Hurry and invite her in lest she falls ill
Yes
Greetings, Your Majesties
At this time, the sun is high
why are you bringing the princess around with you?
You're all right, but can she take it?
Your Majesty is right
But the princess has been crying since the morning
I thought it was because she hasn't seen the Empress in some time
and was missing her
Forget it. I haven't seen the princess in some time either
Come, let me carry her
I haven't seen her in a few days, but why does the princess feel lighter than before?
The weather is hot, the princess' appetite has waned
and has thus lost some weight
Wen Yi is young and afraid of the heat
I'm afraid the concubines won't be able to stand it either
The weather's too hot
Why don't we go to the Yuan Ming Gardens to escape the heat?
The Yuan Ming Gardens have been kept ready
Your Majesty may go anytime you wish to
I want to go there and stay for a couple of days
Because of my Father's funeral matters
I haven't been there for two years
Going there is easy
But the concubines who can follow are not many
Which ones do you want to go?
Needless to say, these two are included
the mothers of my children will necessarily follow as well
so that it will be convenient for them to look after the children
Aside from them, ask Pin of Respects and that will be all
Princess Duan's health is the weakest
I'm afraid it won't be easy for her to recuperate in the palace
She should come along too
But of course
As for Princess of Glory...
Why don't we let her stay
to look after the rest of the concubines in the Forbidden City?
This step-shake
I gave it to Princess of Glory
Yes
Every time Princess of Glory wears it
the princess will smile
so Princess of Glory gave it to me for the princess to play with
Princess of Glory shall go too
Yes
Who arranged this? So considerate
His Majesty knows that young mistress likes aroma
to avoid heat, burning incense is not proper
His Majesty ordered us to go and get some fresh flowers
and use the fans to spread the scent
It really does smell nice and feel cool!!!
it is not like this in the other young concubines' rooms
you are the only one who has this
this strategy is really good
his majesty really did work hard with his heart
the weather is not hot yet
when the hot weather comes,
we will put ice in here
then it would be luxurious in here!
his majesty ordered us to do this early in the morning
the minute young mistress feels hot, we will immediately bring out the ice.
we don't dare disobey his majesty's orders
you've worked hard huang gong gong
please go and inform his majesty,
that later, I will go and say "thank you"
Servant is unqualified with young mistress' appreciate
but his majesty will go and practice his archery skills,
rest a bit young mistress, then go there later.
playing archery now? who is with his majesty right now?
prince guo and precious cao
precious cao?
yes
Princess Wen Yi has just gotten back to health so his majesty...
wants to see Precious Cao.
I heard that His Majesty likes Yuan Min Yuan.
This is my first time to come here.
Oh yeah, young mistress,
I heard that Concubine Duan has come too.
we don't even know what Concubine Duan looks like.
Concubine Duan has been sick for years
It's been a long time since she has traveled with His Majesty.
what is this!!!!!!?????
very good archery
This is JIng Xi's wild pigeon.
It's famous for dexterous and nimble.
It is very hard to aim for one and succed in shooting it.
This person's archery skills are very precise.
Greetings Precious Wan
Is His Majesty in the garden practicing his archery?
Duke Guo came.
His Majesty and Duke Guo have worked together to shoot wild pigeons.
The real Duke Guo has finally come.
I heard from Liu Zhu that
that day when his majesty and young mistress met,
His Majesty has said to be Duke Guo
now the name has returned to its real owner.
His Majesty's archery is very precise.
Duke Guo's archery skills are so good,
that even His Majesty praises him.
It is said that Duke Guo is talented in literacy and art,
I never knew that his archery skills are good too.
you don't know
Duke Guo is talented in many things.
Xiao Xia Zhi, quicky bring this wild pigeon to His Majesty
Also go tell His Majesty on my behalf,
that I will go and say my greetings later.
I shall take my leave.
I remember,
your archery skills, were taught by our Imperial Father.
Imperial Brothers archery skills were taught by
Man Zhou's best archery master.
I am not smart enough.
Even though I was taught by our Imperial Father,
I still could not master our Imperial Father's exact archery skills.
My teacher taught me archery skills,
but what Imperial Father taught was father to son education.
Imperial Father really did dote you.
(Chinese Idiom) When God is about to place a great responsibility on a great man
(Chinese Idiom) it always first frustrates his spirit and will
Because Imperial Father spoiled me,
I became a useless person.
You've become tired today. Rest early.
I shall go back to Qing Zhen palace.
His Majesty takes his leave!!!
Respectly send your majesty
Greeting Your Majesty,
you arrived.
Duke Guo,
journeyed far away, and came back with this tea green-above-snow
it really is good tea.
come and enjoy it with me.
Your Majesty is in a good mood today.
I heard this tea is only grown in rare parts of a snow mountain.
it is very hard to get.
There are only about ten tea trees in the world
Because of the snow-broth's nourishing
it tasts cool, superior
Duke Guo has really worked hard.
Xiao Xia Zhi.
yes.
Set aside the other factors
now that the weather is warm,
bringing this teas back is very hard.
it is his intention that worth
Your majesty said just now
it is fine for this time
If every year this happens then it would cost too much
Duke is thoughtful, and your majesty has perspective
Precious Smile
this sentence is just on the point
I heard that today His Majesty was very successful in playing archery with Duke Guo today.
how come now I don't see the Duke now?
maybe he heard that Precious Wan your beauty is like a fairy's,
so he run away to avoid arousing suspicion
Precious Cao has oversaid my beauty.
Your Majesty doesn't to to worry much about the duke.
It must be that duke heard I was ugly
so he hid to avoid me.
Listen, if she was ugly
the others in the Inner Place
would be more ugly
Precious Wan is humble. Your majesty don't listen to her joking
now try this Green above Snow
It really is good tea.
the scent is great and energizing.
Duke is certainly thoughtful
I have heard that, the day your majesty and Precious Wan met,
your majesty thought Precious Wan would be frightened,
so your majesty used Duke Guo's name as his own,
and played music along with Precious Wan.
That was what caused today's relationship
it really is a nice story.
Precious Cao even knows this story,
then his majesty must have told you himself.
I never said that.
Precious Cao heared this herself.
So Duke Guo is really the person
who brought His Majesty and Precious Wan together.
Precious Wan should be thankful.
Many Royal families,
and courtmen have heard about Duke Guo,
and have anticipated their daughter or grandaughter to marry Prince Guo
Has Precious Wan ever heard,
of Duke Guo's name?
Before I came into the Forbidden City, I was always kept home.
After I came into the Forbidden Palace, I never really did wander outside of my palce much,
so I haven't heard of the Duke's famous name
I must have really missed a lot of news.
His Majesty is awsome at literacy,
and is very nice to us concubines and preciouses,
Who knew, maybe his majesty had done the same thing
to get close to you
Princess Wen Yi must be hungry at this hour,
Your Majesty, I'll go back and check it out now.
That is fine.
Ever since Princess Wen Yi recovered her health, she has been crying a lot lately.
Imperial Doctor Zhang has been checking Princess Wen YI to make sure she is healthy.
As he does that, ask him to see why Princess Wen YI has been crying so much .
Yes. After Imperial Doctor Zhang has
found the reason, I will inform His Majesty immediately.
This qin is a beloved object of the late Emperor's Princess of Su
Before you came, I wanted someone to play it for me
But Precious Cao -- Cao Qin Mo (mo means silent) -- just as her name
is not good at it
May I send someone to ask Mei Jiejie to come
Mei jiejie play the qin so well
Meizhuang is more proficient in melody than you
but there's no feeling in her melody
the instrument is good
but it will be worthless if there's no feeling
So you play it for me
I'll play it for your majesty
Wonderful the tone is so clear and melodious
bluish waves and cool breeze, enjoy the tea and listen to the qin
so enjoyable
play Living in the Mountains
I screw it up
Please forgive me
The sound was wonderful, but you were not concentrated
You were thinking about other things
I disappointed your majesty,, please forgive me
It's your fist time to play this qin
may not familiar with it, and can't be concentrated
But I have another doubt
I know your affection to me
but I wonder
when it begins
Whom I see is the one in front of me
no matter his fame and name
Explain
Your majesty enjoyed the xiao and flowers with me
in the name of Duke Guo
Even though I adored your talent
but I thought you were duke
so I was cautious
and not dare to break the rules and get any closer to you
After your majesty told me the truth
your majesty has been very considerate to me
not as the normal considerate as to the other concubines
I treat your majesty not only as emperor
but also as husband
If I must tell you a certain time
when my affection began
My affection to your majesty began
when your majesty helped me with Yushi's trouble
I was flustered at that moment
thought it was as easy as lift a finger to you
but in my eyes
your majesty was a hero helped me in need
I'm not serious
Please let me speak it all
It may be a capital crime to offend your majesty
I regard your majesty as the emperor
but more than the Emperor
I regard and love your majesty as my husband
I know
so I love you, too
Huanhuan, today it's me oversensitive
don't blame me
Si Lang
Young mistress, are you suspect that someone
told the Precious Cao about the story
of how you and your majesty met
I'm just suspecting
and have no evidence
But such private thing
only those who are close to young mistress know
I also didn't know until today
There's only Liuzhu
knows this
but Liuzhu
came with you as a dowry maid
I know
Liuzhu has been with me for so many years
I trust her
right
she can't get close to Cao Qinmo
and betray me
I think so
Is it possible that Liuzhu speak it out unaware
the speaker is unaware, but the listener is aware
So it goes orally
then the Precious Cao heard it
Only in this way can we explain
Thanks to his majesty trust me
if not,
I may die without anywhere to bury me
Right
Except for his majesty's trust
the other things are not important at all
Niangniang, as your instructions
I've instructed the kitchens to cut down the dishes
and use more vegetable
Fine, his majesty require the Inner Palace to be economical
I have to set a good example
Agreed, madam
Princess of Glory and Princess of Regularity must follow these measures
Only then would the others listen
Madam is very brilliant
I am not brilliant
It was the Precious Shen's suggestion
put forward in front of his majesty
This credit
I cannot steal from her.
Niang Niang,
here are the dimsum snacks.
There seems to be fewer items
Why is my favorite crabmeat pastry snack missing?
The imperial kitchens say that the ingredients are too pricey
The Empress has instructed them
to not use such expensive ingredients anymore.
I can live with daily items being reduced
But cutting even dim sum items is petty
Please do not be angry
Xing Palace cannot compare with the Palace (Xing Palace (current location): Imperial temporary palace)
The Empress has always been petty
It's just a few of us
How much can we spend?
Lunch and Dinner both suck
Cucumbers and other vegetables!
I hate the sight of such food!
My appetite is already poor in the summer.
With such food, I have an even less appetite
Madam, even the Empress' palace is in the same situation.
It's that Lady Shen's fault
She persuaded the Emperor
She hasn't assistanted in managing the six palaces
She has learnt to use a chicken feather as an arrow [gone vicious?]
Song Zhi
Take some cash
Everyone can handle hardship
Buy something for the maids
Yes
The freshly made plum soup is delicious
better than the one in my palace
Try it
Big Sis, I don't like sour food
Oops, poor memory
I'll drink yours too
Young mistress has 4 or 5 bowls before sleeping
Be careful not to hurt your stomach
You are right
It's warm. That's why this helps
Yes, it's well made
Who is this Fu Ling?
A maid in Xing Palace
She takes care of Young Miss
Right
Princess Wen Yi turns one next month on the 19th
The Emperor wants a big celebration for the princess's birthday
The Emperor is fond of the prince
That's why he has seen the boy's mother often
Huafei's dirt didn't affect her.
She's even more pleased than before
Yes I heard about that
This person...just a few words from her
can make His Majesty doubt you. She cannot be overlooked.
It's good the Emperor has forgotten
No matter how much the Emperor loves one
without a child, one is powerless
Look at Huafei
although she has power over the 6 inner palaces
but she has no child
All her power can be taken away just like that
Without a child
all your words ring hollow
Big Sis, you are not like her
Indeed we are not alike
The Emperor has not been to visit
Because of 3rd prince, he still sees them
Even if you have a daughter
the emperor also loves his daughters
As long as you have a child
You are recognised
Happiness with the Emperor passes
and one is discarded
By my calculations,
Big Sis, you've been with the Emperor a year
Why no 'good news' yet?
The emperor only visits a couple of times a month
I've been busy with the accounts and learning from the Empress
I haven't had time to concern myself
[sigh] Maybe I'm barren
Nonsense!
Huafei has also not had a child
We are still young
There's lots of time
We will have children galore
and they will attend upon and please us.
Don't worry, Bis Sis.
I'm not afraid to share secrets with you
Though it's the god's will to give birth to a prince
the planning lies with man, the outcome with god
We have to plan
It's up to the Emperor if he wants to come, right?
Who can affect that?
You are imperial physician...?
Physician Jiang went home to mourn
The imperial hospital specially sent me, Liu Ben
to take Precious Shen's pulse.
My lady is inside. Please wait.
Ok
Look, I used every possible means
to get this prescription from imperial physician Jiang.
If you follow these instructions, you will have a son
You try the prescription too
Which Dr. Jiang told you?
Are there any other Dr. Jiangs?
he's the best Obstetrician and Gynaecologist
Jiang Cheng?
His younger brother Jiang Shen
is the imperial doctor who cares for Precious Cao and her daughter.
That's the guy.
Can we believe this prescription?
Don't worry
I was also worried
so I sent many people to check his background.
It turns out that Jiang Cheng and Jiang Shen have different mothers
and their mothers don't get along well
so do them
Otherwise, how would I dare use him?
Use it without worries
I also perused many medical books
before deciding to use this prescription.
I don't like it
Put the prescription away for now
Only use it after we've asked Dr. Wen
Liu Zhu, go to the imperial hospital
Check if Dr Wen is around
Invite him over at once
Young mistress
the Lord Sun was badly ill
He has had to leave on a case
He lives in Sun's mansion
Wen will come back
only when Lord Sun get well
When did he leave?
Yesterday afternoon
The old Lord Sun suddenly got ill
so Dr. Wen left in a hurry.
That's unfortunate
Never mind
I've already taken this twice
I feel fine
You don't need to ask him
We're going to drag Dr. Wen all the way here?
I just saw
an imperial doctor standing in the courtyard.
Since you have a visit from the imperial doctor, I won't disturb you anymore
I will come to see you again tomorrow
Liuzhu
Servant pays respects to mistress
Greetings to the Young Miss
This imperial doctor looks very unfamiliar
I've never seen you before
It is my first visit to you
From your speech, you seem to have a Ji Zhou accent
Just several days ago,
servant was transferred here from Ji Zhou.
We are from the same province
It is my honour
Fuling, go pour a pot of Longjing tea
Yes
It's Princess Wen Yi's birthday in half a month
There are so few children
Naturally we should have a grand celebration for her first birthday
According to his Majesty's instruction, though we're not in the Royal Palace
we can't make it simple
It must be a huge exciting celebration
This matter
The Internal Affairs Bureau is on top of things
Thank Your Majesty and Empress,
Princess and I are eternally grateful.
You bore a daughter for the Emperor
You deserve credit. No need for thanks.
Having many children is a blessing for our country.
His Majesty doesn't have many children
Sisters, please
help share in this burden.
Yes, Empress
His Majesty doesn't have many children
but here is one, once we are here,
Princess of Glory, don't violate the forbidden subject
Others can violate it, but I can't
Is a servant's child also fit to be a royal?
4th Prince's mother was indeed lowly
but His Majesty's child is his child no matter what.
Just the same, brothers with 3rd Prince
Is he fit?
Enough, why are you talking about this?
We have all been with His Majesty for a long time
Even though you don't care of violating the forbiden subject
what about his majesty's feelings?
I dare not
When you have time, go over lessons with 3rd Prince
in case His Majesty starts testing him.
Many thanks for Niang Niang's concern
Lately 3rd Prince has been very hardworking
3rd Prince is studying till late
That's good
3rd prince is His Majesty's eldest son
He should set a good example
Hard-working is not enough
maybe he is not as good as the lowly one
When I was walking over,
I saw 4th prince at the creek reading aloud
It was much better than 3rd prince's.
Empress, tell me. Li Jingui died early.
Who taught 4th Prince
to be even more intelligent that the distinguished 3rd Prince?
You...!
Princess of Glory, don't lose your propriety
Princess Wen Yi is about to turn one
Your rank should also be promoted
But His Majesty said
Now is the time to use military force,and there are a lot of difficulties.
We must wait until after the war has subsided
to give you a glorious title ceremony.
It's not a rush
Right, I'm appreciate his Majesty's kind intention with my heart
But I'm lowly
I don't dare to take this
I only want to accompany
Your Majesties
I know you are reasonable
His Majesty gives you a pair of white jade Ruyi
to used as princess' pillow
In a while, I will have someone bring them to you
Thanks Empress
Qiu Gugu!
Why are you here?
Why aren't you with your momos?
They don't care about me
Can I pay my respects to the Empress?
Niang Niang just started resting
Then can I pay respects to Imperial Father?
Wait until he summons for you, ok?
Men
Escort 4th prince back
Yes. 4th prince, please.
Niang Niang, this lotus is hard to peel. Be careful not to hurt your hands.
I know His Majesty likes to eat lotus seeds
so I will peel them myself.
In a while, stew some lily lotus soup
for His Majesty to drink.
Niang Niang's sincerity towards His Majesty
is priceless
What's the use in sincerity? I have no offspring.
Niang Niang, just now 4th prince came over
Why did he come?
He wants to see the Emperor
Forget it
If the Emperor sees him,
he will be reminded of the troublesome past again.
He will be upset again
Actually, 4th prince's birth mother passed away early
He's lonely and helpless, quite pitiful
Do you mean that I should raise 4th prince?
Servant thinks
that if Niang Niang feels lonely without children,
4th prince is also a candidate.
4th prince is the Emperor's least favorite
What's the use in raising him? Never mind that.
When the weather gets hot,
my face starts sprouting pimples.
Look at this one...and this one!
All right
I think these pimples
look good on your face
A couple days ago, Jiejie's face had some pimples
Now they've healed, so you make fun of me!
Fine, then I won't make fun of you
If you like, I can teach you a trick
Liu Ben from the imperial hospital is from the same village as me
When he came to check my pulse the other day, he gave me a home remedy
Look, they've already healed
But I've never heard of Liu Ben before
He came from Ji Zhou just recently
His medical skills are quite good
Fellow-townsmen met
Is he a decent person?
I think he's pretty decent
That's good
For people serving us,
medical skill is secondary.
Most important is an upright character with a clear history
Of course
You have a Wen Shichu
Now I have a Liu Ben
We complement each other
Since Jiejie trusts this person,
did you have him look at the prescription
Jiang Cheng wrote last time?
Yes
He said it is indeed a good prescription
Really?
Respects to Niang Niang
I thought that
we were the only three taking a stroll outside.
I didn't think Precious Smile and Precious Shen were also taking one
The weather is rarely this cool
It's good that Wan Meimei is here
I was just about to look for you
Why do Jiejie look for me?
Last time, I misspoke
I even heard that it caused a disagreement between His Majesty and Meimei
But I really had no ill will
Now that I see you,
I must apologize to Meimei.
It's not your fault
I just talked a few words
with his Majesty
It's nothing major
Meimei, you received the emperor's favor.
Since being the favoured one
Chatting with the emperor is a common thing
If it was someone else, it would be a big deal
How can we compare with Precious Smile?
Even though we want to talk with his majesty
we can't get close
Enough enough
Why are we talking standing here?
Come to my place to continue the chat
I specially ordered a feast
so I can apologize to you.
Here, I even invited
Lingering Xin and Princess of Regularity as company.
Wan Meimei, you must do me the pleasure
Precious Shen
I hear you play the [chinese instrument] well
It is said: when the host is cultured, guests frequent his house.
But a host as me
I don't have your talents
So I must ask
Please come and play us some music
Thanks for your invitation
Young mistress, the plum soup has cooled
Ladies, please try the soup
You just served us meat and fish
Now you're cleaning our greasy mouth
You are so thoughtful
What happened, Precious Shen?
Maybe I ate too much white trotter
and felt ill
Ill?
You were fine just now
Why would you be nauseous now?
How long have you felt nauseous?
Lately the weather has been blistering hot
I've felt this way for about a week
You may be pregnant...
Let me ask you
Have you had your period this month?
I...
We are all sisters, don't be shy
Quickly tell us!
It's late by half a month...
It's quite certain then
Princess of Regularity, don't you think?
Any other symptoms?
Do you feel lethargic?
Like you don't want to budge for days?
Or weird cravings for spicy food?
Get the doctor!
Yes
I want Dr Liu Ben
You are here first, Your Majesty
Is it true Lady Shen is pregnant?
I have only just heard
and don't know the detail, to avoid mistake
I've ordered the servant
to fetch the record from the House of Respectful Affairs
Let's go in together
Emperor arrives
- Greetings Your Majesty and Empress - Sit sit
Is it true?
Imperial doctor, did you confirm that she's really pregnant?
I congratulate Your majesties
Young mistress is indeed pregnant, and has been for about a month
All rise
Thanks Your Majesty
Jian Qiu, bring me the records
Your Majesty, look
Served by Precious Shen, March 16th
The date matches up
Where is Lady Shen's personal maid?
Reporting for duty, Your Majesty
You two are close maids of Precious Shen
She is pregnant and must take special care
You are to send a report of her condition every morning
Yes
The Empress is most thoughtful
Since Lady Shen is pregnant
should we appoint a dependable doctor
to take care of her?
Your Majesty, the one who just came to take my pulse
is Liu Ben from the imperial hospital.
I feel he suits me fine
We are also from the same province
Let him be in charge
That's good
Your health is of paramount importance
Look after yourself
You must not have any mishaps
Yes
I've been negligent
Your Majesties have been here all this time
and I haven't served you any tea.
I was simply too happy to remember my manners
I'm getting thirsty
What would you like?
I knocked over a bowl of plum soup
I'm still thinking of sour plum soup
Quickly, the soup!
Yes, yes, yes, we do have it
If Meimei likes it
I will tell them to send it to you everyday
Precious Cao is sooooo thoughtful
Bring the plum soup
Your majesties must be thirsty
Other people are okay
Remember Precious Wan does not like sour food
Add some sugar in hers
Yes
Thank you for your kindness
Thank you for watching! Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki