~ Episode 24 ~
Bao juanwho do you think is going to be in deep trouble now?
Whoever harmed Lady Hui of course
how sad that even Hua Fei doesn't even know herself
but one has many thoughts and dreams during the night
perhaps after tonight
Emperor wouldn't be angry anymore
How do you think she will react when she knows of this?
According to Hua Fei's personality
she would either go to Chief General Nian
or she would immediately kill Lliu Ben
then she would go to the Emperor crying, begging for mercy
Yeah, when she throws her tantrum
it would be hard for Emperor to not get angry at her
When we passed Palace of Wings earlier
it was quiet inside
it was pretty quiet
but before she was the mistress in the palace
now the one who determines whether she's quiet or not
is Lady
then go quickly
to Palace of Wings
Niang Niang
you're always in the Imperial Hospital searching for medicine books and looking up drugs
now that you're back, you're still looking at them
Now it's almost one o'clock
Niang Niang, you should go rest now
Look at you, your eyes are red
you are just rambling useless words here
go bring more candles here
Yes
Niang Niang, bad news, Liu Ben has been brought back
What? Liu Ben has been found?
Who found him? Where?
Servant does not know the details
Servant only heard An Changzai's palace maid
talking with the servant girls of our palace
that's how I knew
An Changzai...then it must be done by Zhen Huan
a band of useless things
even a weak imperial doctor they can't kill
Don't be anxious Niang Niang. Since Liu Ben's been brought back
he would undoubtedly tell about Lady Hui's matter
Rather than Niang Niang being angry
how about calming down and think of ways to counter him
Hurry. Hurry and go tell older brother
Niang Niang, the palace doors are already locked at this time
If Emperor is angry
even if Chief General Nian comes
he would not be able to interfere with Emperor's household matters
what shall we do then?
I can't sit here and wait for my death
we're all in the same boat
the two Jiang brothers also cannot be exempt from this
Zhou Ninghai
Yes
Tell these two brothers to keep their mouths shut for me
go report to the Emperor when it's morning that I am severely sick
If I am sick
Emperor wouldn't give me harsh punishments
Servant understands. Servant shall immediately go do it
Niang Niang wanting to block those two's mouths
is a good idea
but if you want to regain Emperor's affection
you can't just rely on Emperor's old sentiments
you have to give Emperor what he wants the most right now
Emperor punishing Niang Niang
is because Niang Niang has sinned and you must be punished for sins
you also must be rewarded for accomplishments
If Niang Niang can accomplish something great right now
and atone for your sins with your accomplishment, it would be easier for Emperor to step down
and block those rumorous tongues for Niang Niang
Sins must be punished for and not just easily forgiven
Later go send out my edict to Palace of Wings
YeServant shall go right now
Everyday in court I am worried by the plague
I don't know when this will come to an end
The Strong labor the body, the Wise labor the heart
Emperor labors both the heart and the body so you are extra tired of course
Your coaxing
will help me stay energized even when I'm the tiredest
Yesterday I didn't state myself clearly
don't let it get to you
Courtier Concubine doesn't dare
Fortune to Hua Fei Niang Niang
You may rise
Where's the Emperor?
Emperor's changing right now to go to the morning imperial court session
Servant was just about to go to Palace of Wings
No need. I have a matter to ask of the Emperor
Niang Niang, right now Emperor is
too busy to see you
Whether he has time or not to see me is the Emperor's business
Whether to tell the Emperor or not is your business
Then Niang Niang please wait for a moment
Emperor, Hua Fei, I mean Nian Pin is here
and wants to see you
What is it?
Nian Pin Niang Niang is here with Jiang Cheng and Jiang Shen
the two imperial doctors
and said they must the Emperor
it seems to be of urgent matter
Did you tell of her of my edict?
Nian Pin Niang Niang arrived here hurriedly
and did not allow Servant to reply
If you didn't tell her, then don't keep on calling her Nian Pin
Take them to Warmth of the West Pavillion to wait
Yes
Emperor arrives
Courtier Concubine/Courtiers greet the Emperor
Ten thousand fortunes and golden peace to Hua Fei Niang Niang
You may rise
Thanks Emperor
What is it that made you so urgent to see me?
Congratulations Emperor. Courtier Concubine hears that
the two imperial doctors Jiang Cheng and Jiang Sheng
have crafted the medication for treating the plague
so I've especially taken the two imperial doctors here to report to Emperor
Really
That's right. Courtier Concubine doesn't possess much knowledge in the medical field
so I'll let the imperial doctors to report the specifics.
WindWinterSummerHumidityDrynessFire
Those six evil energies enter through the mouth and the nose
If too much is inhaled, it can produce the air for plagues
and invade the lungs
while creating conflicts between the vital organs to create the plague
Stop with the technical stuff. Tell me all the important stuff first.
The plague is often caused by unsanitary food
which damages the spleen and the gastrointestinal areas
We courtiers have read through many ancient medical books
and crafted a prescription for the plague
It has been named the "Plague Emergency Pill"
This medicine is warm in nature and cannot stand humidity
It will heal the liver and the kidney while recovering the original energy
Do the imperial doctors of the Imperial Hospital
think it is viable?
Yes
It's already been administered to a couple of little eunuchs
After two servings, they've shown signs of the fever decreasing
Good. Good
Niang Niang
Emperor forgive this crime. Courtier Concubine was unmannered
Are you unwell? Hurry and sit down
Thanks Emperor
When Niang Niang heard us courtiers talk
about how the prescription might be inside ancient books
she has stayed up just to look through all the volumes
The last several days she has stayed up late also
Thus resulting in her body feeling weak
Courtier Concubine is foolish and doesn't deserve to serve Emperor
only making the Emperor angry every single time
so I've tried to find ways
to help the Emperor with your worries
My beloved Fei has worked hard
Su Peisheng
Servant is here
Take a few people with you and go with Imperial Doctor Jiang
first take the medicine to Lady Hui's Preserved Chrysanthemum Hall
and then it to all the palace servants
Yes
Lady Hui
I've already recovered Shen's position
I had wronged her in all those previous matters
Then Family Shen's Mei Mei has truly been wronged
Emperor really should compensate for her
Congratulations to Lady Wan
You and her, being sisters, can finally be at rest
Many thanks to Hua Fei Niang Niang
Courtier Concubine won't ask the Emperor to forgive my mistakes of the past
but only ask that Emperor's dragon body won't be damaged
because of being angry at Courtier Concubine
Courtier Concubine is just an unimportant person
but Emperor's body belongs to all the citizens
Ok. Today you really did achieve a great feat.
If this medication can really heal the plague
it would be the fortune of everyone
I am not one who commends and chastes wrongly
Emperor is divinely wise
Lady Lady
Is Emperor still going to punish the two imperial doctors?
and his edict concerning Glory Fei Niang Niang?
does Servant still need to send it?
Servant should be asking Emperor about this
but you see, there are people inside
So Lady, please pity Servant
Under the current circumstances, there's no need for you to go
If you go
it would probably be an edict for adding the titles
Milord Wen, Imperial Doctor Jiang sent Servant here to give you
medicine for curing Lady Hui's plague
What? Imperial Doctor Jiang has aso crafted
medicine for curing the plague?
Place it here for me to see
Emperor arrives
Ten thousand fortunes and golden peace to Emperor
Hurry and rise. You are having breakfast?
Is it suiting your appetite?
Even the best food will taste foul to me. People who eat bone marrow once will lust after it more.
They're all works of the Imperial Kitchen
Courtier Concubine doesn't dare to be picky
Sit
The Imperial Kitchen's meals
must suit everyone's taste
They won't exclude one person in making the meals
just like I have to care for the bigger situations
Yes, Courtier Concubine understands
Right now the epidemic is raging
The medicine created so painstakingly by Glory Fei and Imperial Doctor Jiang
can be counted as a repentance for their crime
As for Liu Ben, I've already given him the death sentence
that will take away some of Lady Hui's injustice
Liu Ben wasn't the main meditator for harming Jie Jie (older sister)
I know. Right now there are no other solutions
I haven't forgotten the matter about Lady Hui
and I won't just easily let it go
The most important thing is Emperor's health
Courtier Concubine doesn't have any insecurities
That's good. But these days
I might have to ignore you a bit
Emperor is busy with governing the court. Courtier Concubine understands
Then I shall go first
Emperor leaves
Emperor's eyes are black and blue underneath
It seems that he really has been tired these few days
Emperor was tired last night
Tell Little Kitchen to make a bowl of ginseng soup
and take it to Palace of Resting Soul
Lady, Emperor also has no choice in some matters
In the harem, a woman's future and the amount of love she receives
all rest on the Emperor's pillow
Emperor's situation is the same
When two people are deeply in love, all conflicts will eventually dissolve like smoke
I guess it's mutual understanding
This kind of thing is common in the palace
Lady doesn't need to mind it so much
I don't mind. I'm just disappointed.
I never thought that Emperor would suspect me
I know about Emperor's oversuspicions
Even when he wronged Mei Jie Jie that day
and I thought about it
will Emperor distrust me one day?
but even now, I'm still very sad
The battles and conflicts between royal concubines
are the least important
The most important is who Emperor chooses to trust
so Lady, instead of being sad here
why not think about how to lessen Emperor's suspicions
Why didn't you say "how to make Emperor not suspicious?"
If Lady thinks you can do it
I can also say it like that
What happened?
How did you go from being well to vomiting and chest tightness?
wasn't the fetus already stable?
Answer Emperor: no worries
Lady only ate too much and was bloated
that's why she feels chest tightness
she just needs to take a lighter dinner and she'll be well
How did you not differentiate between feeling bloated
and actually feeling unwell?
Courtier Concubine was only afraid
Enough. You lie here and take a rest
I still have matters to take care of. I'll see you tonight
Emperor
Ok ok. When I tell you I will come, I will come
Emperor leaves
Escorts Emperor out
Good. Good
Nian Fu didn't disappoint me
and stopped the revolt at Mountain Zhuo Zi
Without a tiger-like father, there wouldn't be such a fierce son
Emperor, it's almost time for lunch
Are you going to eat here at Palace of Resting Soul
or to one of the ladies' palaces to eat?
Didn't the Imperial Kitchen make
pearl sea rice with simmered quail?
Yes
I remember that Fei of Glory liked it the most
so let's go to Palace of Wings
What a coincidence then!
People from Palace of Wings just came to invite Emperor over
it seems that I and Fei of Glory have connected heart and mind
abalone braised pearls, fish stomach simmered with sausage
Shark chicken stew, and mushroom with cabbage heart
these are all Emperor's favorites
these dishes all require the most effort to make
you must have woken up at the latter half of the night
to keep an eye on the cooks
Emperor's food
Courtier Concubine must see for myself
Just eating one meal causes you so much effort
I really feel reluctant
To pour out my heart and soul for Emperor, Courtier Concubine would do anything
Emperor must be hungry after reading papers for the whole morning
drink a bowl of chicken soup to warm up your stomach
Emperor's appetite is good today
have there been any happy events?
Guess
Is it because of that child Nian Fu who didn't disappoint the imperial grace
and pacified the revolt at Mount Zhuo Zi?
Your reporters are really fast
how did you know so quickly
the reports came in the early morning
Courtier Concubine is happy for Nian Fu as well
Nian Fu is young but talented
he didn't fail Nian Geng Yao's teachings to him
This child Nian Fu's first military expedition ended so quickly
Courtier Concubine was happy for a whole morning
What does Emperor think should be his reward?
Since you love him so much
reward some silver and the four treasures of study
A boy who's on the battlefield
doesn't care for these
then you say what he shold be reward with
My older brother's oldest son Nian Bin has already been knighted
Though Nian Fu is only the second child
but his courage and skills are not below his brother
Emperor why not reward him with a knighthood position?
that would allow them two brothers
to all the more help Emperor together
Nian Fu is very young, and he only just made an achievement on the battlefield
if I grant him a knighthood now
it would be too early. Wait two years
Emperor now loves Courtier Concubine's older brother more than Courtier Concubine
If older brother were the one to suggest this
Emperor would surely think older brother was
being understanding to the warriors and appeasing them
If Courtier Concubine was the one to say it
Emperor would think Courtier Concubine was only thinking like a woman
Your brother also came to seek a reward for Nian Fu?
Older brother loves Nian Fu the most
that's what Courtier Concubine thinks
Eat first
Fine. Fine.
I will grant your older brother with the knighthood of First Male
and Nian Fu will inherit his position. How's that?
Emperor~Emperor always makes Courtier Concubine impatient
to go my way. What if Courtier Concubine doesn't comply?
Emperor
Lady, the medicine is ready
Lady, this medicine will help make your cough better
The air is always different, suddenly cold and suddenly warm
I will probably get well slower
Getting well is like pulling silk. How can you get well so fast?
As long as Lady treats herself right, you will get better
Report to Lady: at the eighth hour (around 1-3 pm) Emperor wants to
see Lady at the Western Warmth Pavilion
thanks to Gong Gong
Servant shall leave now
Gong Gong leave peacefully
This paper from Nian Geng Yao
when did it come in?
It was around lunch time
At lunch Fei of Glory pleaded me
to reward Nian Fu
This paper from Nian Geng Yao begs me
to reward all the soldiers who ceased the revolt
these two siblings' thoughts
really are at one
Su Peisheng
Servant is here
do you still want your head as the head eunuch?
Emperor, Servant deserves to die, Servant deserves to die
but Servant is foolish, Emperor please clarify
so that Servant can die knowing what I died for
your eyes are not sharp enough
there are people messaging back and forth in and out of the palace
and you did not even know
You are just like me, a foolish person
Emperor forgive me. Emperor forgive me.
Emperor please let Servant go this time
Servant will certainly strengthen the security from now on
If I don't let you live and pay for your error
Why would I be scolding you? Get up.
Thank you, Emperor
Emperor, please have some tea and calm down
Call Wan Concubine
Of Course
Look at this.
I dare not look at this
This is a family matter. I'm allowing you to look
Emperor, Zhao Zhi Yuan is accusing my father
Zhao Zhi Yuan is accusing your father of being
as a bad minister and disobeying my orders
what does he mean by this?
All he's saying is
is because my father didn't bow to the general like all other men
Everyone think I favor and trust Nian Geng Yao (the general)
So they all fawn over him
because they think they are following in my steps
Emperor, your respect for the general
is because the general has done great things for the nation
But no matter what good he's done, he as to obey the rules
He has to respect you and the other dukes
He should obey the ettique that has been set
You also think I've over favored Nian General?
I dare not, I just think
that even with the favor of the emperor
Nian General shouldn't be too egotistical
and disrespect all other officials
Also, Zhao Zhi Yuan is a official of internal affairs
He's not actually reporting on internal affairs
and is complaining about manners and etiquette
He's finding every excuse to help Nian General
This paper has deep implications, I need to look it over carefully
Little Mistress, be patient
The Emperor is talking to Wan concubine
Since the emperor has important things
then it's okay that I wait
How about this, I will go in again
and announce your arrival
thank you for your troubles
Emperor
What is it?
An Cheng has been outside for a long time
I am busy
Emperor, An sister has been sick
The wind is fierce outside, it's not wise to let her stay outside too long
Perhaps I should go?
I still have things to say to you
Suo Fei shi
Your servant is here
Tell An Cheng
I don't have the time to see her
Tell her to go back and rest
yes, emperor
Little Mistress, I'm very sorry
The Emperor wants you to go back
Right now, Wan concubine is in there
The Emperor really has no time to see you
Since the emperor has elder sister to serve him. it's alright
Then I shall go first
Little miss has been at palace
for so long and in the cold
now your cough is worse, what to do?
It's my fault
I knew that Wan concubine was in there
I still tried foolishly to try and see him
And was sent back
That wan concubine
She knows that your body's weak
Since the emperor has no time
then she should have reminded him earlier
instead she made you wait in the cold wind
Little Mistress, your hands must be cold, hold this
Royal Concubine, I've just heard
That at the Emperor's morning meeting, Wan Concubine's father
Was demoted to a lesser position
yes
In all of the concubines, she's been so show-off and standoffish
because her family has been powerful
now that her father's been demoted
I want to see how she'll lift her head now
Zhao Zhi Yao seems like someone who knows how to do his job
I having given my brother (nian general) a hint
Zhao Zhi Yao made that report
It seems that Wan Concubine doesn't have alot of the Emperor's heart
New people are like new novelties
but now she's not new anymore
of course, how can she compare to you, who has been in favor for many years
I've heard that these days
the emperor only say wan concubine once
Her novelty's worn off
she's no longer the flavor of the month
when the time comes to remove her
it's be up to you of course
The food is cold
Little mistress, why haven't you eaten?
I feel annoyed, I don't want to eat
Are you mad about father's situation?
You have to becareful of your body
Even if I was upset, what use would that be?
it's all the emperor's will
Little Mistress's appetite has been bad
Should I call for the royal doctor?
no
Wen doctor has to take care of Mei concubine's health
I think it that a couple of days ago
ate some oily foods
I'm really tired
I'll go and sleep now
You've been sleeping alot, like a cat
it's almost spring
but i still feel cold all over
go and get me a soup
Since the emperor has indicated that he's going to spend the night with you
little mistress, you have to try and appear beautiful
I went over to Concubine Wan's
I feel bad for her
it's a wonder that she still can sleep
Concubine Wan's father being demoted
Concubine Wan must feel terrible
There a great deal of people looking foward to see her embaressment
that's probably why she's making the excuse of sleeping, so she won't have to see anyone
Since the time she's enter the palace and recieved favor
she's been very self-satisfied. No one knew that she would face a day like this
Little mistress, you are so kind hearted
That day on the steps of the palace, she made you wait outside for so long
and yet you still pity her
Bao Juan, to be honest
Not only do I feel pity for her
I am a bit jealous of her
jealous?
Concubine Wan is better at everything than I am
She has more favor, the emperor likes her better
her family is better than mine
but now that her father's been demoted
I feel that
I am a little less distant from her
I don't feel that she's above be anymore
Little miss, it's been hard on you
I am the one pregnant with the dragon seed (emperor's child)
It's not Concubine An Cheng Zai
Why does the Emperor go to Concubine An?
I think that someone is taking the opportunity since I am pregnant
And seduce the emperor
Don't pay attention little miss
Fu Cha usually bullys the soft spoken
This kind of ugly talk
Since I've lived at Yan Xi palace
I've heard of it a lot, I'm not going to pay attention to it
yes
Since it's getting warmer
are you getting better?
Thanks for your care, I am better
Now that Hua Concubine is taking care of the court
I have alot of time on my hands
Before, it was because of your headaches
So that's why I gave the management of the court to Hua concubine
I haven't even given any orders
All the people in the court
are only listening to Hua concubine
She's young and efficient
Hua concubine has the experience
of course she is very skilled
Now that the inner court is siding with Hua concubine
I have no choice but to let her take care of the court
The issue with Shi Yi, Hua concubine played an improtant part
now that she's more cautious and organized
we can reinstate her old position of helping you to take care of the court
as long as you make the decision, i'll follow it
but there is one thing
I want to talk about on behalf of Concubine wan
I know what you want to say
Wan Concubine's father has made a mistake
I have punished him
this is not Wan Concubine's fault
Emperor you've always been able to separate your personal and work
but the people in the inner court do not think like this
Wan concubine has been a favorite
but now her father has made her a joke
it the Emperor has the heart
you should go see her tonight
Didn't you say
that An Concubine missed me?
I've chose An concubined tonight
Emperor, you've always been too busy
Which concubine doesn't miss you?
But An concubine and wan concubine have always been good friend
this matter about wan concubine
I think An concubine will understand
this might be better
I don't want to see wan concubine
becuase of the troubles of her father
face difficulties
your servant is here
Call wan concubine to Yang Xin palace
Yes, emperor
Little Miss, the emperor will come,
just wait a moment
The emperor rarely comes
you should go and better prepare yourself
you don't know when the next time will be
Concubine don't worry
when i see the emperor
I will tell the emperor of your worries
Are you saying I won't be able to see the emperor?
How could i?
I just don't want to see you miss the emperor so badly
So I'll tell him in person
what a joke, I am pregnant with the emperor's child
I can see him whenever I want
Of Course
But the next time you see the Emperor
You shouldn't say that there's no child
when he hears this too much, he'll be annoyed
How dare you...
Fu Cha concubine, An Concubine, greetings
Su Gong Gong, why are you here?
the emperor has decreed
Tonight you don't need to wait for him
But he chose me tongiht
yes, he did choose you tonight
but the emperor has ordered Wan concubined to go to him
She's been taken to him already
The emperor's change of heart, is a normal thing
The Emperor understands that your cough has not been healed
he wants you to rest a while
thank you
then i shall leave first
It seems i've overestimated you
no chance this time, there's next time
pity you look so pretty tonight
the emperor doesn't even take a look
even though he chose you, he reneges
but you guys are good sisters
since you have no chance Wan concubine replaced you
whoever serves the emperor is the same
it must be difficult for her
her father's been demoted
and yet the emperor still thinks of her
this kind of skill
you should learn from her
why? why did you take my chance?
why did you have to steal mine?
you've gotten thinner
you're words are less too
it's because of the spring, I''ve become lazy
no matter how lazy, you have to move
you can get sick if you are not too careful
Emperor
Fu Cha Concubine
wants to see you
She wants you to go over to her palace
You should go, I'll be fine
Let the doctor go to her
yes, emperor
Fu Cha concubine is pregnant the first time
it wouldn't harm her if you went to see her more often
its good that you are so considerate
okay, sleep here tonight
and go back to your palace tomorrow
that way you won't have to go back and forth all the time
yes
greeting to the Emperor and Empress
rise
thank you, emperor
you don't look good, sit
look at you, you have dark circles
I heard that Fu Cha Concubine also asked for the Emperor
saying that she didn't feel too good
its no problem
Fu Cha was being bratty
She was blaming me for going to late
and gave me a headache
If there are any evil things in the palace
Hua concubine must be vigilant
So from today I;m giving Hua Concubine her power to assist in keeping the peace in the inner court
Thank you, emperor
You must be accountable
and help the emperess
congrats, sister
Jin Ping has been serving me for eight or nine years
Jin Ping is diligent and well mannered
You are now Royal Concubine
what? So happy that it made you dumb?
Have you forgotten to thank me?
Thank you, Emperor
The ceremony will be next month on the 19th
Since you and Hua concubine entered the same year
you are an old hand in this inner court
you must help assist Hua concubine
and help the empress with the burden of governing the inner court
I will do my best
and share the burden with the empress
rise
congratulations on your joyous news
I have to go to He Nan to see the problem
The inner court will be managed by the queen
Hua and Jing Concubine will assist her
I will do my best as Empress
Madame
Greetings little mistress
I heard that you are to help Mei concubine until she is no long sick
it must be hard on your part
thank you
She is much better now
Do you feel better, older sister?
I feel a little better
Why is it so noisy outside?
What's going on?
The emperor made Jing Concubine into a Royal concubine
THey came to congratulate her
now that you are better, you are a Gui Ren (honored person)
What's the difference?
it's just a tittle
You've been so sick and depressed
You've suffered so much
it's no wonder you feel wronged
Even if I say I am innocent
will you believe it?
Since you are well now
you should get up and walk around
I don't want to go out, I get annoyed when I see people
it's so peaceful in here
Doctor wan is here
I should thank you, you cured her
I dare not accept
it's the collective effort of the royal doctors' office
I was able to cure her due to their medicines
You are so humble
Everyone knows
that you are skilled, why deny it?
someone should have announced your arrival
my mesy appearance is so embaressing
Sisiter even though you are sick you are beautiful
Xi Shi had a pain of the heart
But Dong Shi still wanted to copy her
No matter if a beauty is sick or not she will always be beautiful
Also
Wen doctor has taken care of you for so long
he is familiar with you
let's not care too much about etiquette
yes doctor wen has been very good takin care of me
If Little mistress eats these light foods
even if it is very simple
it has no good nutritonal value
why do I prescribe some foods
I see that Wan concubined doesn't look good as well
why don't I order some stewed lamb meat dishes
it will help with the blood circulation
thank you for your troubles
you can always make people go the extra mile for yo
don't you think so? doctor wen?
This should be part of my job
then I will go and order these foods
You've spoke alot
you must be tired, go and sleep
you don;t look good as well, what's wrong?
nothing, i didn't get enough sleep that's all
even though I live in a well
but it's not like I don't know what it's like on the outside
Now that hua concubine has so much power
Hua concubine has power over the inner court now
All our efforts have gone to waste
Thank you for watching! Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki