In the year 1722,
Emperor Kangxi of the Qing Dynasty passed away.
Nian Gengyao, Viceroy of Sichuan-Shaanxi
and Long Keduo, Director of the Imperial Infantry
distinguished themselves during the Princes' fight for the throne
by notable service to the victory of Fourth Prince Yìnzhēn
They are now ministers highly esteemed by the new Emperor,  Caption: Yōngzhèng
holders of unparallelled political power,
and central figures in the new government.
Kneel
First Kowtow (bow).
Second Kowtow.
Third Kowtow.
All rise.
By the mandate of heaven, the Emperor hereby decrees
Long Keduo, by loyal service to Emperor Kangxi,  Caption: Sū Péishèng (Emperor's personal eunuch)
esteemed service to me, and to the nationCaption: Lóng Kēduō
is hereby knighted Duke of First Class.  Caption: Zhāng Tíngyù
appointed president of the Board of Civil Appointments, concurrently charged with running the Li Fan Yuan.
Nian Gengyao, Viceroy of Sichuan-Shaanxi, is hereby knighted Duke of Second Class.
All affairs related to the military  Caption: Nián Gēngyáo
as well as ministers of border defense, funds,  Caption: Zhēn Yuǎndào (father of Zhen Huan)
and the governors of Sichuan-Shaanxi and Yunnan Caption: Guāěrjiā Èmǐn
shall all report to General Nian. This is the Emperor's decree.
Gratitude for His Majesty's benevolent grace.
His Majesty indeed thinks very highly of General Nian
– and Sir Long Keduo. – Congratulations Sir Long!
You have done the country a great service.
General Nian,
His Majesty truly appreciates you greatly.
Sir.
You have rendered invaluable service to His Majesty.
Please wait for a few moments, Great General Nian.
Great General.
Imperial Eunuch Su, what can I do for you?
His majesty is concerned about the wounds on your arm
and has specifically instructed me to deliver this precious medicine to you,for your use.
The humble Nian Geng Yao, appreciates his majesty's merciful grace.
I wish to ask, Royal Eunuch Su, is my younger sister doing well in the Palace?
Hua Fei Niangniang's beauty and status surpass all in the Imperial Harem
Rest assured, Great General.
Please take care of her, Imperial Eunuch Sū.
It is my duty and pleasure.
(Hall of a Resting Soul: The emperor's study)
Your Majesty
From the House of Respectful Affairs. (Records the Emperor's nightly visits to different concubines.)
Your majesty, please flip a name board over.
Caption： Xú Jìnliáng
Your Majesty, it's been half a month since you've stepped foot into the harem.
If a name isn't flipped tonight, the Empress Dowager will surely punish me!
Your Majesty!
You talk too much.
Your Majesty, the Empress Dowager is here.
Hurry up, show her in.
Yes, sir.
Caption: Empress Dowager (tàihòu)
Greetings, Your Highness. (literally, "may safety be with you")
Greetings, Imperial Mother
The weather has been warm lately. I asked the Royal Kitchen to make some mung bean &amp; lily bulb soup.
I thought it was pretty good.
I brought you some, knowing you were awake.
Many thanks, Imperial Mother.
Your Majesty
These are the pickled vegetables Sir Long Ke Duo brought for the Dowager Empress fresh from Yang Zhou
He said that these are more delicious and refreshing than those made by Sanbi.
Over here.
Stop it with the long face.
It's like this everyday, no big deal.
It's already been over six months since His Majesty's coronation,
but we can count the number of his visits to the harem with one hand in any given month.
It's natural for the Dowager to be reproachful when the House of Respectful Affairs has less to do.
It must be distressing for you to be stuck in the middle.
Thank you for understanding my position, Royal Eunuch Su.
I hope you can bring the issue to His Majesty's attention on my behalf.
The Young Mistresses need His Majesty's presence,
the same way a dry field needs the rain.
We have said enough.
But His Majesty is so busy with state affairs lately that he can only manage to sleep 4-6 hours.
We wish to remind His Majesty to visit the Harem, but how do we even begin?
If Mother is bothered by the heat,
I can instruct them to bring some ice
to your palace.
The heat is not so bothersome now that I am old.
What worries me most is you.
You are always busy with state affairs...
But you can't neglect your own health.
I understand.
As busy as you are, have you looked over the third prince's lessons?
I examined his work a few days ago.
His calligraphy is coming along, but
knowledge of his subjects still leaves much to be desired.
The former emperor had 24 sons, including you.
Your Majesty cannot compare with that.
I am not blessed with many children. I only have three sons.
I am sorry for making you worry about me.
It is not your fault.
The former Emperor had more consorts so naturally more children as well.
You only have a few consorts.
The Empress, Princess of Modesty (Duan Fei), Princess of Regularity (Qi Fei),
they are no longer young.
It would be difficult for them to give you children.
I am also concerned that my children are but few.
It is the Imperial Family's duty to have many children.
Only then can the dynasty see a long succession of heirs.
It's for this reason that we need to audition new consorts every three years, to fill the harem.
It is as you lecture Mother.
Then we have agreed on hosting an audition.
I will do everything as per your arrangements.
I am old, what could I possibly arrange?
Let Internal Affairs Authority pick a propitious day.
After rounds of auditions,
the outstanding women will become your wives and consorts.
I will be waiting for my grandchildren.
The Empress is busy. Hua Fei assists her in managing the Harem.
Let Hua Fei manage the audition.
She is not only competent and beautiful,
but has already enjoyed your adoration for so many years.
It would not be a bad thing to have someone new.
Your affection should be shared equally by the harem, not adorning a single woman.
Yes, but I have just one request, Mother.
What would that be?
Since we are hosting an audition now, I do not think it necessary to host any more in the future.
Every three years is much too wasteful.
I have always believed that the Manchu and the Han are all part of the same family.
So this time,
I would like to choose more girls from families of the Han military banners.
These are just details, I see no problems.
As long as Your Majesty agrees to add to the harem.
But don't forget the existing consorts either.
No matter how important state affairs are, you should still visit the Harem regularly.
And your Empress, she will always be the center of your Harem.
I understand.
Caption: Palace of Benevolent Hope (Jǐngrén gōng) (the Empress' residence)
My apologies for asking you to come at this hour.
I must have interrupted your afternoon nap.
How could I possibly as blessed as Niangniang as enjoy so much free time?
Caption: Empress (huánghòu)  (娘娘 "niángniang" = "Your Highness" or "Her Highness")
May I inquire what urgent business niangniang wishes to discuss?
The auditions are almost at the final round, where His Majesty will choose those who will remain.
How is everything?
Rest assured, Niangniang. Caption: Huá Fēi (literally "Princess Consort of Glory")
Huang Guiquan sent a reply in the afternoon.
saying that everything was in place.
Since His Majesty said the treasury was not as "strong" at the moment,
that we should learn to economize.
Although I cannot make money appear out of nowhere
I will at least uphold the Imperial honour.
How can other people understand the difficulty of MY job?
I must thank you for your troubles, Meimei. (妹妹 "mèimei" = "younger sister", often used figuratively)
Also, I have ordered some new pastries to be made.
Meimei, please have a taste.
Huichun.
Meimei, pick for yourself.
Take whatever you wish.
Or maybe you have already had enough of these.
Jianqiu, bring the Peony Rolls to Hua Fei.
Yes.
– Songzhi.  – Yes.
Many thanks, Niangniang.
Aiya! Empress Niangniang, please forgive me!
I did not mean to.
Such a lack of matters!
You've shattered Niangniang's kind offer!
Hadn't you better beg for Niangniang's forgiveness?
Please forgive me, Empress Niangniang!
You have served me from before my marriage into the Imperial family
And yet you are still capable of incomprehensible mistakes like the one you just made.
Why do I even bother teaching you anymore.
If the Empress will not forgive you,
I will not let you off lightly.
Meimei, these are just small matters. Caption: Sòngzhī
There is no need to be so angry.
She is not very bright and she is clumsy.
Thank you for forgiving her.
I will give her a good lesson after we take our leave.
Sòngzhī is your servant from your maiden home.
She is different from the other servants.
Do not make her do things like serving tea or water.
Do not be angered, even if you think her incompetent.
Right?
Fuzi.
Greetings, Empress Niangniang.
Greetings, Hua Fei Niangniang.
She is newly selected by Internal Fairs Authority.
She is actually a bit intelligent, so why don't you have her?
Although Songzhi is clumsy and stupid...
The Palace of Wings has plenty of servants.
Why not keep her?
I have heard that servants from the Palace of Wings (Hua Fei's Residence) are competent.
Fuzi should learn from them.
Perhaps, with Sister's governance and by helping Songzhi do some heavy chores,
they will learn manners.
I will take my leave.
- We are leaving. - Yes.
I wonder how the audition is going.
The Harem truly needs new faces,
so that His Majesty can finally have more children.
Go away. Such audacity to think you can walk beside Niangniang!
Go, follow us from behind.
I cannot achieve prominence in affairs of the state as men can,
But I will not take myself lightly
If I were to marry someone,
I must marry the best man in the world.
Form a true conjugal bond, from which only death will separate us.
Bless me, Bodhisattva.
Hide my name from notice, so that I can be spared from entering the harem.(Cap: Zhen Huan)
The Bodhisattva in this temple is said to be especially effective.
Young missus, your wishes will surely come true!
Young missus, other girls in the audition all pray to be selected.
Only our miss wants the opposite!
Caption left: Liúzhū  Caption right: Huànbì
The Bodhisattva will definitely grant your wish.
Shhhhh. If you say a wish out loud, it won't come true!
Caption: Wēn Shíchū  (an imperial doctor)
What day is this? Even Doctor Wen is visiting the Bodhisattva?
This Imperial Doctor Wen is definitely strange.
Everyone knows that without consent from the Palace he cannot accept patients outside of the Imperial Family.
But he comes to our residence at least twice a month.
You two talk too much.
Maybe I should ask Doctor Wen for a prescription
that will fix the two of you.
— Shichu Gege.  — Huan Meimei.  (哥哥 "gēgē" = "older brother" or figuratively)
I went to your manor just now to check on your family's health
Auntie Zhen said you came here to offer incense.
Walks are a nice way to relax.
Sister Huan, you do not have to hide it from me.
I know you have been worried
about the final round of auditions for quite a few days.
I do what is possible for me, the rest I can only leave to fate.
Sister Huan, when my father was alive, he would often say
"my heart is as pure as ice in a vase of jade"（line from a Tang dynasty poem; representing sincerity)
He asked that I give this vase to my future...
This has always been my wish as well.
If you accept it, you would not have to attend the auditions anymore.
In Emperor Shun Zhi's time (grandfather of the current Emperor)it was decreed that
girls who qualify to be selected for the harem(from families belonging to the Eight Banners, 4 Manchu, 4 Han)
cannot marry without first having being eliminated from the audition.
Brother Shichu wants to save me,
but you need not have offered an item of so great a value and sentiment.
I cannot accept this.
Sister Huan, although I am only an imperial doctor
who does not have an exceptional salary...
but I promise that I will do everything in my power to ensure you a happy, secure life.
I will cherish and protect you,
Prioritize you above all else.
Originally, my visit every half month to examine your family's health
and the opportunity to occasionally glimpse your smiling complexion
was more than enough for me.
But who could have thought...
and I know that,
you really have no wish to participate in the audition.
By saying this, Brother Shichu,
you will ruin the sibling-like affection we have always shared.
I do not have any brothers so
I have always valued you as my real older brother.
I naturally trust that you would treat me with kindness.
Of course, once you find me a sister-in-law,
you will treat her even better.
I may have startled you. But I truly hope you can
avoid the audition.
Not just because of how I...feel about you,
But also because Mr. Zhen once saved my father's life.
- Our families are friends of more than just one generation.- What are they saying?
- That happened long ago.- I don't know either.
It was nothing extraneous, please do not concern yourself over it.
But back then my father was also framed because
of battles within the harem for the Emperor's favour.
He could not isolate himself from their intrigues.
If a mere imperial doctor can end up like this...
If you are selected,
you will be embroiled in their conflicts.
I understand everything you say.
But if I do not go to the audition, Yurao will still need to go one day.
Since my family has no sons, I should at least be a filial daughter.
So pretty! (Cap: Shen Mei Zhuang)
Walk a few steps. Let me have a look.
Here.
Very Nice. Our young mistress walks very elegantly.
The Emperor would approve of a more willowy waist.
Speak a little.
Shen Meizhuang, paying respect to Your Majesty the Emperorand Your imperial Highness the Empress Dowager.
May all fortune and good health come to you.
Good. Very well behaved.
Should His Majesty ask what books you have read?
The Book of Songs, Mencius, Zuo Zhuan.
Wrong.
His Majesty is auditioning for concubines
to fill his Harem with women
who can give him children.
He is not looking for ministers or academic skill.
An ignorant woman is a virtuous one.
Yes. I understand.
(Hall of Health)
Royal Eunuch, here you are.
Hmm. Come here, all of you.
As per order of Hua Fei Niangniang,
in ten days the Hall of Health will host the final rounds of the auditions.(Cap: Huang Gui Quan)
It must be cleaned thoroughly.
Clean and bright.
Should anything go wrong...
You all know how Niangniang is.
Watch your heads very carefully!
We understand, Royal Eunuch.
Now get back to work.
Yes.
Niangniang, please eat something.
Wait another minute.
It has been over ten days since His Majesty last came for a evening meal.
I heard that Hua Fei has already invited him.
I reckon His Majesty will have the meal in her palace tonight.
You will starve yourself, waiting like this.
The audition is in a few days.
His Majesty will doubtless come today.
Your Majesty shows much favor for Great General Nian and his followers.
But the majority of officials prove that
merit is easy to earn, but hard to keep.
You are...cautioning me
against those who would exploit my esteem and take advantage of the service they have rendered, to commit wrongdoings?
Your Majesty is indeed omniscient.
I have perhaps worried needlessly.
I humbly take my leave.
Your Majesty, the tea is cold.
Let me pour you a new cup.
Not necessary.
Your Majesty, Zhou Ninghai from the Palace of Wings is waiting outside.
Hua Fei Niangniang invites you to take meal in her palace.
I will not be going there.
Then Your Majesty would like to...
I will...go see how the Empress is doing.
Yes.
His Majesty is going to the Palace of Benelovent Hope.
Niang Niang, the dishes are getting cold.
I will reheat them.
Heat them when His Majesty arrives.(Cap: The Palace of Wings: Hua Fei's residence)
(Cap: Zhou Ning Hai)
Niang Niang, His Majesty will be...having his meal at the Palace of Benevolent Hope tonight.
Alright.
Niang Niang, do not be angry.
Why would I be angry?
She is, after all, the Empress.
His Majesty should take a few meals with her.
Tonight is not the 15th.(Night of the full moon, which families customarily spend together.
(Only the Empress is the rightful wife; a concubine, no matter how adored,is only a mistress, thus not "family"
in the way a wife is.)
Your culinary skill has improved again.
I'm happy that you like it.
You are Empress now.
Servants can handle the cooking.
Save yourself the trouble.
Although I am Empress, I am still your wife
as a wife, doing something for her husband
cannot be called troublesome.
This soup is flavored tastefully.
Jianqiu
Your Majesty.
Our ancestors have a rule. Never more than three.
Although this duck soup is good,
you have already finished three bowls of it.
If you don't stop now,
it could be half a moon before you will be able to stomach it again.
I am fortunate to have you remind me.
Love fairly; regulate your affections, and it will be prolonged.
With food, as with people.
Is what you want to say.
Your Majesty sees right through me.
Your Majesty favours this dish.Here, have some more.
Silence should be observed during mealtimes and during slumber.
Today's tea is really good. Please have some.
No thank you. I will go to check on Hua Fei.
Take care, Your Majesty.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Come here.
Don't wait outside from now on.
The autumn weather has cooled, you could catch a cold.
Thank you for your concern.
You are new here?
Yes, the Empress appointed me to serve Hua Fei Niangniang.
Not a bad looking girl.
Good enough to serve in your palace.
How old are you?
Seventeen.
So young.
Now that I think about it, you were seventeen when you married me,
back then I was still a Prince.
Your memory is infallible, Your Majesty.
Do be careful.
Han and Man Military Banners, line up accordingly.
Two in a row.
Allow me to remind you young misses.
You have passed numerous rounds of auditions
to be examined personally by His Majesty and the Empress Dowager.
This is a huge honour,
but don't be nervous.
As long as you observe the imperial rules you will all be fine.
Two in a row!
If you are not chosen, His Majesty will announce for your name board to be dropped.
His Majesty will bestow a flower onto you, and you will be allowed to go home.
If you receive a satchel, it means that you are either selected to stay,
or you could be immediately betrothed to someone of noble birth.
But if you are more fortunate, you will become a concubine and enter the Imperial Palace.
In which case you will remain temporarily in your respective homes.
Once you receive your titles, all that is needed is to wait for an auspicious day to enter the Forbidden City.
Everything will depend on your destiny.
Stop.
Continue.
Go
Two in a row!
Han and Man please stand apart.
Two in a row.
What happened? Why are you so late?
How do you do, gugu?  (姑姑 "gūgū" = "paternal aunt", also used for senior servants)
You almost missed it.
If the city gate had closed,
this entire year would have been in vain for you!  (Caption: Ān Língróng)
I live very far,
and I could not find a fast carriage.
That is why I was stalled.
Please forgive me.
Okay. Come inside.
Thanks to GuGu, I made it.
If I had run into someone else, I would not have been so fortunate.
You are very good with words.
Hurry. Follow them at the end.
- Just go. - Thank you, GuGu.
Go. Hurry up.
Mei Jiejie!  ("jiejie" = "older sister" or figuratively)
Huan-er! I had heard that you made it, meimei.
But I never found a chance to see you!
I had hoped that I wouldn't be selected!
Jiejie must have been exhausted to come such a long way.
I have spent my time in the capital recovering,
so I feel much better now.
Now that you are living in your house in the Capital City
Unlike the old days when you lived in your grandparents' home,
We live practically next to each other in comparison,visiting will be no difficult task.
Yes, I often think about
our bond growing up together.
You are dressed so plainly today.
But if you look closely, you are still a beauty.
Pleasing no matter what.
Oh Great Beauty Shen, hardly!
You've become so pretty that
His Majesty will never forget you again once he lays eyes on you.
Wait,
Everyone here is fantastic.
I may not get selected.
Unwanted gossip may arise if others hear us.
Xia Ruhua, daughter of the Magistrate of Jiaxing, is dropped.
Bestow the flower.
Fu Hua, daughter of Deputy Chief Fu An of the Bureau of Letters, is dropped.
Cao Xiangyu, sister of Deputy Minister Cao Biying of Human Resources,
is dropped. Bestow the flower.
Lin Qingyun, daughter of Deputy Officer Lin Tingzheng of the Army,
Which family are you from?
How dare you pour such hot tea on me!
You don't want to live anymore?
In the imperial quarters, so close to His Majesty.
Who dares to be so impudent.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Answer the question. Whose daughter are you!?
My...My name is An Lingrong
My father... My father is...
Are you telling me you don't know your own father's rank?
My father is An Bi Huai, Magistrate of Songyang Town
Just as I expected. An ignorant country girl from some poor, backward village.
Why go looking for shame in the Imperial Palace?
Do you have any idea who you've just offended? She is Baoyi's (3rd highest rank of Royalty) daughter Xia Dongchun
It's my first time in the Palace,
I panicked and made a grave error in splashing hot tea on you, Xia Jiejie.
It was not at all intentional.
Please forgive Lingrong's carelessness.
You have no hope of being selected, even if His Majesty sees you.(Cap: Xia Dong Chun)
What do you have to panic about.
For you to even step foot in the Forbidden City
is already the chance of a few lifetimes!
How dare you dream of getting selected
If Jiejie is still angry
I can offer you a new set of clothes to compensate for the one I ruined.
Compensate?
What you have on right now looks newly made?
Such obvious stitch marks...must have been made in a hurry.
The fabric is Zhihua Silk,
something that has been out of fashion in capital city for quite some time.
This outfit here is made of Suzhou Silk.
Are you planning to pay me back
with those two remarkably plain, silver zanzi in your hair?
Or do you want to pay me backwith these two gold-plated, copper bracelets
that no one would want, even as a gift?
What happened here today was my fault.
Please forgive me.
I can forgive you,
but you must kowtow and beg for my forgiveness.
Only then will I be generous and...forget what happened.
Jiejie, don't make enemies
His majesty would never select a country bumpkin to be his concubine.
But Xia does have a chance of being selected.
Why aren't you kneeling.
It's only a dress.
Xia Jiejie has a soul of benevolence and generosity, this is hardly a matter to get so worked up about.
And you are?
My father is Zhen Yuan Dao, Coordinator of the Supereme Court.
Coordinator of the Supreme Court? Hardly a high ranking official.
Justice belongs to righteousness, not to rank.
Are you trying to boss me around because you think yourself pretty enough to be selected?
Not at all. I am only concerned on your behalf.
Today is the audition for families of the Han military banners.
Jiejie might disturb His Majesty if you continue.
His Majesty's censure is not a matter to be taken lightly.
And even if His Majesty does not hear about this,
should anyone else find out about today's events,
Not only will it undermine your virtuous reputation
but it will also bring shame to the entirety of the Han Military Banners.
I do hope Jiejie will reconsider the stakes at hand before you make a rash decision.
I will remember this.
Your beauty is so indescribably moving thatYOU will be remembered by all who have glimpsed your face today.
- Are you okay? - Thank you for helping me.
I will never forget your kindness.
Please, think nothing of it.
That Miss Xia is not one to take anything lying down.
You incurred her wrath for my sake.I fear that it will bring you distress.
If anyone should be distressed it is her,not me.
I can't believe how reckless you are, did you forget where this is?
This is...?
This is Meizhuang jiejie.
How do you do, Meizhuang jiejie?
No need for formalities here, meimei.
People will scrutinize the attire before the attired.
It is an unfortunate fact, regardless of where you go.
Your attire does lack some slight adornments.
It's not especially surprising that some of them appeared slighting.
Take this pair of earrings as a token of our first meeting.
I can't!
I wish that you receive all your heart desires,and rise above their prejudice.
I thank you for your generosity.
I am but from a humble family with humble connections
I may disappoint your kind intentions.
Origins do not decide a hero's fate.
You have beauty. Why look down on yourself?
Next up: An Lingrong, Yi Bingqing
Jiang Rulin, Dai Yin. Go
Liu Lianzi, Qi Siqin.An audience of six.
Daughter of Magistrate of Songyang Town, An Lingrong
Sixteen
I, An Lingrong, pay my respects to Your Majesty and the Empress Dowager.
I wish you great fortune and glorious peace.
Dropped. Bestow the flower.
I, An Lingrong, appreciate your time.
I wish your majesty and Empress Dowager her highness a healthy, peaceful and joyful life.
Others who were dropped allowed their dissatisfaction to show on their faces,
But you have surprisingly remembered propriety
It is an indescribable honor for Lingrong to come to the Forbidden City
and see the faces of Your Majesty and Empress Dowager Her Highness.
I have been blessed with fortune.
The flower in your hair is a nice touch.
Mother, she already wears a flower
what use would she have for another.
An Lingrong. Nameboard kept. Bestow the sachet
Father, Mother. I got selected.
I finally made it.
I didn't let you down. I got selected
All so vulgar.
Perfection may not exist.
Please consider the next generation of the Imperial family.
She'll do.
Daughter of Baoyi Director, Xia Dongchun. Eighteen.
Interesting name. Keep the name board. (Xia=Summer Dong=winter chun=spring)
Many thanks to Your Majesty
Xia Dongchun. Nameboard kept. Bestow sachet.
Daughter of Coordinater of Jizhou County, Shen Meizhuang
Seventeen
I, Shen Meizhuang, pay respects to your majesty and Empress Dowager her highness.
I wish your majesty countless blessings to accompany an infinite life.
I wish your highness serene peace and precious health.
Have you read any books?
I humbly plead forgiveness for my dullness,
Having only read the "Rules of Women" and "Guidance of Women"
knowing but a few characters.
These two volumes are about women's virtues. Fitting.
Have you read the Four Books?
I have never read them
Ladies should focus on sewing and embroidery.
It's already very good that you can read a few characters.
Thank you, Empress Dowager your highness.
Keep her name.
Shen Meizhuang. Nameboard kept. Bestow a sachet
Daughter of coordinator of Supreme Court, Zhen Huan
Seventeen
I, Zhen Huan, pay respects to your majesty and Empress Dowager her highness.
Wish you all the blessings
Zhen Huan.
Which character is your Huan?
Huan Huan, a twist of a beauty's waist. This is my nickname
Cai Shen's poem
Yes
You are well versed in poetry and literature.
Zhen Yuandao educated his children well.
But I don't know if you deserve that name
Let me see your face.