Episode 46
Xiao Yun Zi can never leave the Forbidden City
I have already arranged for you to serve Lady Hui.
Ping Er will serve Imperial Consort Jing.
Liu Zhu is dead. Huan Bi, if you wishes to stay behind in the palace.
I can also make arrangements for you.
To serve Lady Hui or Imperial Consort Jing.
As for Jing Xi,
You previously served Dowager Empress.
Why don't you go back to serve her?
As for the rest of you
You will be reassigned.
I don't want to serve anyone else. I have already resolved to serve you.
I only have you my Lady, my only kin. Liu Zhu is already dead.
I want to be together with my lady.
and never part.
Why make things difficult for yourself?
Your servant has been able to leave the forbidden city since age 25,
but in this world, your servant is all alone without a family.
therefore your servant and huan bi
want to stay with you my lady
Even if we are in a temple,
at least there would be company.
If you're not afraid of suffering,
I can't bear to be without you guys either.
Little sister
Is this really your only option?
Every day longer that I am in the forbidden city,
will only endanger the princess.
From now on,
Older sister
will be the princess's mother.
Rest assured
I will take care of her as my own
Long Yue is sister's child
Of course you would treat as your own child (saying that she is already the princess's only mother)
I trust that older sister will take care of the princess.
I know. You could have entrusted this child to anyone
to raise
but you entrusted her to my care for my sake because I don't have any children to depend on
I beseech sister to think of old ties
and help me to take care of sister mei
Don't worry about it
Leave right now, before I regret my decision
My lady, the jade shoes that his majesty gave can be brought along
I don't want anything
Just bring some of the usual clothing and item
so that I can bring along my memories
My lady, the items that his majesty gifted
are in this cabinet
Lock it up. The internal affairs department will clear it up
The carriage will be here soon. You should probably change now.
Please make an exception.
Let me have a word with my lady.
Make it quick. We have a schedule to follow.
Huan Er.
My lady, don't worry. Uncle zhen is already much better
and able to eat normally
I believe he has recuperated.
Once my father recover, It won't be convenient for him to remain in the capital
just in case
His majesty has the same sentiment
After your father gets better
he will immediately leave the capital, sent to exile in ninb bo ta
I know
the emperor will not change his mind
since your going
might as well treat this as a relief of burden
Sister you take care. I'm afraid
I will no longer have the chance to see you again
You leaving me alone behind
what meaning is there in staying behind for me
I wish I was sent away together with you
sister don't put it this way
sister as long as you're in the palace
you must be wary of An De Rong and the empress
Don't get emotional because of me
its more important to ensure your own survival
Ok.
Lord Wen. My sister is all alone
I entrust her in your care. Stay safe
Don't fall prey into others's trap
Lady Wan Ping. You take care too
Whenever I get the chance. I will pay you a visit
Once I enter the monastery
My lord you will be somebody from the forbidden palace
please don't come and visit me
if my lord, you really have the heart
please look her the princess on my behalf and sister mei
that is my only wish
your highness please speak no more
let's go
Young mistress, we've arrived.
my lady, the wind in October has already turn cold
my lady has just given bith
its better not to catch a cold
benefactor are you from the palace?
the abbot has already instructed us
to show you inside
Thank you.
you have come
sorry to make you wait
no problem no problem
my name is jing an
instruction came from the palace saying my lady has yet to taken the tonsure
even so
regulation must be abide by
Yes.
now that you have join us
you are no longer a member of the forbidden palace
naturally you must be away from worldly affairs
you can no longer use your name
you should follow the others using the word mo
between your brow you still have a lot of worries
you shall be name mo cho
thank you for the abbot's effort
I shall accept it in my heart
now that you're entering to practice in the monastery, you shouldn't have followers to serve you
but since the palace has given special instruction
as you were a royal concubine previously
sin sin...
since your are the first precedence
the two of you shall stay by the lady side
thank you for understanding abbot
mandarin's dew can quench worldly woes
now that you are away from the red city (referring to forbidden palace)
you should abandon all your woes
this person here is jing bai
she is in charge of all things in this monastery
if you have anything in future, feel free to look for her
its getting late
you should take a rest
thank you abbot for your arrangement
please follow me
this is the place
tidy up the place yourself
my lady have a seat
my lady take a seat first I will go unpack the clothes
what is there to unpack
its just a few clothing items
my lady's Buddhist name is indeed special
mo cho, doesn't sound like the typical Buddhist name
on the other hand it sounds more like lady's name from the harem
the abbot is trying to tell me
since i'm here
I should not dwell on the past
that's true
from now onwards
I can only pray daily
I hope my father, mother, yu rao, rong yu
can be safe
this is my only wish
this is also my only wish
what wrong my lady?
your don't look too good
my lady has just went through labor
i'm afraid its because of the long journey
what should we do
let find some red sugar to mix with hot water
forget it, where can you find red sugar here
I shall bear with it
how can you do that. sickness in confinement cannot be taken lightly
if not well taken care of you might suffer in the long term
how about this
you take good care of my lady, I will go next door to borrow from the other nuns
alright
my lady, you should take a rest
master, do you have red sugar?
can I get some from you?
jing bai master, may I ask if there is any red sugar nearby?
zhen huan lady has just went through labor recently
im afraid because of the journey she has caught a cold
jing bai mast...
what the...
they said there isn't any red sugar
nobody gives a shit about us
the abbot mention previously, this practice originated because of Royal Concubine Su
how fast the abbot has changed her attitude towards us
there's not even hot soup nor hot water available
looks like there another empty room over that side
I wonder which sire lives there
I shall go try my luck again, take good care of my lady in my absense
master...
who are you!
did you just went through labor?
yes I did
it has already been the seventh day
when bother to go through labor for those digusting men
you deserve it
this should be enough for your consumption
stop bothering us with your petite issues
you.. RED SUAGR!?
there's at least 2 jin (1kg)
really...
I thought those that took tonsure are righteous...
how come the nuns here are so obnoxious
they are entirely different from those in the palace
we have been dispose and chase out of the palace
without power nor influence
being cast aside is expected
just now this nun
through her words are spiteful and she appears cold
but she has a warm heart
the princess is really precious and lovely, just like her mother
in future, long yue's mother is concubine jing
I have already
dispose of concubine's wan title and position
chase out of the palace
plant in a monastery outside of the capital to practice
since she has already given birth to the princess
why is she so stubborn
she wants to break ties with me
I shall let her be
that would at least spare the princess from this kind of mother
and learn the wrong things
your right
duan concubine has already raise wen yi princess
jing concubine can be consider a reliable person
oh right your majesty...
after wan consort leaves the palace, there will be fewer imperial concubine
since the birth of the princess this happy occasion
we should promote a few ladies
who do you think is suitable
noble lady qi's father has credit
on top of that he is a Manchu flag noble. she is the right candidate
don't you think that noble lady hui can also be promote
wan ping left the palace because her temperament is stubborn
as your majesty consort, it is of utmost importance that she is understanding, docile and obedient
Noble lady hui is also of stubborn temperament
from the way I see things, she is still not ready to be promote yet
do as you deem fit
what's going on?
smoke all over the place
jing bai nun is distributing the winter's charcoal wood. but there isn't our share
she just threw us some dry wood
and want us to process it charcoal wood
how can this be
no pre made charcoal wood?
yes there is
but is mo cho on order to practice here
or to enjoy here?
jing bai nun
to process the drywood this way, how long will it take us
our lady ever since her labor has yet to recover
can you please make some concession and take care of us for two days
at the very least our lady is here on orders to practice
on order to practice?!
that is just for outsiders to believe
for the people in our monastery
there no need for such words
as the saying goes. you can hide from the higher brass but not to those below
you think we are all idiiots
who doesn't know mo cho is chased out from the palace
I have a better solution
there is tons of firewood back in the woods
you can go ahead and chop down some to make charcoal
this is no palace
you can whatever you want
your lady is no longer an imperial concubine
you got to know where you stand
my lady
rely on yourself instead on other
that's right
my lady has always has a weak constitution
how can you take on this toll
whats more my lady is not used to these chores
no matter how spoil I am . its already a thing of the pass
this bai nun has hinted her displeasure
I cant just watch you guys suffer in silence
I shall do it myself
my lady you shouldn't do this!
don't touch it
since my lady has put it this way
there is nothing that we can say
but this one thing
my lady hasn't recover still yet
if you can move about
go pick up some small twig
for things like chopping of woods and burning them
leave it to us
alright
come
greetings your majesty
get up
ok
take a seat
now that your busy with the harem
don't tire yourself out
thank you mother for your concern
imperial concubine an and qi are they doing well satisfying the emperor?
they are doing great
that is good to hear
its time to place some reliable person close to the emperor
their personality has to be gentle and docile
otherwise they be all like wan consort
that will make his majesty upset
let bygones be bygones
being dispose and leaving the palace
in this lifetime, she wouldn't be able to come back
if you have the time, look out more for the people under you
don't slip up
I will remember mother's teaching
fang ruo
how come fang ruo is with you mother?
isn't she suppose to server his majesty instead?
fang ruo is wan consort's tutor
his majesty held a grudge
thus he replace her
based from her previous performance
I keep her here to serve
oh right
his majesty said that the northern empire because of the winter is in ruin
he's afraid it might affect the coming harvest
let the harem prepare an offering
how does the empress plan to go about it?
the palace always pray in bao hua room
im thinking to wait until spring then make an offering at gan lu temple
one, we can save on the expenditure of hiring nun to come in the palace
two. I can also bring all the concubine out of the palace
to show off our sincerity
are you adamant on going?
I will follow your wishes
oh well
you know what your doing, we shall do it your way
hold it right there
jing bai nun
these firewood that you pick how is it useable?
these firewood must be from hill behind
only judging them from their length and thickness
but their water content is high, they are the most unsuitable for firewood
I thought you are smart from first impression
but who knows your just a stupid woman
I wonder if the ladies from the palace
all lacks the knowledge of survivability
being bask in a life of luxury
chief is right
look at her foxy looks
how would she know how to differentiate the firewoods
she only know how to use her looks to make others pity her
she thinks shes still in the palace
I bet in the palace she just a vixen that smith the emepror
amitaha
gogo...
the sight of you irks me. (she's just jealous -.-)
you pick some more then come back
otherwise no dinner for you
dinner is going to be ready, where are you going?
there is not enough firewood, im going to get some more
you cant just go on an empty stomach
go after you eat finish
forget it, go early come back early
your not in good health let me accompany you
shhhh!! whats wrong??
she pinch you again didn't she?
other humiliate you, don't you know how to retaliate?
im the cause of it
it should be fine after applying some ointment
don't you know you can report to the abbot?
lets not kick up a fuss.
don't say anymore of this
greetings to your majesty
its already so late. what are you guys over here for?
you may rise
thank you your majesty
grant seat
i heard your majesty is busy lately because of the planning for the trip to gan lu temple
i came over specially to see if there is anything that your majesty needs help with
are you worry that i will place qi fu li in gan lu temple?
your majesty is wise. your servant is slow
Indeed my heart has doubt
I'm doing this because I know that in the emperor's heart
still can't let go of Zhen Huan
Zhen Huan has already been expelled from the Palace, her family exiled to Ning Gu Ta.
What else is there to worry about?
With how much attention the Emperor pays to Princess Long Yue, it is a rather unpleasant surprise.
And now even Fang Rou has been shooed out from the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
The Emperor has no one by his side to serve him.
She's only a lowly palace maid. Can hardly be considered a big problem.
Fang Rou was Zhen Huan's ettiquette teacher.
The Emperor is doing this because he can't let go
That's why he doesn't want Fang Rou around him.
Even Hui Precious knows
After Zhen Huan left the palace, the Emperor hasn't wanted to see her.
Even when he goes to Xian Fu Palace to see Concubine Jing.
He wouldn't even consider making a detour to visit the neighboring Hall of Chrysanthemum.
It's just as well that the Zhen family has no relatives in the capital.
Zhen Huan is helpless. Even presuming she wants to return, she won't be able to.
Though that is the case, I still can't help but worry.
Zhen Yuan Dao has good fortunes and has arrived alive at Ning Gu Ta.
Beyond the reach of our power.
Rather, we should properly crush the weeds that are before us.
Your highness show great foresight.
We will leave them behind in our dust.
Jian Qiu, bring me my red jade necklace.
Yes.
Niang Niang
This red jade necklace was a tribute from a foreign country.
I found this color to be young and fashionable
But I'm afraid that it's too flashy for me.
But it seems very suitable for you Imperial Consort Qi
Thank you Empress
This red jade sure smells lovely,
I believe it must be a very special scent.
I wouldn't give you guys something that's isn't good.
Since Huan Er left the capital
You have been very low spirited.
It's been 3 months since we've bid farewell.
I'm worried about Huan Er's situation outside the palace.
If it's possible, I am willing
To visit on your behalf, my lady
However, Gan Lu Temple is a temple where numerous nun's reside
Even if I wanted to go, I am unable to.
If someone questions you
Say that I ordered you to go
It seems like I will not be able to leave this Forbidden City.
I hope you can visit her frequently.
I humbly accept your order.
Of course, you also need to avoid arousing suspicion
Don't stay for too long
Yes, I understand.
Aiya!
My lady, your frostbite is starting to relapse again.
This year, it seems to be swelling even more.
It seems like there are some things that you can't forget even if you want to.
Just like this frostbite. Relapses every year.
This pair of hands is full of frostbites
Red, blue, purple
My lady, look. These red ones are coral
The blue ones are Green Jade
And these purple ones are Amethysts.
When this lowly servant first entered the palace,
I was a lowly palace made who made wine and swept floors。
As we were new to the palace, it was inevitable to be bullied.
During winter, we had to wash the older maid's cloths
Our hands were full of frostbite
At that time, Empress Chun Yuan
was still Prince Yong's legal first wife.
When she came to greet the Dowager Empress
When she saw my hands, she said you pitiful girl
Your hands have become so frostbitten but how come you're still washing cloths
So then,
Internal affairs transferred me to do other jobs
But lucky that at the time I learnt how to do these heavy chores
Or else, I won't be able to serve you well right now my lady.
Here, let me help you.
You shouldn't
Little sister Huan
Lord Wen
How can you do these heavy chores?
I'm only someone who's in training.
What is there I can't do?
It's enough, it's enough
There's already enough water for today.
Today's water?
Don't tell me, that you're being worked this hard everyday?
Everything
Is done by ourselves for our own gain
This is nothing
Everyday, my lady has to join us in chopping wood and warming water.
Washing cloths, cooking
I don't mind me and Jin Xi working
Cause it is our duty
However, our lady's hands
It's nothing
Let me see. Let me see.
Lord Wen
Please allow me.
Here, rub some on.
Here, allow me
Allow me.
Since I've left the palace
Is sister Mei well?
Is Long Yue well?
You promised me
that you would look after them
My lady and the princess are all well
My lady is worried about you so she thought of a way to allow me to visit you.
As long as they're well, then I can be at ease.
I don't have any other talents
Whomever you wish for me to take care of
I will do my best to make sure that they are well cared for.
Many thanks
You and I don't need to say thanks
There's only this much of this medication left.
You will have to make do with this for now
I will bring some better ones with me the next time I visit
Many thanks.
Hurry up your with your work
Hurry up
Make sure to clean the temple rooms and the gardens properly
It's this late and you've only just returned from chopping wood?
You must have gone to be lazy somewhere
Bring over the bucket
Go
Scrub the floor of the temple rooms clean
Scrubbing the floor is the most tormenting job
Can't straighten your waist. Can't lift your head either.
The temple is also so expansive
After a few hours all the bones in the body feel like they've scattered
It seems like Jing Bai sure knows how to torment people
I heard in a few days
We're praying for a prince and princess from the palace.
Mo Cho also gave birth to a princess
She doesn't have a place in the prays
Her? She's a abandoned slut
She's even more lowly than us. As if she's worthy enough to go pray.
So right.
Jin Xi, I'm fine
It's me.
Duke Guo
I came late
When did you return?
Three days ago
Emperor brother ordered me to return to the capital.
This place isn't convenient to talk
Let us find a place to talk
I never got to say thank you to you
I felt very guilty
I only did what I could do
But I wasn't even much help
I feel very ashamed
If you mention thanking me again
I will feel even more guilt ridden
I ended up in this position because I'm not the type of person who want to cause harm to a person.
Because you helped the Zhen family deliver our letter
You've were sent off to Mukden Palace (Shenyang Imperial Palace).
This few month
I'm the one who has caused troubles for you
Please don't say that
Since my return to the capital, Emperor brother has treated me like he always has.
I'm still Duke Guo.
Things are no different from before.
You don't need to worry about it.
My trip to Mukden Palace this time
It's just like that time when I was sent to Shu Zhong (a place in shi chuan province)
Just sight seeing.
It's called reflecting one's action as an excuse only
It's just a bluff
But it's still due to troubles caused by my family
If you continue to say this,
I won't dare to tell you why I'm here today
Please speak my lord.
Two days ago when I was at the Palace.
I suddenly met one person
So thus, I returned and drew a portrait.
My lady, please help me evaluate
and advise me on my technique.
I'm no expert at calligraphy drawing
How would I be able to advise you my lord?
This is Imperial Consort Jing.
This is sister Mei.
This is
My first time meeting Princess Long Yue
So I drew this portrait
This is to express my gratitude at being her royal uncle.
It's only been such a short time
Long Yue has grown so big already
Children always grow particularly fast
I hear that in a while
Princess Long Yue will turn one
I thought that my lady, you being the mother of Princess Long Yue
will naturally want to know how your own child is doing.
My lord, your picture is better than a stranger's thousand spoken words.
Thank you your highness for your kindness
I very fond of Princess Long Yue
Luckily my humble pen are able to draw some decent strokes.
How about this. In the future,
I'll bring you a drawing every two month
And let lady to evaluate.
My lady, what do you think about this idea?
Many thanks.
Over there is the Piao Miao Peaks (It is a peak in Shan Xi province that is a major attraction for tourists).
My summer home is over there.
Every month, I usually spend ten or so days there
In the future, if there's anything you need help with my lady
just send someone over to inform me.
I will do what I can
To be able to see this drawing of Princess Long Yue
I'm already very touched. I have nothing more to ask for.
I say this because
There is something I would like your ladyship to help me with
When Princess Long Yue turns one
there will be a celebration feast in the palace.
At that time, I hope your ladyship will be able to lend me a helping hand
As her royal uncle, I need to
present her with some cloths as a birthday gift
How every my embroiderers
aren't very talented
so I can only ask for your assistance with this my lady.
Really?
Can I really personally make cloths for Long Yue?
You're her mother,
it's only natural the cloths you make will fit her the best.
Written on this piece of paper are the measurements of Long Yue
Five days before Long Yue's birthdate,
I will personally come collect it
I will await here for your ladyship.
It is still early,
even if you take time making it, you will be able to make it in time.
Long Yue is clever and cute
She's very affectionate with you
Most definitely.
I heard when Long Yue first came here, she couldn't drink her fill of milk.
Cause of this, Imperial Consort Jing got so angry at the wet nurse.
And then, even though a new wet nurse was hired,
However, Imperial Consort Jing still personally
made sure that the princess was well fed and lulled the princess to sleep.
It's only natural that the princess is so affectionate to Imperial Consort Jing isn't it?
The Princess's closest person is Your Majesty
Your Majesty please look. Even though I am holding her,
however her little eyes are always looking towards you Your Majesty.
You're right, she is always looking at us.
Children always very closely resemble both parent.
When the Princess looks at Your Majesty, she's also seeing herself.
Her eyebrows and nose resembles us,
the rest of her features all look more beautiful than us.
You're right. Princess Long Yue's mouth and chin
really resembles Lady Wan. It looks near the exact same.
Who did you say she looks like?
I...I said the Princess resembles her mother.
The Princess only has one mother.
and no other.
Your Majesty, please cease to be angry. I understand my error.
I will never make this error again.
We welcome Royal Empress. We welcome all Young Mistresses.
You can all rise.
Yes.
How goes all the preparations for the prays?
All has been prepared properly.
My ladyship, please enter the main hall and light the incense.
Please lead the way master.