Episode 61
Greetings to Empress
What happened to your face?
I did something wrong
Fei Wen, stop watering the flowers. Go get this month's money.
Yes
Fei Wen
- Where are you going? - Jian Qiu
Huan Bi asked me to get money from Imperial Household
Is that so? I'm going too. Let's go together.
The Board of Rites gave our princess three titles. Which do you like?
The Board of Rites naturally chooses the best words. It's all the same.
Our princess has a mild temper. In contrast, Hongyan is mischievous.
But I think Hongyan's pleasant and cheerful temper is good.
Hongshi always lacks vigor and is afraid of seeing me.
Emperor wants to be a strict father, so you can't blame your son being afraid of seeing you
I promise you, I will be a benevolent father in front of them.
You should also think of a good name for our baby princess.
Although two lovers are separated
Their hearts beat as one
Shall we call her Lingxi?
Lingxi? Lingxi
You and I have chemistry for the past ten years
Our baby shall be titled Princess Lingxi
Your Majesty. Your Lady Highness.
It's time to feed Prince and Princess
The wet nurses have to bring them out
Ok
Yes
Huanbi has followed you for many years
She seems to look more and more like you
You've said that before
You said that her eyes look like mine
Her good looks are incomparable to you in the past
Even though her eyes are like yours
Nevertheless, she's just a servant. Now that she has grown older,
her character has become similar to yours.
What has happened to you today?
Singing praises of my servant. Aren't you afraid it might cause a rumour?
You're already a mother. Yet you've become petty?
If she wasn't your private servant, I might not even have sung her praises
It's just that Huanbi reminded me of Longyue
She has grown and becoming more and more like you
When she's much older, I'll let her come back
So that you and her can be reunited
Longyue, do you like this little rabbit?
Mother, I want a little tiger
It's too difficult to cut a little tiger. I don't know how
Mother knows. Mother knows everything.
Ok, for my Longyue, I'll learn to do everything. I'll try it now.
Greetings to Niangniang
Rise
Thank you Niang niang
Gui Fei Niang Niang said she hasn't been free the past few days. Since the weather is fine today,
she wishes to invite you over.
- Ok, you may leave first. I'll go over soon. - Yes
Niang Niang, do we need to bring Princess Longyue?
Longyue, wait here for me. I'll be back soon.
- Coax Longyue to nap. I'll be back soon. - Yes
Jing Fei has arrived
Gui Fei Niang Niang
Have a seat
It's a rare chance to be free today
We should have a nice chat
Gui Fei Niang Niang is busy taking care of your twins
and taking charge of the trivialities in the Imperial Harem. Don't you wish you had more time?
How would I dare to come and disturb?
Jiejie has now come to call me Niang Niang. Have we become estranged?
Even though Meimei doesn't mind, we should still follow the rules of hierarchy.
Taking over of Hua Gui Fei's position as Xi Gui Fei
You truly deserve the honour
If we talk about etiquette and experience,
don't you think you can become Gui Fei too?
Aren't they all the same?
I still remember when you left the palace, Emperor once mentioned you
He sang praises of when he first met you
He said your smile was breathtakingly beautiful
He hasn't forgotten you all these years
Who isn't beautiful when they're young?
But time catches up with us too fast
It's only a matter of time when he is sick of our aged looks
Whether or not women in the Imperial Harem live a good life
is of unimportance
Fortunately, Emperor has you in his heart
Jiejie has always been intelligent
and sees all matters clearly
Since you know Emperor treats me very well,
then why do you want to challenge and oppose me?
You know it already
You must have told Empress about the relationship between Jinxi and Su Peisheng
They're both discreet
The only loophole is that jade piece
It has been once spotted by Jiejie as Jinxi's handicraft
Other than I, it's only you and Meizhuang who were present that day
And during those days, you have made frequent trips to Jingren Palace
Gui Fei Niang Niang is very smart
Since you have already known, then why ask?
It's good that you already know
Saves me the trouble of worrying
I've done you harm this time. It's my fault.
Jiejie doesn't fight for Emperor's favour, and doesn't do evil
In the past, even under Hua Fei's power, you could give in in order to survive
Whatever you've done now
is just to keep Longyue at your side
If not for Longyue, I'm afraid my life would be meaningless
Meimei, since your entrance, Emperor has always favoured you
How would you understand my loneliness?
Do you know?
My palace has a total of 326 bricks
But I've touched them all umpteenth times
Lines have started to form in 31 of them
If not, how could I have survived through these lonely nights?
Actually, I knew it all along
that I'm just a pawn of Emperor to divide Hua Fei's power
You've never mentioned this to me
When you asked me to look after Longyue,
I not only have someone to rely on,
but also have someone to spend my time with
Throughout these years
I have always treated Longyue as my own
I've never imagined that you will return
And you still returned?!
Did you know
I didn't investigate your deed at Jingren Palace
It's Empress who leaked the news on purpose
If she really treated you well, she wouldn't have let anyone know what you've said to her
But the news spread to my ears
Think carefully
Empress wants to let you know on purpose. She wants the two of us to be in dispute.
Meimei, please believe me
I didn't harm you on purpose
I only wanted Longyue to be with me for a few more years
Just a few more years
I've promised Empress
I'm only doing harm this once. Just this time.
But then
I still fell into her trap
Whether it's using me against you, or you against me
it all benefits Empress
It's not that you haven't thought carefully
You risked just for Longyue
A loving mother willingly does anything for her child
It's either you or Empress
I've no other choices
I have nothing to say anymore
I will accept any punishment that Xi Fei Niang Niang gives
In that case, please help me take care of Longyue
until she marries
But- but she's your flesh and blood. How would you bear to?
My time is all used to take care of Hongyan and Lingxi
Longyue treats you as her real mother
If I were to force her to be with me, then I would have killed our mother-daughter relationship
With your words, I will love and care for Longyue with all my heart
Jiejie loves Longyue with all your heart
Even as a biological mother, I don't think I can do better
Your help in taking care of Longyue
means that I am able to save all my three children
Thank you
On the Royal Decrees of His majesty
Xi Fei Niuhulu being virtuous and modest
Under the edict of Empress Dowager, promoted as Xi Gui Fei
Gratitude for His Majesty's benevolent grace
Thank you, Emperor
Emperor arrives!
- Greetings to Your Majesty - Rise - Thank you
What has brought Emperor here?
I can't wait to see you. I'd rather accompany you than wait at Jingren Palace.
Today is an important day, the more we should watch our manners. Emperor please leave first, I will follow suit
Must you be so strict on rules all the time?
I dare not break the rules in the past, the more I should follow the rules now
You said this when we first met too
You still remember
I'll never forget
Xi Gui Fei Niuhulu blessed by the heaven to serve within the palace
May you be well-behaved, live in harmony within the harem, serve the Emperor well and continue the family line
Grateful for Your Majesty's advice
Xi Gui Fei is smart and thoughtful
Since Empress hasn't been feeling well
You should retire
I have decided to let Xi Gui Fei deal with matters of the Six Palaces
She shall take charge of all trivalities. What do you think?
That's great. However, although my health is poor,
she still has to take care of her children
and Longyue has to return to Yongshou Palace soon
I'm afraid she doesn't have the time
She and I have decided
to let Jing Fei raise Longyue
There's no need to move
And the wet nurses will take care of Hongyan and Lingxi to take the load off Xi Gui Fei
So I've worried too much
But she's new in taking charge of the Six Palaces
though there aren't much to deal with, they aren't small matters
I'm afraid she may be stressed
What Empress said is right. I'm still young and inexperienced
Duan Fei entered the earliest, while Jing Fei has some experience
I'm keen to learn from them
That's good
Does Empress have anything else to add?
Xi Gui Fei, in future you are the head of all concubines
Not only do you have to manage the harem well, you also have to serve the Emperor well
and bear more imperial heirs
I will not let you down
You've kneeled too long. Hurry rise
Thank you
Make good use of your gold pendant
It's not just a piece of stone anymore
I've to change. Shall Emperor and Xi Gui Fei leave for
Chong Hua Palace to receive congratulatory note first
A husband's passion is like hot liquer, a wife's wish is like soft silk
Hot liquer may cool, but silk is everlasting
May Emperor's love for Xi Gui Fei be everlasting like silk
Emperor, please drink up
Sure
Congratulations Xi Gui Fei
Everyone take your seat
I'll go to your palace tonight
It's Hongyan and Lingxi's full month celebration today. I'm afraid Longyue may be jealous
Why don't Emperor go to Jing Fei's palace instead?
Longyue will be elated
Ok then
I must treat Longyue fair too
The water Lady is using is made of the best rose petals
Your hands will become soft and silky after using
- Where's Hongyan and Lingxi? -They are being nursed right now
Lady, there are too many gifts to handle
You've good taste. Just choose those you like
Duke Kangjin has given a bamboo fan made of illuminated raw silk of a fawn
What's special is that its handle is as cold as jade
Also, Pei Guo Gong Fu has sent a pair of ivory chopsticks
Though silver chopsticks can also detect poison, they aren't as rare as this
The most evil are those who use poison. They're hard to prevent.
I appreciate his sincerity
Is his surname Meng?
Yes
His daughter Meng Jingxian was the one betrothed to 17th Prince
I wonder if she's married now
She hasn't. She only has heart for 17th Prince
She has become an old maid
Does she think that she will be able to marry 17th Prince if she waits?
There are so many girls who admire 17th Price
I'm afraid he doesn't even know how she looks like
Why are you so agitated
and mean?
I just can't stand her
As if she isn't afraid others don't know she's waiting for 17th Prince
An embarrassment to him
These gifts are all the same
Keep the common ones to reward others in future
Others are not worthy of a mention, but look at this red coral bracelet given by 17th Prince
It's exquisite
Though this beautiful coral is in my hands
I can never own it as someday it will go to a better person
Lady
Since Emperor is staying at Jing Fei's Palace tonight
and Mei Jiejie isn't feeling well, let's go visit her
Greetings to Xi Gui Fei
Stop
Greetings to Ning Guiren
What pleasant mood. Are you out for a stroll?
Just walking around
I'll hug my cat to sleep when I'm back later
Your cat is adorable
Has it grown?
If you're interested, please come to my palace to take a look
Can Niang Niang give me the honour?
Yet, Niang Niang is followed by many servants
I'm afraid my cat will be frightened
Niang Niang should know that it's the cat's purr that's interesting
It's a beautiful night. It would be a pity if I decline your invitation
Huanbi, come
What a rare invitation
I shall go then
All of you stay here
What do you want?
Be careful of this dagger
I've once been injured by a leopard
I sneaked into its nest
and cut its throat
If Huanbi screams
then this dagger
will make a slit through Xi Gui Fei's throat
Don't frighten Huanbi
You've lured me here
yet allowed Huanbi to follow
I bet you've a foolproof plan
Niang Niang is wise
Even if I accidentally killed you and your servant
It's Jiaolu Palace nearby
I can make Qi Guiren the scapegoat
Since she already wishes to kill you
I can make her wish come true
Aren't you and I enemies since a long time ago?
If not why would you let your cat lead so many other cats
to come get me and my children's lives?
Since you've guessed it correct
then why keep your cool for so long?
I don't want to make things difficult for you
You're Emperor's favourite consort
I don't worth your killing because of 17th Prince
because of 17th Prince
You knew
You love pink siris flowers more than your life
and someone also told me
there was once when your life was imperil
it's he who summoned an imperial physician to save you
But if he knew he saved an evil girl
he would be disappointed
He saved you once! But you're evil
You don't deserve admiring 17th Prince
You aren't this agitated when I said I was about to kill your Lady
What happened to you when we mentioned 17th Prince?
You
Demon
Yes I'm a demon
That makes Xi Gui Fei the head of all demons
Since you've had an affair at Ganlu Temple, why sought the love of Emperor again
and returned to his side?
Is fortune more important than the love of 17th Prince?
Ever since I met him,
I knew he is the most chivalrous man on earth
I've never seen him in such pain and misery
Since your return to the palace,
my suspicion has rose
until the evening of Mid-Autumn celebration
You were the one who was eavesdropping
So what? You think I can't admire him too?
I feel you don't deserve to admire him at all
If I killed you, there will be one less unfaithful woman on earth
If she's hurt anywhere
17th Prince will be devastated
All these years, only 17th Prince treats me the best
So anyone who makes him upset shall all die
If you killed me, it will only upset him more
It's not that I want to kill you
It's all faithful ones out there
Have you ever known
that being unfaithful is sometimes more difficult than staying faithful?
Where is this from?
This red coral bracelet
is a precious piece that 17th Prince attained from South China Sea
He's never given to anyone
Why is it with you?
You should ask him instead
17th Prince, you don't owe her anything
why are you obsessed with her?
Forget it
Since he has given his heart to you
if you still have some conscientious
you should feel guilty
His little empathy towards me
maybe be nothing to you
But to me
it's incomparable warmth and love
I'll let you go this time
as a form of repayment to his kindness
She's insane
Forget it. Ning Guiren also someone grateful
Xi Gui Fei is blessed
Her twins
have earned her a life of good fortune
It's not a feat to bear children
if she can't raise them up
Qi Meimei seems to put it so simply
Of course
An Pin Jiejie is not the same
Hui Pin avoids you since her pregnancy
If you go to Xi Gui Fei's Palace,
then can her children still live?
Shut up!
All you know is talk
but don't know how to keep Emperor pleased
Qi Guiren, ever since you're freed from grounding
you haven't been able to get Emperor's favour
An Pin, you've been trapped by astronomical signs for so long
but aren't able to save yourself
You can't help me
yet still create internal conflict
What's the use of keeping the two of you here?
Try harder
If not this harem will be controlled by Zhen Huan
How dare this shrew fight for power with me?
An Pin, you come from a lowly background
and yet in the same position as me for so long
I've tolerated enough
Lady, calming medicine is ready
Have a good night after drinking
Baojuan
My voice
What happened to my voice?
Lady, what happened?
My voice... I can never sing again
Baojuan
Lady, there must be someone who wants to harm you
Lady, I must report to Empress
I'll go ask her for help
Baojuan, you mustn't go
I earned Emperor's favour all based on my voice
If someone found out
then Emperor would never like me again
When that happens, I'll be a useless pawn
A useless pawn
Baojuan, remember, I've only caught a cold
I'll recover very soon
Understood
Look, Niang Niang
Sister
Yurao
Young Mistress
Greetings to Niang Niang
Yurao, let me take a look at you
We have been separated for years, we should be happy now
Why are you crying?
Bi Jiejie
Young mistress has grown taller
In order to please Niang Niang,
Emperor has invited Niang Niang's family into the palace
He also allowed
young mistress to stay in the palace
to accompany Niang Niang
Where are my parents?
Are they coming?
Old master is still recovering
Emperor has allowed your parents to come to Beijing Capital
So as to give you a peace of mind
Young mistress has traveled without stopping to come first
I believe
your parents will arrive very soon
I'm grateful for Emperor's kindness
But my father is still a criminal
Although Emperor shows mercy
and allowed my parents to return
but what's the point
It only caused them tireness and distress
Although Emperor has recovered your father's position
but he has already employed workers to renovate your old house
to renovate your old house
in order to let them stay in the Capital
until their old age
I understand
I will thank Emperor tomorrow
You may leave
Yes. There's one more thing
17th Prince said
as a gift for your promotion,
excluding other gifts,
he will give all pink siris from Ninghui Tang
to you
He also said
these flowers can sooth the mind and body
Niang Niang can admire them
or add them into porridge in future
Just don't waste it
I appreciate his sincerity
Please thank him on my behalf
This prince has an exquisite taste
He doesn't give common gifts
such as gold and jade
Young mistress has only visited the palace briefly
Actually 17th Prince
still has many other unique skills and interests
When Niang Niang was away
I have already asked the servants
to clear and tidy a room
for Young Mistress to stay in
That's good
Let's all go in
Then Servant leaves first
You've read a whole night
It's hard on you
Xi Gui Fei is busy taking care of her twins
and is not free to serve Emperor
There are many other young consorts in the harem
You should go visit them too
I've heard that An Pin ate something wrong
and ruined her voice
I'm afraid she won't be able to sing again
Such a pity
Initially it's nothing but a cold
and thought she'll recover soon enough
But the medicine hurt her throat instead
I'm afraid she won't be able to speak properly in future
Let her rest well then
I haven't visited Hui Pin in a while
Now that Huan Huan has given birth
There's still Meizhuang's good news
Jiejie
Who is it?
Stop
Greetings to Xi Gui Fei
Long time no see
Have you forgotten me?
That's not the case
But you've become much thinner
I believe you've suffered a lot
I'm used to suffering
and being despised
I'm not afraid of bitterness
Emperor has adviced Meimei to recover in your palace
so as to prevent trouble
Why have you come out?
Others think I'm a jinx
But you know me better
that I'm not truly a jinx
I'm meant nothing
Why do you think
you're a jinx?
The way you belittle yourself
upsets me
Since you aren't well
why still come out?
The state you're in today
is because you've worried too much
I come from a lowly background
I can't help to feel sorry for myself
in comparison to the other concubines
Only I can help myself
That's good
Just don't harm others blindly and risk your life
Greed is a bottomless pit
It can end your life
Nowadays
no one is more powerful than you
There's no one as helpless as me
Jiejie is the most powerful in the harem now
If you help me,
I will be saved
I won't have to worry if you can help me
Thanks for your reminder
I still remember
how you treated me in the past
thus I will help you as much as I can
I'll never let you down
Me too
Seems that her voice
is really ruined
I wonder if it's the works of heaven or of man
Lady, she has lost favouritism now
Why don't we...
silence her in secret
Within the harem, death is the easiest way out
She has Emperor's favour for many years and she's obstinate
Now that she lost His favour
It's worse than death for her
Understood
I will let all the palaces know about this
and let them treat An Pin nicely
What are you doing?
Wrecking havoc here
Stop
We're doing this for you
Even Emperor thinks you're unlucky
We have made a trip to Bao Huan Dian specially
to get talisman and holy water
Continue
Don't forget the blankets and closet
What are you doing?
Stop it
Are you out of your mind?
Even if Lady is unlucky,
you've no right to come and make nonsense
An Pin's bad luck has affected the Six Palaces
So anyone has the right to take things into their hands
How would talisman work without burning?
Hurry burn them
Lady, Zhen Pin and Kand Chang Zai
have gone to Yanxi Palace
Does Empress know?
I think so
But she made no comments
Nevermind, there will be more nonsense in future
Lady, there is no more charcoal
Can you carry a hot water bottle first?
We're only left with a little hot water
We still need them for drinking and washing
We don't have enough to make a heated bottle
It's snowed again
It's getting colder
I've helped you added as many blankets as I can
If not for the medicine, we would have frozen to death
If we freeze to death
would anyone know?
Lady
How is An Pin?
Zhen Pin and I miss you
What are you doing here again?
Since we're sisters,
knowing that you lack charcoal,
we've brought you some specially
Bring it
Ignite
Without charcoal
how are you going to get through this winter?
You've to understand one thing
that time has changed
We don't have any good charcoal
Please bear with what you get
Stop it, we're choking
Hurry, ignite them. It won't heat if you don't
In the name of the owner of Yanxi Palace
I order you to leave
Stop all your nonsense
Do you think you are still a favoured consort?
Save it
Your state right now
is worse than my servant
Stop ordering us
What's all this nonsense
Empress Dowager is sick and needs to rest
Who dares to make noise here?
Empress has heard of what happened in Yanxi Palace
Here's her order: As servants of Yanxi Palace
are unable to protect their Lady
They shall be fined one month's salary
Servants of Kang Chang Zai and Zhen Pin
being unable to prevent their Ladies of mischief,
shall be fined three months' salary
Yes
Hurry leave
Lady please put your mind to rest
Although Niang Niang is also in trouble,
she has never forgotten you
Here's the blankets and charcoal
Please get through this winter at ease
Thank you Her Majesty
Baojuan, accept them
Yes
Ever since Lady lost her voice
Empress hasn't mentioned you
You should think of a new solution
Niang Niang
Is everything settled?
Yes
What's the point of improving on perfection?
It's better to give when it's most needed
I've said everything to An Pin
Hope she understands
When one has no other choices,
one has nothing to lose
This is a lesson for her
Since Qi Gui Ren has already made her move
An Pin will never recover her voice anyway
Why don't I end it all for her?
Even Ning Gui Ren's parrot can sing poems
She should think of an alternative
Empress is wise