~ Episode 19 ~
His majesty has arrived
You may all rise
Thank you Your Majesty
What is worth arguing about?
I heard that someone disobeyed your orders
so I came to investigate
Greetings Your Majesty
Why are you here?
I was talking inside with Pin of Respects
Respects to Princess of Glory
Why are you here?
Where should I be?
I was just keeping Pin of Respects company
I was just looking for young mistress
So you went to Pin of Respect's
The things young mistress prepared for Promise Shen
servant already brought over.
Just now, when I was in Pin of Respect's main hall, I heard a huge commotion
I thought something big had happened
Princess of Glory is not at Hall of Cool and Refreshing
What are you doing here?
I heard someone had entered Xianyue Pavilion without permission
to visit the grounded Promise Shen.
So I came to check
Do you have the Empress's command?
I came here in a rush
so I didn't have time to ask for her command yet.
When I confined Promise Shen I said
that without my permission, no one is allowed to visit her.
Did you forget?
I...
Then what are the results of your search?
The head servant lady Fang Ruo blocked me,
so I didn't have a chance to yet...
Very good!
Worthy to be my servant!
Servant cautiously obeys Your Majesty's orders, I dare not violate
Your Majesty, Princess of Glory has always handled matters resolutely
She must have evidence if she came
Why don't we go check Xianyue Pavilion
On one hand, Niang Niang's trip won't be in vain
On the other hand, have a clear conclusion
What does Your Majesty think?
Promise Shen is suffering confinement
If she's also accused of violating imperial decree
and disobeying Your Majesty,
I really can't bear the thought of it.
Your Majesty, please send people to check Xianyue Pavilion
to clear her name.
Although Promise Shen is confined for a crime,
she must not be disgraced for something she didn't do.
Su Pei Sheng
Servant here
Bring some people inside to take a look
Yes
Duke, this small boat is the only way
to travel back and forth the lake.
I will take Duke to the island at the center of the lake
Why are there so many lotus lanterns on the lake?
Last night was ghost's festival
These lotus lanterns were used for prayer
How could these lotus lanterns compare
to the real lotus flower?
By now, the real lotus flowers are almost all withered
Then, I have more reason to look at the flowers that haven't withered yet
This...
Everyone go back
I will row the boat over myself
Duke, if the emperor found out,
he would blame us for not serving you well.
It's not imperial brother's first day knowing me
It's not a problem. Go back to your own chores.
Ajin, you go back too
Yes
Replying to Your Majesty,
aside from Promise Shen and several maids,
no one else is inside.
I am terrified to have listened to others' false information
causing today's misunderstanding.
I really hope Your Majesty will forgive me
I know
Rumors and disputes never stop in the harem
You have helped manage the six palaces for so many years
You should know what's trivial and what's important
My oversight, please forgive me Your Majesty
I thought that you had changed after contemplating behind closed doors
but you're even more impetuous than before!
I originally wanted to reinstate your power over the six palaces
but after today, that seems entirely unnecessary!
Go back to your palace
Stop causing so much trouble!
Thanks Your Majesty for your kindness
You're not allowed to visit Princess Wenyi again
to avoid corrupting my daughter.
Your Majesty, I still have a request of you
Speak
I was thinking
that Promise Shen has been confined for so long, and has always followed the rules.
Could Your Majesty please remove half the guards?
First, it's really unnecessary to waste so many palace guards here
Second, there are many women
It's inconvenient to have guards here
Their presence makes us uneasy
That's fine
She lives in your palace. Take the trouble to look after her.
I obey. I will take my leave now.
It's good that you weren't implicated
I wouldn't put myself in dangerous situations
or want to violate your orders.
Emperor leaves
I was careless in the moment, actually falling into your trap!
Careless or not, you know the clearest
You set me up today
Not taking you down earlier
was my mistake!
Niang Niang jokes
We're all sisters in serving the emperor
If he hears this,
he will be angry again.
Of course you're pleased right now, currently being in favor
Unfortunately, under my watch,
I will absolutely not tolerate a scheming person like you!
To tolerate or not is up to you
Whether I can make Niang Niang tolerate me is my skill
The days are still long, we will wait and see!
Go back to palace!
His Majesty orders
that half the guards at Xianyue Pavilion be removed.
Your troops can leave
Yes
These are rewards from Precious Smile
some tea money
Then we...
Don't worry
Pin of Respects knows how hard you've worked
She's even prepared some tea and snacks
Pin of Respects is kind
But we're on duty
How could we eat?
So what?
Your hard work here
Pin of Respects has seen.
In the future, if you do a good job,
Pin of Respects can put in some good words for you before the emperor.
Auntie is right
Then we cannot decline
Alright, then let's go together
Alright
You will also receive rewards after you're done eating
Alright, brothers, let's go
Young mistress surmised correctly
Not long after young mistress and Liuzhu left,
she left through the side hall's back door
and went to Precious Cao's.
Young mistress
Do you want servant to arrest her?
No need, act as if nothing happened
Yes
You can go back
I will personally question her
Yes
When young mistress returns, it shouldn't draw anyone's attention
I take my leave
Help me change
Vile woman!
Colluding with Zhen Huan to trick me!
Niang Niang don't upset yourself
Those two are obviously collaborating,
pretending to surrender to deceive me!
Yes, I was also careless in this matter
allowing that pitiful-looking Huanbi to trick us.
You are usually very careful
Today, how come you told me this news
as soon as you heard it?
I am always thinking of Niang Niang
I was only thinking of Precious Smile's disrespect towards you
If she's not eliminated early, she will only become a future threat
Then I've troubled you
Niang Niang
Smell this Huanyi fragrance and cool your temper
No matter how angry the emperor is,
it's only because he cares about you too much.
I'm just afraid that he only sees the new people smile, not the old people cry
Auntie
Now happens to be the time when the guards change shifts
Just now, I sent away half the guards
the rest also lower their guard
I put some drug into the food
they are sleepy now
The door is open, servant will follow young mistress
you go back first, quietly, don't attract anyone's attention
Yes
Jiejie
your hands are so cold
Not too bad
Fangruo Gugu always says you are fine
I was not believing
now I saw you, I can be relieved
I'm very well, but I'm worried you
Two young mistresses, servant will watch outside
please be quick
This place is no longer the Xianyue Pavilion of the past
But you still have status
Those servants are too unreasonable
Princess of Glory is in power
Those servants in the palace
follow the way the wind blows,
habitually insulting me.
If Fang Ruo didn't secretly look out for me,
I wouldn't even make it to today.
Even servants
don't use this kind of candle.
The fumes are so strong
It's alright, my heart is already dim enough
If I don't see more light, wouldn't it be total blackout?
Jiejie don't worry
I will definitely implore His Majesty to release you soon
I heard Fangruo say
that you weren't implicated by me.
I feel much more relieved
Fortunately you still have Lingrong
You're not too isolated
Right, does His Majesty like Lingrong very much?
Yes
Although you have her, but if anything comes up,
you must still make decisions yourself.
I'm fine. I'm just worried about you.
You must take good care of yourself
You heard the commotion outside just now
Finally took out some anger for you
I heard
But...she's not that easy to deal with
Fortunately His Majesty still trusts me
Jiejie's pregnancy...
what exactly happened?
Everyone says I faked the pregnancy to gain favor
Even you don't believe me?!
With the favor I was getting back then, I would have been pregnant sooner or later
Why would I need to fake it?
They intentionally made you think you were pregnant
then fabricated the evidence.
I'm afraid that from the moment Doctor Jiang gave you the prescription,
to Liu Ben,
it was all deliberately arranged.
They had set me up from the beginning
using my desire for children to lure me into their trap!
It's all my fault...for being so useless
Until Fuling showed up with the bloodied pants,
I actually didn't know
that I was not pregnant at all.
Originally His Majesty wanted to reinstate Princess of Glory's power over the six palaces
If I didn't get her in trouble today,
I'm afraid that in the future, Lingrong and I
will be in constant jeopardy.
I'm no longer useful
It would be best if you could save me
But if you can't, you must take good care of yourself!
Be extremely careful
You must not fall into my current condition
Jiejie, rest assured
His Majesty...
he will take care of you.
Take care?
Back then when we were unmarried
All I wanted was to marry a good husband
Eventhough I knew I'd marry the emperor
and I wouldn't expect he could respect and love me
I hoped he could trust and cherish me
so that I could have someone to rely on
Seems like...in the end I was wrong
I already told our families
to catch Liu Ben with all-out effort.
When the truth is revealed,
His Majesty will definitely make it up to you, and return your innocence.
Make it up to me?
The pain I've experienced
How can he compensate for that?
Holding me in his palm, but abandoning and mistrusting me
The emperor
He is so heartless and fickle
He didn't consider our past feelings at all
I know
that these words sound piercing to you right now.
But only in my condition can you understand
that the emperor's favor is nothing more than that.
But the emperor is very good to you
I don't think you will ever end up in my plight
My words
are just the sad words
of a sad person.
Young mistress, please come out soon
Any later, you'll be discovered!
Jiejie
You must take good care of your health
I will definitely think of a way to save you
- Young mistress, please come out immediately- Yes
Young mistress, please come out immediately
You must take care
Go
Auntie, I entrust you with her care
Young mistress, rest assured
After the incident today, it will be quiet for a few days
Young mistress Meizhuang's days won't be too bad
Young mistress, please hurry back
Who's there?!
Who's on the boat?
Who is it?
Who's disturbing my good sleep?
I didn't know Duke was here
Please forgive me for my disturbance
Go go go, don't ruin my mood
Why is Duke here?
The emperor wants me to stay in the palace tonight, must you ask?
Yes yes
It's fine
I will row you back
It will be a shortcut and faster
Many thanks Duke
I used to know
the ten-mile's lotuses on the lake are fragrant
surprisedly, when I am surrounded by lotuses
I find even the water chestnut leaves and the reed are also fragrant
It seems to be more interesting to get in
than watch on the side
There are only a few lotus receptacles now
where can you pick up so many lotus flower
these are the last cluster of lotus this summer
I rowed deep into the lotus and finally found these.
Duke likes lotus
It seems like that men like pine and bamboo more
Pine and bamboo are rigid, but too rigid means easy to be break off
unlike lotus, rised unsullied from mud
lotuse's cleanliness is always being appreciated
but I like its Buddhahood more
mild as mother
Right, Precious are right
I smelled the pollia japonica
but it doesn't grow in this season
Precious' nose are sharp, it is from me
Pollia japonica flower stands for love
are you in love with someone
It's a real joy to share a boat with a beauty
It makes me feel like I am boating with Xishi (one of the four famous beauties in Chinese history)
on the Tai Lake
If I knew your real meaning,
I would definitely be upset.
Duke, please don't compare me to Xi Shi
Is Precious also like everyone else,
thinking Xi Shi brought the destruction of the kingdom?
If Xi Shi brought the destruction of the kingdom Wu
then who brought the destruction of kingdom Yue
Precious stand to sense, why did you say such words
Fan Li was Xi Shi's lover
but he himself sent Xi Shi to Wu to be the Princess.
so ungrateful
though later Xi Shi forgave what he had done before
and rowed boat with him on Tai Lake
her young girl's mood had gone
most of people sigh for Xi Shi or scold the emperor of Wu
but never scold Fan Li
Precious' way of thinking is unique, I surrender
silver moon light, beautiful scene in a good day, are hard to come by
beautiful scene in a good day, and my melancholy
Duke also read Peony Pavilion?
I like this sentence most
I don't know where the love came from, but it grew so deep
the living thing could die, and the died things could live again
the word -- love
if you ask where it begins, its hard to answer
We don't know where the loves in the world begins and ends
It is so lucky for Duke to have somebody accompanied
I always accompany his majesty
I wish I could have this love
Duke has lost something
Thanks
This pouch is my favorite thing
If I lost it just now, I would be regretful
It's just a pouch
don't be so serious
since it is Duke's favorite
don't show it to anyone again
in case it causes some trouble
I have one thing in need of your help
just say it
That night on July 7th
I got into some trouble
It was thanks to Princess of Modesty who helped me.
so if the Duke hears anything
about that night
don't tell anyone you've met me
just like tonight
If Duke agrees, I will appreciate so much
I won't tell a third person
It my fortune to chat with Precious
If Precious has the chance someday
I'd like to meet you at my Cool and Refreshing Villa
and chant about the history or the modern things
the midsummer has just passed, the Cool and Refreshing Villa is too cold
I'd better not bother you
Bye
Young mistress, you finally come back
Huanbi, bring me a cup of water
Was everything smooth
you came back so late, I was worried
about what
about young mistress' safety
I'm fine, but Princess of Glory is a pity
His Majesty reprimanded her
She's not allowed to see Princess Wenyi again either
Originally, he was going to restore
her power over the six palaces.
But now, she can't even save herself
His Majesty reprimanded Princess of Glory?
Yes
She tried to steal the chicken only to end up losing the rice
Harming others only brings retribution
Huanbi, don't you agree?
Of course young mistress
Huanbi, you've worked hard lately
Thanks for your hard work
Why does young mistress say that? Huanbi can't accept.
When Precious Cao tried to create conflict between me and His Majesty
by bringing up his use of 17th's identity,
even back then I suspected that someone close to me
had leaked the information.
Today, as soon as I left Bitong Study,
someone went to tip them off.
I just don't believe it
For no reason, how would Princess of Glory
know I was going to Xianyue Pavilion?
I'm not the only person who knew
you were going to visit young mistress Meizhuang.
How do you know it was me?
You are indeed careful
But you neglected one thing
What is it?
The small box of Mihe fragrance which was a tribute
His Majesty gave it all to me
I then gave it all to Precious Cao
I saw her put it in her bedroom, with my own eyes
If you are loyal to me as you claim,
then how could that fragrance leave her bedroom?
And how is it that you smell like Mihe fragrance?
I...didn't
If you won't admit it,
smell yourself.
Do you smell the Mihe fragrance?
This scent stays for days
The smell is faint, not easily detected
Still won't tell the truth?
Young mistress
But I should still thank you
If you hadn't tipped them off,
how could I take down Princess of Glory so easily today?
I'm just afraid that Princess of Glory now hates you to the bone
and thinks that we two colluded.
I've seen a lot of treachery
I never thought that the one who harms me
would be my own younger sister.
You know?
Yes, I've known for a while
Father told me the night before we entered the palace
Because of that, it's especially hurtful
Father...how did father say it?
Father said you've suffered all these years
and told me to treat you well.
This is also the reason I brought you into the palace
I planned to find a good family for you, make you first wife
If you had stayed at the Zhen estate,
the best you could do is marry another servant.
Young mistress
Are you still going to call me young mistress?
You should call me older sister
I know you feel unwilling
Although you are Father's daughter,
your name is not on the family tree.
Even your mother's memorial tablet
cannot be placed in the ancestral shrine for worship with incense.
But Huanbi, you are in Father's heart
You are also in Older Sister's heart
No matter how good you are to me,
in this inner palace, everyone fights against each other.
If I don't have anyone to recommend me,
how can I make something of myself?
You think that by relying on Precious Cao's help, you will become something?
Look at Pin of Beauty and Yushi
and you'll know the fate of being used to others' advantage!
Hypothetically,
even if you gain the emperor's favor,
look at the inner palace.
whose favor lasted for a long time
Once it's exposed that your mother came from a family guilty of crime,
do you know what the outcome will be?
Not only will the entire Zhen clan be implicated by you,
Father's crime of secretly taking in a guilty subject's daughter
is enough to banish him to Ancient Ning Tower!
I didn't purposely want to harm you and Father
I didn't want to fight against you either
Precious Cao said that the emperor likes you so much
Even if you made a mistake,
he wouldn't blame you much.
At most confine you for 10 to 15 days
And because I look a bit like you,
I would then have the opportunity to get close to the emperor.
You actually believe Precious Cao's words?!
I have no mistakes
Instead, I am living everyday on the edge of their knife!
If the emperor really becomes angry with me,
your resemblance to me will only make him dislike and reject you!
if he doesn't kill you, you should thank the god
I was obsessed at that time
Your lapse of judgment
nearly broke our sisterly relationship.
Do you know how much I admire you sometimes?
You and I are different
My life is already determined by fate. I must accept it.
But you still have the opportunity to pick someone you like
from among the good men in this world.
Grow old with him
In this palace,
although I can't openly acknowledge you as my sister,
but when the time comes, you can be Father's adopted daughter
and marry from the Zhen family.
Your mother's memorial tablet
can also be added to the Zhen family ancestral shrine.
Your name can also be added to the family tree
Your wishes will finally be fulfilled
Older sister, Huanbi was confused!
I didn't know you were that good and considerate to me
I made a huge mistake
Yurao is still young, and there are no boys in the family
They can only rely on us sisters
If evil people can instigate conflict between us,
hurting only ourselves, then our family is really doomed.
Huanbi has disappointed older sister
Please forgive me
Have you ever told Princess of Glory about your mother?
I only wanted to use Princess of Glory and Precious Cao
to get the emperor's attention.
I had no intention of harming older sister
Mother's matter has great importance
I dared not mention it before them
You're very lucky you didn't say anything
For what happened today,
Princess of Glory and the others will definitely hate you.
From now on, you must be extremely careful
I've already been wrong once. I am overcome with regret.
Please rest assured, older sister
It's cooling down earlier in the day, and there aren't as many mosquitos
In two days, it will be mid-autumn
Young mistress
Is young mistress thinking of something?
His Majesty has very high regard for Pin of Respects
Pin of Respects
is virtuous, and never causes trouble or fights for favor.
Of course she would be more respected
The way His Majesty treats Pin of Respects - it's not exactly favor
He just treats her with courtesy and respect
In this inner palace,
many people hide their abilities.
If she really had no redeeming qualities,
how could she live secluded under Princess of Glory
for so many years?
I actually suspect Precious Cao for what happened this time
Young mistress, think
Even though Princess of Glory is an extreme person,
Precious Cao is fairly cautious.
Even if young mistress purposely sent Huanbi to report the news,
how could Precious Cao get Princess of Glory
there so quickly?
Was she not really looking out for Princess of Glory,
or did she actually believe Huanbi completely?
Then Cao Qinmo purposely let her go?
If Princess Wenyi's incident last time
was not Cao Qinmo's doing,
then Princess of Glory was the mastermind?
Cao Qinmo only has one beloved daughter
This created distance between them
it is not impossible
So it seems that
things are more complex.
Add more honey! Otherwise it will be too sour!
I heard His Majesty's personal servant Xiao Xiazi say
that lately Duke Guo
hasn't been coming to the palace to play chess and look at paintings with him.
He went to vacation in Shu
What does it have to do with us?
He's a duke. He can go wherever he wants.
Unlike us, all we see above
are these rectangular skies.
Look at you, full of complaints
When you get married, you can go wherever you please
Look at you, talking all about marriage!
Could it be...that you want to get married?
Nonsense! Be careful or else I'll rip your mouth!
Amitabha Buddha! Why are you angry
You care so much about whether Duke Guo comes to the palace
How about...you just marry him?
You are more and more unreasonable
If you keep talking nonsense, I will really start ignoring you!
Good sister, I was just joking with you!
If I'm really right one day,
it won't be too late for you to thank me.
Nonsense!
Stop!
How anxious you look!
Keep talking nonsense!
Your Majesty, Empress is still putting on clothes in the bath
If you're tired, go to sleep first
I'm reading Sushi's poem
It has been ten years, you are dead, I'm alive
I don't want to miss you, but I can't forget it myself
excellent poem, every word points my heart
Your Majesty, servant doesn't understand these
You don't understand, the Empress might not either
If Precious Smile were here,
we would have a little talk about it.
Take something to Palace of Shattered Jade for me
Yes
Young mistress, Su Gong Gong is here
Young mistress, it's servant's fault
for disturbing your rest.
Gong Gong came over so late, is there something?
His Majesty insists that I deliver something to you
I hope young mistress will have a good night and good dreams
Only Huan Huan to open
Belts on our waists, a true love knot in our dream
His Majesty wrote this himself?
Yes
Gong Gong, please thank His Majesty for me
Yes, congratulations young mistress
His majesty worked so hard on national affairs, he's tired
Where is Su Peisheng
I saw Su Gonggong take a box
to Palace of Shattered Jade
What was in it ?
A true love knot
Niangniang, don't be angry
What am I angry for
Has his majesty been to Princess of Glory's palace
since he came back
They usually meet
but Princess of Glory didn't serve
Thank you for watching! Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki