This is the fresh moisture cream made for Xiao Zhu by the imperial hospital
even Xiaozhu loses weight
your skin won't loose
put more on then
It is done.
you go to help me
what's happening , Xiaozhu?
Xiao Zhu! Xiao Zhu!
An Pin is fainted at Yanxi Palace
was a doctor called?
They did. But when they got there,
An Pin didn't allow them in
I heard from the little maid who went to the doctor
An Pin was painted because of overly food restriction
Why is she on a diet?
since she lost the favor
she's been practicing ice skating every day
An Lingrong has a brain,
trying to use this to get the favor
Qing Emperors in every dynasty
all like ice skating
and have a skating show every year
and set skating, wrestling, Manchurian, and riding and archery
as the culture of Qing dynasty
I heard that some guards of the previous emperors
had become high ranked officers because of skating skills
How Niangniang respond to this?
I don't need to do anything.
she's on a way of self destruction
self destruction?
your maid..., your maid is ignorant...
if skating is not learnt as a child
you can't be succesful
dancing on ice
requires a dancer's body light as if without bones
one can't get it in a short time
though An Lingrong is slim
how could she be as light as cloud
after these years in the palace?
No wonder she tries to go on a diet.
Niangniang is exactly right
diet would hurt appearance yet won't get the result quickly
it seems she's burning with impatience
there is actually a way to a result immediately
if someone tells her
she must've felt like finding a treasure
absolutely cannot let her know the way
we must let her know!
Zhao Feiyan became the favorite of Han Cheng Emperor
her body was so light that she could dance on a palm
it was the effect of Muscle Resting Drug
put it into your belly button
it melt inside the body
that would make the skin as white as snow, the body very light
and the appearance shines gloriously
only there is musk in it
musk would damage woman's body
not only causes infertility
even she's pregnant
it would make the fetus die early
An Pin understands spices better than most
she won't be deceived
I know
I don't want to deceive her
it's up to her whether she wants to use it or not
I've heard that
using lamb flower soup wash
could dissolve the poison of musk
would An Pin know this method?
if that has such magic effect
how come Zhao Feiyan was never pregnant
even they had all the power to
wash with all lamb flower soup she needed?
it's good she knows that. she'd think lamb flower is effective
she'd be fearless
has An Pin got the muscle resting drug?
An Pin saw it, and took it without a word
she's obedient
I heard she'd asked the imperial hospital secretly
before Niangniang gave it to her
look like she truly doesn't want a child
isn't that good!
so we don't have to try something
right
I feel better using the person without child
the effect of this drug is remarkable
Xiao Zhu looks slimmer these days
only this drug is very severe, I worry
what's there to worry
it's New Year's eve tomorrow
I know how much musk it has
I boiled a pot of lamb flower soup
Niangniang takes a soak
since I've taken so much various drug soups these years
it's the same whether I'm soak or not
Xiao Zhu isn't be able to be pregnant
you have to find some way
under control of someone
I can't make a decision even for getting pregnant
you know how much I hate?
but Bao Juan, I'm helpless
I have to obey the empress
last year's skating was really good
The Neza Made Chaos in Ocean really made me happy
Taizu Emperor was good at walking on ice
he walked faster than Calvary in battle
I heard when Emperor was Fourth Prince
he won in the riding and archery on ice every year
if headwind could understand, it won't destroy easily
Zhen and you met through plum flower in the past
Huangshang still remembers
there's rhythm in fragrance,
pure to extreme won't feel cold
did Huangshang remember when Sister just came
she often recited this poem
never thought Cunyuan Empress was like me
appreciate the lonely and pure state of plum flower
Cunyuan and you are same kind of naturally pure people
Huangshang, ten thousands happiness
your voice is still not recovered?
Chenqie ate something bad
I'm afraid that my voice won't recover
you wear such thin cloth without getting health back
your hands are icy cold
Su Peisheng, fetch my marten coat
don't hurt yourself in such cold weather
pity you lost your voice
lose in the east, gain in the west
though An Pin damaged her voice
her dance on ice
surpassed Feiyan!
Bengong see An Pin can be called
Feiyan on ice
it reminded of Chenqie Xi Guifei's dance of surprised goose
also like a fairy coming down from sky
Xi Guifei's and my lovely consort's
each has its strong point
it's my luck I have such a lovely consort
how would I be dared to compare with Xi Guifei?
I, like Dongshi, only imitate Xishi
Zhen forgot to ask, how had you came here?
Chenqie really missed Huangshang
thought I'd be happy
if I could just see Huangshang from afar
Chenqie has no luck to serve Huangshang
I'm lucky to dancing for Huangshang today
since I shouldn't go out
the dance is over, please punish me
Chenqie takes it willingly
it's ok. staying with Zhen for New Year
Yi Guifei had gave birth of a son safely
Ronger, before Hui Pin's deliver
don't go to her Suiyu Pavillion
Chenqie obey imperial direction.
yet Chenqie and Hui Pin sister are like real sisters
but can't go to take care of her
I feel regret
cunning
Long live the Emperor, ten thousand years
pick lotus in the river south,
Huangshang has been favoring An Pin these days
if this keeps going, promote her to Fei is not far away
it's not easy for her
her appearance does not ont top of others
and she came from that kind of family and has no child
she could get such a position.
didn't she just pretend to be pitiful?
yet Huangshang likes it so much
not only Huangshang; all men in the world
are all like that
Xiao Zhu had put away this bracelet
why did you take it out today?
Huangshang gave this to me
such good thing is rare nowadays
you take it to Yanxi Palace in a moment
give it to her
the emeralds of tributes are getting worse year after year
Xiao Zhu wants Nubi to give to her?
Nubi feels pity for such good emeralds
?what pity or not
tell Zhen about it
Huangshang ten thousand happiness and golden peace
servants outside are really ignorant
didn't announce when Huangshang is here
Zhen was afraid you were napping so didn't want to wake you up
didn't expect you two were gossipping
rise
Chenqie is having Huanbi find something
Huangshang takes a look, is it good?
this seems something Zhen gave you last time
you like it too much to wear it
why did you take it out?
precisely because I like it too much to wear
I'll get it out to give to Sister An
even Huanbi said
if such emerald is not matched with a beauty
it would be pity
the empress has gave her many things,
she's got a lot just from the Internal Affairs Office
what she's got is one thing
what I give to her is another thing
I try to use the thing Huangshang gave to me
to please another
I have to ask whether Huangshang allows or not
Zhen has seen that there is coral bracelet
on your wrist, very pretty
coral is not something expensive
but Sister An likes emerald
Chenqie tries to please her
Huangshang tries to get Sister An for
my other things
Ronger came from lower background, and is afraid a lot
too much Pins and Feis in the harem don't like her
only you, treat her as really sisters after this many years
it's rare
Huaihuai, there is a thing I've some difficulty
Huaihuai may not solve the problem for Fourth prince
but like to hear
it's about your parents
they may not come to see you soon
why?
Guaerjia gathered many officials are against it
criticize Zhen lost fairness because of favoring you
in fact, Huangshang has no reason not to know
what happened to my family in the past
it's more like a fabricated charge
Huangshang has also had to think about Hongyan's future
can't let his grandfather be a criminal
could Huangshang consider to review the case?
Qi Guiren has no big error in the Harem
Guaerjia clan can't find anything right now
if open up the case in the past
that would shake the court, cause disturbance
Chenqie can wait
Guifei sister-in-law
it's still cold, how come Beile's cloth is so thin?
should put more cloth on
Thanks, Guifei sister-in-law
when I was at Shoukang Palace to see Dowager
Dowager also reminded of me
I feel that if it's too warm
that could weaken the will of a person
so I chose some thin cloth
Elder sister, I've been looking for you
Hongyan would cry if you don't go back
Haven't met this Xiao Zhu
is everyone having a face and head
married to the Emperor? I'm not
what marry or not?
words out of a girl's mouth have no subtlety
Beile, don't view her as an outsider,
she's my little sister
Xiaomei doesn't go out much
no wonder Beile saw her not familiar
Xiaomei grew up in a remote area
doesn't know much of rules
please don't laugh at her, Beile
hasn't you greeted Beile?
no wonder Prince mistook me for others
I can imagine that anyone with a little pretty look
in the Harem would get attention of the Emperor
that's what made Prince thought me as such
Yurao, you're more and more reckless
Guniang is so high-minded and proud that
even views the Emperor and richness as nothing
it looks only the fame of 17th Prince
could mean something for Guniang
what do you mean? is only son of royalty good?
I'd rather marry an ordinary man for life
than step in the gates of the palace or royal house
sorry, I underestimated Guniang
my little sister always talks without much thinking
not intentionally naughty
please don't be offended, Prince
let's go, sister
what has happened today?
what's in your mind
that you hold back and can't laugh out?
why would I want to laugh?
you can't hide from me if you have something
don't hide! tell your 17th elder brother.
saw a girl, big, hot temper
and, look down upon us
what do we have that are good?
merely born in the royal family
more likely than not that the brothers are trying to
kill each other, and many were rid of their status
nothing can be envied
don't say these depressing words, 17th brother
go, let's race!
let's go
Niangniang, Dr. Wen is here to check you
has him in, quickly
Weichen greet Niangniang
don't stand on ceremony
How is the pregnancy of Sister Mei?
Hui Pin is expecting in less than half month
she's been calm for months, and the fetus seems fine
though what you said is same each time
I feel better each time I heard it
so many old acquaintances have passed away
these years, it's fortunate you're still here
yes, it's fortunate that the close acquaintances are here still
by the way, Uncle Zhen is getting better
Weichen will go to see him when free, be as ease
Bengong are not easy to go out due to the rule, please look after my father
after Hui Pin gives birth safely
Weichen'll visit your father more
elder sister
second miss runs so fast, be careful
Jingxi will take care here, you can go now
Xiaoyunzi is playing paper crane with Hongyan. it's interesting. would sister want to go to see?
greeting to Guifei Niangniang
Su Gonggong
huangshang said to go to see Sixth Ahge with Niangniang in the afternoon
okay, sorry Su Gonggong had to make a trip to tell me
Niangniang is polite. isn't Bi Guniang here?
good, otherwise she'll have heart ache if she knew
Niangniang knew that 17th Prince is not in good health, has fever often
doctor's diagnose is cold air invaded his body
no one expected he fell from the horse yesterday when he went to ride with Beile Shen and the horse was upset
he didn't hurt much
only his temperature was very high at the midnight
Nucai have to report to Dowager so that Dowager would be at ease
such a big thing, how come no one told me?
Niangniang is busy in managing the affairs of the Harem
How could we bother Niangniang with this? furthermore, Empress takes care of the royal household
right. Bengong thought
Empress just recovered, and has to take care of Dowager. that's why I asked about it
Niangniang's virtues spread through the Harem, naturally concern about the royal household
even Niangniang didn't ask for yourself, should do it for Bi Guniang
you hurry up
Nucai is withdrawn
Yurao, I'm tired
you go playing with Hongyan and Lingxi
could bother you once?
if it's not you go to see him, I can't be at ease
you still can't put this away?
that his body invaded by cold wind was caused by me. I owe him too much
view this as paying him some back for me
you worry about his health
go to see him
something I couldn't do, it's good that you can
one more person would be at ease
really? the question is how can I get out?
you go to see Su Peisheng,
he can arrange for you. go
are there words Xiao Zhu want to bring to the Prince?
I don't . you go
Huaner. ---Prince
Ahjin, Prince is awake, bring tea here
Wangye, you are awake
Wangye
did Huaner ask you to come?
no, I beg Su Gonggong to let me come
thanks for your care these days
lots of things in the Harem, you go help Huaner, it's not convenient with her alone
no rush, Jinxi is there
Wangye is ill. if I didn't take good care of Wangye, no one would be at ease, and I would waste my chance of coming out
it's up to you
how come didn't Huangshang come to the Harem lately
too many things at the court, plus set a new office, Huangshang is too busy
no wonder
Empress looks more spirited
I heard Qi Guiren had a nun from outside to talk about the scripture
why? the monks from Baohua Temple are not good?
I heard that Qi Guiren kept saying that she didn't feel well
always saw the masters from Baohua who made her tired
she probably invited some masters from the royal temple
Nubi should've paid more attention to these
but early this morening Empress sent me to teach new maids
didn't expect it took whole day and haven't looked other things
also, Su Peisheng said today
Wangye's fever is gone
but needs a few more days to rest
Huanbi Guniang needs to be there for a few more days
I envy Huanbi sometimes
Sister envies because Huanbi can go out of the palace?
I see that though Yongshou Palace is large
the sky can be seen is square, not as free as outside the palace
yes, I envy that Huanbi can go out from time to time
Sister don't think I'm busy playing, I'm willingly here to be with you
this balsam is new from the garden, called Carmine, it's very pretty to put on fingernail
it's not easy for them to having it out in Spring, it looks very good on Sister
Greetings to Guifei Niangniang
rise
Empress Niangniang asks you to go to Jingren Palace right away
for what matter?
it's important. Niangniang asks Empress Niangniang, it's not convenient for Nucai to reply
prepare sedan chair
Wangye is just getting better, be careful not to catch cold again
thanks a lot
if Wangye thanks me, that treats me as a stranger
you look that kite
it seems fly so high
but only hangs by a thread
how insecure it is
didn't know Wangye likes to watch kite
no, I feel the situation Huaner in is like a kite
I'm fine, Huanbi
you go back to help Huaner
Wangye don't need to worry
Niangniang has Huangshang, and Huangshang's child. she's nothing to be afraid of
Qi Guiren, you insisted on accuse Xi Guifei, and wanted Bengong having everyone in the Harem here, for what matter?
Chenqie want to expose Xi Guifei has an affair, promiscuous in the Harem, the crime deserves to die
palace rules are strict, Qi Guiren can't make irresponsible accusation!
if Chenqie lie, let me die hit by thunder, never have bereincarnated
that's what you swore on?
who would know what happen after death?
swore on such illusory thing,
Qi Guiren is obviously not serious
Chenqie swears on the Guaerjia clan that if Chenqie lie, the whole clan would have no descendants
you say that Xi Guifei has an affair,
who is the adultery?
Doctor Wen Shichu
Wen Shichu is a confidant of Xi Guifei, and checks her pulse everyday
it's possible they feel for each other
furthermore, when Xi Guifei first came to Harem, she was ill for a while, and it was Dr. Wen made diagnosis
Kang Changzai has a good memory. the crime started at the very beginning
How could two sisters make a guess like that? Xi Guifei was seriously ill when she first came, and Dr. Wen went to see Xi Guifei
not only he's very good but his family knows Sister's family well
it's reasonable to care for her, where this affair thing came from?
from what you said, they've known each other since childhood
it looks what Qi Guiren said could have some credit
what evidence you have for the nonsense several of you said?
of course, Chenqie has evidence
Wen Shichu had proposed to Xi Guifei before she came to the Palace
Qi Guiren, you sit first.
Nubi greet Empress
speaking with your head raised
Piner
you're Piner
Xi Guifei recognizes her
she' the wife of Chensi in my parents' house. when Zhen family was exiled, all their servants were sold
she'd starve to death if not for my parents that bought her
Piner, stand and speak if you have anything to say. --- Nubi not dare
stop nonsense. when you worked at Zhen House, did Wen Shichu propose to your eldest miss?
did Wen Shichu propose to your eldest miss, that is, the current Xi Guifei?
you've to speak louder in front of Empress, didn't Chensi tell you?
Dr. Wen did propose to Wen's a half month before she entered the palace; but
he didn't say to Master and Madame
he said to Xi Guifei privately
did Xi Guifei accept? --- no, no
Chenqie thought
if Xi Guifei had her heart on Dr. Wen, she wouldn't be in the Harem today
it's obvious that Xi Guifei has clear conscience and didn't have affair with Dr. Wen
Xi Guifei didn't have high regard for an imperial doctor then;
but how could Dr. Wen propose if Xi Guifei didn't show any affection?
there must've exist some feelings from the childhood
Chenqie don't believe feeling from childhood
only believe destiny set by heaven
fated gathering, even torturous,
won't be changed by human interference
Qi Guiren, Bengong knew you hold grudges against Xi Guifei; but you can't spread such vicious nonsense
if it's like you said that Xi Guifei and Dr. Wen had affair
they would want to hide and not let others know
others will know unless you didn't do
things are done more, someone would see
Feiwen, the little maid from Yongshou Palace, has seen a few times
Feiwen, when did you see, and what did you see?
tell Bengong everything clearly
Niangniang and Dr. Wen were talking in room alone on a day,
Nubi accompanying Second Miss entered the room and saw
Dr. Wen's hand held Niangniang's hand, and sat and facing each other,
Dr. Wen withdrew his hand when he saw Nubi
Nubi also saw Dr. Wen's sleeve was rolled up
and embroidered a five bamboo-leaf
I was scared that Niangniang would kill me if she knew what I saw
so I begged Qi Guiren to protect me
you little maid saw such thing
wouldn't this happen a lot when you didn't see
this is a big thing
ask Dr. Wen come to Jingren Palace
Xiao zhu is expecting; Dowager said that can't let you know anything outside
out of way; involving Xi Guifei, I have to go to see.
this would reach Huangshang; no matter what, Huangshang would help Guifei; Niangnian'd better be at ease
you still have time to go if something happens; your baby is more important
allright
Jiang Gonggong
Wen Daren, Empress Niangniang asks you to come to Jingren Palace immediately
Xiaguan never serves Jingren Palace, don't know why Empress Niangniang calls me?
that has to ask yourself
Wen Daren, please
haven't check Hui Pin Niangniang's pulse
it would be enormous if Dowager's order didn't carry out
what do you want to do?
allow Xiaguan to check her pulse before going to Jingren Palace
okay
Niangniang's date is near
Weichen added a few more herbs in your prescription
to assure that everything goes smoothly when Niangniang gives birth
you seem in hurry; are you going somewhere?
Imperial hospital needs more drugs and send Weichen to purchase
it's windy. don't go out; don't get cold
go, but come back quickly
I have something important that I need you
report to Niangniang, Dr. Wen is here
Greetings to Empress Niangniang. greetings to every Xiaozhu
rise
forgive me, Wen Daren
this embroidery is elegant, you always have it?
Weichen's mother likes bamboo, so all Weichen's sleeves have a bamboo leaves embroidered by my mother
to express her feelings to me
Empress Niangniang
Chenqie thought the embroidery on Dr. Wen's sleeve is not just for a day or two
any careful person could see
this couldn't say anything
it's strange. how come a small doctor saw Guifei as if come to his own house, talking face to face
if like this in future, if doctor can roll up sleeve or unbutton his cloth in Guifei's room, what he couldn't do?
Guifei asked Weichen about Hui Pin's baby's position on that day
when heard everything was good, she was happy and granted me tea
I lost the ceremony when I took the tea and rolled my sleeve
if Xi Guifei is not because she doesn't trust anyone but you
how could she ask you to take care of Hui Fei who is like her sister?
it looks Xi Guifei has special feeling toward you
Xiaozhu, you...