ma'am
have you listened about doctor Wen's persuading words
if you listen to Doctor Wen word, living with him peacefully for whole life
it is also good though.
Jin Xi, you are the person who know me best.
so why you come to test me now?
I won't be with him.
Father is severely ill, and locked up at Ningguta.
The Zhen clan has no one to look after them.
What Yunli could help me with in the past, I have to shoulder it on my own now.
Wen Shichu can't help me.
I can only rely on myself.
Alright. Since you have made up your mind, you won't be alone.
Your servant and Huanbi will follow you, Mistress.
What will you do, Mistress?
Yunli's death is very suspicious. I cannot ignore it.
Before he left for Dianzang, he told me...
The rebellion from Zhange-er tribe is not ease yet.There are a lot of spies sneak into Dianzang.
His accident was caused either by rebellion from Dainzang people
Or the spies from Zhange-er tribe is unkown.
Perhaps...it may even have something to do with the people in the palace.
Regardless of which cause it is,
just based on my own efforts,it's impossible for me to avenge him.
The child I am carrying...
I must be responsible for.
I can't let his bloodline die.
I must give this child an honorable name
And have the child grow up well
Also my father
Before I was careful to only protect my family
But recently my father has been sick
I can't just stand still and watch him
Mistress, if you want to do these things,
In this world, only one person can help you.
That is right...
Yunli has told me before
The emperor has spoken my name in his dream
I am not 100% confident
But I'm must work hard on something
The emperor's hand...
Everything of the emperors, I must use to revenge
Mistress
This step is dangerous and risky.
Have you thought about it clearly?
Do I have a choice?
Yunli is dead.
With my current status what do I have to lose?
Mistress, are you saying that...
You plan resolve and gain the Emperor's love?
If Mistress and the Emperor can meet
But I'm afraid we won't be able to cover up one thing.
If the palace becomes alerted, some people will want to kill.
If that's the case, then all we can do is wait (Chinese idiom meaning waiting for death)
Let's return to the palace.
Dr. Wen
Huan'er
I look ugly don't I?
How can you say that?
Recently, you just haven't had enough air.
So your face is a bit pale.
I'm pregnant, so low blood concentration is not good for me.
So please prescribed me some medicine that would refuel the blood for me. And
Do you still have goddess powder (medicine) from previously?
What makes you think of that since everything is fine.
Mistress insist to give the birth to the child, but she does not look very well.
So the child will probably don't look well,too.
Therefore, she needs to eat some healthy food for the blood plus the goddess powder (medicine).
It would be best if you just treat yourself better.
As for the healthy food that refuel the blood, they need to have effect as soon as possible.
I hate seeing myself sick like this.
Alright
I will prescribed everyday use to Jinxi, you have to take good care of yourself.
Let me take your pulse.
Your pulse is gentle, and seemingly normal
Huan-er, you have to be careful, don't be very emotional.
I must go back now.
I will send the medicine as soon as possible,
Jin Xi
Please send Dr. Wen out.
Yes. Please Dr. Wen
Don't tell anyone about my return to the palace
Yes
It is very fragrant.
Emperor, are you teasing me?
Can I not compliment you?
The Emperor is at YeXi palace.
Yes. After the Emperor felt better,
He went to YeXi Palace and ChunXi Manor
I'm not worry about Precious Ning, but An ping...
An Ping seems to be docile, but it is hard to know what she is thinking.
I won't let her get pregnant, what other methods would she have...
Tell Hui Chun
She must watch An Ping have her non-pregnancy medicine or else there will be consequences
Yes.
Bao Juan
Hurry and dump this.
Yes
Jin Xi, Is there anyone in the palace,
Who can speak with the Emperor?
The only who can speak to the Emperor is Su Pei Sheng
He has serve the Emperor since he was small, so he understands him the best.
If Mistress wants to return to the palace,
You must encounter the Emperor to have a chance
But now were are outside of the Palace
There is nothing that I have that can be of use
You are wrong Mistress.
Su Pei Sheng, has always been with the Emperor so he hasn't seen much.
To buy Su Pei Sheng, it isn't money and power
Then?
Su Pei Sheng is one of the most miserable person because he cannot marry a wife and have children.
It is the worst thing of all.
Consider it as them comforting each other in their sufferings.
It's better than nothing.
JIn Xi
I won't let you sacrifice yourself for me.
This is the best plan.
I and Su Pei Sheng are from the same village.
When I entered the palace,
Su Pei Sheng took care of me.
Plus we have been in the palace for so many years
Su Pei Sheng has been faithful only to me.
I am willing to try at least.
Jin Xi.
You have been suffering with me compare to others
Because of me, you are willing to be with a Eunuch
Even if it takes a long time
But he isn't even a man
Mistress
I've already thought about this path already
Even if you try, it's no use
I'm willing to do anything for you.
About the future, we won't know if we don't gamble.
What if my fate is to depend on Su Pei Sheng
I will go and get ready
Where are you going?
Su Pei Sheng has a private house outside the palace, I know where it is.
That will let me meet up with him.
Jinxi, you don't have to do this for me.
There is other ways.
This is the best option
Beside, if you return you will have Su Pei Sheng support
If one day you really gain the attention and love
It will only be a good thing for Su Pei Sheng
And with my weak efforts,
we will have assurance.
Mistress, please rest assure
Jin Xi, it's you
Men...
Exchange the tea set with the Emperor's new one.
Drink my tea first
Thank you Eunuch Su
At my house you don't have to be so formal, just say my name.
Pei Sheng
Sit down
The house has been re-design, how have you been living?
It's ok. It's just lonely with just myself living her.
It's been so many years, I'm use to it.
I came here to be with you
Although I'm a bit late.
What? You are now willing?
You must be tired. Your legs must hurt.
Actually, matters of this world are full of twists and turns like this.
The person who is beside me
I should be with that person.
But what a pity with Wan Ping
Ever since she has been alone, no one is there to take care of her.
It's hard to hold it in.
Are you talking about Concubine Wan and Emperor?
Are you sure?
If Concubine Wan still has a chance, then wouldn't it be best for both?
Right now at Emperor's side,
he's still missing a diligent person
In the palace Huang Hou is the highest and biggest
If Wan Ping enters the palace, I'm afraid it would be difficult
Whether it's difficult or not. It's all depending on the people.
As long as she works hard, then it will be fine
One day, if the Emperor
Can be with Wan Ping...
Then you and I would be a couple.
You have return.
Eunuch Su
I greet you, Niang Niang
Please rise and sit.
Thank you. - Huang Bi, please serve the tea
Yes. - Sit down
I'm no longer a Niang Niang. You don't have to call me that.
For me to call you that,
It is my honor
I don't understand what you mean.
The other day, Jin Xi came to look for me
Although she didn't say much, I am able to guess it.
Seeing Niang Niang today, even though you live in a Buddhist abode, you still are radiant.
This lets me have a better understanding.
Then what is your purpose that you have come for?
I am here to congratulate you,
congratulations on your wish being granted.
Please continue speaking
Niang Niang, I've been with the Emperor for many years.
What ever the Emperors wants, he would receive it
If back then you were willing to bow down
He wouldn't have let you leave the palace
Lets no longer talk about the past.
So do you mean...
I insisted in leaving the palace...
However, my family has offend the Emperor
How can I face the Emperor...
Ever since I left the Palace, I've missed the Emperor
Please relay my feelings to his Highness.
Yes
Niang Niang, that year you were ordered by the Emperor to Gan Lu Si to practice Buddhism.
Today you are here.
I understand that you suffered at Gan Lu Si.
In this wild,
You have suffered, Niang Niang
Actually there suffering is nothing to be afraid of, excepting not being at peace
If by living this way, I can have the opportunity to see the Emperor and the princess again
then I could die content.
I am indebted to you for your kindness to me in the past.
I will try my best.
Please rise
Life is always changing. I'm just afraid that the Emperor already has someone new by his side.
He has already forgotten about me.
Niang Niang exaggerates. If I didn't have some certainty, I wouldn't have dared to come see you so quickly.
So Gong Gong already has a plan?
Ever since you have left, the emperor has been missing you.
Because of his position, he cannot come save you.
Niangniang, you are wise. You would understand.
If not for His Majesty's silent consent,
Empress Dowager's approval would not have been enough for Fangruo to keep visiting you, Niangniang.
When His Majesty was seriously ill, he has never called for anyone other than Empress Chunyuan.
You're the first, Niangniang.
That day the Empress Dowager was present too. It gave her a shock!
This is the lingering feeling that His Majesty has for you, Niangniang.
It's an extremely important lingering feeling too!
To tell you the truth, Prince Guo was present then too.
He heard His Majesty too.
It's a pity that the Prince won't be coming back anymore.
Why won't he be coming back?
This is supposed to be a secret in the palace. I'm not supposed to say anything.
His Majesty's intention is for the mourning to be done in secret.
It's a pity.
Prince Guo's life has just come to an end so suddenly.
Niangniang, you must be tired. Have a glass of water first.
Wang Ye was so young, such a pity.
Isn't it?
Why are we talking about other people?
Actually, it's not impossible for you to meet His Majesty.
I tried me best to convince the Emperor to come to Gan Lu Si to worship
and I will lead him to here.
It's been hard on you, Gonggong.
This matter is not easy to handle.
Gonggong, please make the effort.
It's not that difficult.
Allow me to think of some way.
Eunuch Su
I really don't know how to repay your kindness
Ma'am, by helping you
I am also helping myself
If anything happens I have someone report it to you.
Then I will leave first.
Huan Bi see Eunuch out
Please stay, there is no need to see me out.
No need. I will see him out.
Keep this for your use.
This-
Take it, Xiao Xia is behind me right now.
In two days I'll send over someone with some fabric.
The clothes you are wearing now is already out of style
You should change them
I'm leaving.
We're heading back.
Come here, little princess. Slowely.
Here. Be careful.
The Emperor has arrived.
Rise.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I just visited Mother. Her complexion still isn't too good.
I heard that you've been taking care of her.
It's only right for me to be filial to the Empress Dowager.
Rise.
Emperor, the weather is so nice.
Indeed
In a few more days it will be the Longtaitou Festival.
It is custom to go sightseeing and also to pray for happiness and burn incense.
Your Majesty, are you still intending to pray at Baohua Hall?
Every year, it's at Baohua Hall. I haven't even left the palace before.
How is that considered going sightseeing when spring arrives?
I heard all the citizens are all heading out of town for the festival
They do.
Then I should just stay in the palace and quietly do my work.
Your Majesty...
Longtaitou Festival is a big day.
Proverb says that on the 2nd day for the 2nd lunar month the dragon will raise it's head and there will be great harvests.
This is the day to pray for good weather for the year.
Your Majesty shouldn't carelessly let this go by.
This day, the people love to worship the Flower God to welcome spring the most.
The Flower God Temple is the most popular, there's a big crowd there every year.
I was stuck in the middle of the crowd last year,
and my toes were nearly trampled into the ground.
Where there are a lot of people it is too noisy.
I don't want to approach this kind of spectacle.
There's a place that's most suitable for it.
I remember going to Ling Yun Feng when I was young,
and then I head to the Gan Lu Temple afterwards, it takes exactly one day.
I had the exact same idea as her majesty.
These days Gan Lu Si's spring colors are really beautiful.
Plus, Gan Lu Si belongs to the Royal Family, it's less crowded
Gan Lu Si
I know that there is a person there that Your Majesty doesn't wish to see.
We're only going there to worship anyways, not to see her.
Plus we can pray for the Empress Dowager's illness,
we will only go to Ling Yun Feng if we have time.
Second day of the second month, everyone heads out of town.
Alright then.
Then I'll use this to see the feelings and attitudes of the people.
Yes. I will make the arrangements right away!
Greetings, Imperial Father!
I've heard that on the 2nd day of the 2nd month the Emperor will leave the palace to pray for the Empress.
Leaving the palace?Where to?
To Ganlu Temple.
He mustn't go!
I have checked . Zhen Huan has tubercolosis and sent away.She is not at the temple.
That's good. Get someone to keep an eye on it.
Let His Majesty go and return early.
Su Peisheng has put a lot of effort into it.
These clothes must have based on my measurements
These clothes are for you.
The colors and patterns are ones you like
And so it is. Let fate take it's course.
What?
I like it.
Su Pei Sheng wants yuor ladyship to dress up
His gifts are for this purpose
I understand Shu Pei Sheng's reasoning
He hopes I can win the Emperor's heart
But there is a risk it may have the opposite effect
But Shu Pei Sheng said the Emperor secretly misses you
Even if that is true
Someone who treats everyone like his shadows,
He has hurt himself and those around him.
His Majesty can be merciless. Does he know what true love is ?
Jin Xi are you moved ?
I noticed Shu Pei Sheng's report did not move my lady
Does my lady not have any hope .. ?
First hurting every part of you,
then applying medication to treat you.
What's the point
Whether there is point , as long as His Majesty still thinks of you
Our efforts will not be in vain
Emperor, please have some tea
Where is Consort Wan Ping ?
Your Majesty , Wan Ping was taken ill and she has moved to an abode in Lin Yee peak
She's sick?
How long has she been ill ?Is it serious ?
Wan Ping .. I believe she is alright now
Nonsense , what do you mean by " I believe"
You are the abbott - do you not know ?
You explain to me.She was well when she arrived.
Why has she fallen ill ?Please forgive us your Majesty
Wan Ping came to study buddhism .. it's an honor for our temple
All of us were very respectful and treated her well
But Wan Ping did not want to bother anyone.She insisted on doing everything herself.
She even looked after the older nuns.She washed, cut wood and drew water ..
But she was weak from the start and she caught pneumonia
Yes.
So .. she washed , cut wood and drew water.Yes ..
Yes, yes.
How is she now?
Since she fell ill we let her rest
Think of it . . she is much better now
Indeed ..
Then, lead me to her
Yes
Mistress you perfumed your hair .. it is fragrant
It smells good
Let's hope the flowers' fragrance will not dissappoint
Mistress I am afraid...
I am afraid .. of failure
But if we succeed
The road ahead will even be more difficult and dangerous
Except for this road
I have no choice
Mistress why are you dressed so simply in these Buddhist robes?
Since you have decided .. should you not dress and make up ?
In the palace , his Majesty is surrounded by beauty
I want to be simple on purpose
Let's go and pray
This dressing is appropriate for this place
His Majesty is arriving
It is one to wish and not to be asked
Abmi Buddha..
Mistress you did not sleep well .. perhaps ..
Your Majesty
Majesty ? Why would his Majesty be here ?
Mistress . it's true.It's his Majesty .. I am not lying
Huan Huan
The abbott tells me you are here because you are ill
I was told you should be well by now but you still look pale
Majesty this is the first time I am here with you.Who would have thought Nun Mo Chu .. erh .. Wan Ping has fallen ill
What did you say ? Wan Ping is not sleeping well ?What do you mean by that ?
Your Majesty. We were barred from the temple because they said mitstress had tubercolosis.
In the winter her condition worsten
But it was not tubercolosis.She was just never able to fully rest and recover
With spring and medication there is improvement
But mistress misses Princess and Your Majesty
With worry on her mind - her sleep is disturbed
So her illness has dragged on and she's not fully recovered
Everyone away
Go.. goDon't let anyone come near
No
If anyone speaks of this
he will lose his head - understand ?
Understand.Go.
His Majesty ..?
His Majesty is in the company of his lady.Stop being a busybody - Go.
Wan Wan I am here
Si Lang I waited for you
I feel pain
Si Lang
I never expected it to be so smooth
Both have love in their hearts
It's wonderful
Let's leave
Why are you crying ?
Everyone will fall ill when they are old.
We can be wrong till there is no turning back.
Huan Huan knows it herself.
I only know of it today.
It seemed like there was nothing wrong to it back then.
Huan Huan has always thought that your majesty has no feelings for me at all.
But because I am Lung Yue's biological mother.
I was only able to stay in the palace because I resembled her majesty.
Huan Huan treating Si Lang like this, it was all because of Huan Huan getting hurt from all the feelings.
There is no use in saying such things now.
Si Lang
At least Si Lang still have some feelings for me.
No, even if its just a little
Huan Huan will die without regrets.
Huan Huan has left Si Lang for three years. Not seeing Si Lang for three years
Si Lang still thinks of Huan Huan.
I heard his majesty say
Your highness immediately heads here afterhearing that I fell sick
As long as Huan Huan knows that Si Lang still have some true feelings for me
there will be no regrets from separating us.
If I knew earlier, I would rather lose ten years of my lifespan..
Don't say that.
Huan Huan,
Three years at Gan Lu Si has soften you up a lot,
if you weren't so stubborn and head strong, I would have never let you leave.
I voided all your titles three days after Lung Yue is born,
I wanted you to reflect
If your titles still existed,
how would you truly know the hardship outside the Palace?
Nothing matters anymore,
Huan Huan just wants Si Lang to be here
Si Lang,
I was so scared I will never see you again.
and Lung Yue too
Our Lung Yue
Lung Yue is good, she's an obedient girl
Jing Fei loves her very much.
Too bad I can't bring her here,
Huan Huan has been sick for a long time
it's karma for being so stubborn before.
Even though I left the city,
but not a single person do I not miss.
Fang Ruo came and visit me,
I don't even dare to ask about you
I'm scared that Fang Ruo will tell me that you have new girls beside you,
I can only pray a thousand times a day
hoping your health, and Lung Yue's
Now that I have reunited with Si Lang,
it's already used all the luck in my life
You have already received punishment for the past,
if you didn't leave the Palace for three years,how am I suppose to realize how much I miss you?
Si Lang's love,
puts me into shame.
Did you know
how much the Palace has changed?
I don't even have anyone to talk to
After you left,
I went to Xui Yu Xian once,
Other than Chang Xiang Xi, you didn't bring anything else
Even this was left onto the table.
Chang Xiang Xi was given by your Highness,
Other than Xiang Xi, there's nothing that I can't leave behind.
Huan Huan,
I made you leave behind everything for me, For me again, you should start dressing up
I will obey everything that Si Lang says
I just one thing to ask,
I am just an abandoned concubine, being able to serve your Highness again is my luck
I don't want to stir up any trouble in the palace.
Still calling your abandoned? How did I address you in front of Jin Xi and them?
Huan Huan, you never left my heart all these years
I've always treated you as Huan Pin.
If you don't wish to cause any stirrups,I won't even tell the Queen
Your life here on after,
I will make sure Xu Pei Xing takes care of it.
As long as you still have me in your heart,
I don't mind spending my life here.
Huan Huan is so understanding,
I won't let you be along your whole life.
The Empress Dowager is feeling unwell, I shall make Gan Lu Si hosts prayers every month,
and I will come here myself.