Subtitles brought to you by The Legend of Zhen Huan Team
~ Episode 9 ~
Precious Wan and Precious Shen are close sisters
How could you forget to share with your sister
when you were specially favored
Niang Niang wants me to copy the female analects of Confucius
for the purpose of instructing the women in the harem.
How could I not know
that jealousy and hate are unvirtuous?
Although I am untalented and slow,
I absolutely wouldn't dare be unvirtuous.
Although you may be virtuous,
others might not be the same.
I've been in the palace for many years
Cold-blooded
and constantly changing hearts I've seen many cases of.
Many thanks Niang Niang for your reminder
Niang Niang has already asked Jiejie to copy the Confucian analects
in order to instruct the harem women
against fighting over favor
and causing disturbances.
Niang Niang has really give much thought to the matter. We will most certainly comply.
Precious Wan's words sound so good
Precious Shen and Precious Wan have been here for a while
Your sweet-talking skills are getting good
You can't be overlooked
I got up early to pay respects to Empress
and then talked too much just now, really tired
Let's go back
Today you have seen with your own eyes
Never mind Princess of Glory
Jiejie, do you blame me?
If it's not you, it will be someone else
If it's someone else, I'd rather it be you
Don't blame me for saying something selfish
If someone else is favored,
I'm afraid that one day she will harm me.
Huan'er, you wouldn't
Mei Jiejie
Among so many people in the palace,
the only one I can trust is you.
Although Lingrong is good friends with us,
after all she did not grow up together with us.
If even you and I cannot support each other,
then how can the next 10 years
be endured?
Jiejie, it is not what I'm supposed to be
and I can't avoid it on my own
but no matter whether I was favored or not
you are always my good sister
even I was favored by his majesty
please don't break up with me
Being favored is not a surprise because of our talent
even if it's not forever
we must keep alive,
and not involve our relatives
Why are you awake
I can hear the rain outside.
can't sleep, you are worried
No
Don't lie to me
Your Majesty, I am afraid
I'm here, what are you afraid of
You are very kind to me
Have you ever heard that the most favored
is also the most hated
Does anyone give you troubles
No, no one gave me troubles
The palaces will be peaceful only if each one recives equal amount of rains
In this way we can continue the Royal Genealogy and fortune
I dare not be the most and only favored one
What if I don't agree?
The Feis and Pins in the palaces have complicated relations with the former dynasty
A slight move in one part may affect the whole situation.
Your majesty is a wise emperor
A wise emperor?
It has been seven days
Your majesty has lots of government affairs
if the harem is fulled of hatred,
you will be worried
If your majesty only favors me
and desolates the others,
they will inevitably say that
men are fickle, love the new and loathe the old
I can't let your majesty worriy,
I know
Your son is here to show his respect for the Empress Dowager
Bless the Empress Dowager
Sit down
Thank you, Empress Dowager
The Emperor looks healthy
The person who recently serves the Emperor, is she smart?
Your son really likes the new Wan precious
Wan precious? I haven't heard you mention her before
She is the one who entered the Palace last year
the smart and clever girl who got picked
She was ill before. She became well only recently
That is good
The most important thing for the Emperor
is to have someone intimate besides you
Dont be like No. 17
Even now he is still not settled down, and marry a wife
I have not seen him coming into Palace recently
I do know what is he busily doing
Empress Dowager, if you miss him
I will ask him to come in at noon
No. 17 is filial
However when I see him
I will be reminded about the time when former Emperor was alive
His mother Princess Shu was the only favored one in the Palace
All other princess were jealousy.
I was not happy about that period,
I am getting older. When I have free time, I will think too much
So I would be nagging
Every words said by the Empress Dowager is precious. I understand
Next time when the Empress Dowager has time
I will send Wan Precious to you
Please teach her
There are a lot of ladies in the harem, more than flowers
Those with precious titles
are just like the daisies covering the whole ground
They are all over the place
When she gets rasied to Pin position,
then I will see her
Okay
Sun gugu
These 2 days the Empress Dowager was not feeling well
Did the Princess of Glory come to visit?
The Princess of Glory was too busy helping manage the harem.
This morning the Empress came
She left after serving medicine to the Empress Dowager
Yesterday the Pin of Beauty came
She chatted together with the Empress Dowager
The Pin of beauty
The nameplate of the Pin of beauty
How could it be covered with dust?
Send it back and make a new one
These 2 days
Dont just send in some random nameplates for the Emperor
Princess of Regularity
Eunuch Xiao Xia Zi. Why are you here?
Niang Niang
The Emperor is coming to the Hall of Ever Spring
Your servant come to let you know first
NiangNiang, please get ready to welcome the Emperor
The Emperor is coming?
Is the Emperor really coming?
Yes
Hurry up to put this away
And that
Niang Niang
NIangNiang, be careful
This is a mess
How could I welcome the Emperor
NiangNiang has served the Emperor many years
You already knew about Emperor's taste
The Emperor has not visited me for more then half a year
How come today he suddenly visit me?
NiangNiang, you are not happy?
Happy! Happy!
Go, bring a cloth for me.
I want a pink one
The Emperor likes me wear pink
Yes
Hurry up
Yes, NiangNiang
Don't just stay here
Help me dress and groom
Yes, Niangniang
Oh. Hurry and get the 3rd prince for me.
Niangniang, it is rare for the Emperor to come
You should have some quality time with him
With the 3rd prince here
How could you talk with the Emperor intimately
Yes. The child speaks too care free.
Let's avoid to make the Emperor upset again
Don't call him then. Hurry hurry! Dress me up.
Yes
Niangniang, your servant leaves now
Niangniang, drink swallow's nest and take a break
Did the Emperor flip her nameplate again?
The Emperor went to the Princess of Regularity
Why did he go there?
It does not matter who she is
as long as she is not Wan Precious
What time is it?
The time is early. It just went dark
Didn't the Emperor ask Precious Shen
to learn to look at account book?
Let me teach her well
Call Precious Shen
Yes
The candles are too bright
Blow 2 candles out for me
Yes
Don't wait anymore, my lady
The Emperor turned the nameplate of Princess of Regularity today.
He went to the Palace of Ever Spring
That is good
What my lady just said
sounds happy yet also sounds unhappy
I am confused also
I hoped his majesty not come
but it can't cheer me up when he really didn't come
Anyhow, Precious Shen is a girl from respectable families
how come the illegible handwriting
The candle light is too dim, I couldn't see it clearly
Please forgive me
You copied the account book yourself
must know how huge the expense is in the harem
I am the head of all the princesses
have to set an example to be economize
Besides, I heard that if one's handwriting is beaultiful
even the darkness can't bother
Your excuse is unconvincing.
What about I copy it again
Fine, I'll take a nap
Songzi, it's too bright here
blow two more out
Yes
Sit
It's alright, I'll just stand to serve your majesty.
I'm not tired
You get in the light,
how can I read
get in the light
Your majesty, reading in the dim light is harmful for your eyes
Drink a cup of mum tea will keep you awake
Didn't you just let me drink the ginseng soup
I forgot
Your majesty, the 3rd prince grow taller
He is an adult, how come he "grow taller"
That's right. He's grown stronger.
He has followed Your Majesty's instructions
and is practicing on the hunting grounds every day
Your Majesty's words
are previous to the 3rd prince
I hope so.
I hope that he will remember them
Yes, Your Majesty
The 3rd prince studies late into the night
and gets up before dawn to practice archery and horse riding
Whenever I see the 3rd prince,
I will say
"Hong Shi,
you must follow your Father's instructions."
"You are your Father's oldest son
you must live up to his expectations."
"In the future, when your Father needs someone to share his burdens
it will fall to you."
These words of yours
will cause Hong Shi's ears to grow worms
My ears too
Don't you have anything else to teach your son?
Yes... I...
This set of clothing doesn't look nice. Don't wear it anymore.
Your Majesty, I remember
that you liked it most when I wear pink.
Pink is delicate and young
How old are you now?
Your Majesty thinks I'm old?
I'm speaking the truth
Wearing blue or jade will suit your status better
Sleep early
Your Majesty, where are you going?
I'm returning to the Hall of Resting Soul
Your Majesty!
Tell me, Princess of Regularity hasn't seen His Majesty for so long
she should be very happy, right?
Mistress, don't think too much
Get some rest
There is heavy rain, at Dongting Lake
There is heavy fog, at imperial mausoleum
I was looking forward to seeing you, but you didn't come
The surface of the lake ripples slightly
Mistress, stop playing
This song is called 'Princess Xiao's complaints'. It's inauspicious
Princess Xiao's complaints?
The palace girls' loves and hates
have never left behind deep marks
much less their complaints
What do I have to complain about?
I was the one that told him to go
Halt
Your Majesty, are we returning to Hall of Resting Soul?
Or are we going to Palace of Wings?
Palace of Shattered Jade
Halt
Put down the palantine
This is Princess Xiang's Complaints
Your servant does not know this
Obviously the song is full of sorrow and complaint
that her heart's desire has not returned home
When I'm not around, she is unhappy
You've played with my heartstrings
Greetings, Your Majesty
Get up
Why is Your Majesty here?
I become thinner in order to miss someone is worth.
I finally got the taste of that feeling
Aren't you supposed to be at Princess of Regularity's palace?
I've seen her
On my way back, the moonlight was bright
so I wanted to come and see what you were doing
Such good playing, it's a good thing I didn't miss it
With your words, I have no where to hide my face
The great and mighty ruler
has actually learned to eavesdrop?
You're becoming more audacious
You shall be punished to play another song
By coming here, Princess of Regularity will be upset
Can you bear to see me go to someone else?
I've said that Your Majesty is a wise ruler
I will be a wise ruler tomorrow
Tonight, I shall be a confused ruler
Then I will be a virtuous concubine tomorrow
And ask Sister Qi for forgiveness
Dearest 4th, what tune would you like to hear?
What did you just call me?
I was being rude
I like you calling me that
Your maiden name is Wan Huan, what number were you?
I didn't have a number
Then I shall call you Huan Huan, all right?
Huan Huan?
Finished copying?
I know that my calligraphy is not great
so I copied each ledger twice
please take a look at them
It's late, go back and rest
I will let you know when I have read them
Yes, I take my leave.
Princess of Glory was clearly making things difficult for Mistress
There are only numbers on that ledger
Yet she purposely made the room dark
So that writing it once won't be enough
Mistress' eyes are red
What can I do?
She is the Princess of Glory
Can't mistress tell the Emperor?
She's using His Majesty's instructions to teach me
If I tell His Majesty,
even if he helped me,
would I be allowed to continue to learn how to manage the back palace?
Since I gain nothing out of it, I won't do it.
Your servant feels bad for you
It's fine, I've passed that ordeal
This is near to the Thousand Carp pond
Accompany me for a walk over there
I heard the Emperor added lanterns there
Red fishes are most beautiful at night
There's not much fish food left
Xiaoshi, go and get more
Yes
Mistress, look
So Mistress is here
Your servant had a hard time finding you
Why is Gu Gu coming out so late at night?
Does Niang Niang have any instructions for me?
Niang Niang said that Wei Zhou just sent in some good ink as tribute
and wanted to give some to you
But you left so quickly
Caiyue, follow Gu Gu back
And leave you here alone?
Go and return quickly
Yes
Help!
Save me!
His Majesty has arrived!
Your Officials greet you, Your Majesty
Rise
Thank you, Your Majesty
How is Jiejie's condition?
Replying Precious Wan, Precious Shen is all right now
She just swallowed some water and got scared
and thus is still unconcious
Your Officials have written prescriptions
As long as Precious Shen follows the instructions and rests
she will recover quickly
It's just that...
Don't speak in starts and stops
Yes. It's just that Mistress' shock is not light
I'm afraid she will have to rest for some time
before she will regain her spirits
You have been looking after Precious Shen
make sure she recuperates
Yes
Then Your Officials will go and brew her medicine
Don't bother with the bowing
Mei Jiejie
How do you serve your mistress?
Please punish us, Your Majesty
You were ordered to be careful
How did Precious Shen drown?
Your servants are not sure!
This is ridiculous
You are Precious Shen's close servants
How can you be unsure?
Your servants are maligned, we really do not know
Mistress was feeding the fishes at Thousand Carp Pond
Your servant went to get more fish food
I was on my way when I heard the news
What about Caiyue?
Songzhi said that Princess of Glory had some good ink that she wanted to give to Mistress
but forgot to give it earlier, so she asked me to go get it
So what you're saying is that
when Precious Shen fell into the water,
none of you were by her side?
Your Majesty, Princess of Glory is here
It's already so late, why are you here?
I heard that Precious Shen nearly drowned
and rushed over
Is Precious Shen all right?
Go and take a look
Yes
How pitiful, someone as delicate as her
having to go through such an ordeal
Niang Niang please don't worry
The physician has said that once she wakes up, Precious Shen will be fine
Your Majesty, the guards in the palace have not been patrolling well
that's why Precious Shen was not discovered in time
It's my fault for not handling the back palace well
Please punish me
The night patrolling guards have their shifts
If I punish you
the Empress, as the Centre of the Inner Palace, will not be able to escape punishment either
Ignorant fools, how do you serve your mistress?
Letting His Majesty worry
Useless
These kinds of servants should not be kept around Precious Shen
I think they should be sent to the Bureau of Cautious Punishment
Your Majesty, Xiaoshi and Caiyue
have their bad points
but their actions do not warrant being sent there
If we don't do this, it won't be enough
If all the servants do their jobs thusly
the imperial ponds will be full of drowning people
The servants of Palace of Whole Blessings are incompetent
Pin of Respect cannot escape punishment either
I will listen to Niang Niang's teachings
and punish them suitably
Your servant is at fault for not looking after the Mistress
But Mistress hasn't woken up yet
Please let your servant take care of her until she wakes up
before going to the bureau to receive punishment!
Servants are cheap
Clinging onto this place because you want your mistress to plead for you when she wakes up?
Princess of Glory, please be generous
Cai Yue and Xiaoshi may have been remiss in ther duties
but the whole accident cannot be blamed solely on them
Instead of punishing them,
why not have them serve Mei Jiejie with dedication
to make up for their mistakes?
Does Precious Smiles think that offences should not be punished?
If we let them off lightly,
there will be ugly rumours in the back palace
The servants will think that they can atone for their missteps by making up for it
without getting punished
Niang Niang's distinction between reward and punishment is a must
But Caiyue and Xiaoshi
have always served Mei Jiejie
If we send them to the Bureau of Catious Punishment now
Jiejie will not have any experienced servants by her side
That would be counter-productive
They can't even ensure Precious Shen's safety
what's the use of keeping them by her side
Furthremore, Thousand Carp Pond is less than a hundred paces from Palace of Wings
Such a thing happening within my territory
How can I let them off lightly?
I am worried about exactly that
Niang Niang obviously differentiates between reward and punishment
But less-informed people will think
that because the incident happened near Place of Wings,
it could have an impact on your reputation
which is why you are so impatient
and not because Precious Shen nearly drowned
Servants are insignificant, but Niang Niang's reputation is important
Please reconsider
Precious Smiles' words make sense
Why don't we wait for Precious Shen to wake up before deciding?
At that time, it would not be too late to send them to the Bureau of Cautious Punishment
I have one more thing to say, although I'm not sure if I should
Speak
Why Jiejie fell into the pond is still a mystery
But it's the guards' who did not save in time
thus making her inhale too much water and unconscious
In my opinion
It's better to replace the guards in Palace of Wings
Otherwise, this time is Mei jiejie
if there's another carelessness next time
and it hurts Princess of Glory, that is not good
Precious Smile said one can make up for his mistake just now
Why are you suggest replacing the guards in my palace now
Isn't there too much partiality?
I am just concerned about Niangniang
His majesty always love Niangniang
How can his majesty let such careless servants protece Niangniang's palace
and put Niangniang into dangerous situation
Besides, it's only replace them
not punish them
It's not important
But such things can't happen anymore
Tomorrw, I'll let Su Pei Sheng
replace the guards in Palace of Wings
This way, I'll be more relieved
Thank you for Your Majesty's concern
I got two superior wild ginsengs
It's the best choice to recover her body
You are concerned about the affairs in the Back Palaces all the time
It is too late for you to be working
Go back and rest
Your majesty have to go to the Royal Court tomorrow
don't be too tired, too
Befor I came, I asked the servants to cook the Dong-E-E-Jiao longan soup
It must be ready now,
Your majesty may have some first and then rest
You are so considerate
I'm hungry
Go with me and have some
the foods in Princess of Glory's palace are top-notch in the palaces
Your majesty overpraised me
Come with us, Precious smile
I don't have the luck to eat such good things
Your majesty, please eat my part for me
I want to take care of Mei Jiejie here
Alright, also take care of yourself
We respectly send Your Majesty
and Princess of Glory out
His Majesty is leaving
It's too late at night
Pin of Respects go back early and rest
OK, don't be too tired
Are you not weary, niangniang?
How about having some supper
Poor Precious Shen
What does Niang Niang think about tonight's incident?
Dong-E-E-Jiao longan soup
Princess of Glory was well prepared
Niang Niang has sharp ears and Precious Smile has sharp eyes
Princess of Glory was dressed too tidily
She had every step planned out
Right, want to act a fox
she should hide her tail
But, what a pity, once get dizzy with success
the tail came out itself
She is too busy to hide the tail
Having cooked the soup
asking his majesty to go there is a must
she had to make up well
His majesty was concerned about Precious Shen,
may not see this
Needn't we tell his majesty
no use
she has an eye on our Palace of Whole Blessings
mean to pick a hole in us
do we need to make it for her?
It's almost fourth watch of the night, young mistress, you need a rest
I can't sleep, I'm worried
Servant is also worried
Servant just can't believe
young mistress could fell into the water herself
Think carefully
at that time
did you see anything strange
Of course, this is merely my conjecture
Why the acident happen to jiejie
once you are not with her
Now, jiejie is unconscious
If you miss something
we'll all be fooled
Servant know this is very important
but servant didn't see it clearly
so I dare not to say
It's very important
so you should speak everything out
When servant got the ink and went back
there may be a little Eunuch
slide out of the pond
Because of the darkness
I'm not sure if it's my eyes' illusion
Anyone else know this?
Servant really don't dare to tell any others
Remember
don't tell anyone else
Yes
Because of the slut's one word
his majesty replaced all the guards around me
making it inconvenient for me to get in and out.
Niangniang, don't be angry
it's harmful to your body
how dare she set foot on my head
Niangniang, don't worry
Now, she is favored
there are many people hate her
Who is serving Yu?
I heared she has lost the emperor's favor, and is in a foul temper
she has even driven out the only maid by her side - she is pitifully alone
Your servant Kang Lu Hai is useless,
but is his junior loyal?
You are referring to Xiao Yin Zi, Niang Niang?
He is not as scheming as his master,
but he is more useful
Let him serve Yu
This ink stick is a tribute from the governor of Shangdong
Forgive my ignorance - I cannot identify it
I do require your guidance, Niang Niang
This is called Literate Double Mandarin Ducks ink
It is as solid as a jade and has an even consistency,
adorned with carvings of mandarin ducks on both sides,
and plated with gold. This is ink of the highest quality.
Your humble servant knows not the others,
except the prosperous significance of the mandarin ducks
His Majesty and you, Niang Niang, are in harmony
just like the pair of mandarin ducks
He is able to cater to my pleasure
But as good as this ink stick is
it never can compare with Palace of Wings's ink
when it comes to use
Palace of Wings's ink is used as a trap to kill someone
Though of big use, does bad things
Some things don't have to be said aloud
Yes
But Niangniang, do you really want to leave this alone
You saw how arrogant the Princess of Glory was when she paid her respects to me
From this, you can see
how his majesty has decided how to deal with this case
Even though I want to give a hand, I can't
Anyway, we all know
who did it
His majesty doesn't know
so it makes no sense even though we all know
His majesty only wants peace in the harem
somethings will end up with no definition
Send some tonic to Precious Shen
Yes
Jiejie, you're awake?
Are you hungry? Do you want to eat something?
Huan'er
Someone wants to kill me
Jiejie, did you see who it was?
He pushed me into the water from the back
I could not see him clearly
I just know that he had an inordinate amount of strength
It was either a eunuch or a guard
There are thousands of guards and eunuchs in the palace
Did you see who it exactly is?
Though palace's inhabitants are duplicitous
it is unthinkable that they are malevolent to the point of plotting my death
To be able to do this...
There is only one...
But the Thousand Carp Pond and her Palace of Wings are so near
If she wanted to deal with me
she should not choose to do it on her own territory
She should know to avoid suspicion
Avoid suspicion?
I don't think she wants to avoid suspicion at all
Coming here in full regalia in the middle of the night
throwing her weight around in your palace
and nearly getting rid of Caiyue and Xiaoshi
She even invited His Majesty to her palace
You just left the Palace of Wings
and then fell into the pond after only a short time
Nowadays in the palaces
who would dare make trouble in her territory?
Only she would dare to do so
By doing the unexpected
Others will not suspect
She saw that you had gained the emperor's favor
and was afraid that we would join hands to gain power
until she has no hold against us
So she thought to get rid of one of us
so that our influence would be weakened
and we'll be defenseless against her.
I'm sorry, Jiejie.
I have implicated you.
It's not your fault
When I was being favoured
she already hated me
But it's his majesty's favour
and my tolerance and deference
that stayed her hand
Now
What do you intend to do?
What can I do?
I have no evidence
And she has long had His Majesty's love
I will tell His Majesty
that I fell into the water
out of carelessness on my own part
It seems like that's our only solution
I can't afford to offend her now
but it doesn't mean that this will be the case forever
At least I still have my life
We'll settle our scores with her one day
Thank you for watching!
Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team