Subtitles brought to you by The Legend of Zhen Huan Team
~ Episode 10 ~
Now, the Internal Affairs Authority
chooses the best thing and sends to us
Everyone knows that his majesty loves young mistress
And his majesty asked imperial physician Wen
to make herbal tonic for you once a day
It's not that good as you think
the tonic is very bitter
Oh, by the way, Yu is so mean
I heared that after she moved out of Palace of Essence
she curses young mistress all the time
Leave her alone
I haven't done anything bad.
I won't have any karma coming after me.
But, she cursed so vicious
Send servant to report to the Empress
and ask Empress to help
Let's not make her life any more miserable
Forgive her
She lost his majesty's favor, can't feel well
she'll be fine after some time
Young mistress is so kind
Young mistress, the tonic is ready
The tonic is so acid recently
Maybe Dr. Wen changed the prescription
I just got up not long ago, now I'm tired again
These days, young mistress are sleepy
Shortly after gets up, I got sleepy again
Help me in and sleep
Huanbi
When did I become sleepy
About 3 or 5 days ago, young mistress became easily sleepy
You almost sleep 10 to 12 hours a day
The day before yesterday, when his majesty came
it's almost noon
but young mistress was still in bed
There's something wrong, right?
Young mistress, don't sleep first
I'll ask Lord Wen to come
Don't let others know
You just say it's a regular check up
Young mistress, pardon me. This will hurt a bit.
This acupoint is called Hegu acupoint
If young mistress are just physically sleepy
the needle will not change
If it's due to drugs,
this needle will change color.
Indeed someone has been
tampering with my medicine.
Young mistress, please look
This needle tip has a light blue-green color
What is it? Poison?
No
In my medicine, someone added
more of an ingredient than the prescription called for.
This person was very cautious
A very small dosage was added
so that during young mistress's regular check ups,
it would be very hard to detect.
But even so,
if this dosage is consumed for long periods of time,
young mistress will start to feel exhausted and sleepy at first.
In under half a year,
it will cause delirium, tantamount to dementia.
The conspirator is thinking highly of me
using such a careful way to murder me
Fortunately it was discovered early
young mistress will be fine
after some treatments
Clearly this person wants to subject young mistress to death
This tactic is too sinister
Fighting over favor in the inner palace
has always resorted to extreme, unscrupulous measures.
It is truly impossible to guard against
If not for Lord Wen,
I would probably die in my sleep.
It is my negligence
that caused young mistress to suffer.
In the future, I must be extraordinarily careful
From procuring to preparing the medicine, until young mistress takes it,
I will do everything personally.
I won't let anyone else intervene
Although it's important to take precautions,
the most urgent matter now
is to find that person
who wants to poison and harm me.
All the medicine is delivered here according to the prescription
and brewed in my palace.
In order to put the poison inside my palace
It must be someone here
A month ago, young mistress's palace
got several new servant ladies and eunuchs.
And young mistress's medicine
just happened to have problems
after they arrived.
Seems that in this matter,
I should pay more attention to those new
servant ladies and eunuchs.
Young mistress, what would you like to do?
I would like Lord Wen
to put on a play with Huan'er.
Pretend as if nothing happened, to avoid alerting the enemy
I will do everything that young mistress ask
It is so kind of you, Lord Wen
Lord says I'm fine, I can now rest assured
Feeling drowsy and oversleeping in the spring is common
Might as well take this opportunity to get some good rest
Many thanks Lord Wen
Young mistress, servant discovered
a small hole underneath the palace walls.
It hasn't been there for long, seems a bit strange
Troubles start inside the house.
It must be made on purpose
Just pretend you don't know
When brewing the medicine tomorrow,
you and Xiao Yunzi stay vigilant.
catch him and physical evidence
when he is unprepared
Yes
Xiao Yunzi knows some kung fu
he will not let the assassin escape
Respect to Empress
Respect to each Jiejie
Stand up
Sit
Thanks, Empress
I'm assured
seeing Precious Shen get well
Precious Shen's falling
is really a blessing in disguise
Gains his majesty's favour and visitations
Such a fortune is a wild wish to others
Yeah
Recently, I saw many people
around the Thousand Carps Pond
I wonded why
but I think
Maybe
they want to fall into the pond like Precious Shen
in this way, his majesty's favour would certainly come
You are good at joking
Who will use their lives as a joke?
Right
Precious Shen has always been favoured
Only those old and out of favour
will try their best to keep His Majesty
Hearing Niang niang's words, I am really scared
Who wouldn't one day grow old and ugly?
I'd better go to the Hall of Splendid Treasure and pray
pray to the buddha
I wish that I could stay as young and beautiful as Princess of Glory
Buddha is busy in dealing prays
have no time
you'd better accumulate virtue on your own
and pray yourself
I heard that when Precious Shen was still sick in bed,
Precious Smiles was there waiting on you
Why isn't she here with you today?
No matter how deep one's friendship is
it cannot withstand the Emperor's favour
I heard His Majesty asked Precious Smiles
to his study room
which is why she isn't here today
Oh, I see
your deep friendship is merely thus
Your servant has been standing watch the whole time
while Pei'er brewed the tonic
No one else got close
It's still been poisoned.
Your servant must have slipped up
Please young mistress forgive us
it's not your fault
he can poision under your nose without being caught
and no one get close to it during brewing
We must be missing something.
Huanbi, pour out the medicine later
and don't let others see
Yes
What are you looking at?
I was thinking
If no one personally put the poison in,
then these things must have been tampered with.
Let me see
Nothing seems wrong
Maybe we're thinking about it the wrong way
Come take a look
Isn't the color of the lid
a bit darker than the rest of the jar?
Really!
If you don't look closely you really can't tell
Why is that?
Could it be that this jar lid
was boiled in medicine water for a long time
and absorbed the medicine?
So it turned darker?
Once young mistress's medicine comes to a boil,
it will touch this "drugged" lid.
Then the medicine in the lid
will mix with young mistress's medicine, without anyone knowing.
What a sophisticated method
No wonder we couldn't find anything
So there were preparations made in advance
Who's usually in charge of these things?
Originally it was me
but now they are maintained by the new servant lady Hua Sui.
Xiao Yunzi
Here
Dump the medicine. Then put the jar back.
Don't make them suspicious
Yes
Then check out Hua Sui's background for me
Yun Gong Gong
Hua Sui
Why are you standing so suspiciously behind my back?
Yun Gong Gong, the little kitchen is not clean
why did you personally trouble yourself to come over?
I am Shattered Jade Palace's Head Eunuch
is there anywhere in this place where I cannot go?
If I weren't to come here, I'd still be in the dark
This old medicine pot
How come you're still using it for our mistress's medicine?
An onlooker seeing it
would think that our mistress has lost favour!
Go and get it changed immediately
Gong gong, you may not know this
the tools used to brew tonics don't need to be expensive
On the contrary, ones that have been used the longest are the best
Otherwise, the medicine will lose it's potency so we shouldn't change it so easily
That's reasonable
Then keep using it for now
Yes
Do your job well, and you will be well-rewarded
Right
Young mistress needs to nap after taking her medicine
Quickly prepare the medicine for tonight
Don't delay
Yes
Aiyo
I inquired about it
Hua Sui was previously a servant to Lady Yu
After Yushi was demoted,
several of her servants were sent away.
Hua Sui was among those sent away
She was then assigned to young mistress's palace
Seems like
that wench is taking revenge for Yushi!
What a loyal servant
Ask her in here, I have something to ask her
Yes
Since you're going to the kitchen, bring some pieces of hot charcoal
The kind that turns bright red when it burns
It will definitely be useful later
Huanbi Jiejie is here
Mistress' tonic is almost ready
Not a hurry. I will stay here for a while.
Doctor Wen said these were the best medicines for our mistress
I've been watching it the entire time
Hua Sui, although you're new here,
you're rather loyal
It's my fortune to be able to serve in Palace of Shattered Jade
I dare not be unloyal
Mistress knows that you're loyal
she said she wants to reward you later
Go on in
Mistress wants to reward me?
Hurry up and go in, otherwise you'll be making her wait
In a while bring the coal burner, so that the medicine doesn't cool
Yes
Raise your head, you act like we want to eat you
Don't be scared
I just want to ask you a few things
Yes
Jinxi says you're doing well at your work
and you're very organised and tidy
I'm very happy
and was wondering how I should reward you
so that the others will know that I'm fair with my rewards and punishments
and do better at their jobs
Thank you, Mistress!
I'm just doing my job
You're one of the best amongst the new batch of servants
Which palace were you from previously?
Your mistress could actually bear to let you go?
Your servant is clumsy and lazy, I never followed a good mistress before
Working for Precious' palace
is my greatest fortune
Yu Shi has been demoted
and thus cannot be considered a good mistress
But she must have given you a lot to be thankful for
Otherwise how would you dare to commit an offense deserving death?
Your servant did serve Mistress Yu in the past
But your servant does not know
what Precious is referring to
Do you really not know what I'm talking about?
Then what's the matter with
the lid of my tonic-brewing pot?
Your servant does not know
I am loyal to you
Please investigate!
All right, since you say you're loyal to Precious,
we'll give you an opportunity to prove your loyalty
You have worked for Yu Shi before
which is why Mistress must pay extra attention to you
If you dare to hold this coal burner in your hands
we will all believe that you're innocent and loyal
and treat you very well in future
Hurry up and go
Do you not dare to?
It looks like your loyalty to our mistress is fake!
Please spare my life, Precious
Then tell me honestly
If there is even a hint of untruth
you'll be dragged out immediately and beaten to death
After I entered Palace of Shattered Jade
One day, Mistress Yu asked your servant to go over
She gave me a lot of money
and forced me to work for her
Your servant... was foolish...
I'm begging for your forgiveness
You just keep talking about yourself
This is your chance to redeem yourself
If there are any hidden truths, I will not spare you
Mistress Yu said
your servant need not worry about anything else
as long as I put the poison in your medication and food
Your servant followed Mistress Yu's orders
and dug a hole by the wall
Whenever Mistress Yu had instructions
or wanted to bring something in
someone would stick a note into the hole
and all I had to do was retrieve it
Was that how the poison was brought in?
Was Mistress Yu also the one who taught you
to boil the lid of the pot in the poison?
Yes
Do you have other accomplices?
No, there's nothing else!
Then, what time does
Yu Shi put the note in the hole?
This...
- Xiaoyunzi - I'm here
Force open her mouth and shove a coal inside
I'll speak, I'll speak!
Every other day,
Mistress Yu will have someone place the poison in the hole
All I have to do is retrieve it
Every other day? Isn't that tonight?
At what time do you retrieve the medicine? Are there any hidden codes?
At the first hour of the day
there will be two bird's calls outside the palace wall
Then that's that
Your servant then replies with two bird calls
Have you ever seen the person who delivers the poison?
Through a wall; your servant has never seen him
But it's a man's hand
On his right palm, he has a scar
Xiaoyunzi
lock her up in the storehouse, and don't let her commit suicide
If anyone asks
say I sent her to Precious Shen
Yes
Let's go
Jinxi, pretend to be Hua Sui tonight and retrieve the poison
Then get Xiaoyunzi and some strong eunuchs
to wait in ambush
Yes, I will go do that now
I have to tell Mei jiejie about today's incident
Yes, Precious Shen should know
she can contribute ideas too
What about Promise An?
Lingrong is timid
Don't tell her lest she gets scared
All right
Mistress must be firm this time,
you cannot be forgiving
Mistress, Xiaoyunzi is up there
When the bastard turns up
he will jump down and catch the person alive
Your servant will go take a look
Xiaoyunzi knows some martial arts
If one doesn't pay attention,
one really can't tell that he's there
He's been caught
Xiaoyunzi, he's been caught!
Hurry up and go!
Catch him!
- Walk! - Let me go
- Please let me go - Man up!
- Please let me go - Stop struggling
- I'm begging you, let me go - Kneel!
Mistress, please let me go
Raise his head, I may know him
Xiaoyingzi?
Ying Gong Gong, how are you?
Greetings, Precious
Although we haven't met in a long time
But we were master and servant for a while
Just answer whatever I ask you
Has the paddle been prepared?
Replying, young mistress, it's been prepared
Where are you working now?
I'm working for Official Lady Yu
That must be hard on you
As a servant, I have no choice who I follow
there is nothing good or bad
You certainly look on the bright side of things
At the time, didn't you follow your Shifu
to work for Pin of Beauty?
Why are you with Official Lady Yu now?
Shifu wanted to return to you
and offended Pin of Beauty.
I was also dragged down with him
Pin of Beauty let me atone for my mistake
by serving Official Lady Yu.
Pin of Beauty plans far ahead for you
I want to ask you, what are you doing in the middle of the night
sneaking around my palace?
This...
- Xiaoyunzi - Here
Brutally beat this back-stabbing betrayer
Beat him until he owns up with the truth
Yes
Precious, please spare my life!
Precious!
Precious, please spare my life. Precious!
Everything I've said is true!
Please spare my life!
He couldn't take torture
He already confessed
saying Lady Yu put him up to this.
Tie him up. Lock him up with Hua Sui.
Watch those two closely
Yes
Look at this situation. How could I not be bitterly disappointed?
I treated him well in the past
You don't need to be disappointed in this type of person
Now it's clear
It must be Yushi exacting revenge out of hatred
I have already exercised enough restraint with Yushi
But she's still forcing me step by step
Mei Jiejie, living peacefully in the palace...
why is it so difficult?
Man doesn't want to hurt the lion, but the lion wants to hurt man
You and I haven't forced anyone
Yet they want to take our lives
This matter
should be reported to the Emperor and Empress.
You have all the evidence, Yu Shi can't deny it
It's just that...if His Majesty still has any old feelings for her,
it will be difficult.
Poison and curses haven't killed our mistress
She still has a reason to live
But the act of treason demands the perpetrator's death
Young mistress, do you remember your servant asking you
on the night of new year's eve,
is anyone masquerading in Garden of Winter Plums?
Niang Niang
What's so urgent?
Xiao Yinzi didn't return to Yushi's all night
I received news first thing in the morning
that after entering Palace of Shattered Jade, he never came back out.
Incompetent idiot
Niang Niang, eunuchs have no balls
They can't endure any torture. He probably already confessed.
Yushi definitely can't be saved
Will she rat out Niang Niang?
What do you think?
End things once and for all
No
If Niang niang makes your move now
you will garner attention to yourself
Just let Yu Shi deny everything
She wants Zhen Huan to die for her own revenge
But for the chance of living, why wouldn't she betray us?
She wants to live
But what she wants more is for her whole family to live
You spoke for so long?
The meaning has to be clear, I am not eloquent
If you are not eloquent, then few are
Things have to be said clearly
and it must be said in a way that moves the Emperor, right?
Thank you, Gong Gong, for your advice
We've known each other for so many years
yet you're still doing this?
What did His Majesty say?
What else could he say?
Next, we'll have to rely on you
Su Pei Sheng!
Who are you? How dare you barge your way in here!
On His Majesty's orders, Yu Shi is annulled and will be thrown into the Cold Palace
I don't believe this, I don't believe this!
I want to see the Emperor!
You want to see the Emperor?
The Emperor does not want to see you! Move!
I don't believe you. I want to see the Emperor!
I greet your Majesty, may you have good health
Rise
Thank you, Your Majesty
Did you sleep well last night?
Thank you for Your Majesty's concern
But I didn't sleep very well
I know
Jinxi came by this morning to tell the Empress and myself
From now on, your medicine and food
will be monitored carefully
This dark deed will not happen again
It's my fault for being careless and not realising it
It's not that you did not realise it
It's that the fighting for favour in the back palace
was something that I never expected
I have ordered Hua Sui and Xiaoyingzi to be killed
As for Yushi,
I have had her stripped of her title and thrown into the Cold Palace for life
Huan Huan, you needn't be scared anymore
Huan Huan has never competed with anyone for anything
But because I unintentionally offended Yushi
so many other people's lives were implicated
Huan Huan's sins are plentiful, I have no right to receive your favour
You're thinking too much
You were innocently wronged and frightened
Don't cry yourself to sickness
Huan Huan prayed during the New Year's Eve
I wish. If the wind can understand my heart,
then it shall not break me.
(comparing herself to the winter plums)
But heaven does not abide by the wishes of me.
Where did you make this wish? And what did you wish for?
The night of New Year's in the Garden of Winter Plums
I hope if the wind can understand my heart,
then it shall not break me.
That night, the snow was slippery
I even wet my shoes and socks
Then did you meet anyone?
How does Dearest 4th know?
That night, when I was in the Winter Blossom Garden,
I ran into a male stranger
But because I was outside while ill,
and I wasn't supposed to interact with males,
so I had to lie and say I was a palace maid in order to get away
Don't tell me that man...
I lost my composure, I did not know it was Your Majesty
Please punish me
So it was you. It was actually you
I mistook someone else for you
Su Pei Sheng!
Your servant is here
Send out my edict,
Yushi of Cold Palace has committed treason and tried to poison my concubine
She is sentenced to death (by suicide)
Yes, your servant will do so immediately
What's wrong, Your Majesty? Why do you suddenly want to kill Yushi?
She lied to me
She actually claimed to be
the lady from the winter blossom garden
and used it to gain my favour
She's committed so many wrongs
but because of that night, I've spared her life
Now, however, she has nothing to save her
Yushi's many wrongs
came about because of her admiration for Your Majesty
A ruler does not lie. Yushi's crimes are unforgivable
But, since you have pleaded for her,
I will allow her body to be returned to her family
Thank you, Your Majesty
That day when you were praying in the Winter Blossom Garden,
were you carrying any personal effects on you?
Like a satchet or a jade pendant or jewellery?
Those are just a girl's playthings
If Dearest 4th likes it, Huan Huan can make another
This matter has caused you undue stress
You should wait until you have released this burden to make it
I'm not in a hurry; our days are still long
I asked you over here to tell you something
The Ministerium has been ordered to build a farming field
The Officials are all in a flurry of discussions
Some are for it, some are against it
I was thinking, rather than let them make useless noise,
why don't I make a trip down myself?
It's just outside the Capital, so the trip will only take a few days
Farming fields are what the commoners rely on
Nothing else is more important
When is Your Majesty leaving?
Everything has been arranged I can leave immediately
Your Majesty must be careful while you're out of the palace
I wanted to bring Su Pei Sheng
But he's a Eunuch, it's not convenient for him to leave
When I was a Duke,
I used to travel on the behalf of my Father
so I know how to take care of myself
Stay in the palace and look after your health
Wait for me to come home
Has Precious Cao's matter been dealt with?
Niang Niang, don't look she often head down
like a puzzle.
(puzzle means taciturn person)
What she says
all are reasonable.
She has to settle for Yu's family.
She is careful
If she didn't have the ability to handle matters for Niang Niang,
she wouldn't be suitable to stay by your side.
Speaking of ability
Back then at the Duke's residence you were more favored than her
Why is it that now, you can't compare?
Doesn't Precious Cao have a daughter?
Of course His Majesty sees her more
Yes, even having a daughter is good
Why are both of you so glum?
I am feeling suffocated.
What's wrong?
I hate being ambushed
and I hate Hua Sui and Xiaoyingzi
But His Majesty really ordered for them to be killed
I don't feel good about that
Yeah
I don't feel good seeing someone get killed either
Moreover, we had overthrown one person,
don't know after that how many people are there.
We'll deal with it one at a time
As long as we're united, no one can harm us
Jiejie, really.
You kept something this huge from me
I had to hear about it from the Empress
that Yushi wanted to kill Jiejie
and that she even pretended to be Jiejie in order to win His Majesty's favour
I didn't mean to keep it from you
But such matters are frightening
it's best to be ignorant about it
But I treat you like my real older sister
There is no logic in
a younger sister not knowing when her older sister is in trouble
It's good that everything is over
As long as you're all right
His Majesty has ordered Yushi to be killed
Whoever wants to harm us has to die
Lingrong is usually gentle and quiet
but she's also a person with ideas and fortitude
Mistress
Yushi refuses to die
and is kicking up a big fuss in the Cold Palace
She insists on seeing the Emperor one last time
How can she?
At this hour, His Majesty has probably already left the palace
Are we supposed to let her live until the Emperor returns?
Do you report back to Empress?
These days Empress headache.
Can't get out of bed.
So she can't deal with this matter.
Then only the Princess of Glory can handle this matter
There is no movement from the Princess of Glory at all
She said she's not feeling well
She has been close with Yushi
She must be avoiding the risk of being connected to her
Yushi says that she has been maligned
She broke the poisonous wine and appears to have gone mad
and is even cursing our mistress in the Cold Palace
Her words are vicious and not fit to be heard
Let her be, protesting against death
Jiejie, it looks like it's getting late
I'll go back first
Be careful on your way back
Walk slowly, sister
Baojun, what kind of place is the Cold Palace exactly?
That's where the anulled concubines are locked up in
In the past, a lot of deposed concubines
went crazy or died because
they could not stand being locked up in there
Everyone feels that this is a place of bad luck and evil
that's why it's called the Cold Palace
Then does anyone normally go there?
What kind of place is that?
In the past, servants living nearby
often saw spirits coming from there and heard crying throughout the night
It's terrifying
I want to go take a look
Young mistress, let's not go in
It's scary
Let go of me
Let go of me!
Yushi, just accept your fate
Let go!
Let go of me
Why has Promise An come here?
Zhen Jiejie heard that Yushi is cursing her
and asked me to come here and take a look
Let go, let go of me!
What's wrong? Gong Gong's work is not done?
Still wildly.
Why is it you?
Where is the Emperor?
Let go of me!
- Drag her away.
- Let go of me!
Emperor has a precious identity.
How could he enter Cold Palace easily.
It's all Zhen Huan's fault! That b*tch!
Talking the Emperor into killing me!
You don't want to die so much
just because you want to know the reasons.
Then I will tell you
You were the one who tampered with Zhen Jiejie's medicine, weren't you?
Yes, I was the one that gave the order
If it weren't for her,
I wouldn't have lost favour with the Emperor
and be left in my current state!
I want to gnaw on her bones and drink her blood
so that that wench won't be able to be reincarnated!
What's the use of desperate want?
The winner takes it all. You must hurry to die.
No, I can't die
The Emperor and I met on the New Year
The Emperor likes to listen to me sing Kun Opera
He can't bear to let me die
On the night of New Year's Eve in the Garden of Winter Plums
"If the wind can understand the plums' intention , it will not break the plums"
You took from Jiejie's favour
What grace do you have left to continue to live?
It's her. It's actually her!
No, I can't die. I cannot die!
Your Majesty!
You like to listen to me sing Kun Opera!
Gong Gong, may I speak with you in private?
I'll sing for you again, Your Majesty!
Young mistress
His majesty is vexed, and The Empress has a headache again
For her to continue making a fuss like this will not be tolerated
Your Majesty!
His Majesty granted her death by suicide
But this crazy woman has broken the poison wine jar and ripped up the white cloth (for hanging)
It's practically impossible
Hasn't Gong Gong served His Majesty for many years?
Your servant has been with the Emperor for more than 30 years
Gonggong have worked hard and performed a valuable service
and well-informed in the palaces
always know what his majesty wants
At the moment, His Majesty is away from the palace
Are you really going to wait until he returns to deal with her?
What young mistress means is...?
Since His Majesty granted her death by suicide,
once she's dead, Gong Gong's task is also finished.
Who will actually investigate whether she died by suicide or by other means?
For example,
the concubines should be buried alive with the emperors' death
what would you do if they don't want
Your servant understands
Gonggong knows better than Lingrong what "the night is long and full of dreams" means
With her dealt with,
His Majesty would have put down one burden
Understood. Your servant sends young mistress out
Your Majesty, save me. Your Majesty!
Zhen Huan! Even if you don't die in my hands,
someone else will help me finish you!
You will die a horrible death!
At death's door, she still doesn't know to repent
Yushi will definitely die
But why must young mistress
come to this spooky place
I want Jiejie to know
that I'd do anything for her
You never treat us eunuchs like people
Now you fall into our hands
Xiao Xiazi
Here
Before I told you to endure. This time, don't hold back.
Don't!
I am the Emperor's woman
You cannot kill me!
Greetings, Precious Smiles and Precious Shen
Yushi has committed suicide
It's good that it's over
a quick one
Please rest assured
Rest assured?
Yes
Wasn't it mistress who asked Promise An to come?
Yushi was kicking up a big fuss
Promise An said that she'd be dead either way
which was why your servant strangled Yushi
She was strangled to death?
Yes
This was Promise An's idea?
Otherwise, even Shifu didn't think of it
But Yushi is disliked by all
so no one will say anything about it
Good job, you're dismissed
Your servant takes his leave
Young mistress, are you alright?
She's already dead, leave it be
Why say such disgusting things?
Young mistress, quickly inhale this fragrance
to dispel your disgust.
Greetings, Promise An
Where is Jiejie?
She's having tea with Precious Shen inside
I'll let her know you're here
No need
I exactly want to go asking for a cup of tea.
I will go in myself
Mei Jiejie
Did I overdo it
We will not attack unless we are attacked
But I didn't think that
Lingrong would be so heartless in this matter.
Lingrong did it for us
There are too many killings in this palace
If we are not vicious to other people
other people will be even more vicious to you
I know this
But this matter started because of you
Lingrong was never implicated
But now she's gone to the Cold Palace to order Yushi to be strangled to death!
Such an action is competely unlike
her usual warm and gentle self
Thank you for watching!
Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team