Your Majesty, the Empress has arrived.
Greetings, your Majesty.
Come, sit.
Yes.
It's late, is there something urgent?
Today you left in a hurry
and I forgot to ask.
After New Years is the Lantern Festival.
How do you plan celebrating it this year?
The Empress Dowager has not recovered
A simple celebration would suffice.
The Lantern Festival ushers in the new, and your Majesty has rewarded Hongxuan.
What a good deed.
Imperial Concubine Wan reminded me to do that.
She wanted me to bestow mercy on Yun'e's lineage.
I'm not sure if I should speak my mind right now...
Go ahead.
Yes.
In regards to what you just told me,
Your Majesty, Imperial Concubine Wan enjoys your affection, but sometimes she breaks the rules.
Haven't you always been fond of Imperial Concubine Wan?
What's is with you today?
It's precisely because I adore her, and also because she was recently promoted, that I feel the need to say this.
Your Majesty just said that Imperial Concubine Wan told you to knight Hongxuan
Although I'm pleased at her generosity
I am also worried that she shouldn't be meddling in court affairs.
Hongxuan's situation counts as family business.
Of course it's family matters.
But Yun'e's treasonous acts concern the country.
Family matters and country matters are inseparable.
Because Imperial Concubine Wan is compassionate, I fear that she will be used by others
without even realising it
Simply put, Imperial Concubine Wan
and her father have the same intentions?
Both have sympathy towards the people I don't like?
Imperial Concubine Wan is intelligent and I admire that.
But when it comes to knowing boundaries and staying in the Harem,
Noble Lady An and Noble Lady Qi surpass her.
Noble Lady Qi is quite mature
Noble Lady Qi is a Manchu like us.
But Imperial Concubine Wan is a Han
she may not share our hearts and minds.
Naturally
It takes time to understand someone. Perhaps Imperial Concubine Wan will be even better.
Greetings, mother.
Emperor, sit here.
How has your health been, Mother?
Same old, same old.
Do you like the new Noble Lady Qi?
She is the daughter of a meritorious official.
You mustn't leave her in the cold.
I understand.
The Harem and the Imperial Courts are essentially inseparable.
You can handle this dexterously.
I will remember your advice, mother.
With Yun'e as an example
I have been careful in dealing with my meritorious subjects
I have not conferred too much power on them
As for their daughters
official's daughter
I won't spoil them either
That is good.
Ever since Nian Gengyao's incident
I have been constantly vigilant
I hope Long Keduo...
He would not dare.
I hope so.
As the Empress Dowager, do you
not know what Long Keduo's thinking?
I have known him for dozens of years
and witnessed his devotion to you and your father
Haven't you always said that
concubines shouldn't meddle in court affairs?
You need not worry about what happens there either
You just take care of yourself
I have affairs to attend to
I shall take my leave now. I will come back again in the evening.
Okay.
I know you are busy. But still you have to take care of your health
I understand
His Majesty takes his leave
Can you make anything out of the Emperor's words?
Do we have to get rid of the rabbit to stop the dog from preying on it?
I made this out last time already.
The Empress Dowager rules over the lands
But you must take care of your health even if your intentions are good. Don't try to take on everything yourself.
Official Long Keduo had a part in subduing general Nian.
We all have our own blessings, who else could I look out for?
Zhuxi, go light up my scent for me.
Hasn't this book been banned by his majesty?
How come there is a copy in Yangxin Palace?
I still read it sometimes
so I know what those traitors are thinking all day
How do you feel about this book?
Just a bunch of sycophants
I have decapitated the author of this book Wang Jingqi and displayed his head to the public
to deter others
Stop, your majesty. It's frightening me.
What are you frightened of?
Wang Jingqi deserves his punishment
but displaying his head to the public
will only scare innocent citizens
I've also heard that
your majesty has exiled his wife and children, and demoted his relatives
How do you feel about it?
Wang JIngqi should be responsible
for his own mistakes, but his family
and distant relatives are innocent
If you are criticised for this, I don't think it's worth it
You're saying that I'm wrong?
How could I dare?
I just feel
if this matter is dealt with mercifully
more people will be grateful towards you
You are such a typical woman
who doesn't understand the brutality and resolution of men
Whoever threatens my throne and kingdom
must be killed with no mercy
otherwise
I would be treating my empire as a joke
Yes, I've misspoken
Suiyu Palace is restored
you can move back in
I feel sorry for Noble Lady Qi
She has to live with Consort Qi, and doesn't get to see your majesty often
I've decided
that it's better if you live in Suiyu Palace alone
It's irritating to have Noble Lady Qi around whenever I pay ou a visit
Then it's decided
In spring
I can have a drink with your majesty in front of all the crab apple flowers
and I can do the Jinghong dance amongst the pear blossoms
I can estivate with your majesty in summer
I can ferment sweet olive wine with you in autumn
and watch the dancing snowflakes in winter
I will be with you
and you will be with me
I will be with you forever
Wanwan
Are you there, Wanwan?
Fourth Prince
I'm here
My lady, Noble Lady An
has been waiting for you outside since early morning
For how long?
2 hours
I'll hurry up
so she doesn't have to wait anymore
So early, younger sister. Greetings, elder sister
I'm waiting for you to accompany me in paying our respects to the Empress
I will go to court now
Take care, your majesty
Wanwan, I'll be back tonight
Let's go
You two are early birds
Greetings, Your Majesty
We should be early in paying our respects
You two have just been promoted
it's no wonder you're so much more courteous
It's not surprising that his majesty likes you both
His majesty loves Imperial Concubine Wan more than anyone else
When I was waiting for her this morning,
I was in for quite a surprise
Lingrong!
What are you shy about, elder sister?
Her majesty cares for us
This morning
I heard his majesty call her by her nickname
Wanwan
Your majesty, don't listen to her nonsense
Wanwan, Wanwan...
Wan is your title
His majesty must have such great love for you to call you this
Look at my big mouth!
Please don't be angry at me
It won't happen again
We are all sisters
No harm in telling a joke
I just remembered,
Noble Lady An's promotion ceremony is fairly simple
Imperial Concubine Wan, you must bear with her
And something needs to be fixed up about your promotion ceremony gown
When the big day arrives
I will get someone to deliver it to you
Thank you, your majesty
What a big scar!
not a pleasant sight
At least the wound is congealed
the pus has stopped flowing
that was terrifying!
This is the wound healing paste Lingrong gave me
It cured my wound from the cat scratch
It is gone!
But your wound is small unlike mine
I have some more, you can use this
I can get Lingrong to mix some more
My Lady, Dr. Wen is here
Invite him in
Yes
You won't even let Dr. Wen take your pulse anymore
Now he's bugging me everyday
What a nice scent!
Greetings, My Ladies
Get up
Dr. Wen knows his manners
always so decorous
Stop making fun of him
My Lady, what is that?
This is a paste for healing scars
May I take a look?
Something wrong?
I've used several tubes already
they seem to be fine
I can't say what the problem is right now
may I take it with me?
Sure, please examine it
You said Qian Mingshi has an epistolary
like this
I just found out from Courtier Zhen
I thought this epistolary was not bad
so I took it home
but I realised
Qian Mingshi and Nian Gengyao were both from the Kangxi Emperor era
they are closely related
Qian Mingshi was a traitor like Nian Gengyao
so his poetry must be subversive too
How does Zhen Yuandao feel about this epistolary?
Did he procure it on the streets?
This epistolary has not been published
it can only be obtained by Qian's close friends
I found this in Courtier Zhen's home
so it cost me great effort to bring it here
Zhen Yuandao
never engaged with Nian Gengyao
That's a fact I'm aware of
Me too
Maybe Courtier Zhen
has only engaged with Qian Mingshi
but not Nian Gengyao
But the fact that Zhen owns this epistolary
may be quite significant
Tell me
This epistolary
contains lines
that flatter
Nian Gengyao
Such fawning words
Especially the last two lines, which flatter
your 14th brother Yundi
and 10th brother Yun'e
whom you have incarcerated
You telling me that Zhen possesses this epistolary
because he empathises with Yundi and Yun'e?
I don't know
whether that is the case
but Imperial Concubine Wan has pleaded your majesty
to give Yun'e's son a rank
this is well-known throughout the internal palace
Even Noble Lady Qi
from a
Emin
Yes
You have been gotten along with Zhen Yuandao all along
why have you told me all this?
Although I'm Zhen's colleague
and we get along well
but I owe everything to your majesty
to your majesty
which beats any friendship I have
Alright. You may leave.
Su Peisheng
Yes, your majesty
I want to see Imperial Concubine Wan
Yes
Actually, I'll pay her a visit myself
Did his majesty say anything to your father
after your father spoke with him?
From what I hear
his majesty didn't say much
after my father spoke with him
Wasn't he even the slightest angry?
My father said he couldnt tell
Your majesty, maybe my father
didn't get his point across?
His majesty has been paranoid since the Nian Gengyao affair
and abhors sympathisers of his enemies
Nian Gengyao and Yun'e's paid their price for their
sympathy towards Yunsi and Yuntang
Let alone
a traitorous official who has just been promoted
But His Majesty did not blame
Zhen Yuandao and Imperial Concubine Wan
that's precisely my worry
I've been with his majesty for dozens of years
I know his temperament best
apart from the Empress Dowager
I'm concerned that his majesty will
change his temperament for Imperial Concubine Wan
that would be disastrous!
Your majesty, Imperial Concubine Wan will be promoted to Consort soon
I know, at such a young age too
I'm getting old and stale
I may even have to relinquish my throne
His Majesty is here
Greetings, your majesty
Get up
Thank you, your majesty
You've just moved back
I just wanted to tell you
Suiyu Palace is renovated so well
it's almost too opulent for me
You will be promoted to the rank of Consort soon
you deserve a dwelling
that befits your status
Have some tea
I have an epistolary here
for you to have a look at
Who is Qian Mingshi?
Just read the poems
They're not that amazing
You're right, but
they are hard to obtain
Who would collect them anyway?
Maybe those who enjoy it
or friends of the poet
who else?
Why are you asking me this?
Just curious
I regard these poems to be
overwhelmingly sycophantic
and adulating evil
The poet should be stripped of his post
and exiled
I didn't read them carefully, but
I don't see any adulation of evil
The poet was eulogising Yun'e
Was it written recently?
Or back in Lord Dun's days?
The latter
As a lord, he will always have fawning supporters
such poems must exist in profusion
How should I punish the poet?
I don't dare comment
Say whatever you like
The times have changed
why not just let it go?
Burning these poems will be enough
As for the collector
If your majesty punishes him
people will think of you as a tyrant
It's better if you let it go
to soothe everyone's hearts
Good,
I'll think about it
You will be having
your promotion ceremony soon
Have a rest, I will visit Noble Lady Qi
Take care, your majesty
Congratulations, Consort Wan
Get up please. Thank you, my lady.
Give the master of ceremony some gifts
My lady, you must go receive your instructions from the Empress
and thank his majesty too
The master of ceremonies has told me
Liuzhu, get my gown.
Right away.
Spread it out, how exquisite
Oh no!
I can't turn up with a torn gown!
If I get caught this will be a deception and insult to his majesty
Where's Manager Jiang from the Internal Affairs Department?
Just outside
Hurry!
Manager Jiang
Look
It's my mistake, please punish me
Manager Jiang, this gown from the Internal Affairs Department is torn
you can't escape responsibility
But I need your help
to resolve this dilemma
My lady, this gown
is woven from gold and silver threads
there are not enough threads to tailor another one
We will have to open the warehouse
if it needs to get fixed, which may take two to three days
What? There's no time!
I have to pay my respects to his majesty right away
My Lady, we can't stall any longer
If we are late we will get blamed.
My lady, I have a plan
What is it?
A few days ago the Empress brought over a gown
that resembles the promotion ceremony gown
Although it's not as identical as this
it will have to do
Are you sure?
The style of that gown is old
it was probably worn by the Empress previously
It's been left there for 2 days
it's our only option.
Then go get it!
Yes
Although this gown is old
it is still resplendent
Let's hurry.
This gown does fit you well.
but it looks so familiar
Like I've seen it somewhere before
Really?
No time to worry about that, let's go.
My headache's bothering me again
it's all my fault
I don't want to hold everybody up
No worries, you can go when you're feeling better
Your Majesties
Consort Wan has arrived.
You go first, your majesty
I will be right behind you
Sure.
Wanwan
Greetings, your majesty
Wanwan, why don't you call me Fourth Prince anymore?
Fourth Prince
Wanwan!
Wanwan, you're finally back.
I, Zhen Huan, pay my respects
to your majesty
It's you?
Greetings, your majesty
Where did you get that gown?
How dare you!
Your majesty
What on earth happened?
Huichun!
A few days back, her majesty was going through
the late Empress Chunyuan's old clothes
and found that this gown needed repairing
as the buttons were loose
so I took it to the Internal Affairs Department
I wanted to bring it back
but I
was too busy
I don't know why Consort Wan
is wearing this gown right now
Please forgive me, your majesties
Useless!
How many times do I have to tell you
Chunyuan's belongings need to be well cared for
but you've been ignoring me!
And especially
this gown
This was the gown Chunyuan was wearing the first time we met
Your majesty
don't you?
Of course I do. Remove it.
I'm so careless
but this was an accident
Consort Wan is a meticulous person
she couldn't have done it purposefully
Why?
Just before I got here
I found my ceremony gown torn
so I borrowed this one
I don't know the history behind it
Please forgive me, your majesty
I don't want to offend (the late) Empress Chunyuan
Consort Wan, she...
Consort?
Although the ceremony is over
she hasn't received your instructions, so she hasn't been promoted yet
Suiyu Palace has been revamped
Go back and think about what you've done
The Emperor orders
that Suiyu Palace will be closed off
No one shall enter or leave
Who are you? What do you want?
Manager Jiang has been executed
I am the new manager of the Internal Affairs Authority
Close the doors!
What are you doing?
Whoever disobeys orders
will be executed too. Yes, Manager Gou
Shh!
don't startle Imperial Concubine Wan
What should we do?
My lady
He's sealed off Suiyu Palace, hasn't he?
Yes
Don't be too sad
it's not good for your health
At least
it's quiet now
I feel guilty that you have
to bear all this with me
No, my lady.
Jinxi,
I once asked you
why are you loyal to me?
You said it was fate.
Can you tell me the truth now?
It's because I look like Empress Chunyuan
right?
There is some resemblance
but not much
Really?
Now I know
why Consort Duan
was so shocked to see me the first time.
And said what she said.
She was the first concubine to enter the palace
and is familiar with Empress Chunyuan's visage
50 percent resemblance in both appearance and personality
has won his majesty's heart
50 percent resemblance
in appearance and personality...
is enough to win your loyalty too, right?
No,
your loyalty lies with Empress Chunyuan
My Lady
that's not true
I didn't have the fortune to serve Empress Chunyuan
but I was lucky enough to win her compassion on one occasion
And you, my lady, only resemble her
when you put on her gown
Empress Chunyuan was too innocent and kind
And so are you, my lady
previously
my loyalty to you was
partially influenced by Empress Chunyuan's benevolence
But after that, it was all about you.
But I have been forsaken
and may never be loved again
Your loyalty is futile.
My lady, today's incident is
partially my fault.
I knew the gown looked familiar, but I had no idea
that it belonged to Empress Chunyuan.
And Manager Jiang had never served
Empress Chunyuan. It looks like
we've fallen into someone's trap.
Unfortunately, Manager Jiang
has already been executed.
I'm responsible
for his death too.
He's just another pawn in this scheming chess game.
Jinxi, I shouldn't have
doubted you.
Even if Empress Chunyuan is the reason
behind your loyalty
But his majesty...
Oh Empress,
you scheming devil
How do you know, my lady?
If it weren't for her
who else would have Empress Chunyuan's clothes?
How could there be such a coincidence?
I was oblivious to the dangers behind me
otherwise I wouldn't have become a pawn in the Empress' chess game
You've always been loyal to her
but your rapid promotion
has made her concerned.
I've lost his majesty's love
and the Empress despises me
and this affair concerns Empress Chunyuan
which is His Majesty's deepest wound
It seems
that this disaster is irreversible
We can only wait.
Wait?
for what?
This is just like being in the Cold Palace
My Lady
His Majesty once sought to protect me
from the palace conflicts
by despatching me to Penglai Island
Such affection
And look at
where I am today
Whatever
whatever...
Wanwan
I am only a substitute
for Empress Chunyuan
Your Majesty, you haven't eaten all evening
Have some tea
How dare you!
All of you!
Tell the Internal Affairs Department, Imperial Consort Wan
shall only receive the salary of a Second Class Attendant. Yes.
Your Majesty, is this comfortable?
I heard that His Majesty threw a fit in Yangxin Palace
And so he should.
Imperial Concubine Wan,
his sweetheart, has committed an unforgivable fault
How could His Majesty not get mad?
It's only over a gown though.
Empress Chunyuan is the most important person to His Majesty
and on account of Noble Lady's Qi's father's words to his Majesty previously
His Majesty was already furious with Imperial Concubine Wan
Oh sister, you're such a good sister
you can still help me
so many years after your death.
And protect me.
It seems that Imperial Concubine Wan is doomed.
But Manager Jiang was innocent.
Those who know too much have short lives.
Your majesty, I will give you my
unswerving loyalty.
I know, get up.
Yes.
Imperial Concubine Wan has been locked up.
I'm worried that his Majesty's fury
may only be transient.
If His Majesty forgives her
your efforts would go down the drain.
Even if she is forgiven,
Imperial Concubine Wan will have lost her affection for His Majesty.
She's a strong, proud woman.
If she learns that she was only
a substitute all these years
how could she bear it?
Your plan
has no doubt worked.
I admire your wisdom.
Your Majesty, Noble Lady Hui is here to see you
for Imperial Concubine Wan?
Probably, she's distraught.
Tell her to leave.
Yes, your Majesty.
Noble Lady Hui,
Her Majesty has a headache
Then please let me know
when she gets better!
I will
certainly let you know.
Caiyue, take me to Shoukang Palace
My Lady,
the Empress Dowager is asleep at this hour
Both His Majesty and the Empress refuse to see me
If I don't see the Empress Dowager, what else can I do?
She's quite ill, you'd better not disturb her.
It's cold outside, let's go tomorrow.
I don't care, take me to Shoukang Palace.
My Lady...
Is the Empress Dowager asleep?
No, but she's too busy to see you.
Why? She doesn't want to?
Please ask her for me again.
The Empress Dowager wants me to tell you
that the weather is cold, but you, my lady, are hot-headed
But Imperial Concubine Wan is like my sister
The Empress Dowager said
hot-headed people inevitably make mistakes.
Before you came here, you must have
already visited Yangxin Palace and Jingren Palace
If His Majesty and the Empress have ignored you
there's no point for the Empress Dowager to see you either.
Please return, Noble Lady Hui.
Aunty...