Episode 68
You can go rest up a bit.
I still have matters to tend to.
I'll see you tonight.
When the king comes you have to go?
I still have petitions to review.
Then the king has to come at night
Okay.
King, please watch your steps
Baojuan, Baojuan!
Xiao Zu Xiao Zu, What's wrong?
HURRY, call the doctor!
GUARDS! CALL THE DOCTOR
Consort Li is alright?
Palace Yanxi's people have their lips sealed.
Nothing can be detected from them.
They all say that Consort Li didn't sleep well, causing pregnancy complications.
No worries.
Hopefully.
Greetings Noble Consort Xi.
I greet Noble Consort Xi.
This flower sure is pretty.
These are the lilies that just bloomed this year.
I personally picked out a few to give it to you
This flower is called fox-tailed lily.
You see that the petal is pink and curling.
Just like a fox tail, right?
It also has a fresh smell and is easy to raise.
Wherever the palace has water, wherever this flower thrives.
Did you give some to Consort Li?
I haven't...
Just now Palace Yanxi said
that Consort Li hasn't slept well.
Lilies are the best at easing one's mind.
Tell the floral department to deliver some to her.
Yes, I understand.
Niang Niang
Mistress has a steady pulse.
There are no big troubles.
I will now go prepare some smoked herbal pouches.
We trouble you then.
How did you have complications so suddenly?
Empress Niang Niang, I have been upset these days.
I feel as if I can't bore this child
I'm sure you can't
Your body has long been ill-fitting for childbirth.
If it wasn't for saving your father and securing the palace's position,
I wouldn't have forced you to become pregnant.
Yes, I know
If it wasn't for Niang Niang's arrangements,
my father wouldn't have been safe and sound now.
But you still haven't done the most important thing
Noble Consort Xi said that she's sick and refused to see me.
For now, I can't blame my miscarriage
on her.
Most importantly, the things she has sent here
are all inspected by the doctor so there's no room for error.
You must wait for opportunities.
I've already asked the doctor
Your child will be kept for six months at most
If it doesn't get miscarried by then,
then even your own life will be in danger!
There's still a little more than one month.
You think of something.
I understand.
The imperial doctor has said,
you must not move impulsively at this time.
Also you can't sleep with the Emperor
or you may really miscarry the child. Understand?
Yes
Drink up the stabilizing medicine.
Later Imperial Doctor Xu will prepare smoked herbs for you.
Remember, this matter must not be spread.
If anyone asks, say that the fetus is well.
Yes.
Niang Niang leave carefully.
Mistress likes peach blossoms. Why did you deliver lilies?
The workers of the floral house heard
that lilies has a calming effect on the heart.
So they asked me to cut these
and put them in Niang Niang's palace.
Imperial doctor Xu,  Here.
Please inspect for me
whether the lily has any issues.
Alright.
Niang Niang, the lily does have a calming effect.
Niang Niang has been suffering from insomnia.
Having some lilies in your room will produce benefits.
Then put them there.
Yes.
Were the lilies delivered?
They've been delivered.
The floral house has been sending them everyday.
The imperial doctor has inspected the buds
and said that they have no harm.
Consort Li also likes them.
A few days from now will be Consort Li's birthday.
The Emperor will definitely go to her.
We don't need to worry then.
Niang Niang don't need to have any worries.
You can just hide and fake sickness.
If I don't avoid her,
if she gets into some accident,
she will definitely frame me.
I can't bear that.
You write so well.
When I was learning calligraphy,
I didn't write as well.
I saw Fourth Brother practicing calligraphy for a whole day.
His hand was shaking yet he refused to stop.
Your fourth brother is the most hard-working.
Yes, even the Emperor said,
the fourth prince was enlightened the latest,
but his talent is the highest.
He's also willing to endure harships.
This is all thanks to your teaching.
I heard that the court is pushing more and more
for the eldest being the crown prince.
Third Prince is the eldest,
and is also raised by the Empress.
Naturally he's the most promoted.
But looking at Third Prince's intelligence,
it will be hard for him to even defend a city,
let alone become a good emperor.
So the Emperor
has set all his hopes on the Sixth Prince.
The Sixth Prince is still young. What can he accomplish?
It's still Longyue who's the best.
She learns everything immediately.
The silk bamboo sound has been heard all day.
Palace Yanxi is indeed lively.
Celebrating your birthday while pregnancy is naturally the happiest.
Today, this flower has been prepared personally by me.
Is it pretty?
It's pretty.
Niang Niang's craft is better than those floral house servants by hundred times.
Then have the floral house send them to Palace Yanxi.
to add to all the happiness.
After delivering them, some water should be sprinkled on the petals.
Then the colors will stay longer.
Emperor,
After a whole day of feasting,
I can finally quiet down
and talk to you.
and drink some wine.
So the Emperor doesn't like liveliness?
I like it.
But I like you more.
It seems to be a bit bigger.
Five months.
Five more months until it's born.
It must be as cute and nice as you.
You smell so nice.
Emperor, the imperial doctor said
that you can't be intimate with me.
It's already five months.
Nothing serious would happen.
Imperial Doctor Xu said that you are well.
But the imperial doctor also said
You don't like me staying here?
Two Niang Niang, something bad has happened.
Consort Li has miscarried.
It's just a miscarriage, why are you so panicked?
My reply,
Consort Li miscarried because she and the Emperor...
Emperor himself was also shocked.
Hanzhu, watch Longyue for me.
Noble Consort Xi and I will go to Palace Yanxi.
Yes.
Mistress,
Why is there so much blood?
Yeah, what will we do?
Emperor, Empress,
Hurry and rise. Go see Consort Xi.
Yes.
Mistress, Mistress!
Take them out, take them out.
Mistress, you must endure it.
My child!
How is Consort Li?
Niang Niang has produced so much blood.
This child definitely can't be saved.
While pregnant, passionate love-making is not allowed.
Why did Niang Niang and the Emperor lack such self-control?
Besides this Niang Niang,
Mistress, what will we do?
So much blood.
How is it?
There was a lot of blood.
But the imperial doctor said
the child definitely can't be kept.
How did she go from being well to this?
It's all my fault.
It's all me.
The child is gone.
Huan Huan
I have lost another child.
I thought that after so many years,
you have produced a child for me,
Mei'er also bore a child.
I thought that the heavens has already forgiven me.
But,
but Rong'er's child,
was lost because of me.
It was me.
It's ok, it's ok.
There have been so many princes and princesses born safely.
How could the heavens not have forgiven you?
Today's matter was only an accident.
It wasn't an accident.
I shouldn't have been drinking with Rong'er so late at night.
After drinking some wine,
I was with her alone.
I clearly knew she...
Actually
Consort Li was already pregnant for five months.
Didn't the imperial doctor say the pregnancy was well?
Even if,
Even if the Emperor favors Consort Li,
you should have controlled yourself.
I also know that.
But whenever I'm alone with Consort Li,
I've been unable to control myself.
A couple of times before because I remembered her pregnancy I was fine.
But I think today may have been the alcohol.
The Emperor hasn't calmed down his heart yet.
How about you rest at my place today?
Imperial Doctor will take care of Consort Li well.
Consort Li's matter is not as urgent as politics.
Emperor should go rest at Empress's palace.
Yes.
Consort Li's game was a loss.
Consort Li's pregnancy was suspicious.
The imperial doctor clearly told her not to get intimate with the Emperor.
Why did she do it then?
The one in the wrong is the Emperor.
But why was the Emperor so lacking in self-control?
According to my knowledge,
the Emperor doesn't reside in the Palace Yanxi often those past days.
He actually stayed more at Ning Pin's place.
Was it because Consort Li wanted to fight for favor?
Stupid!
But this matter,
I feel like Palace Yongshou
has had a hand in this.
Palace Yongshou has always claimed sickness.
It has removed itself cleanly from this matter.
Does Niang Niang want to investigate it?
No.
If we investigate,
we would know then that Consort Li
wasn't able to keep her child in the first place.
The relation between Imperial Doctor Xu and us will also be discovered.
By then we won't even have the Emperor's pity for Consort Li.
It would even implicate us.
Then we can only vaguely end this matter.
We weren't able to remove Noble Consort Xi with this pregnancy.
Such a pity!
Don't worry, Niang Niang.
Without Consort Li, there are still plenty of new ones.
If Consort Li was smart enough,
she would know that a man's pity and sympathy
would be enough to stabilize her position.
Emperor, eat a piece of dessert.
I don't have the appetite.
Ever since Consort Li had the accident,
you have been depressed.
You must also take care of your own body.
How is Consort Li?
Still the same.
She refuses to see anyone and doesn't like to talk.
Emperor,
Lingering Kang has come to greet you.
Let her in.
Yes.
I greet the Emperor and Noble Consort Xi.
Rise.
I heard that Emperor does have good appetite lately.
So I've especially asked someone to make some peach blossom pastry.
Put it here.
Your hair accessory...
Heartless wench!
The palace just lost a child,
Consort Li is still sick,
whom are you so dressed up for?
Emperor forgive me! I...
Take your thing and leave!
Emperor calm yourself.
I have, in many circumstances with no alternative,
done many things against my will.
All for Qing's peace,
I have killed many.
But this time
Mistress, you have woken.
Imperial doctor said your body is weak and shouldn't be in a breeze.
Really?
I don't feel it.
Mistress,
Emperor heavily rewarded your father.
Is the Emperor comforting or compensating?
Compensating that I can never bear a child from now on?
Actually,
this child was never meant to live from the start.
I also knew that this day would come.
No matter if it's me,
or the child.
We are just pawns used by others.
We wouldn't be protected forever.
Mistress, don't be so sad.
The Emperor actually cares for you still.
Baojuan, do you know?
I feel so tired.
I've never been this tired.
But I know,
when I'm well,
I would be manipulated by others again.
I would have to fight again.
But Baojuan,
I really feel like I'm exhausted to the bones.
I can't fight anymore.
Mistress, you've gone mad with your sadness.
You may go.
Zhen Huan,
originally I was the one in the wrong.
Revenge wasn't sweet.
It was meant to be.
Empress Niang Niang,
smell the fragrance I prepared today.
How is it?
The fragrance is intricate and has a relaxing effect.
I just got this treasure
and wanted to share it with Niang Niang.
Talking about fragrances,
no one can rival Consort Li.
That's right.
Jixiang,
let Empress Niang Niang see it.
Yes.
Consort Li's Minglu fragrance really is a good thing.
It's as refreshing as flowers.
Such a good thing
really is a treasure.
If anyone in the palace has even a bit of this,
they will be able to keep the Emperor's heart.
What is this exactly?
Empress Niang Niang,
When men and women are together and aren't stimulated,
they can use fragrances.
Was this fragrance really found at Consort Li's place?
Empress Niang Niang knows
I have no reason to frame Consort Li.
Is this fragrance poisnous?
Not poisnous.
Perhaps Consort Li was being foolish for the moment
and just wanted to keep Emperor at her side.
That day when Consort Li miscarried, I've been suspicious.
The Emperor's alcohol tolerance is high.
How could he lose all his self-control after just a few cups?
He clearly knew she was pregnant.
Even if he wanted to sleep with her,
he wouldn't have been so brutish.
Why was he so lacking in judgment?
Consort Li also knew she was pregnant.
Why didn't she resist?
So I've sent people to investigate.
And they found, in the fragrance ashes Baojuan threw away that day,
this thing.
I saw Internal Affairs Department's records,
before Consort Li's birthday,
Emperor was either in his palace tending to the proposals
or staying at Ning Pin's place.
He went few times to Palace Yanxi.
Unless Consort Li,
in order to gain favor,
with her five months of pregnancy,
and stable condition,
decided to act so foolish?
Imperial noble consort,
perhaps there was some misunderstanding in this?
Consort Li, no matter how brave,
wouldn't take imperial descendants so lightly.
Did someone deliberately harm her?
Noble Consort Xi's guess is not without reason.
Jixiang, you say it.
Yes.
Under the order of Imperial Noble Consort, I investigated
and found in the backyard of Palace Yanxi
a half-empty fragrance pot.
The ashes contained this object.
After asking the imperial doctor to confirm it,
I've asked the servants of Palace Yanxi,
who all said that all the fragrance materials
are kept by Consort Li herself.
I've also secretly taken a peek when others weren't looking.
There were a few important boxes that weren't locked.
Without the key, they can't be opened.
Continue.
According to the imperial noble consort's orders,
I've taken all the boxes containing the fragrances.
Among them, there was one box
that contained the exact same contents as the one we saw just now.
And a couple locked boxes
were placed in high shelves.
I heard the palace maids say
that Consort Li doesn't plan to use them in the near future.
But don't know why she used them now.
Why else?
Using such a lowly trick to gain favor
and harmed even the imperial fetus.
Definitely evil.
Niang Niang don't worry. We are only searching the palace.
You are searching the palace like you're going to seal it.
I know that Palace Yongshou has been searched before.
Fengshui really does go around in circles.
Today it's come to me.
After the good days end,
the bad days come.
A day's good or bad
isn't just decided by a castrated person like you.
Gonggong, we found it.
A castrated person is still a person
and still say human words.
Whatever, Consort Li.
Come to the Palace of Resting Hearts now.
Using such lowly things in the palace,
how does the Emperor think she should be punished?
I've already ordered a palace search.
After all, she just lost a child.
How about removing her title and downgrading her as a Promise?
I think
that Consort Li losing her child is already a lesson learned.
It's enough.
But daring to use such dirty objects to bewitch the emperor,
messing up the harem.
You must not go easy on her.
Though Consort Li is wrong in concocting strange fragrances,
she has lost her child
and cannot reproduce again.
This counts as a lesson learned.
Emperor should forgive her this time.
And Consort Li making fragrances
does have its benefits.
That year when my face was scratched by a cat,
Consort Li gave me this cream,
which healed me completely.
Now there's not even a sign of a scar.
Please remember her good from the past days,
and forgive her this time.
I remember when Noble Consort Xi was scratched by that cat,
it was your first time pregnant, right?
Yes.
Why does Imperial Noble Consort ask?
Emperor.
I've always been physically weak and had no fortune to reproduce.
What Imperial Noble Consort just said
I have just remembered it as well.
That year when she was healthy and strong,
even with Nian Shilan making things difficult for her,
how could she miscarry after kneeling for just half an hour?
Thinking back on it, don't you think it's strange?'
Even a healthy and strong body can't withstand harms done in the dark.
Where is Wei Lin?
He is outside.
He has been waiting to take your pulse.
Tell him to come in.
Summon Wei Lin!
I greet the Emperor.
Inspect this healing cream
to see if there's anything off.
Yes.
This object contains large amounts of musk.
If applied on the face daily,
miscarriage will occur within three months.
How is that possible?
It was Ling Zhong who killed my child.
That is correct.
The ointment is already dried up,
indicating that Niang Niang hasn't used it in a long time.
To remove the scarring, two boxes of this would be necessary.
If accumulated this way, miscarriage would be inevitable.
Emperor. Emperor.
Lingrong's heart is so cruel!
Playing such a cruel hand to one of her best friends!
And she even did it without any errors.
Human hearts are unpredictable!
Because of An Lingrong's palace maid's false report,
Shen Meizhuang became shocked and went into labor.
Now we know this person has a scheming heart.
The palace maid's false reporting must have been under the order of An Lingrong.
It's a pity that Princess Jinghe lost her mother so young.
Whenever An Lingrog sees the princess,
I wonder how she feels.
Very good.
The woman I spoiled for so many years doesn't deserve to be human.
Emperor,
I brought people to Consort Li's place
and searched some things.
Those musk have a rich aroma.
They're all extremely valuable.
Their intensity is unrivaled.
Nobody knows how many lives have been taken by those musks.
Throw it out quickly.
Emperor.
I brought Consort Li here
and is outside right now.
Consort Li,
the emperor has asked you to go in now.
I will never get to see
the beautiful sunshine again.
Nobel Consort Xi's child
Shen Meizhuang's death,
because of you.
Since I did it,
I knew there would be consequences.
Consort Li,
You've accompanied me for many years.
You've never disobeyed me.
Why...why are you so cruel?
I don't like the title Consort Li.
Consort Li (Li meaning a type of bird)
I'm merely a pet bird to you.
Emperor,
Have you ever liked me for just a little bit?
Your treatment of me,
and your treatment of a pet cat or dog.
Is there a difference?
As for cruelty,
in this deep palace,
who hasn't been cruel?
Did anyone order you to do this?
Do you have anything to rebuttal?
Everything is my fault.
Please pass your punishment.
Everyone has moments of cruelty.
Because in this palace,
everyone has moments they can't control.
But your cruelty
is already hundred times that of a normal person.
I won't let you die.
I will also keep your title of Consort Li.
Palace Yanxi will be your cold palace.
When your body is well,
I will have people spank your mouth daily
and have you kneel in front of Buddha daily
to repent for your sins.
With you as an example, no one will try the same thing again.
Su Peisheng.
I'm here.
Take her away.
Forbid her to step outside Palace Yanxi.
And allow no one to serve her.
All of the servants that have served her before
kill the close ones,
and sell the rest as slaves.
Ban them forevery from the capital.
I will see how she self-destructs.
Prevent people from killing her
in case they dirty their own hands.
This offering
is for my unborn first child.
The child's spirit in heaven can finally rest now.
Look at this petal's color,
it's exactly like that fragrant stimulant.
Yes,
Little Yunzi's accidental discovering of this fragrance
became the object that allowed us to destroy An Lingrong.
The fox-tailed lilies delivered by the floral house slaves daily,
who woud have thought that only the petals of that night
had some fragrance and water spprinkled on them.
An Lingrong is an A-class fragrancemaker.
So she also used fragrances to dig up her own grave.
Su Peisheng said
that he will take care of her well in Palace Yanxi.
Don't let her die.
Su Peisheng knows how to do things accordingly.
Niang Niang don't need to worry.
Emperor has already ordered to kill An Bihuai.
The execution day is in these two days.
Pick an appropriate time to tell him
He should grieve for his daughter at least.
Yes.
Niang Niang, Su Gong Gong is here.
Greetings to Noble Consort Xi.
Su Gong Gong,
Niang Niang, Consort Li said she wants to see you.
That's fine.
There are some matters I want to discuss with her in person.
Su Gong Gong, you must be discreet.
Don't startle anyone.
Don't worry, I'm at your service.
There's also another matter,
Consort Li said she wants to eat bitter almonds.
Emperor said
that clothing and food will still be provided.
She's still Consort Li.
Jiejie came.
Looking at me,
do you think I aged a lot?
Do I still look the same as before?
Meimei's appearance is still the same,
but the heart is not as pure as before.
If I was still that pure and innocent,
in this palace,
I would have died hundreds of times already.
Do you know who taught me embroidery?
It was my mother
My mother used to be an embroideress in Suzhou.
My father really liked her.
Back then,
my father was only a small businessman selling fragrances.
With my mother's money from embroidery,
she got him a small court position.
My mother killed her eyes while working for my father.
She was also not as beautiful as before
so my father married many concubines.
Though my mother was the wife,
but her beauty waas long gone
and she didn't have a scheming heart
so she was taken advantage of often.
As a result, in the end
my father refused to see her.
After entering the palace,
Consort Hua was so fierce
and Empress's network was so deep.
Even the palace maids dared to bully me.
I was very scared.
Every night I dreamed
that I became the same as my mother
Blinded eyes,
and humiliated by others.
Death better than life.
Everyone knows that life in the palace is difficult.
But no matter how hard life is,
how calculated it must be,
you shouldn't harm those around you.
Especially those who treat you like their sisters.
Before,
I also thought you genuinely treated me well.
You had so many things,
a high-class bearing,
a beautiful face,
and the Emperor's love.
But I, because of my low bearing
was often insulted by others.
And even because of your favor with the Emperor,
I had to endure humiliation from Consort Hua.
Later I understood
that your good to me
your care for me, your help for me,
was merely some charity food for beggars.
You wanted me to fight for favor in place of Shen Meizhuang.
So that I can stabilize your position in the palace.
Ever since entering the palace, we three relied on each other.
The things you didn't want to do, I wouldn't have forced you to.
That day when Meizhuang was under palace arrest,
if I didn't unite with you,
I would have become preys for everyone.
This bitter almond is delicious.
After staying in the palace for so long,
even bitter almonds become sweet.
Don't hold a grudge against me.
And say that I'm cruel.
In reality,
I'm just a bit unresigned.
I was unresigned to stay here soundlessly
and become someone else's stepping stone.
I was unresigned to live soundlessly.
I had to fight for my favor.
I had to hold a grudge against the empress, the emperor,
all those who treated me like pawns,
and all those who treated me like a toy.
When did I not know that the Empress wasn't sincerely helping me?
And how did I not know
that Emperor never loved me?
But in this harem,
there's no place for sincerity.
In the end,
I still hate you the most.
Because you have everything,
With the end nearing,
I have lost everything.
If you hadn't entirely gone back on your conscience,
think back to your past.
How many have you harmed?
I don't want to look back.
The palace's nights,
are so cold and so long.
How I endured every second,
I dare not to think about it.
No matter how cold,
you shouldn't use others' blood to warm yourself.
What warmth?
Jiejie,
you are already my eternal enemy.
Enemy?
I'm not going to hate you.
I also don't want to forgive you.
Because it's too undeserving.
I agree.
My whole life
has always been not worth it.
Empress,
kill the empress!
Sorry.
Your peaceful life,
was destroyed by me in the end.
This life,
this breath,
has never been controlled by me.
But today,
I can finally control it
and become its master for once.
This sunrise
is just like that day when we first entered the palace.
But the feelings are not like before.
Why did Niang Niang stay in there so long?
What did Consort Li say to you?
Nothing much.
She's truly pitiful.
Consort Li Niang Niang has died!