Episode 57
Niang Niang, you're back
His Majesty just came by. He heard
you went to say your greetings
to the Empress Dowager. He'll
come back again at night.
I know
You just had a scare. It's better to have
Doctor Wen take a look at you to be safe.
I'm fine.
What happened? Both Niang Niang's
complexion don't look good.
Someone can't control their
behavior anymore. On our
way back, the servant
stepped on a pebble stone.
It made him slip, almost causing him
to drop Huan Er from the carriage
The carriage is so high.
If you had really
fallen, you would have
certainly lost the baby.
Are you okay?
I'm fine
the pebbles were carefully
chosen, how could it be loose?
how did the poor quality pebbles get here?
someone must have done it
who?
must be her
if it is for the royal
lineage, it should be her
there are also others too
If there's a first time, there will
be a second time. A thrid time.
As long as Niang Niang is still
pregnant, they won't give up
it is not something we can prevent
Niang Niang, since his
Majesty is coming over at
night, you must tell him
about this incident.
Xiao Yunzi
Where is that pebble stone
you picked up earlier?
Here it is.
find someone you can trust
and ask him about this pebble
Yes.
this doesn't look like
normal moss on the pebble
Yes.
Doesn't matter who. Since
they had the audacity to
do this, don't blame me
for not letting them off
His Majesty is here.
greetings
Your Majesty, Our Niang
Niang is not feeling
well today. She's inside
sleeping right now.
Has the doctor been called to examine
her yet? Why didn't you tell me sooner?
Why are you not feeling well?
Your complexion looks so bad.
Your Majesty
Just hold me like this, please?
ok?
Huan Bi
yes
your majesty
tell me
tell me, no one will scold you
my king
this afternoon
on our way home
my lady almost fell
from her sedan
and had a shock
how is it
possible?
the path was slippery
where
near the Liuling Shizi road
that is supposed to be non-slippery road
I don't want to punish the servants
to settle this
You're suspicious that someone
wants to harm you, right?
How could I be?
I don't dare to think that way.
I just feel
my luck is down.
You dote on me
and allow me to serve you
I may not have the good fortune
to keep my child
our child is very precious
today
Today's incident
isn't so simple
it is not the fault of the servants
Looks like someone can't stand that I
adore you so they purposely did this.
Su Peisheng
call the servants here
After the beating question them.
I won't forgive those who
bully the ones I love
yes
please wait
don't make it a big thing
even so
obviously there's someone who is
deliberately making things hard for you
if I don't punish now, what
should I do if it happens again
even if there is really someone
who wants to trouble me
please treat it as an accident
I don't wish
the palace to be in disarray
and for you to be worried.
If I don't punish anyone..
and this regards our child.
I feel uncomfortable
please take it as accumulating
fortune for our baby
ok
if it happens again
then punish the culprits
and
the servants are not at fault
forgive them
huan huan
you are very understanding
the king is still with her
he has not left yet
Niang Niang, go to bed first
she is pregnant, he can't stay for long
even so
he wants to keep her company
ai..
your pulse is weak.
Niangniang must not be eating
or sleeping well these days.
if I am not here
you wouldn't let Cai Yue ask for me?
she had a shock yesterday
I was worried, but I didn't
have a solid reason.
she didn't eat well
my health is alright
even if you don't take care of your health
I can't let you remain like this
if you don't eat well
you will spoil your appetite
and hurt your body
and hurt your body.
Thankfully it's just because I am
thinking to much and not eating enough.
you will be worried if it is HuanEr
it is
normal that I worry
Can't I worry?
Niangniang's heath is important.
I will return to the hospital
and write a prescription for you
I take my leave
you are tired
I will pour tea for you
I've already asked.
What is it?
They said that the pebbles are
unique to specific areas.
This is niumaoxian
it grows by short fir trees
mostly found as bonsai in the palace
where Zhuxiu court and the place
where Lady Qibin and Lady Xin stays
Lady Xin is pitiful after serving
the king for so many years
And she's only a Precious.
That Imperial Concubine Pin.
She hates us so
much she would want us
to get eaten by crows.
Maybe Precious Xin is helping.
Miss, why didn't you strike
while it was hot last night?
I wasn't harmed.
Even if the Emperor found the culprit
he wouldn't severely punish them.
I'll leave it be.
Then when something big
happens that will be better.
greetings
Ladies QiBin and Xin are here
to visit you
Lead them to the formal room.
I will meet them
greetings
to my lady
take a seat
we haven't met for some years
you looked good Lady Qi
you looked young too
no one can tell you stayed at a temple
really
Back when we lived together at Suiyu Xuan
we were friends last time
it has been 3 years
our fathers were friends too
But then suddenly someone
stabbed him in the back.
It seems that people's attitudes
change faster than their appearances.
you have the gift of the gap
and change black to white
In order for you to come
back, the Emperor was
willing to change his
flag into a Man flag.
It's not difficult.
At least it's not as scary as someone's
heart turning from white to black.
I thought Lady Qi respect you
She even wore the Empress's
gift of red jade to see you.
Who knew that when she spoke
it would still be so biting.
It's been years since I've
seen you, Precious Xin.
my lady
We are reuniting
so don't speak so formally.
Thank you for thinking of me.
sure you are
one is a lady
the other suffered for many
years an is only a Precious.
you came
to greet me
Lady Qi you are the lead today
if you quarrel it will look bad
you are an understanding person
but this court is meant for you only
if anyone else can take your place
that would have taken a few
generations of fortune to achieve
I see
Lady Xin
How difficult is that?
I will save you your time
to act
Lady Qi
do you know that this court
is assigned to Lady Xi
by the king personally
for her alone
who do you think you are that the
king should retract his edict?
I am uncomfortable, I will take my leave
excuse me
see
she is very rude
do you know how much I suffered under her?
it has been some years
your life has not been smooth sailing
since I shifted there
she has give me trouble
though I came earlier, her
rank is higher than mine
why don't you ask to shift out
Lady Qi is well liked by her majesty
if she prevents me from
leaving, how can I leave
I spoke with the king
he told me off
Since Gui Ren is already here
these words
If you have something to say
Gui Ren might as well say it directly.
Niangniang thinks and speaks fast.
I really can't stand her anymore.
you want me to
ask the king to let you shift out
yes
that is my wish
you have guts
these years spent at the temple
I've eaten simple meals for too long.
it is better to have less problems
I have no
one to help me
my family is far away
since you are back
in glory
you must have suffered too.
I am willing to help you
I understand your heart
I don't wish to fight any battle
Some people are provoking me
so I am willing to get involved
with your status
you can do anything
since you are back
you can't keep away from the politics
I came today and
if you are concerned about my sincerity
you can spend time thinking through
I will think about it
Xiao Lingzi
please bring the short fir tree here
yes
I know you like the fir trees
I asked them to bring it for you
including the pebbles
see if you like it
yes
the niumaoxian's colour is beautiful
It must be something from
Niangniang's palace.
PeiEr, keep it
yes
as long as you like it
it can't compare to
the beads on your neck Lady QiBin
it was given by the queen
she wears it daily
to show off
it is very good
smell good too
very light and good smell
then that is a good thing
I seen through Lady Xin
she went to tell tales
as if I bullied her
since you are higher rank than her
you should put her in her place
or else she may become worst
she thought Lady Xi will look after her
she came back because of her pregnancy
do you believe them?
5% yes, 5% no
I can't tell what is the truth
when I gave her the short fir tree
looks innocent
she stayed here long even to learn to act
have you spoken to PeiEr?
yes, she missed you
Wait for me to ask her and
then we'll make a decision
The more I think about
it, the angrier I am.
Did she forget about when she used to
kiss up to you with every opportunity?
you think she is stupid?
she knew that our relationship was deeper.
she is only acting in front of me
if I can't help her, definitely
the queen won't either
so she would rather
turn her tables with me
if there is no child, there
is no way out for us
why do you say that
did you see the beads Lady QiBin wore
The Hongmannao beads?
No matter what she has
don't we have it too
that is rare
Hongshe fragrant beads.
this looks like Hongmannao
so rare that
there are only few in the palace
I heard from Lady Xin
that the bead gave off a sweet smell
It is made from Jixiong.
If you wear it for long,
it affects your health
so you can't give birth.
why did she wear it then?
Does no no tell her?
It's rare so normal people
can't distinguish it. Also,
didn't you hear
the queen gave it to her
even if the doctors know
no one dares to tell her
go to the kitchen
to see if the food for Lungyue is ready
I don't know if she likes the food
Lungyue left you when she was young
she will be distanced from you
it will be better after
you spent time together
I hope so
Here Princess. Eat.
Good girl. Princess.
Here. Let me feed her.
Come, Longyue.
Let's eat.
Here. One bite.
Good girl.
Good. Eat some more. Princess still
listens to Niang Niang afterall
Look how well she eats.
Niangniang
greetings
Niangniang is eating?
we made some food
hope the princess likes them
It looks wonderful.
she is having her meal now
Then I'll excuse myself first.
Okay.
lets eat more vegetables.
yes
Good girl.
The Emperor is always thinking of you.
grow the lotus in the large pots
so you can see them growing here
lotus has a nice smell
it is easy to attract insects
Lady, is it the lotus
flower you don't like,
or is it the person who arranged
these flowers that you don't like?
this year's
birthday, I saw many lotus
Later the people did this
whatever others do now,
is just a shadow of it
PeiEr is here
invite her in
yes
stand up
thank you
look at you
I am not fortune
I can't serve you
I heard from Lady Xin
I had to come and pay respect to you
so I followed her
I heard JuQing has died
what happened?
when you left, AnPing said
JuQing died of a stomach disease.
I took a peak
her blood were all black
it means she died of poisoning
JuQing served Lady AnBin
she originally served me
But when I left...
it is a pity
if Lady Xin doesn't treat you well
tell me
thank you
After Niangniang left I was
assigned to Precious Xin's place.
So I went with her to ChuXiu Palace.
But ChuXiu Palace's master
is Imperial Concubine Qi.
She hates that I served you before.
Lady QiBin scolds and beat me up
Go get the medicine.
Yes.
when I left
I can't do much for you
I am already fortune to work for you
to others people we
are invaluable servants.
I am of low status, how can I
have Niangniang do these things.
bear with it
didn't she speak up for you
when Lady Xin sees Lady
QiBin scold or beat us
she will speak up
only that made
Lady QiBin more angry
The head of the palace can
punish anyone in the palace
even if PeiEr is Precious
Xin's she can't protect her.
so it is real that they can't get along?
yes
I understand you
if you are not happy
I will ask you to serve me
you know that
do you want to help me
keep an eye on them
yes
king
the Jinshifang staff are here
I have not met Lady Xin for some time
King is here
greetings
come
don't run after me
what is that
Lady QiBin has her nightmares again
king
please visit her
don't come
I will go and visit her
are you coming back
I wanted to visit you
I will be back
I had a nightmare again
my heart is still racing.
I feel scared
look at you
why don't you consult a doctor
about it
I did
he said the YinQi is strong here
then only
I have strong YangQi (positive energy)
is it?
of course
you can stand up to any negative energy
come here
why didn't you stop him
he won't be back
every time he came, she had a nightmare
I knew it
I can't block him if I wanted to.
I tried to stop him before
really?  Precious Xin
doesn't have much favor.
Lady Xin can't keep the
King with her last night
Then the Empress or Consort
Jing don't do anything?
Consort Jing has a bit of reputation
she can't say much about it
With Empress, she only thinks
it's two consorts being jealous.
She doesn't say much.
what
I heard
that they are working to
path a way for the future
Xiao Yunxzi
since Lady QiBin always have nightmares
cook some brown rice and
barley soup for her
since her nightmare is bad
there is no need to cook it
until it is fully soften
as long as it is boiled that should be fine
give her personally in front of the king
yes
let her finish it
-I will go and prepare.
-You seem to dislike her
you seems to dislike her
your lady can't keep the king with her
why did you splash water here
are you still frighten
If you don't come, I am always frightened.
let me listen
I have something for Lady QiBin
what is it?
This is good for preventing nightmares
drink it
I don't want to
if I drink, you won't come
these are different matters
this is good for you
drink it
take it away
if you don't drink, it
means you are not sick
so you have buff me all along
Niangniang said that you must drink it all.
Why are you angry with Lady QiBin
she is just such a person
she is overboard at times
although she is still cute to me
you think you can allow
her to behave this way
you didn't know
that others in the palace
will learn to be like her
With that kind of attitude there
will be a lot of resentment.
And Imperial Concubine's becomes
arrogant when she gains favor.
If one palace is unsteady then
the entire harem is unsteady.
this will create problems in the long run
I see your point
just as you say
I should teach her a lesson
then this will comfort Lady Xin
Since this matter, no one dares
to be arrogant. . After hearing
this, Tai Hou was delighted and
couldn't stop praising you.
The Empress Dowager knows too?
Who doesn't know in the He Palace?
Lady Xi is very imposing,
just like that you stopped
the harem's bad atmosphere.
At first, Tai Hou doubted you,
but now she can be relieved.
You wouldn't know how this
made things difficult for me
if it wasn't for using
Lady Qi as an example.
It's inevitable for Tai
Hou to doubt me because
she's scared that I
bewitched the emperor
Now that I've made a
move and made it known,
someone will hate
me like an eyesore.
Now more people will make me their target.
Making Tai Hou happy is the most important.
In Tai Hou's eyes,
these are only petty tactics.
Even then, the harem's bad atmosphere
will never be kept under control.
It just weakened a bit.
I can't even walk properly
after having such bad luck
stepping into mud.
Don't be mad, it will harm your health.
Xin Precious is usually quiet,
now she complains in front of other people.
It's really true that a dog
that bites doesn't bark.
I got bitten by a dog,
of course I'm unlucky.
Please bear with it for
now, even the Emperor
is siding with Xin Precious
helping Xi Consort.
What is Xi Consort?
Taking advantage that the Emperor's still
giving few glances at her bewitching face,
she comes and humiliate me
and he doesn't look at what she is.
Not only was she not
behaving in the Bhuddist
Temple , she even goes
and seduce the Emperor
She thinks that being pregnant is all that,
I need to let her know how powerful I am.
I don't know how powerful you are,
I just know that the walls have ears.
Lady Qi, just take good care of yourself.
Having such skill at cursing others,
why not drink a few more
brown rice barley soup
to cure the problem with your nightmares.
It was Xi Consort,
it was Xi Consort!
Shh, don't make a sound Lady!
Mother
you're not mad?
Always remember that with unworthy
people and unworthy matters
do not waste your time
and energy with them.
Yes.
An important guest has arrived, forgive me.
Sorry for my lack of manners.
It's been many years. Duan
jiejie's coloring looks well.
Thank you, this way please.
With Wenyi,
these slow days pass quicker.
Or else living one year after another,
I wouldn't have anything
to look forward to.
Jiejie has such good fortune.
My Longyue doesn't bother with me.
Consort Jing cares for Longyue
as much as I care for Wenyi.
She's been brought up by her.
Longyue will be closer to her.
Recently Consort Jing has been anxious.
That said,
if Imperial Concubine Xiang came
back and wanted to take Wenyi
I would also not want to.
I understand
Jin Consort,
is an understanding person,  but
even an understanding person
cannot control her feelings
let alone it's the love between
a mother and daughter.
When you weren't in the
palace, you didn't know。
That year,
Long Yue was sick
she didn't sleep for days and night.
If at that time, she couldn't save Long Yue
she would've been sad to death.
As a mother,
I indeed did not put any
effort into being a mother.
How can I dare to ask Long
Yue to be close with me?
I only hope
that she can acknowledge me as her mother.
When talking about a mother's care,
Even I feel wronged listening to you.
At that time, you left
the palace after giving
birth to Long Yue after
only three days.
In those three days
everything you did was to make
sure she had a good future.
But I still need to advise you one thing.
Don't try to rush Longyue
into accepting you.
Even though you want to be with your child,
you must be patient.
You came back to the palace
under a different identity.
Don't get so involved with Imperial
Concubine Wan of Zhen's daughter.
That way you can avoid gossip.
Jiejie's words I will remember.
Okay. Look how how you are.
Mother will take you to Qianli pond okay?
Okay
Meimei,
Longyue, give your greetings to Consort Xi.
Greetings, Consort Xi.
Let mother take you to play, okay?
I don't want to.
Longyue is still in the mode to
play and doesn't want to be hugged.
Just for that sentence
to make her go live with meimei,
she threw a tantrum for an entire day.
Why don't we let her live at
Xianfu palace for a few more days?
What is jiejie saying?
Of course your child shall live with you.
I just wanted to bring
her to play for a bit.
Oh, we wanted to go to Qianli
pond to feed the fish.
Meimei why don't you come along?
I still have some things to attend to.
You should play with Longyue.
Longyue, say goodbye to your mother.
Niangniang isn't mad?
Why should I be mad?
Another person to dote on the
princess is a good thing.
But Consort Jing has forgotten who
Longyue's birth mother really is.
Just now, Consort Jing wanted Niangniang
to go feed the fish with the princess.
If Niangniang went,
wouldn't that have been a
good opportunity to get
closer to the princess?
If Consort Jing wanted me to go she
would have asked me from the start.
It's for them to get closer.
If I went,
who knows how much drama it would cause.
I am not interested.
Consort Jing isn't wrong.
Longyue's birth mother is of the
Zhen family. I am of Nuhu lu family.
What birth mother?
Jiejie.
Greetings.
It's been long, meimei became a Precious.
Jiejie is the real Precious.
I thought that jeijei would flit around
the outside and live a lonely life.
It made me sad.
But now the tables have turned.
There's never a perfect time and place.
There is always something unsatisfactory.
Even if meimei becomes
an Imperial Concubine
there will be a time when
your life is unsteady.
After jeijei left, I had to take
care of the Emperor for so long.
I served the Emperor for so long
But I don't have a child.
I have bad luck.
But your own daughter
became someone else's child.
How do you feel?
Longyue hasn't been with me. Of
course she isn't as close to me.
But I believe
that a person will have gains and loses.
Compared to meimei
the child in my stomach
perhaps will have more fortune.
I am just afraid that you will
lose more fortune than you gain.
Meimei's words are truthful.
But compared to so me people,
they try their hardest, but manage
to lose other people's trust.
I'm afraid that in the end
they use a bamboo basket to
carry water and it's empty.
Jiejie is completely right.
Actually when you were by
ChuXiu Palace and almost fell,
I heard about the incident.
Thankfully jiejie is alright.
I am relieved for you.
Putting her at ChuXiu Palace,
Precious Xin serves the Emperor more.
Her attitude becomes more bold.
You honestly think it's Precious Xin?
Jiejie please think about it.
In ChuXiu Palace
who has the longest grudge against you?
Her father is her father.
She has never done anything to me.
Jiejie is kind hearted.
She has always wanted to replace you.
Jiejie, why don't you understand?
She is the Empress's favorite person.
How can you say such things
behind her back without evidence?
Before I've done too many wrong things.
I've seen other people
make many bad choices too.
Some things I originally
wanted to bring up again.
But you just came back and was sabotaged.
How can I continue hiding anything?
The mistakes in the past are already over.
I hope that today I can
compensate it a little bit.
I don't know when to listen to your words.
In the Emperor's mind
you are the quietest and warm hearted.
So,
you have done shameful things in the past?
Your words imply that you
don't want to forgive me.
I really don't know how to tell the
people's hearts in this palace.
But Lingrong
we have been sisters for all these years.
I cannot repay for the crimes
I've committed in this lifetime.
I hope that you can
safely deliver your baby.
You must be very careful.
It's so fragrant.
This is a gift from Precious Xin.
Do you like this scent?
I understand your intentions.
I will be careful.