The Legend of Zhen Huan
Episode 27
She is now pregnant and has not recovered from her injuries yet.
She is sleeping on the bed.
Didn't you hear what the doctor said?
Our head master is pregnant.
That will be against the rules.
Its really kind of the emperor to visit her everyday.
Indeed so, our young mistress is highly regarded by his majesty.
I'll worry about this.
I'm afraid that the baby would be a princess
then his majesty will be delighted.
Don't spout rubbish.
If your young mistress were to give birth, it would be a prince. There's no use in a princess.
Are you trying to curse her?
Prince prince prince!
Of course it will be a prince!
Concubine,
His Majesty is here, His Majesty is here!
Understood.
Mistress, its best you that you greet him.
His majesty has arrived.
Greetings
your majesty. Rise.
Have you taken your medicine?  Are you feeling better?
In...
Much thanks for your concern, your majesty.  I just feel slightly tired,
the doctor advices to stay in bed.
Let's sit and talk.
From what I see,
you look more alert.
Much thanks for your concern.
Its all thanks to Doctor Wen.
Mei Er,
Its my fault
for the things in the past.
Your majesty is the Son of Heaven; how can the Son of Heaven be wrong?
When you've full recovered,
I will get the board of internal affairs to hang up your green name plate.
I will be leaving now.
Yes.
Safe journeys your majesty.
Departure of the carriage.
His majesty has arrived.
Greetings his majesty.
I long knew that you were pretending to sleep.
Its not convincing at all.
I can see the strands of your hair moving.
Si Lang sure likes to tease others.
That scar,
the color has lightened.
Peasant has become ugly. Please don't look Si Lang.
Have you used the medication that I have sent you?
I used it.
It will be returned to its formal self in a few days time.
Such magnificent beauty.
Who can be compared to
you in this world?
I have a younger sister
name Yu Lao,
her looks is definitely on par to mine.
To be able to be on par with you
I must have a look.
That won't do.
When Si Lang catch sight of my sister,
you can't wait to take her in as your wife.
Then I will have no place in your heart.
It will make you jealous.
It might be someone superior.
It seems that I must get a new wife,
What do position do you want your sister to have?
precious? Maid servant?
or to be assigned as consort immediately?
Its a pity that
she is barely 10, and would have you to pardon her.
What are you thinking of?
I was thinking, since the times are good,
something like that.
Huan Huan...
You bear my child.
Do you know how happy that makes me?
I am happy too.
The white radiating from the flower
is comparable to your beauty.
The flower loses its color as it falls
it seems that Huan Huan's complexion is just as radiant.
While trying out the plum blossom make up, also known as plum make up
Its hard to bring out the white in the pear blossom.
Such a pity...
Actually, its not hard.
Really?
What do Huan Huan think of this?
There is elegance in the petals of the flower.
The white of the pear blososm
it does not look real when applied with the fingers.
Beautiful is enough, there is no need to seek realism.
This look, I will call it pear look.
Si Lang shall name what ever he creates.
I'm worried that others might think that you are bias to me.
I have made it clear that I will only be bias towards you.
Aren't you glad?
Sister Mei just recovered, you should visit her too.
I have visited her just now.  It seems that she has gotten cold towards me.
Its because she has been sick for so long, its natural that she is bored.
Please pardon her for any in formalities.
Speaking of epidemic,
I just thought of something worrying.
Would it be alright if I hear about it?
I have heard from Concubine Qin
that there seems to be progress in the fight against the epidemic over at Jiang Sheng and Jiang Zhen.
But they took money
from the maids and Eunuchs.
Treating people base on power,
they neglected those with less power
to take care of themselves.
Its the doctor's duty to help everyone.
Even though they can provide effective treatments, but they are going against their ethics.
I feel
that this was also the reason
why the plaque could not be stopped in time
I feel that way too.  Does your Majesty still recall
how Consort Hui was framed?
I have not forgotten It's just that
the plaque had not been contained , thus they cannot be killed just yet.
I will like to recommend someone to your Majesty
He can cure the plaque
Who is this person?
Imperial Physician, Wen Shi Chu
Why is that?
When Imperial Physician was treating Consort Hui, there was marked improvement
And i have heard that the Jiang brothers' cure originated from Wen's formula
If your Majesty don't believe me, you may investigate this in greater detail
Anyone who was treated by Imperial Physician Wen would heal that much faster
and with none of the side effects observed in those treated using Jiang's formula
Only because while the Jiangs' used Wen's formula as base
the medicinal dosage is more agressive
I will like to meet this Imperial Physician Wen
If what you said were true, the Jiang brothers cannot be allowed to remain any longer
Your Majesty spoke truly
however, with the plaque situation improving
the Jiang brothers are currently being credited hence it is not appropriate to eliminate them just yet
Yes. They are, after all Consort Hua's men.
However, if i had really wanted to punish them
there are lots of means to do so.
Alright, enough of this talk.
Alright.
Your birthday falls on April 17, and you are bearing my child.
I wish to get the Internal Affairs Department organise a celebration for you
I will leave it to your Majesty
Good! I will help you decide
Sure.
As long as both you and the child are happy
Your majesty loves the child so much
and you've always stayed at consort Hua's place.
Why is consort Hua not pregnant?
I heard that
she has a miscarriage.
Is she injured because of the miscarriage?
I still have matters to attend to.
Xia Yi,
help me to exterminate 2 people.
Do it cleanly,
do not rouse any suspicion.
Yes I will take on your command.  You and your team
did well before.
Help me keep an eye on the former officers
and rebels.
The emperor has arrived!
Greetings your majesty
The 2 doctors were murdered on their way home.  Even their heads were missing.
The murderer dared to kill
in your majesty's presence.
That is simply breaking the rules!
Milady, I was
startled when I heard of the news.
I have already sent men to investigate.
Jiang gave treatment
to the victims. He will be
given credit for that.  Money will also be given
for his funeral.
Don't worry.
What will happen now that 2 doctors have died?
You don't have to worry about that.
I have commanded Doctor Chu
to take over.
Congratulations.
Thank you.  Do look out for us in the future.
How is the painting?
The lady looks mild and kind,
the artist did well.
A beauty
must have brains too.
Else, there will be no meaning in a beauty with no brains. She would just be a piece of wood.
So that is why
your majesty
This coming 17th is her birthday., I've come here to arrange a party for her.
To make it a joyous occasion for her. Its just that the situation in Henan
just stablised.
I have many things on my hands now, would like to get someone to help me arrange it.
Does your majesty want me to do it?
All I want for Lady Wan is some jewelry
But if I really can't present the surprise to her
I'm afraid she would not be sincerely happy.
You have to come up with some good ideas for me.
Such a free man as I am, I am best at this kind of duties.
Don't you worry about it.
This peony stage has an excellent view of the river.  The late King Kang Xi
have always come here to admire the peonies.
His majesty is celebrating her birthday here
isn't that over flattering her?
Where is Prince Guo?  Indeed, everyone is present all except for Prince Guo.
I'll get someone to look for him.
He's always behaving like this.
We're not aware of the latest make-up these days.
Why did she draw a blossom
on her forehead?
His majesty drew it for her.
Its called the Pearl Flower Make-up,
Its quite famous in town.
Its just like normal make-up.
Nothing special about it.
His majesty drew it on for her, can't you tell how deep his love is?
Your majesty.
I would like to visit Sister Mei.
Okay, go along then.
His majesty loves Lady Wan more.
Not biased to her but his heart has been tied to her.
Other than Lady Wan, who else can serve his majesty in the Imperial study room?
This is the first party that you have attended since your recovery.  Is your body doing okay?
I am doing fine, don't you worry.
Even if you've recovered, you're not as healthy as before.
I am really worried about you.
Doctor Wan's skills are superb
but no matter how good he is ,
he can't cure my heart.
You have to take good
of yourself and your baby.
You need the love from his majesty
in order to survive in this palace.
The love from his majesty only last for a span of 30-60 years.
Everything is changing
nothing is for sure.
Seeing so, there is not point in worrying about it.
What happened?
Fu Jin is sick
I'll go over and take a look.
Are you not feeling well?  My heart is in pain
its an old problem of mine.
Do take a seat.
Sorry for making you worry and dampening your mood in this party.
Please don't be.  Its normal for people to fall sick.
All will be well after taking some medicine.
Are you still taking the pill?
Yes, I have it with me all the time.
Sorry to be disturbing you.
We're sisters in the place and also relatives in our family.
You don't need to be so formal with me.
Prince is busy with work, you have to take good care of yourself.
Thank you for your concern.
Is this the famous make-up?
Yes indeed.
Not only can we look as pretty as you, it also promotes the love between lovers.
This is a great love story that has spread throughout the town.
The people have always said that his majesty loves you the most.
You're so friendly and nice, no wonder his majesty showers you with so much love.
You've flattered me.
Prince Guo has already prepared your present at the lake side.
He has asked you and his majesty to make your way there Understood.
I will make my way there now.
Prince Guo has a lot of surprises, who knows what he's come up with.
Lets go and take a look.
Look!
Today is your birthday. Please make a wish on this kite.
Its unbelievable to see so many lotus flowers in April.
Listen!
Such a nice melody.
Such a beautiful melody,
well played on the flute.
It is every women's dream to in love with their husbands forever.
Has your dream come true?
Greetings miss,
in a lake filled with lotus.
Thank you for the hard work, I like it very much.
I asked you to come with special ideas for me.  Who knew you did so well.
Your majesty has tasked me with the planning of her birthday celebrations,
I will most definitely try my best.
May I know how you managed to make the lotus flowers bloom at this time of the year?
The lotus seeds have been planted a long time ago.
Using the water from the spa
the lotus was able to bloom.
Thank you, your majesty.
You're milady now, naturally, your family members will be given a title too.
I've already given your mother the title of Madam of Gao Ming.
Thank you, your majesty.
My mother is the real Madam of Gao Ming.
Now her mother has also been given that title.
Maybe his majesty made the decision rashly.
No.
His majesty promised to name my mother Class 2 Madam of Gao Ming.
But the empress objected because I am only a consort.
My mother can't be given the title of Madam.
My mother did not get the title in the end.
Zhen Huan is just a concubine.
But his majesty is flatter her like this.
If she gives birth to a prince,
she will bully me.
That won't happen. Why won't it?
Other gave birth to a baby, you gave birth to a baby too.
But you end up being just a honored lady.
She becomes a Concubine even before she got pregnant.
In the end, you're just useless.
Don't be angry.
Don't suffer because of that anger.
Not be angry?
My anger will only be subdued if I kill her.
Miss...
I know what you want to say.
We must continue living our lives no matter how hard it is.
I'm worried about you.
There is no need to worry about me. I'm used to it already.
She dared to shout at you like that even though you are the mother of the princess.
My only wish is for my princess to grow up peacefully.
Other things don't matter at all.
But Consort Hua and Lady Wan don't get along too well at all.
Its risky to stand between them.
She is only interested in me getting rid of Lady Wan.
But she does not know how hard it is.
She is powerful now,
she will become even more powerful than Consort Hua the moment she gives birth to a prince.
You have to decide for yourself.
Decide? What else can I decide for myself?
Life in the palace has always been the same, nothing special at all.
Summer palace is much more fun than this.
The weather is great today. Why don't you accompany to fly a kite?
I kept 2 kites for you during your birthday.
You're really playful.
I heard that you broke a vase that was given by his majesty while playing last night.
His majesty won't be angry at me.
Stop reading Sister.  Let's take a walk outside.
You're always staying in this room.
Who knows, your baby prince might grow up to become a lazy prince.
Sure, why not. I'm feeling a little bored too.
Miss, do stay indoors.
Hasn't Lady Fucha's incident have you worried?
We call for more servants to escort us.
Let's go out, shall we? Okay.
How's my kite flying?  Very well.
I loved to fly kites when I was back in my house.
Because you're good at kite flying, his majesty said that
he will give the title of honored lady after mid autumn.
His majesty likes me and you right?  Yes, we all do.
Do you like seeing me fly kite?  I do.
I used to ask Sister Mei to fly kites with me back when I was trying to sew.
I will bring your baby to fly kites in the future too!
I wish my princess will be as active as you.
Oh no! The thread broke! I'll go retrieve the kite.
Follow her and help her get the kit back.
No one is to follow me They'll only get in the way if they do.
Follow her from a distance. Yes.
Don't follow me and wait for me here Yes.
At ease. I have a message here for your general.
Yes I know.
The people up there are all looking to be officers. Go see if the general have any use of them.
Yes, just as general had said, if there is anything unsatisfactory, I will pass on the message.
The general will settle it for you Good.
Tell him that we must have our own men in the palace.
Try to destroy all those who are against us, Lady Wan's father for example.
Yes.
General did not kill her father the last time, fearing that it might arouse his majesty's attention.
I am not concerned with how he did it, when he did it.
Don't make a noise.
It'll be worse if we shout.
Don't come to my palace without my permission. I don't wish to arouse any suspicion.
I will call for you when I want to.
Yes/
Be quiet!
Greeting Lady Cao
Greetings Lady Wan
At ease.
Its okay.
Such a coincidence to be meeting you here.
Take a seat.
Its been a long time since we talked.
You can call me sis.
Sis,
You should be more careful since you're pregnant.
You now dare to send people off.
Stop joking around.  I am with you now.
If anything bad were to happen to me, it will naturally be blamed on you.
I will surely take good care of sister.
No one will be here to push me anyway.
Aren't you humorous.
Who would dare to push you?  I doubt they would even dare touch your finger.
How is Princess Wen-Yi doing?
Don't you worry.
Its only a small cough, nothing serious.
True, as long as there's no mix up between potato powder,
I'm sure she'll be most fine.
Didn't his majesty already punished Xiao Tang who mixed it up?
I'm sure this incident will not happen again.
I hope so too.
I'll be a mother too soon.
I can fully understand how a mother feels.
Its not easy for you to take care of princess.
I heard that you have a difficult time giving birth.
Yes.
Becoming a mother is not an easy task.
Having to worry about her all the time.
My heart aches whenever she's sick or in pain.
I rather be the one in pain.
You are a smart person. I'm sure you know how to take care of princess.
But I would to remind you of one thing.
Its good to have the protection of others, but its also important to note the person protecting you.
Or else you will be suffering other the actions of others and be able to express your sorrows.
Your little sister is a little silly, pardon me.
If sister doesn't understand, how would I?
But I do know of one thing. The reason why Consort Hua is not doing anything
is because someone is helping her.
I feel thankful to her even though she's not doing it to help me.
I also understand that...
those who aid the hands of evil will come to no good.
The best way to protect yourself is to leave the evil doings and join the good.
Lady Wan, let's go to the rocky areas.
Men!
Why hasn't Lady Chun returned?  Didn't the eunuchs follow her?
Get men to look for her!  Hurry!
Have you found her?
Found her -Good.
Its late, I'm sure she's hungry. Are the desserts ready?  - Ready
Bring it here then.
What happened?
Is she being punished?
Miss...
Lady Chun...
She died in the lotus lake.
By the time we found her,
her hand was still holding on to the the thread of her kite.
Miss!!
She was still flying her kite in the afternoon,
how could she have died in the lotus lake?
She's only 17.
Miss.
We were chatting happily in the afternoon
I even told her that
his majesty will rank her as honored lady after mid autumn.
She was even eating the food that I prepared for her.
She said,
that she wants to be my child's god mother.
The bangle is still there.
Don't be too sad miss.
Madam
Lady Chun's body is now placed in the Rain Chamber.
Miss!
Look after Miss, she must not run!  Be careful Miss.
You must not go.
His majesty does not allow you to go because of your pregnancy.  Please don't go there.
You can't go there!  Please think of your baby and yourself!
Miss!
His majesty has arrived.
Your majesty!
Don't be sad.
Its all my fault, I shouldn't have gone kite flying with her.
I should not have allowed her to pick that kite by herself.  Your majesty.
Boil some sedative soup. Yes.
I feel sad about her death too.
I promise you. Her funeral will be held based on an honored lady.
Please your majesty. I beg you to let me look at Lady Chun for the last time. Please your majesty.
You did a nice and clean job this time.
I will give you credit for that.
I dare not accept credit from your highness.
God is helping me this time. If we did not know about her presence, it might ruin my wealth.
and destroy my plan.
Madam is merciless, no one will dare get in your way.
That kid is wicked.
I'm sure Zhen Huan is deeply saddened because of her death.
It brings me joy to see her tears.
Madam is elegant, Zhen Huan can't be compared to you.
Don't think too much, Miss.
No one would have wanted this to happen.
That...
Is that Yu-Er?
You must avenge Lady Chun.
What happened? Tell me.
Lady Chun...
died under the hands of a murder.
That's not something to be taken lightly of.
Lady Chun lived near the river since young. She's a good swimmer, its not possible for her to drown.
There is more to her death.
Jin-Xi, what did the people who followed Chun say?
They said that Chun ran really fast. She was near the rockery in no time.
They could not catch up with her.
They lost her after that.
She was last found near the lotus lake.
Everyone thought that she fell into the lake.
I think there is something more to it.
Lady Cao
asked me to take a look over at the rockery.
Does she know anything?
or did she purposely...
came to stop me from finding out about this sooner?
I have got to ask her -Miss.
There's nothing you can get out of her now.
We've not no evidence now.
If Chun really was murdered, I will avenge her.
I won't let her die in vain.