I report to you, Young Mistress...
We may no longer serve you!
What happened? Tell me about it.
Eunuchs from Internal Affairs Authority has told me,
Pin of Beauty from Palace of A Blissful Beginning,
asked me to serve her.
I see.
It's a good place to go
It's a fortunate thing for you.
Pack your stuff and go.
Thank you, young mistress.
I don't want to leave you,
Please take care
Huanbi,
Get everyone here.
Yes.
Subtitles by The Legend of Zhen Huan team @ Viki.
Please do not reuse or redistribute our subs.
It's been 2 months since I fell ill.
I don't like noises.
I don't need too many servants.
So I want to ask you all something.
If anyone wants to leave Palace of Shattered Jade.
Huanbi will give you some mony and you may leave.
Everyone, let's congratulate Kang Gonggong and YIn Gonggong.
Pin of Beauty has asked them to serve.
They will leave as soon as they finish packing.
Young mistress always treats you well.
Kang gonggong is flattery like a dog.
But now you find a better spot you just leave without saying anything
You don't even care about loyalty.
Liuzhu, you are wrong about me.
I want to serve young mistress with my whole heart.
But Pin of Beauty specifically asked for me.
I had no choice.
"No Choice"?
I don't know why anyone will force you to serve her.
Since you want to serve young mistress with your whole heart.
Then we must make your wish come true.
Why don't you go refuse Pin of Beauty's offer?
Tell her,
You are too loyal to serve another mistress
Pin of Beauty won't blame you.
And I will apologize to you.
But I'm afraid someone is just bluffing.
Liuzhu
Kang Gonggong is such a loyal servant.
that he will do the same thing to every mistress.
Huanbi, give him money.
Kang gonggong. Have a nice trip
Yin Gonggong. Hold tight.
Learn that loyalty from your shifu.
You will have a bright future
Thank you. Young mistress.
Anyone who wants to leave may leave.
Now we still have leaving allowances for you.
If you want to leave after today?
Young mistress will report it to the Empress.
You will be dragged to Bureau of Cautious Punishment to serve as a hard laborer
Think twice!
I'm too stupid to serve you.
I am willing to follow young mistress. I will never betray you.
I wll also follow you.
I received such a big favor from Lingering.
I will never betray you.
Why do you say this?
My brother in Imperial Warehouse is so sick. Nobody cares about him
You still care about him even if you are sick.
You also asked Doctor Wen to treat him
Otherwise,
Otherwise, my brother will be dead already.
You have been so great to us.
I will be loyal to you till the end of my life.
Even when I am dead,
after my reincarnation as a cow.
I will carry you to be a Buddha.
Idiot.
That's exactly what's on my mind.
I will never lie.
All right now.
Stop Kow towing. You will abrase your head.
Then I have to get Doctor Wen here for you one more time.
Other people are saying
Everyone in Palace of Shattered Jade
is sick and unhealthy
Now it's winter. Cold at night
Little Yunzi will be affected by the weather while on duty
Prepare a thicker blanket for him
Yes
Thank you, Young mistress
Since you are following me
who is sick all day and doesn't receive any adoration.
You never have any good things coming.
But you still treat me like this.
I have nothing to return the favor.
As long as I live for another day
I won't let you feel wronged.
Thank you, young mistress.
Internal Affairs Authority is so lazy.
They think that our young mistress is not powerful enough.
They won't even deliver any decent charcoals to us.
Quiet. Look.
Young mistress is still sick
She will feel bad if she hears about this.
Is the water ready?
Yes
We can't use this charcoal. Too smokey.
Let me get a hand warmer ready (using hot water)
Put it onto young mistress's bed. That will make her feel warmer
Go ahead
Greetings, young mistresses
It's getting cold. Does your mistress sleep well?
Greetings, Precious Shen, Promise An.
This room is so cold
How is it? Are you feeling better?
Sister
Your hands are so cold
Are you feeling better?
It's still the same
You can't stay like this forever
Your jade ornament has such a good color
It must be a gift from the Emperor right?
Mei Jiejie is in the Emperor's favor right now
Palace of Shattered Jade is cold and remote. It's not suitable for a patient to live here.
I brought you some silver charcoal. Just use them for the moment.
I saw Jinxi was using black charcoal.
It must be those sneaky servants from Internal Affairs Authority who won't give you supplies.
I should report it to the Empress
I've been sick for a long time
It's no wonder that they don't treat me as well
It's better to have one less problem than one more
Not to mention since you're in favor right now
They don't dare to treat me too badly
Not to mention, you guys have brought it to me anyways
Bring me something when I need it desperately. Nothing can compare to this favor.
It's all because you have a good personality
You can even tolerate Kang Fuhai's leave. He is such an ungrateful thing
Since he is ungrateful,
It's better not to keep him around
What you mean is?
It doesn't matter if you have a lot of servants
What you need are loyal ones
That's right. I should pay attention to that when I go back
You too LinRong
I don't know how to educate my servants
Thanks for your reminder
Your illness hasn't improved in a long time
It's because you're worrying too much right?
I'm ok. How about you?
Have you served the Emperor?
Why would the Emperor remember me?
Don't think too much about it
The wars in northwestern regions are pressing
It's natural that the Emperor doesn't come to the Inner Palace
Sooner or later you will serve the Emperor
I know the Emperor is busy
I've heard that it's been over 10 days since he visited the Harem
Yes, if the Empress Dowager finds out she'll nag about it
I know the weather is cold, need to hold a warmer
With this cover, you won't burn your hands
So I made this for you overnight
Flower Woven Silk. when we all came into the palace
we all received a piece of this
Such good cloth
made into a warmer cover, isn't it a waste?
It's not a waste. I don't have anything good enough for you
As long as you like it
I like it
It's almost the end of the year
The Empress wants me to visit the palaces
and see how the decorations are going. I have to go now
Go ahead, be careful on the road
Then I will also come visit you another day
Your body is weak, it's cold outside
so don't walk around outside, or else you'll catch a cold
It's ok, I like being with you both
Jin Xi, escort them out
Yes
Take care of yourself
It's time for your medicine
How long do you have to keep drinking this medicine?
Medicine is still part poision, I'm afraid it'll harm your body
This medicine just doesn't let me recover as fast
It's fine
No one's found out right?
It's only me and Liu Zhu, no one else knows
However
Why do you also hide it from Precious Shen and Promise An?
Because we are like sisters,
I can't tell them
There's always a possibility
that someone finds out
I won't drag them down with me
Look
It's rare for Cai Yue to come here
Please sit
Bring a chair, invite her to sit
I'm not sitting
I just helped Precious send some things to Palace of Shattered Jade
So I came to get this month's allowance
Go wrap up Precious Shen's monthly salary
and give it to Miss CaiYue
Yes
You were at the Palace of Shattered Jade?
That's right
My young mistress is friends with Lingering Smile
Lingering Smile is sick
My young mistress thinks about her often
Lingering Smile should get some treatment
Of course
Since she's sick, she needs some extra care
Palace of Shattered Jade is always out of stuff
Thankfully my young mistress picks out good things to send there
Or else who knows what it would be like for them
This isn't something Precious should worry about
This is our Internal Affair Authority's lack of attention
I will definitely get someone to replenish them
You're in charge of everything in the Interal Affairs Authority
There are a million things for you to do every day
It must be your servants who forgot about it
SongZhi Gu Gu, what brings your honor here?
Don't flatter me
It's almost the new year
Palace of Wing's gold paper is running out
I'm afraid Niang Niang will use it to wrap gifts
so I came over to pick up some
Why didn't you say so earlier
Palace of Wing's gold paper was sent over first thing
We also doubled the amount
Just now the Empress's palace just took a stack
What's remaining we still have to give out to each palace's young mistresses
I'm afraid We don't have any extra
Huang Gui Quan
I'm afraid you don't want your job any more
It's always been that you'll give whatever the Palace of Wing's wants
Since inventories are low, just bring them all to me
and purchase some for others later right?
This...
Some people's young mistress's have low standing
They're not good enough to have gold paper to wrap gifts
Wouldn't you say so?
Here
Thanks
You've come to get this month's allowance?
Congratulations
I'm afraid I remember the wrong date
I thought Precious Shen was still under punishment
and not able to get her monthly salary
Huang Gui Quan, let me tell you
When the time comes and you don't have any
don't blame Niang Niang for getting mad at you
What the heck...
It's so cold out
Has the annual bonus come out?
Yes
For Precious Shen's sake, Internal Affairs Authority
gave us all of it
Thankfully we have Precious Shen
Just now Precious Shen sent someone over
and gave us a bunch of stuff
Really?
Now we can have a good new years celebration
Today is the 25th right?
Don't know if young mistress's illness can get better
Don't want her to miss out on the new years eve feast
Just now Jiang Fu Ha came with an edict
Saying that since young mistress is sick
Empress is allowing her to stay here and rest
She doesn't need to attend the new years eve feast
That's great
We'll be waiting for the new year to come
And have a good new years celebration with young mistress
That's right
The Emperor and Empress have arrived
Greetings Emperor and Empress
Today is a family feast, don't be so formal
Sit
Thank you your Majesty
imperial brother always says we don't have to be formal
But acoording to rules, we still have to be
(Duke of Fruits, Yunli)
Only 17th brother would say this
He's most afraid of being formal
Today he hasn't escaped and was not late
It's already a very rare thing
Everyone is here today, how can I be late?
First give a toast to Imperial brother
Wishing you longevity, pease and health
May our country have peace and prosperity
Good
Wishing your majesty a hundred years' peace, health and fortune.
May the Emperor live forever
Drink
This wine is great
Princess of Glory
Did you also drink it all?
Of course
Your Majesty seems very happy today
This afternoon there was news from the Northwest
Nian GengYao put down Robzang Danjin's rebellion
Capture their generals and officials
What a good Nian Gengyao
What a good General Nian
Congratulations Your Majesty
Congratulations Your Majesty, all is well now
Your brother, very good
Brother is working hard in the frontier
I am working hard here in the Harem
That's what we should do
Everything's good in our yard
except for a few winter plums and pine trees
With this snow
the yard's all empty
If you feel it's empty
We can cut some window flowers
It will seem even more lively
Sounds good
Then please get me some colored paper and gold or silver papers.
Let's cut window flowers
Good good.
I'll go get the papers
Then I'll go get some scissors
Then I'll find some patterns
I'll go with you
Niangniang, Princess of Modesty's palace has sent someone here.
saying that Princess of Modesty's old illness striked again.
They want a doctor.
Today's new year eve. She is bringing bad luck
Don't send any doctors
What if Princess of Modesty send someone for a doctor on her own?
Pass my words to the imperial hospital
Whoever dares to treat that bitch
acts against the will of Nian Shilan.
I see. Excuse me
Your majesty, let me toast you
Where is Lingering Smile?
Lingering Smile is still recovering.
It's so cold outside. So I told her to have a rest.
Jinxi, let me see.
Look at the peacock spreading its tails. Jinxi made it looks like a real one.
So nice
Yes
But the portrait of Two Gods of Love made by young mistress is better.
Look. They almost come to life.
Two Gods of Love don't actually exist.
I was just thinking of a pattern
But I heard there are people,
Their paper cut works look exactly the same as a real person
But I haven't seen such talented people.
Young mistress, we have someone who can do this
I saw Little Yunzi cut your portrait.
And he hides it in his sleeves
- Really?
- Don't talk nonsense.
Little Yunzi. Don't be over modest.
Let me see
Take it out.
So vivid.
Little Yunzi, you got a talent.
Exactly
I'm not that good.
I can't cut out something as beautiful as you are.
Next time let me cut something better for you
It does look like young mistress.
But if we only look at those eyes and eyebrows
It also looks like Huanbi
How can I be compared to Young mistress
Let me see
Huanbi has served me so long
that we actually look alike
Why wouldn't I look like you?
If all of us looks the same,
That's scary
But you are as naughty as I am
I heard people in the forbidden city say that,
In new year's eve
If you hang something precious to you onto the branches.
as high as you can,
Then you can make a wish.
If young mistress likes this portrait.
why don't we hang it onto the tree in our yard?
Then we can pray that everything will go well in the new year.
This is also a blessing to Little Yunzi
Good idea.
But in our yard there are nothing but withered trees
There's no point hanging the portrait there.
Why don't we find somewhere with winter plums
And hang the portrait there
-Good
Garden of Winter Plums is a great choice. It's also close.
Are there white ones?
Jade green stamens and wingceltis colored center.
the blossoms are like red clouds. So beautiful
Not bad
Red plums with white snow
Subtle scents are floating around
That's what we call a great scene
Let me check it out
Young mistress!
You haven't fully recovered.
It's not good to walk around
And Empress has explicit orders that since you are still ill, it's better to avoid walking out.
If Empress heard about this, she will blame us.
- right
It's already late night.
Everyone is in the family feast
I will wear my cape.
It's warm and inconspicuous
I've been sick for such a long time
It's time to go out and get some distractions
Young mistress!
-Nobody is allowed to follow me
I will go by myself
If anyone dares to stop me
I will let him kneeled in the snow for the whole night.
5th Brother. Let me toast you.
Wish you peace.
- Wish you all go well
Have the winter plums flowered yet?
Beautiful blossoms despite the snow.
I want to see.
It's cold ouside.
Please watch out for your health
Beautiful blossoms despite the snow
I can't let them down
Don't say anything
Su Peisheng
Your majesty?
Don't let anyone follow me
I want to be alone for a while
To sober up
But your majesty,
Don't say anything
- Your majesty...
Your majesty, are you going anywhere?
Empress Niangniang, what should we do now
It's dark and slippery outside
17th brother,
His majesty won't allow anyone to follow him
But it's dark and slippery ouside
We have to send someone to accompany him
Why putting red plums out.
Princess of Glory isn't aware of it.
The decorations are Glory's responsibility
Rest assured, I'll check him out
What the heck I'm sent to do!
It's New year's eve
(Yu. (Family name Yu))
Only I am sent here in such cold weather
cutting flowers for worshipping the heaven later
They are just bullying me because I'm new here.
When entered the Harem
girls will pray for his majesty's adoration
I only wish that my parents and my younger sister can be heathy and safely
that I can survive the Harem
stay safe untill I'm dead
In the Harem there are only endless schemes
It's hard to keep myself safe
I wish. If the wind can understand my heart,
(comparing herself to the winter plums)
then it shall not break me.
Who is that over there
Who is that?
If you don't show yourself
I will ask servants to search the whole Garden of Winter Plums.
I'm a maid from Garden of WInter Plum
I don't want to disturb your highness. Please forgive me
You received education?
What's your name?
I'm too humble. Don't let my name distain your ears.
Don't get any closer
My socks and shoes are wet. I'm changing
This year the blossoms are as good as in the past.
Every year, the flowers are always alike.
But every year, people change.
Pincess of Glory has cut many plums and put them in vases
She didn't do that on purpose
It's my fault
Princess of Glory married me for a short time. she didn't know anything
All these year, you still can't let go?
What are you talking about?
I'm waiting for spring when it gets warm
Then you can come to visit me. Let's chat and play chess
That's exactly what I intend to do
But now I can smell the intoxicating scents of Plums
I want to drink.
Such a nice plan. Let me join you
Looking for plums in the snow. Let's have the best of the moment
We should drink
Another wonderful thing
I didn't expect a maid can have such learning.
It's a nice suprise
Congratulations
You are back, young mistress
You are back!
What's up?
Here. Have a cup of tea
Are you frozen with cold?
What's going on?
Two cats were runing at me
It scares me
Young mistress is afraid of cats since she is a kid
Two cats at once. She must be scared
Let me make some ginger soup
It will help you stay warm and calm
Young mistress,
people in the forbidden city love to keep cats as pets
Cats are wild animals
If you are afraid of cats
be careful
Young mistress, do you make a wish?
Yes
It's too cold. So I came back
How do you find me
Please forgive me
I'm worried. Even if you are going to pass death penalty on me, I'm still concerned
Nobody's serving you
So I followed Duke of Fruits here.
You didn't notice someone following you?
I was thinking abut you. I didn't notice
Since you are here
I need you to do something
There is a maid who has good education in literature.
Find her.
If you find her, I won't blame you for today's disobediency
Yes, your majesty
But I'm not smart.
Please show me.
How to test the maid's knowledge?
You just asked her, what's the next line of
"If the wind understands my heart,"
Yes
They were just talking about lighting up a paper light and wait for the new year to come
But now they all fell asleep
It's my bad. I am so sleepy
Today you have good luck. You won several games
But please leave us some for the new year
You all are just trying to make me happy
I haven't been here for long. I don't know anything about the patterns on clothes.
I want to ask you,
a dragon swirling pattern
What kind of people will wear that?
Why do you want to know this?
Today's feast, all royal and noble families are invited
You were thinking about this?
Dragon swirling pattern is for highest class
Dukes and Earls cannot use them
It must be a brother his majesty really favors
The former emperor had many kids
But as to someone who can join the feast
which dukes are we talking about?
5th Duke and 10th Duke.
And 17th Duke.
Although they don't have the same biological mother
They are both raised by Empress Dowager
That's why they are very close
I heard about this before I entered the Harem
17th Duke is as unworldly as a wild crane or a floating clouds
He is an expert in the classical six arts
(propriety,music,archery,riding,writing,arithematic)
He is one of the best fluter in the capital.
When the former emperor was still alive
9 princes of his were fighting for the crown
Only 17th Duke indulge himself in books and poems
That makes him a noble and lucky survivor today.
Your words makes sense
Sometimes
I will have more blessing not to compete for anything
That's why you are also blessed
I wish so.
It's not early. Please go to sleep
His majesty have an edictment. The whole forbidden city is celebrating new year
The whole forbidden city is celebrating new year
His majesty came up with a couplet
whether you are a eunuch or a maid
as long as you can come up with the next line. His majesty will award you
Then please tell us about it
Although we are not educated
we can still join all of the rest
Listen carefully
The upper line is "If the wind understands my heart"
Anyone knows?
"Then it won't destroy me"
You are distracted. That's why you've already lost.
I lost the game
I can't compete with you in chess
Your majesty, the thing you asked me to do
I have tried my best
But...
Brother only told you the first line
Su Peisheng doesn't know what the second line is.
It's a tough job.
If you can't accomplish the task, that means you are getting past it.
Don't get mad, your majesty
You have played chess for quite a long time
You must be thirsty
If you want to scold me
please scold me after having a cup of tea
The tea is made of the snow water on winter plums?
I can smell the winter plums in it
Please forgive me, your majesty. It's the scent of me
I some how get winter plums scents on me
Sorry that I disturbed you
Your majesty's servants
are more and more pretty
When I came back
I will ask my servants
To get the scents of winter plums
I don't recognize you
When did you start serving me?
If the wind understands my heart, then it won't destroy me
Gardening in Garden of WInter Plums is tough
Thanks to General Director Su
I am fortunate enough
to serve you once.
Is it cold on the way here?
The snow has stopped
Better than New year eve when my socks and shoes are soaked with water.
you came up with a nice idea
I still have work to do in Garden of Winter Plums
Please excuse me.
Garden of Winter Plums has nothing but winter plums
Here in my palace, I need some winter plums scent
You can stay
Thank you your majesty
What's your name
My name is Yu Yinger
Confer Servant Lady upon Yu Yinger,maid in Garden of Winter Plums.
Grant her a residence in Palace of Esscence
Yes
May you live forever
Even if it's a town house made of jade and gold. I wouldn't want to be there. (A Poem)
I only want to plant a winter plum and indulge in wine in Luoyang City (Poem)
You don't understand what his majesty means?
I don't understand. Please tell me, Duke
It's a poem written by Li Bai. (It's acutally not Li Bai)
His majesty likes Li Bai's Poem
I see. Thank you, Duke.
Have a safe trip, Duke
Where are you going?
I am going to Internal Affairs Authority
I have to report to House of Respectual Affairs
Since you completed the task, his majesty will award you
It's a huge blessing I don't dare to have
Have a safe trip
It's not a problem if you walk the wrong way
But if you find the wrong one.
Then it's a huge problem
Can you sing Kun Opera?
My father is a memeber of a Kun Opera Group
That's why I can sing a few lines
You said finding the wrong one?
You mean?
Please tell me
I was just talking nonsense
A strange thing happened.
Anything new?
His majesty somehow
likes a maid from Garden of Winter Plums
First grant her as a servant lady
A few days later she was promoted to Promise
Garden of Winter Plums?
Yes
This kind of thing that the emperor suddenly fall in love with a maid happens a lot
Nowadays, his majesty really likes her.
Can she beat you?
Almost
I heard she can sing Kun Opera
That's new
watching winter plums and listening to opera
I would like it if I were the emperor
But however his majesty likes her
She still came from a humble family
She can never defeat you
I know
But Linrong is not happy about this
Right
It's a long time since she eneterd the Harem
She hasn't served his majesty yet.
It's okay that other people served his majesty
But that girl was only a maid
She is 10 times more humble than linrong
Now they are both the same rank
No wonder she feels bad
Linrong hasn't served his majesty for such a long time
Is it because she doesn't want to?
His majesty doesn't vist the Harem a lot
And when he does, he usually go to Princess of Glory
and other favorable princess consorts
You know how snobbish the people in the forbidden city can be.
Without his majesty's favor, she can live worse than a servant
Other people can complain about this
You have received constant adoration from his majesty
I'm a little scared when I see other people's tragedy
What if one day, his majesty doesn't like me anymore
You will never lose his majety's favor
because of the love his majesty has with you
not to mention your family's power
I wish so.
Young mistress, the bonus for the Lantern Festival has been delivered to us
Please take a look back home
Then I have to leave
Greetings, Precious Shen
Thank you, Yu Meimei
It's cold and slippery. His majesty is concerned that I might fall.
So he bestowed me a palanquin
Please forgive me for not getting down to greet you
Exactly
If you fell, how would you be able to serve his majesty?
Precious Jie Jie
I have just came back from Princess of Glory's place
I was going to the Empress to greet her.
Can you make way for me?
Thank you for watching!
Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team