Subtitles brought to you by The Legend of Zhen Huan Team
~ Episode 7 ~
He didn't come.
Are you talking about Duke Guo?
it's my fault, I'm stupid.
He is a respectable Duke
In this heavy rain he's not at home appreciate the rain, reading poems
why he has to come here for nothing?
That day may be he was just joking
yet I thought it was true
May be he truly asked you to come
Only because the weather
makes it inconvenient to enter the palace
shao zhu
let's go back
Don't get wet
let's go
Is the Inner Palace still in harmony?
Everything is fine
That's good
I'm old now
I cannot take care of that much anymore
The Emperor has to take care of the country
The Inner Palace you Empress have to look over.
You need to pay attention to everything.
Yes, Empress Dowager.
Your Majesty, just now this servant come here to see
Really there was nobody
This rain is so heavy, not coming is also understandable
Your Majesty
Nobody is as important as your health
It's stormy, please hurry back
Your Majesty, these days you work till late
you're coughing now
If you also get a cold
then it's my crime, your Highness
Your Highness, please come back
Over the high mount, a little moon comes out
Small as it is, how come the moon is so bright
My love is at a far-away place
One day no see, my heart is not at peace
What are you playing?
Nothing
The sound of music reveals a person's feeling
Xiao zhu's heart is missing something, cannot put it down
He is a Duke; you're a Lingering
Please forgive my garrulousness.
but you shouldn't have gone out today.
I know
I'm just a quiet, no-favor Lingering
I don't even know how the Emperor look
Nonetheless
I cannot have any relationship with the Duke
As Xiao zhu enters the palace, you belong to the Emperor
and that person is the Emperor's younger brother
If there were any rumors,
nothing would happen to him.
You would be the only one enduring the pain.
I know
Jiejie
The rain just stops and you've already visit me
Are you not scare of the slippery road?
The Emperor is sick. I don't need to stand by him
If I don't come to see you, I would be so bored.
Mei jiejie takes care of the Emperor's sickness
She has to see Hua Fei again
she's going to endure a lot
Please have some tea
Ok.
His Majesty's sickness is also strange
How did he get a cold so unexpectedly?
There is also time when your body is not at its best
Your Majesty, the medicine is ready
Bring it to me
It's better to have me serve you
You stayed up all night yesterday
Go back early to rest
I'm used to serving you
I don't liking giving this job to others, I don't trust.
Mei Zhuang always does everthing thoroughly.
Even if it is so
Precious Shen is still a new person beside you
It's sometimes hard to avoid being lacking
Xiao zhu, Caiyue is here
Greeting Huan Lingering
Our Precious says
The Internal Affairs Authority just has some new fabric for the spring
please have Xiao zhu come over and choose
Why does your Xiao zhu have so much free time today?
Doesn't she say the Emperor is not well
and she has to take care of him?
His Majesty has recovered?
That's true
From last night
Our Xiao zhu doesn't have to stay by his side anymore
Brilliant spring sunshine
I let it (the beautiful weather) down
Because your Majesty loves the beauty of spring
you gets the cold at the Royal Garden
Hearing the Empress Dowager talking about the flowers at the Royal Garden
Originally wanted to fulfill my filial piety
I went to the Royal Garden to select some pretty flowers for the Empress Dowager
Didn't expect the chilly spring breeze would give me a cold.
Those who know the story will think your Majesty is filial
Those who don't know
will even think the flowers in the Royal Garden all become demons
seducing you
Saying those words means you're narrow
You don't read much, only good at arguing
Alright, you must have been tired all these days.
Go back early to rest
Yes
Your Majesty just finished meeting the officers
I already ordered the servants to brew the medicine
You should take the medicine before reading the officers' reports
Su Pei Sheng
I'm here
Follow me for a walk
Yes
First help get change to casual clothes
Here again.
Who is sitting on the swing?
Seeing my Xiao zhu, are you still not coming here?
Still not coming? I'm talking to you
My Xiao zhu is Huan Lingering at the Palace of Shattered Jade
Is there any Lingering that dress so simply?
Is there a Huan Lingering in the Inner Palace?
Why haven't I heard about her?
Xiao zhu, there is really a Huan Lingering at the Palace of Shattered Jade.
Because of her illness, she rarely comes out
Promise Yu shi greeting Huan Lingering
Good morning, Promise Yu
Are you in the mood of taking a walk?
I have to serve the Emperor
don't have as much free time as Lingering Huan does
However, I have some words to advice Lingering Huan
If you're sick, you shouldn't come out
You should avoid spreading bad fortune to others and getting the blamed for it.
Thank you for your advice
I however also have something to tell you
Not sure if Lingering Huan have any brilliant words for me?
I hear that the Emperor always like people that are refined and courteous
Yet when Promising Yu saw me
you didn't perform formal greeting to me
Maybe it's because you aren't familiar with the rules in the palace
Let's do it like this
I'll have my maid do the greeting first
for you to learn
Yes
Promising, please have a look
Promising Yu shi greeting Lingering Huan
Wish Lingering Huan happiness and peace
I normally hear sisters in the palace praise Promising Yu's intelligence
can learn with one look
Then, Promising
please follow Liuzhu's model
and do the greeting one more time
You at most are a no-favor Lingering
Now you want me, a Xiao zhu,
to formally greet you?
Do you deserve that?
Xiao zhu, Lingering Huan's status
is really above yours, Xiao zhu
You're a servant that eat the apple tree and protect the pear tree
Do you really think that
role order truly follows status?
Whoever the Emperor favors has a higer status.
Otherwise, even if her status is high,
she is still a lowly woman
Furthermore, your status
is only higher than mine by just a little bit.
You base on what to order me around?
If it's me who orders
you to do formal greeting to Lingering Huan, then what will you do?
Greeting your Majesty
Your Majesty, why are you here?
Then why are you here?
I hear that your Majesty recently like to visit the Royal garden
thinking that the view must be charming
so I also take a walk here
These aren't honest words
I only wish to always be by your Majesty's side
How can you know where I'm going to so well?
Xiao zhu, xiao zhu
Greeting your Majesty
Wish you happiness and peace
I
that day didn't intentionally broke my promise and came late
These days although I was sick
I still missed you
Did you come here again to wait for me?
Raise
Help you Xiao zhu. Her body is weak
Xiao zhu
Your bad habit hasn't changed
Look like last time the Empress Dowager punished you too lightly
Your Majesty, I know my fault
Today I was ignorant
so I offended Lingering Huan
Then...then I will apologize to Lingering Huan
Your Majesty please forgive me this time
I'm little sister today commit a horrible mistake
don't dare to ask for your forgiveness
only ask Lingering to think about the fact that we both serve the Emperor
please ask his Majesty to spare my life
Your Majesty, knowing the mistake and fixing it, nothing is better
I think Promising Yu truly know her fault
Your Majesty please forgive her
Since Lingering Huan has already spoken for you
then I cannot let her down
But you never reflect your fault, it's really annoying
Su Pei Sheng
I'm here
Remember, demote Yu shi to Servant Lady
pack her things out of the Palace of Essence
send her to where I cannot see her
Your Majesty
Didn't you say
The status of Lingering Huan is only higher than that of you just a little?
I now promote Lingering to Precious
Your Majesty, promoting Lingering Huan without having her be with you first
I'm afraid it's against the rule
You're doing more and more good things now
even dare to question my order
Your servant don't dare to
I'll go inform your order immediately
Are you so happy
that you've forgotten to thank me?
Firstly, I have made no contribution to the nation
Secondly, I am not of royal blood
Truly...don't dare to receive such a great honor from your Majesty
If I say you can, then you can.
Raise. Kneeling every now and then
don't even think for your body
Mistress Yu, please go back
I'll take my leave
What now? Scared?
Your palm is all wet. Are you scared?
You're the Emperor
Before you weren't scared, you had a guts
Before I didn't know you're the Emperor, but now I know.
Your Majesty's magnificence echoes everywhere
I'm just an insignificant woman; I'm unable to not feel fearful
Fear will cause restrain feeling
Feeling restrain will turn the relationship into that of the king and officer
That day there was a storm. I didn't intentionally miss our meeting
In only a few more steps I would reach the Royal garden
But the Empress Dowager called for me to the Palace of Health
When I came back to the Royal garden
beauty was no longer here
and I got a cold for many days
Is your health getting better?
Am I not soundingly standing here
talking to you?
I'm senseless
Caring causes confusion
Then I thought back. That day it was raining heavily
You were still in recovery
You might cannot come
Truthfully, that day I also kept my promise
Really?
Then you were in the rain. Did you get sick?
Thank you for your caring
I'm also soundingly standing here talking to you
That's good then
I only think that you just entered the palace and have already got sick
your health must be weaker than normal
Your Majesty, why did you lie to me?
It's not lying
I just don't want that
don't want you because of the status, fear of me
obey me, flatter me
Even more, I don't want to become a lonely person because of my status
without even a confidante
I and your Majesty haven't known much about each other
I dare not be your confidante
I like you becauce of your true nature
If you were like other people
I wouldn't have treasured the promise with you so highly
I'm foolish
I couldn't see anything
I purposely hid it from you. How could you know?
Only hard for 17th brother
The many times I had to call him into the palace and jail him here.
Your Majesty's heart is deep and thoughtful. How can I know?
Why is your hand so cold?
Is it because of the wind?
I'm not cold
You've been here for a long time
Let me take you back
Walking is tiring.
I'll carry you
I don't dare to
Why not?
Others will talk behind you
I care for the woman I like
If people want to gossip, let them
Greeting the Emperor. Greeting Precious Huan
You guys get the news quite quickly
Your Majesty endowing Xiao zhu
is endowing everyone in the Palace of Shattered Jade
We sevants all gladly receive your Majesty's generousity
Raise
Thank you your Majesty
You're very good at speaking also. What's your name?
I'm Liuzhu, servant from home of Xiao zhu
Really like mistress like servant
Thank you for your praising
My hands are tired
Are your Majesty saying I'm heavy?
You're not heavy
It's because I'm afraid if I hold you too tightly, you'll be hurt
but if I hold you too loosely, you'll fall
Two hands struggle don't know which way to go
therefore they get tired
Your Majesty are used to making fun of others
When Precious Huan was a Lingering
Were there only you guys who serve her?
Yes
I need quiet time for recovery
so I don't need so many servants
That's not Ok
Who are the maid and eunuch managers here?
Responding to your Majesty
I'm Jin Xi, the manager of the maids here
There's no manager of eunuches at the Palace of Shattered Jade
The old manager of eunuches
Two months ago
was called to worked for Li Pin
This is not a problem
It's not all right to not have a eunuch manager at your place
Tomorrow I'll order the Internal Affairs Authority to select some experienced servants
You choose one to be your manager of eunuches
I gladly receive your Majesty's caring
Actually there's no need to cause too many troubles
I think Xiao Yun Zi is very good
How about promoting him to this role, then training him latter?
Thank you your Majesty! Thank you Xiao zhu!
I'll definitely do by best to serve Xiao zhu
Ok. You say he's good then he's good
Avoid having outsiders
who don't know your style
Your Xiao zhu thinks highly of you
you must work even harder
Yes. I'll obey your order
You're promoted to be Precious
now you need more servants
Tomorrow I'll order the Internal Affairs Authority to select some good servants
Thank you your Majesty
Your Majesty
Zhang Ting Yu wants to see you
I know.
Rest well.
I will come back to see you in a few days
I send Your Majesty off
You know my rules
I know that when practicing your writing,
Niang Niang doesn't like to be disturbed.
But...
Promise Yu has been punished. She has been demoted to servant lady.
His Majesty's intention?
Yes, exactly.
This matter was sorted out faster than I expected.
Have someone watch her. Don't allow her to make a fuss.
Yes
Yushi is frivolous. She wasn't fit to serve His Majesty.
and she does not know caution.
How was she incautious?
She overstepped her bounds
and insulted "Precious Smile"
Has she been promoted to Precious already?
His Majesty must like her?
It seems so
But it is against the Palace rules to skip a rank.
you should talk to His Majesty.
Palace rules were set by the ancestors
Ancestors are Sons of Heaven.
The Emperer is also the Son of Heaven.
She is not ordinary; it was going to happen sooner or later
Lu Gong Gong, go well
Many thanks Gong Gong
Greetings Precious Wan
The moment he returned to his study,
His Majesty instructed me to bring you some things.
Thank you for your trouble, Gong Gong
It is servant's honor to serve Precious
Precious, please look
This is silk lace
A pair of 'Jing Tai Lan' bangles
A box of orchid head ornaments inlaid with gold and precious stones.
Two boxes of wishful headdress flowers A wishful beads curtain
Sixteen bolts of silk
The last item, His Majesty specially instructed
that Precious must personally take a look.
Many thanks to His Majesty
His Majesty explains that young mistress has been tending to her illness all this time,
she must feel lonely.
so he is giving this to you in hope that you will smile
I cannot personally thank him because of my illness
Gong Gong, please thank His Majesty on my behalf
Young Mistress is too polite
His majesty knows that young mistress has not fully recuperated yet
Too many visitors will impair young mistress's recovery
Except his majesty and the imperial doctor, no one else is allowed entry
He asks that Cui Gugu take care of this
Yes, his majesty is considerate and thorough
Then I take my leave
This afternoon
all the gifts we received will not fit in the storage room.
Exactly
- Huan Meimei
- Jiejie
Finally, you can stand out above the others
I pay my respects to Precious Wan
What are you doing?
Are us sisters going to be picky about statuses now?
Mei Jiejie was crazy with joy
She dragged me here as soon as she heard the news
But I still have to follow the rules and be alert
We can't go so far as to have everyone drunk with happiness
Linrong is right
Let's go inside quickly to talk
Let's go
You all keep watch outside
No need to serve us inside
Yes
How did Jiejie become Precious Wan so silently?
You hid it the secret so well,
not the slightest news was revealed.
I really didn't mean to hide it
I met the Emperor by chance in the imperial garden
There is a saying "the quiet amazes with a single feat"
That is you.
I was sitting in my palace
When I first heard of this,
I thought it was an unfounded rumor!
When his majesty's Su Gong Gong passed down the decree,
we finally believed it.
Then we immediately came over to congratulate Jiejie
Only...how many pairs of eyes will be focused on you from now on?
You must be careful
I know
The Emperor values Older Sister
and promoted you even though you haven't served him.
With his majesty's favor,
Jiejie need not be afraid.
I got promoted without serving him
It's not good that his majesty favors me too much.
You hold his favour now
They wouldn't dare do anything to you
We heard that because Yushi humiliated Jiejie,
she was reprimanded by his majesty.
With her as an example,
no one would dare provoke Jiejie anymore.
Promise Yu was at fault
But I'm worried that one day,
I will also inadvertently cause trouble like Promise Yu.
Would my family be implicated?
Now that you are officially favored by his majesty, you have no other road to take
At least His Majesty protects you
It's better than having no one.
Jiejie don't worry
The most important thing now is to nurture your health
so that you can become a true Precious.
Lingrong is right
As long as our sisters' hearts are linked,
we will definitely survive in the palace.
What kind of place is this?
Why didn't anyone tidy it up?
Young mistress
You can't stay in the Palace of Essence anymore
If his majesty hadn't considered your past affections,
I think you should be sent to the Cold Palace.
You wouldn't have your own room
or be able to keep a servant lady to serve you.
You should not complain about this.
Just settle in.
Gong Gong, please take the trouble to let me see the emperor once
The emperor will definitely forgive me
Young mistress overestimates me
We are all instructed by Xia Gong Gong
Young mistress, don't you look down on eunuchs the most?
We're not fit to serve you
Young mistress, don't be upset
How dare you
Greetings, Princess of Glory.
Servant came over today
to deliver the monthly salary for Palace of Wings.
It seems heavier than usual
It is as it should be
Everyone, high and low, in the Internal Affairs Authority relies on Niang Niang's care
We should honor you with more filial respect
You are quite filial. Get up.
Thanks Niang Niang
Lately his majesty has conferred another Precious title
I'm afraid your Internal Affairs Authority will be busier,
with everyone getting ready.
Many thanks for Niang Niang's concern. We're not busy.
At most, they're only errands for a Precious
Not too much work
That Precious Smile has always remained in obscurity
She must have taken a lot of abuse from your Internal Affairs Authority
She's in favor now
so you have making up to do
Good luck with that
If his majesty hears anything from her,
even I won't be able to help you.
Niang niang please take care of me
How can I take care of you?
You're in charge of tasks for the Internal Affairs Authority
Carefully select people to serve her
Young mistress, Princess of Glory sent over these snacks
Young mistress, have a taste
It is said that pastries from Princess of Glory's palace
are better than the Royal Kitchen.
And she doesn't give it away easily.
You may leave.
yes.
These pastries
is indeed better than the Royal Kitchen's.
Mistress should try it.
Seeing these pastries
reminds me of the punishment
which crippled Xia Dong Chun
Jing Xi, I'm so scared.
Things can change in an instant here.
Being afraid will not solve anything.
But one thing remains the same.
The word "favor" is still the most important thing.
Too much favour will raise the ire of others.
Too little favour
will give others permission to step on you.
Mistress should understand,
regardless of whether you are in favour or not
you are never free
from the power struggles within the Inner Palace.
For example, Mistress, Precious Shen,
and Promise An are good sisters.
Others will see this as forming a front
I grew up with Older Sister
Naturally we look out for each other.
Mistress is close with Precious Shen.
This is good.
But taking care of each other
is not restricted to just the Inner Palace.
It is also between the Inner Palace and Outer Ministers.
Princess of Glory is a good example.
Favour and family background
are closely linked.
I just want my family to be safe.
I just want the Emporer's sincerity.
It is best to think like that.
Since Mistress has been chosen to serve
you are already different to girls outside the Palace.
You have little control over your life.
But this servant can tell that
the Emporer likes Mistress a lot.
Mistress also likes the Emporer
That day I went to the Blossoms Garden
with 3 wishes.
But I didnt get to
make the last wish.
This servant is listening.
Third wish
To find my one true love and grow old with him
But my one true love
is the one man who can never be wholly mine
Then wish for something else
not for his whole heart, but for a sincere heart
Young mistress's health has already improve considerably
But servant can still plead with his majesty
that young mistress's health condition
is still not suitable for serving his majesty.
My illness
has not fully recovered only because I continue to take medicine.
If his majesty sends other imperial doctors to treat me,
will I be found out?
If they find out, what will be the outcome?
Last time, you and I had a choice whether to use medicine
This time, to fully recover without leaving any traces,
you don't have a choice. Neither do I.
Servant follows young mistress's orders
Without Physician Wen in the back palace,
Huan'er would be treading on thin ice.
Servant dares not stand out
I will thoroughly protect young mistress
That's good
Then Physician Wen, please cure my illness
but not too quickly!
One month would be ideal
Then servant will gradually reduce the dosage
and in due time, add in some tonics.
You will be fine
Then I will have to trouble you
Imperial Physician Wen, go well
Servant pays respects to young mistress
Reporting to young mistress, these servant ladies and eunuchs
were all carefully selected to serve young mistress.
Gong Gong please rise
Thanks young mistress
People selected by Huang Gong Gong must be good
Otherwise if I have any problems in the future,
I will come find you.
Yes
Jin Xi
Instruct them well
Everyone come with me
Servant is muddle-headed
Because I was busy lately with some trifle matters in the Internal Affairs Authority,
the matter of painting young mistress's table and chairs...
I had Xiao Luzi handle.
Who knew this incompetent servant would be so careless
and forgot it?
I specially brought him here today
to apologize to young mistress,
for young mistress to deal with.
We don't dare accept Huang Gong Gong's apology
otherwise you will be talking behind our backs again
and make us all angry
Liuzhu, lose your manners again?
Look at what this miss is saying
It's all servant's fault for ineffectively instructing my subordinates
Gong Gong's words are too strong
Actually, there are thousands of things to attend to in the Internal Affairs Authority
all of varying importance
It's only normal for your subordinates to slip up
What is there for you to apologise for?
Thank you for your understanding
From now on, we servants will definitely be more attentive
in serving young mistress.
Right
Servant had them bring a new table
I hope young mistress doesn't find it crude
Many thanks Gong Gong for still remembering
Xiao Yunzi, take it
Yes
If young mistress doesn't have any other orders,
servant will take my leave.
Gong Gong go slowly
Thanks young mistress
Go!
How could you speak so imprudently?
This...this Huang Gui Quan veers with the wind!
Previously he deducted young mistress's expenses
Now that young mistress is favored,
he invariably turns to flattery and blames someone else!
Just keep it to yourself
and know to stay vigilant.
If you make a scene and news spreads,
won't others say we are flaunting our newfound power?
Then...servant won't dare anymore
I know you did it for my good
but you shouldn't have acted out so emotionally in the moment.
Everyone in the palace veers with the wind
not just Huang Gui Quan.
I know I was wrong
It wasn't bad to warn him.
make him fear.
Tell every servant,
don't make trouble
Mistress, Huang Gui Quan is a distant relative of Hua Princess
I know,
I'll tell Jin Xi and XIao Yun zi
make an all-out effort to watch out
I'm won't allow the servants that Huang sent here make any trouble.
And, only let them do menial jobs.
you still deal with my affairs
servant knows
Greetings Precious Smile
In the afternoon, his majesty will pay a visit to the Palace of Shattered Jade
Young mistress, please quickly prepare
Thanks Gong Gong
Then young mistress, quickly change and prepare
His majesty is coming
Young mistress, change into a more vivid outfit to greet him
I will just wear this. It's fine.
It is fine, just a bit plain
It's better to wear an everyday outfit like this
May Your Majesty have health and prosperity
It's windy outside, quickly take me inside
Yes
Lotus flower appearing just above the water, being unaffectedly easy and natural(the emperor is complimenting her on her natural beauty,and does not need to dress up)
My Precious Smile is indeed different from all the others
Your Majesty does not look down on my plain dressing?
You dress without finery
Your palace maids are dressed simply
It's very refreshing
Huanbi is my intimate servant
Huanbi? No wonder she is wearing a jade-colored outfit
Huanbi
His majesty might not like so many people around right now
Let's wait here
That's fine too
Huanbi Jiejie
Other servant ladies also wear the same green-colored outfit,
but only Huanbi Jiejie receives compliments from his majesty.
I thought his majesty would notice Liuzhu first
Her pink outfit is more eye-catching
Liuzhu Jiejie is beautiful too
Just not like Huanbi Jiejie,
with brows and eyes similar to young mistress's.
That's why his majesty took extra notice
Really?
Your majesty, have a cup of tea. I brewed it.
I don't know if it is to your liking
You personally prepared it. This expression I like the most.
Fragrant tea
This tea is especially light and pure, refreshingly fragrant
By it's taste, it's cold tea from Yue Zhou
You put in plum blossoms and pine needles
What else?
Your Majesty has exceptionally good taste buds
This tea is called 'three friends of winter'
It was brewed together with pine needles, bamboo leaves, and plum blossoms
The water is dewdrops collected from lotus leaves during the summer sunrise
which makes it so light and refreshing.
The ancients said, tea can freshen the heart
Having tasted your tea today,
I now know that the ancients' words are true.
Your majesty praises too much
Coincidently,
I received two jars of tea last year, and was reluctant to drink them.
I brought a jar into the palace
and buried it underneath the pear tree behind the hall.
I took it out just two days ago.
Are you accustomed to living in this Palace of Shattered Jade?
I think it's a bit far
Many thanks for your majesty's care
I think it's alright, very peaceful
Palace of Shattered Jade is peaceful
It's just a bit far from my Hall of Resting Soul
But it doesn't matter since I want to come here.
It's enough that the heart is close
Yes, our hearts are close
I see that your complexion has improved much
You should fully recover soon
It was never a major illness
My body is just of weak health
Now that I also have your majesty's good fortune and blessing,
of course I will recover more quickly.
Your bashfulness makes it hard for me to part with you