~ Episode 75 ~
Greetings your majesty.
It's very late.
are you here to do a check up for one of the concubines?
your majesty,
Concubine Xi is a bit sick
I am here to bring the herbs/medicine.
Concubine Xi has heart problems
She has yet gotten over her shock/sadness. Of course, it is heart problems.
It's just fear, not sadness
Of course. Yu Fujin was just buried.
Then take good care of Concubine Xi for me.
yes your majesty.
Why are you here this late?
Replying to Niang Niang
Concubine Ning Ping asked me for some medicine/herbs.
What type of medicine?
Some meds to increase sexsual drive.
She's favored by the emperor
Why would she want these things?
Concubine Ning specifically asked for the love potions that Consort Li left behind.
But that's not important.
The most crucial thing is
She asked me for some pearl powder
Pearl powder. What for?
Your highness might not be aware
Since his majesty ascension
He has been continously taking pill medicine
To seek longevity
Since your highness return a year ago
After his majesty's major illness
His dosage has increase
His prescription contains sulphur as well as mecury
Although its not lethal
But with the addition of pearl powder
He might look well on the outside
But he is getting weaker and weaker as time goes by
plus sensation incense catalysed
Internal and external are both hollowed.
So Official don't dare to give cinnabar to Concubine Ning.
Imperial Concubine Ning wants pearl powder?
Perhaps she may have other intentions for it.
If you feel uneasy about it,just don't give it to her then.
If she wants it,
she'll naturally find a way to get it.
Yes. Your subject understands.
Your majesty has awaken?
It looks like the medication Immortal Zhang gave
is actually working quite well.
The meds Immortal Zhang gave is really working.
Otherwise...
both Guangdong and Guangxi governors wouldn't have strongly recommended me.
What incense did you light?
When I smell it, my heart feels warm.
It's just the usual Longxian fragrance that you use, Your Majesty.
I just added in a little...
other fragrance ingredients that I like.
Just as I thought, the fragrance is legendary.
The scent is not as good as your scent.
your majesy, you have been looking at documents for a whole morning and noon.
and finally you have time to sleep,
how come now your getting up again?
Court matters will always keep me busy.
I will never finish reading all the documents.
Sometimes, I'm lazy.
i want life to be unpainful, and short.
Why should I work so hard and diligent in government affairs?
I agree to that too.
life is short and painful, and you would need some time to rest.
Mother is here?
Greetings, Mother.
rise.
Mother, the wound on your leg just recovered.Sit down quickly.
after my leg injury, I have not have time to come and see you.
Its a good thing that your are a modest child.
you do not need me to worry.
Just read your books. Hongyan and I will just listen.
I'm hopeful that Hong Yan would be as hardworking as you in the future.
your son is not as precious as Hong Yan.
You are both my sons.
Naturally, you won't be lacking.
I do not have as much fortune/luck as Hong Yan.
When I first saw you, you were still young.
you have always been in Yuan Ming Yuan.
I have always felt guilty,
about not bringing you to live with me in the palace earlier.
Only after I met you, Mother,
that I was able to enjoy having a mother.
althoguh now you are not as important as you were before in Imperial father's heart,
whatever happens,
i will never leave you alone, run away, and never care about you, mother
Hong Yan and Ling Xi are still young.
All my hopes are on you.
Yes, your son understands.
Reporting to Your Majesty,
Even though Your Majesty still young and healthy,
but foundation of a nation should be build early.
Your majesty, among your sons,
the fourth prince is the oldest.
Please make the fourth prince, the crown prince,
so he can help you solve the country's problems.
The court never crowns the crown prince based on age.
we only look to see if the prince has the ability.
Your majesty
The fourth prince has always grown up out side of the Imperial Palace.
He is also very educated.
I think among all of the princes,
only the sixth prince is smart and intelegent.
Your majesty,
The sixth prince is very young how can he hold this important position?
Instead, the fourth prince is better.
Your Majesty,
Concubine Xi was never born in a high position.
She can not be the Matriarch of the nation!
Although Sixth Prince is intelligent,
as he is still young, his mother will wield the power.
Once Concubine Xi becomes the Dowager Queen,
she will take control of the court.
Furthermore, Noble Consort Xi was once banished from the harem.
It will invite rumors.
She can not become the mother of the crown prince.
In your opinion,
you have no objections to the Sixth Prince,
but you worry about Noble Consort Xi?
I feel that his young age give his mother the power.
For example, the Lv and Wu messing with the affairs of state.
Furthermore, Noble Consort Xi is not kind by nature.
Otherwise she would not have been banished from the harem before.
I have already said before
Noble Consort Xi left the palace to pray for the nation.
To think that you assume...
that since Sixth Prince is born by Noble Consort Xi,
he will definitely be used by her?
But I have three sons!
two of them are from Concubine Xi
You guys also know,
Fifth Prince is mischievous.
I have never think about who to be the crown prince yet.
the sixth prince is young and relies on his birth mother.
The fourth prince is already a man now.
so he will not have the need to lean on his mother.
unlike the sixth prince who is dependant on his mother.
If your majesty's wish to make the 6th prince the crown prince,
Please learn from the earlier Emperor and plan ahead.
What do you mean plan ahead?
Keep the son, get rid of the mother that way there will be no future troubles.
You want me to order Concubine Xi to die?
Your servant does not dare!
Your servant just wants to persuade your majesty, to put the country's affairs up front.
I heard from Su Pei Seng,
Your majesty has not been well these past days.
I will use your Qing playing as my breakfast.
I do not have such an amazing ability.
Your majesty mustn't put me in such a high position.
or else, one day,
Your majesty will listen to one of the officials,and behead me.
Giving me a piece of cloth and tell me to hang myself.
I thought about it and thought I should let it go.
Your majesty can even still joke.
which represents that your majesty's mood is good.
I am worry about the crown prince's business.
The fourth prince is the oldest.
the sixth prince is my favorite.
I am pressured by each side.
since we've talked up to this point
i always think about the 6th prince's birth condition.
I wish that the court business is fair.
Your majesty, please listen to what I have to say.
say it.
the person saying that Hong Yan is young,
so he cannot become the crown prince,
must be dark hearted and evil.
your majesty's health is very good.
why can't he wait untill Hong Yan grows up?
who ever says that, I don't like either.
so you still think,
our child is the best, correct?
Hong Yan is only so so. He is not suitable to be crown prince.
So for a long term plan,
The 4th prince is the best choice.
The 4th prince is not your biological son.
what your majesty worries about, is who should be crowned the crown prince,
but not if the prince is my biological son.
then what if I,
choose another person that was born with a higher position to be the 4th prince's adoption mother,
as long as it is fair, and the country has a heir to the throne,
I have no concerns.
after hearing this,
I should promote you to the position of empress.
I have already received so much from Your Majesty.
I can not compare with Quan Yuan Empress.
There are already lots of talk about me.
I really don't want to be put in a spot.
Which would put Your Majesty in a tight spot among all the wives.
Thank you your majesty.
if it has to be like this,
I will not force you.
greetings Concubine Xi.
rise.
I past by Ning Hui Hall earlier.
I saw the servants have received ordered
to cut all the Albizzia.
It is said that the Emperor feels that
All the Albizzia's flowers falling to the ground in the Fall, it is really tiresome.
His Majesty is not even willing to keep these Hehuan flowers alive.
Those Hehuan flowers were bestowed upon Wang Ye
by the previous Emperor when he was 15.
It was to wish Wang Ye prosperity and happiness.
but what his majesty says is correct.
The person is not even here anymore, whats the use for these flowers to stay?
Looks likes this is good too.
I know that you won't say it,
and you can't say it,
so I said it for you
say what?
Those Albizia flower, are from when you were titled.
He sent them to you as a gift.
afraid that you would be sad about this,
So I told His Majesty that I wouldn't sleep well at night.
Need to keep the Albizia to cook for medicine reason.
It's a good thing that His Majesty has agreed to it.
He ordered people to put those lotuses...
in my palace.
Thank you
then don't let him go easily.
don't worry.
mother.
greetings mother.
You're already a man with your own family.
Whenever you're happy, you still forget yourself!
Today at Court,
Imperial Father granted me the title of Prince of Bao!
That's what you deserve!
You're the eldest son.
And naturally the first Ruling Prince among the Imperial sons.
But Sixth Brother hasn't been made a ruling prince yet.
6th prince is still young.
Furthermore, I hope...
that his Princely estate will be bestowed by you.
Mother.
if you understand what mother means,
then you must know what to do.
Don't display your intentions, and do not allow people to know your thoughts.
More importantly, don't allow people to guess your preferences.
Yes.
next month,
is your Imperial Father's birthday.
your Imperial Father is getting old.
yes, your son will try his best.
and plan the birthday celebration greatly.
then make it great.
yes
I wish Your Majesty Happy Birthday and have many more of them in the future.
To celebrate Your Majesty's birthday,
My Younger disciple and I have made another 2 elixir. (for living forever)
Special brought it to give it to Your Majesty.
You are thoughtful.
But I wonder, after I consume this pill,
will I really live a long life?
Your Majesty, your complexion...
is looking a lot better than previously.
I've been accompanying Your Majesty everyday.
I too, feel that you've been more energetic...
like before.
That's good then.
After taking the elixir, Your Majesty shouldn't overwork.
Please make sure you remember it.
Then I will move to Yuan Ming Yuan. (The Imperial Garden)
Less rules and trouble.
Niangniang, I have something to report.
Recently, Concubine Ning...
has been asking for pearl powder with increasing frequency.
On the surface, His Majesty's complexion looks good.
But in fact, foundation of his body is getting weaker.
Have the other physicians in the medical department detected anything?
This is a slow poison. It can't be detected.
That's good then.
If Consort Ning asks for it, just give it to her.
Besides, I never heard anything.
Yes. This subject understands.
You guys accompany me
to visit His Majesty later.
Greetings, Noble Consort Xi.
Hearing the qin for too long makes it boring.
I want something more exciting.
Then shall we play something else?
Your Majesty, Meimei and I will guess riddles.
Yeah!
Your Majesty, listen.
Who is inside?
They are two Young Mistresses of the rank of Promise.
Then I'll come back tomorrow to see His Majesty.
His Majesty doesn't take care of his own body.
His Majesty thought that he's regained his strength.
You are the head of the Imperial Medical department.
You should be showcasing your ability.
Don't let him between the wives
feel the spirit is willing but the flesh is weak.
Niangniang, don't worry.
All these stuffs are originally from Concubine Li.
It can be handy to Concubine Ning.
His Majesty is eating it up.
Just remind her to be careful.
Yes.
Your Majesty.
Shall we guess another riddle?
Your Majesty, slowly.
Do you have any other riddles, Jiejie?
Quickly think of more!
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, what's wrong?
What's wrong? What's going on?
What's wrong, Your Majesty?
Summon the physician!
It's summer again.
His Majesty has been nursing the illness on and off for 6 months now.
Even though living at Yuan Ming Yuan (the Imperial Garden) is very quiet.
But it doesn't seem to be getting better.
His Majesty worry about the affairs concerning politics.
Tell Su Peisheng...
to send the folded notebook (relate to work in the old day.)
He will definitely read them.
His Majesty dislike the power taken by others.
Any folded notebook sent to him would be read by him personally for sure.
It's just that his health is no longer like before.
How can he work like before...
and read official documents for 12-14 hours?
Where are Hongyan and Lingxi?
The princess has gone to Noble Consort Jing's residence to play with Longyue.
Sixth Prince is living with Duchess Shen.
He is playing at the garden right now.
Your Majesty, even though it is summer time,
the winds are still strong.
Your Majesty, hold on to my hand and walk slowly.
Don't let the wind blow at you.
It is already summer?
I still feel cold.
It's like there is a leak in my body.
Your Majesty, you're still healthy!
But lately, you've been engaging too much in marital relations.
You have to be careful.
I just like watching those...
flower-like faces...
Looking at Consort Ning so young,
I feel young myself too.
Then, Your Majesty, just look.
Don't let your royal body...
Prince!
Slowly!
Who is over there?
- Don't haul me. - Slow down.
Your Majesty, that's Duchess Shen...
and her eldest son.
He's playing with Sixth Prince.
Her eldest son?
Yes.
Is it...
17th Brother's son, Yuan Che?
Exactly.
Yuan Che, come here!
His Majesty has arrived.
Peace to His Majesty. Peace to Imperial Father.
All of you, rise.
It's so rare for you to enter the palace. Don't feel too constrained.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Hongyan...really needs playmates.
It's a pity this palace...
has no princes who are around his age.
When you're free, bring Yuan Che into the palace frequently to play.
Yes.
The two of them get along really well.
Come here. You too.
They do look like brothers.
It's just that Hongyan looks stronger.
Let me carry him.
Your Majesty!
I can't carry you anymore!
Sixth Prince is older. He is much stronger.
But he does look very much like the young lord.
It's almost like they're biological brothers.
What did you say?
Wet Nurse said Hong Yan and Yuan Che are like blood brother.
Let me take a look.
They really do look alike.
Especially the eyes and the jaw.
It really looks alike.
Emperor, you are tired.
Your Majesty.
I heard that when His Majesty had his dizzy spells, you were present too.
His Majesty was acting weird.
We were talking normally, and he suddenly fainted.
What did you talk about?
We were just talking about Sixth Prince's and Yuan Che's features.
And we were discussing...
that Sixth Prince's eyes and jaw looked like Yuan Che.
His Majesty is not very well.
Don't bring Yuan Che into the palace so frequently anymore...
to lessen any trouble.
I understand.
In this past year the Emperor's health has not been well
Duke Shen is a close relative.
Have him pay more attention to what's going on inside and outside the palace.
I understand
Go.
Fine. All of you, go out.
Go out.
Your Majesty, you must see the physician!
Bring Xiayi over.
I have something important for him.
Yes.
Sixth Prince got a shock today.
It wasn't easy for him to finally fall asleep.
I'm afraid His Majesty got a shock today as well.
Why?
Have you never realized...
that Hong Yan and Yuan Che are looking more and more alike?
They're cousins. Of course they'll look alike.
Jingxi.
I'm afraid His Majesty has gotten suspicious.
What you mean is that...
His Majesty suddenly had an attack because of Sixth Prince...
We cannot not take precautions.
Niangniang, Noble Consort Jing's Ruyi has come.
She said something big happened in the harem. She's requesting an audience.
Let her in.
Yes.
It's regarding the royal bloodline.
You must be extremely conscientious.
And do this job well.
Your Majesty is saying...
that you've done a paternity test with Sixth Prince before?
Nothing is absolute.
Go investigate it again.Remember...
don't let anyone find out.
I will definitely carry it out.
Peace to Niangniang.
Where's His Majesty?
His Majesty just took his medication. He's fallen asleep.
I'll go in to take a look.
Yes.
Open the door.
Meimei, you've come.
Jiejie, dispense with courtesy.
These few days, you've been taking care of His Majesty.
It's been hard on you.
What's hardship are you talking about?
We do everything for His Majesty's sake.
Oh yes...
The weather hasn't been too good these days.I'm worried that your leg ailments are going to act up again.
You must take care of your health, Noble Consort.
After falling from the terrace, the pain in my leg has become a constant.
I've gotten used to it.
I instructed the kitchen...
to steam some ginseng soup for His Majesty.
His Majesty's body has gotten so weak.
He still keeps eating the Elixir. (med supposedly to make you live forever)
Did not holding back at all.
His Majesty is very stubborn.
You and I
often tell His Majesty to take care of his health.
His Majesty often just laugh about it.
Sister has been busy lately.
Take good rest.
I will.
About Promise Sun...
Did Noble Consort Jing mentioned it to you?
What do you think you will do?
This matter,
I got to talk to His Majesty.
You need to take your time though.
Don't let His Majesty got too angry.
Your thought is also mine as well.
Be careful!
Niang Niang, Xia Yi has came to see His Majesty.
Even Imperial Noble Consort got sent away because of it.
Servant is very worry about His Majesty.
I over heard that
it is about Niang Niang and Sixth Prince.
I got it.
Take all the servants with you.
I will be here tonight.
No one is allowed to be in.
Yes.
Noble Consort Xi.
how long have you been here?
When I came, you'd just fallen asleep.
If you're tired of sleeping,why don't you sit up?
You are Noble Consort.
Just leave these chores to the servants.
Everything I have is given by Your Majesty.
So I never forget it.
I can only return the favour by taking good care of Your Majesty.
Noble Consort Xi.
You never use these kind of big flashy words.
In the past, Your Majesty
never call me Nobel Consort Xi in private either.
I was going to touch your hair.
But I ended up with
the feeling of the cold and beautiful decoration. (on your hair)
I remember in the past
when we were here to relieve summer heat (because Yuan Ming Yuan is further North than the Palace)
In the evening, when there is nothing else to do,
we would relax in a cool place.
Your hair were just loose.
You rest your head on my knee
without anything on it.
It was very beautiful.
Wrist on the man's knee
Anywhere is not pitiful?
Noble Consort Xi.
Your beauty hasn't changed one bit from the past.
Thank you for your praise, Your Majesty.
Oh yes. The Empress came to request...
to visit you.
I said it before.
I will not ever see her again, in life and in death.
Then I'll send someone to pass the message.
Your Majesty, drink some ginseng soup.
You've lost weight. Don't work too hard.
My reaction is not that good.
The important matters still need your decision.
So, Your Majesty, you must take care of your body.
Definitely.
Not just for you,
but for our Hong Yan as well.
A father knows his son best.
There's a matter which has been giving me a dilemma.
I already discuss with Imperial Noble Consort and Noble Consort Jing, but we couldn't decide.
We need your decision.
Tell me.
This isn't too difficult either.
It's just that it affects the honor of the Imperial family.
I have no choice but to seek your decision.
Say it.
Promise Sun and an Imperial guard had an affair.
Noble Consort Jing...
has already had them locked up at her palace.
We're now waiting for Your Majesty's decision...
to see how we should deal with them.
I've just fallen ill, and she's having an affair?
Does she think that I'm already dead?
Your Majesty, please calm down.
When did this happen?
Tell me all the details.
The other night, Noble Consor Jing and Imperial Concubine Xin walked by Promise Sun's place.
They over head sound at the garden.
They thought it were servant not behaving properly.
But they discovered both Promise Sun and the thug were disheveled.
The couple were just at it.
Noble Consort Jing detain them both right away.
When I get it in a hurry, they both still sweating like pigs.
Promise Sun's red underwear was on the thug's belt.
It is the absolutely truth. No way to deny about it.
We can only grounded Promise Sun and sent the thug to the torture chamber.
Whore!
- This matter was known by many people. We were afraid to make the wrong decision. Many people know?
Kill her.
Have her body split by 5 different horses!
Your Majesty, calm down. You can execute her in any way you please.
It also happened in a couldy day like this.
I was hiding behind the curtains.
Longkodo hold on to my Mother tightly.
My Father is the son of the God!
I am also son of the God.
Why did all of you have to betray me?
Why did all of you betray me?
You Majesty has not past away yet.
You're all in such a hurry to cry?
How did His Majesty become so seriously ill all of a sudden?
When the eunuch came to report it, we all got a big fright!
Your Majesty's heath could go up and down.
It is still time.
If you can hold it at this point, there will be more days for us to be sad.
So who should stay here to take care of His Majesty? Or should we take turn?
Any of us are not good choice. We, women, cry first whenever things happen.
It will only irratate His Majesty when he hears it.
What about we all stay in our own bedroom.
When His Majesty wakes up, he will call the person he wants to see.
That is good too.
Alright.
The Emperor is very sick
The Doctor has ask His Majesty to rest in quiet.
From now on, no matter which concubine wants to see His Majesty,
everyone needs to go through me and ask the Doctor first before doing so.
Everyone of us needs to take care of our own Princes and princesses.
Kids are still young. If any of them distrubed His Majesty's rest, I won't be able to take on the sin.
Okay.
Right now, His Majesty's health is our primary concern.
If any interfered with His Majesty's health healing process,
don't blame me not to take in the consideration of us being sisters wives.
Why do you need to be using such harsh words?
It is all because of Promise Sun's incident so His Majesty's health decline.
Since His Majesty is very ill, we should contact the Royal Household Bureau to get ready.
The Coffin was already prepared months ago.
What what just happened,
- we need to ask some of His Majesty's brothers to come into Palace.
Okay, I will arrange that right away.
We got to be strong so both inside and outside the Palace won't be in a mess.
We will each do our jobs. We can met if there is anything require we to discuss.
Why is Imperial concubine Xin not here?
You know Imperial concubine Xin's temper. If she wants to come,she comes. If she doesn't want to come, she won't show.
Let her be.
Why did you brought them here?
If I didn't bring them here, you would not have known if your son were kill in his dream.
- Jin Xi. - Yes.
- Xiao Yun Zi. - Yes.
Bring them back to their bedroom.
Xia Yi has use drug to put everyone to sleep and puncture his toe to get some blood.
Xia Yi works for His Majesty so I bet His Majesty ask Xia Yi to do the DNA Blood test again.
But I don't understand. Why does His Majesty want to do the DNA test again?
Hong Yan is who's kid?
Please take a bowl from Zhen Huan.
You have done me a great faour. You have saved Yun Li's children.
Thank you for watching!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki