~ Episode 20 ~
Respects to Precious Smile
What is the important thing that you must bring it so carefully
His majesty specially give this to young mistress
I'll show you
Young mistress, have a look
the shoe sole is made of jade
it is a kind of famous jade from Lantian, touches warm
so it won't be cold when you wear it
And the shoes are hollowed inside
and filled up with many kinds of spices
his majesty said, that's called Every Step Gives Out Fragrant
On the toe cap is a Hepu pearl
it can't compare with our eastern pearl when it comes to the meaning of honourable
but it is mellow, huge and bright
The most precious part is the shoe upper
it is made of goldthread-embroidered Shu silk
Not mention the others
but the Shu silk is very hard to come by
especially the goldthread-embroidered Shu silk
I heard 10 women will cost 3 months to embroider a roll of Su silk
a inch is equal to 10 dous( unit of measure)
It is hard to even have a look
no need to mention it is made to shoe upper
Many thanks to his Majesty
but where is the Shu silk from
I remember the tributary silk from Shu has just arrived in Feb.
only sent to Empress and Empress Dowager
the new silk should arrive in next Feb.
So this is his majesty's special favour to you
The Department of Shu Silk got new type of design and colour
so they sent it here from a great distance
only one roll
then his majesty ordered the Internal Affairs Authority to made it in a hurry
His Majesty arrive
Just talking about him, then he arrives
Respects to your majesty
Wish your majesty well
Quickly put on the jade shoes and let me have a look
Do they look good?
Fits your feet perfectly
Seems like I gave them the right directions
What?
I told the needlework department
to make it according to your foot measurements. Indeed I was right.
But I've never told Your Majesty
my foot measurements.
We've slept next to each other for so long
How could I not know this?
I specially instructed the embroidery department
to embroider the pattern of mandarin ducks.
Your Majesty
Huan Huan
Have I made you unhappy
in some way?
Since returning from the travelling palace, you have been occupied by something
No, you didn't make me uhappy
It's just that you're too good to me
It instead makes me a bit scared
Don't be scared
What I've promised you, I will definitely give you
I will protect you
Huan Huan knows that you favor me
But in the past, you used to also favor Princess of Glory like this
and favor Mei Jiejie.
I'm just afraid that it's nothing more than favor
Favor is love
What if it's favor, but not love?
Perhaps Dear 4th will make an exception for me
As long as all this favor
contains a bit of love,
Huan Huan will be very happy.
Silly words
(Poem) When can we sit together and cut the candlewick under the west window
and chat about the raining night in Ba (Ba and Shu both refer to Sichuan)
Your majesty and I cut the candlewick together
but there's stary sky outside, no raining night to chat about
There's starry sky in Beijing
17th brother's letter says it rains a lot in Shu
luckily, in Ba where he lives, there's beautiful raining night scenery
can comfort his tireness in trip
How is it?
Things get done quickly when you whip the horse
(Poem) A steed galloping up dust wins the imperial concubine's smiling
I don't actually like this color
One dresses like one lives
grandly and gorgeously
Normally Niang Niang likes bright and beautiful colors
Actually this color is elegant too
There are no incoming tributes right now
Getting these two rolls
must have taken a lot of effort too.
Actually, they've put in a lot of thought and effort
Niang Niang look
Even these flowers were embroidered with
bluish white silk thread mixed in with silver thread.
Under the sun, it will definitely be pretty
They're rarely this devoted
This will also let others know
that even the most precious things,
if I want them, I will immediately have them.
Yes, unlike some people,
even if they wear shoes made of Shu silk,
it's just like wearing the imperial robe and not even looking like the crown prince.
Then tell the embroidery department to make this into clothes
Everything else looks fine,
but why have I never seen this floral pattern before?
Right
Before, there were only peonies and phoenix
This is quite fresh
Come look, what flower is this?
Young mistress, this is the morning glory, also called sunset
So unelegant
This flower only blooms for one night
and withers away in the morning.
Shut up! Don't say such inauspicious things!
*****!
This embroidery department is getting more and more out of control!
They actually dare fool me with such a short-lived flower!
Songzhi
Yes.
Rip up these two rolls of cloth!
Take them back to the embroidery department!
Yes.
Niang Niang, most people don't know this flower
It's possible they made an honest mistake
The ripping itself is not a big deal
but if others hear about this,
it will only stir up more gossip.
Since most people don't know this flower,
Niang Niang can pretend not to know
and give it to someone else.
Then let's give it to her
Who?
She already has that pair of shoes
Matched with this outfit,
will definitely look like someone in his majesty's heart
Jiejie, you finally come back
you and An jiejie all went to the Yuan Ming Palace
only left me here
really bored me
Gugu was accompanying you
Gugu scold me all the time
says I'm mouthy
asks me to be quiet
she told me if I can be quiet, I'll win favor just like An Jiejie
Gugu teachs you, you should listen
Gugu also said I have been in the palace for one year
but haven't even talked with his majesty
said I made noises all days
actually, when I meet his majesty, there will be more rules
I don't want
Say these words after you meet his Majesty
Young mistress, Palace of Wings' Zhou Gonggong come
Respects to Precious Smile
stand up
Thanks
Princess of Glory got two roll of Shu silk recently
the color is light
so made it into two clothes, and give them to young mistress
Many thanks to Niangniang
Jinxi, take it
Replying to Niang Niang,
the color is elegant
and the craftsmanship is excellent.
But the Precious Flower Hall's priest said
Precious should be restrained from mouse
even the homophone should be careful (mouse also pronounce Shu)
It's fine if you wear the Shu silk under your feet
as shoes,
but to wear as clothes,
I'm afraid you will have to wait until next year.
Jinxi means that
young mistress cannot wear the clothes that Niang Niang granted?
Young mistress is now the emperor's new pet
Other than gifts from the emperor,
she looks down on things from everyone else.
Our Niang Niang often says
if one is kind-hearted, she'll not be afraid of evil things
Definitely, priest's words can't be distrusted
but Niangniang's kind will protect you
it wil be good for young mistress
Jinxi was only kindly reminding me
Gong Gong need not take it to heart
Report back to Niang Niang
that I will go thank her another day.
Then servant is leaving
Let me see
This looks really nice
Why is Jiejie unhappy about getting clothes?
What flower is this?
Haven't seen it before
This is sunset, or morning glory
Morning glory?
This flower is pretty
But this gift came too suddenly from Princess of Glory
Servant doesn't understand
Not only you
all sudden things must come with odd
Jiejie, this clothes
just matches your Shu-silk-made shoes
If you wear them to the Pageant of Enjoying Chrysanthemum in October
you will certainly stand out from all people
Put it away first
Respects to Empress Dowager
Stand up
Thanks
sit
Why do you come today
It is my duty to serve Empress Dowager
His majesty is busy in political affairs
I shoulde take care of you more
you are more and more honeymouthed
it is already autumn, and cold at night
is Empress Dowager still coughing
It's getting better now
I know you are afraid of cold
so I ordered them to made this fox cloak
It is black fox's fur
Yes
my brother is countering the insurgency in Qinghai
he got two pieces ofblack fox's fur during hunting
I think I am too young
can't wear its vigour out
so I made a cloak to you
I know Empress Dowager respects Buddah
so I used the Indian lotus patterned silk to make the lining
hope that Empress Dowager will like it
Your filial piety is hard to come by
Zhuxi, take it
Yes
Why are you dressed so plainly today?
Although I'm young and immature,
I'm no longer young compared to the other wives.
I should dress more plainly
Unlike Precious Smile and Lingering An
who like to dress beautifully and youthfully.
I often hear you mention Precious Smile
I only remember
she is good looking
It's a pity Empress Dowager hasn't seen her lately
His majesty gave her a pair of shoes made of Shu silk as present
even the soles are made of green jade
Precious Smile also had two outfits made from Shu silk
She looks beautiful in them
Is that true?
But I remember
that now is not the time for Shu silk tributes.
Precious Smile is young and likeable
Is there anything she can't have?
I just don't know how much her Shu silk attire
cost in total.
She just entered the palace, and the emperor treats her like a little kid
Of course she would be pampered a bit more
You has been favored for many years, have the sense of propriety
you should teach her
Yes
In my opinion, His Majesty still cares about you the most
The Huanyi fragrance that you use
His Majesty personally chose the perfumes that went into it,
then had it prepared and brought to you.
Take a look at the entire palace
Who else has he treated this thoughtfully?
Come over here
I dare not accept
Here
When I first became De Fei,
Empress Dowager Xiao Hui granted me this hair ornament.
You're still young and beautiful, like a flower
You also have respectable status
Why dress so plainly?
I think that this hair ornament is just right for you
Many thanks for Empress Dowager's tender love
I love you just like I love His Majesty
Quickly change into more colorful clothes
and show His Majesty.
Then I will take my leave
Niang Niang's hairpin is so pretty
but we weren't able to vent our spleen
what a pity
no need your mention
but it's great to get Empress Dowager's tender love
Right
Light the sandalwood
and bring me the Fahua Scriptures
Empress Dowager also think there's too much jealousy in the room
and have to disperse?
Jealousy is common in the inner palace
no need to be surprised
servant also don't care about such jealousy
but Princess of Glory did so much work
we can see Precious Smile is not simple
you know Princess of Glory
she is always jealous on little things
has never changed
but it's also his majesty's fault
old as he is, he can't take everything into consideration
make me worried
Empress Dowager are worried?
you are the one who should enjoy life most
Go to the Hall of a resting soul
tell his majesty to come after finishing his work
Yes
His majesty comes
Respects to imperial mother
Sit
It's getting cold these days
why not wear more clothes
I came out from the Hall of a resting soul just now
and don't feel cold at the moment
Why didn't Su Peisheng remind you
It's my fault, please forgive me
Su Peisheng works hard
but he can't make everything perfect
with only his own efforts
since imperial mother said so
I'll wear more clothes when go back
Never mind
Su Peisheng, stand up
Thanke for your forgiveness
I'll do my best to serve his majesty later on
Speaking of this
not only does the servants have to watch out for these things
the concubines should watch out too
Is that Precious Smile dedicated enough?
This is hard to say
If I say she is,
today I wore less for the coolness,
Imperial Mother will surely scold her for not being dedicated enough
You will also scold me for being bias
But if I say she is not dedicated,
she is actually an attentive person
It's just that I have been busy with the affairs of the state   I have not seen her in several days
Your majesty said you're not bias
this is the real bias
Don't laugh at me, Gugu
Your majesty are busy with the affairs of the state
but it's only been several days since you've last seen her
Then how often do you see the Princess of Glory?
How often do you see the Empress?
How often do you see the Pin of Respects and the others?
Since Your Majesty is busy
it's fine if you see everyone in the harem less often
but if you appear to have too much of a favoritism
you will hurt the concubines' feelings
Imperial Mother is right
I will remember this
This fine black fox skin
you will only find it in Qinghai
Your majesty has bright eyes and a clear heart
It's so dim in the palace and yet you can tell it's black fox skin
The inner palace and the court are obviously as clear as a flame to you
This black fox cloak is made from black fox skins
Princess of Glory specifically chose
Indian lotus patterned silk as the lining
This is appropriate inside and out and bring out the best in each other
I understand Imperial Mother's lessons perfectly
I heard that today
Imperial Mother gave the Princess of Glory a hair ornament
I believe it should be even more glorious under the candle light
I will have to take the time to admire it
You have to balance kindness and power not only in court
but also in the inner palace
The pacification of Northwest is coming to an end
but the Tusi in the Southwest is still a big concern
It'll take a lot of trouble to gain stability
Nian Gengyao is talented and loyal
As long as he doesn't get too arrogant
Your majesty should use him well
It's a great merit to calm the western frontier
Nian Gengyao will come to the capital in October,
I will reward him nicely
The Princess of Glory ran out of the Huanyi fragrance
This fragrance is difficult to make
Your Majesty is not giving her any more?
For many years she is accustomed to using it
I will definitely give her more
Niang Niang
My brother is back?
The general has calm the western frontier and came back to the capital to pay respects
He went to see His Majesty
His Majesty has always been very kind to the general
they must have many important things to talk about right now
Of course
but it's almost lunch time
Even if His Majesty and Brother have important things to discuss
they still have to eat
Report to Niang Niang
His Majesty has ordered
Niang Niang to come to Hall of a resting soul for lunch
Wait outside
I will come right away
They have many dishes in the palace
but I don't know if they are to your liking
Just try them
if you really don't like them
I will have the Princess of Glory's small kitchen make more
I dare not receive this honour
To be able to dine with Your Majesty and the Princess of Glory
it is already the greatest of honour
Sit down
We are eating as a family
if you stand and sit at every turn
to give thanks and to apologize, what fun is left?
Sit
Thank you Your Majesty, thank you Princess of Glory
This roasted mutton is fresh, tender, and tasty
I really like this dish. Try it.
Indeed tasty
Many thanks Your Majesty
Brother
When His Majesty grants you a feast,
you must be served by the attendants.
I lost my manners
Your Majesty, be sure not to blame me
You have been fighting battles out there all this time
You can't possibly be mindful of every single thing. It's not important.
When I'm in the palace, I can't ignore the rules
You eat however you want
The rules are to remind one of the etiquette between the ruler and his ministers
but not for restricting relatives
Yes
This bird's nest and duck in front of me looks pretty good
I will trouble Su Gong Gong
Great General, enjoy
In only 15 days time,
you crushed Tibetan Prince Danjin's troops.
These 8 months,
you wiped out all the remaining enemy troops, one by one.
You helped me calm the northwest and the western frontiers
You're like a savior to me
I dare not accept Your Majesty's praise
I have not been at the throne for long
Inside and outside the court, not everything is completely stable yet
Not to mention the stupid princes in the palace,
with the disorder in the border region,
I am attacked from both front and back. It is hard to take everything in.
Your great service
not only will I reward you
me,
my descendants and all my subjects
will feel pleased will all our hearts
If anyone shall betray you, they will not be my descendants
If anyone shall be disloyal, they will not be my subjects
Princess of Glory is devoted to you inside the palace
I am devoted to you outside
We brother and sister are willing to dedicate ourselves entirely to Your Majesty,
and serve you with all our energy.
Princess of Glory has served me many years
She has always been thorough and considerate
You have been out there serving as my right arm
To have you as my commanding general of the border provinces
is my fortune.
If I had ten people like you in court,
I wouldn't have to worry about not governing the country well.
Thanks Your Majesty
I toast this cup to you brother and sister
Many thanks Your Majesty
Thanks Your Majesty
Yes
Is it peaceful in the Yunnan-Guizhou and Shanxi regions?
Everything is fine
It's just that before coming to the palace,
I heard that the Zhuozi mountain region's Xieersu tribe is not very stable,
and may cause trouble.
As expected, I received news yesterday
they caused trouble in Zhuanglang county of Gansu province
They are just a motley crowd I believe it will be settled quickly
Your Majesty is exactly right
But I heard that
the Xieersu tribe secretly plans to
form an alliance with Xinjiang's Ge Erdan.
This cannot be taken lightly
Then what do you think of this?
Xieersu is just a small tribe
it'll be too much of a fuss to send a general
and lose our dignity
But if we don't do something, they will become troubles
So, I presumptuously recommend
my second son Nian Fu to fight the battle.
Although he's young, he's had some practice and experience
I want to give him a try
Your Majesty, I shouldn't interfere in politics
It's not suitable for me to stay here and listen to you discuss national affairs with brother
I am discussing both national and family affairs with your brother
It's alright
Princess of Glory is right
I rarely get to share a meal with Your Majesty
We shouldn't discuss other things at a family reunion
Good
Then let's just eat
The weather is getting cold
Starting October 15, every meal in the palace comes in a pot
For Brother's visit today,
although it's only the 14th,
His Majesty still had the imperial kitchen prepare this assorted pot dish.
You must thank His Majesty
Thanks Your Majesty for your kindness
The pot dish will warm you up
You and I, our hearts are linked
I will also feel warmer inside my heart
Yes
Quickly eat
Servant bids farewell to Princess of Glory
and Great General Nian.
Brother, brother
I was scared and anxious during this whole meal
What's the matter?
His Majesty said he liked to eat that roasted mutton dish
Before he even moved his chopsticks,
how could you move yours?
Never mind that
Then you had Su Peisheng serve you the dish!
Who is Su Peisheng?
He was the emperor's personal eunuch for several decades!
He's worked for the emperor since they were kids
And you dare order him around?
You know my temper
I hate the stench of these castrated people!
Since I can not disobey the rules of the palace
of course I have to get the most esteemed eunuch to serve me
I'll say something unpleasant,
I just came back from the battle fields  and earned great merits
and I can't even have a eunuch serve me?
He serves His Majesty and serves me
it's no big deal to serve Brother once
Don't do it again
Li Bai has little literary talent and yet he made Gao Lishi (a eunuch) take his shoes off
It's Su Peisheng's blessings to serve me
There's more,
there are things His Majesty can say
but you shouldn't say
When His Majesty say we are a family, that's courtesy
When Brother say we are a family, that's overstepping
Brother, you didn't even drink  why are you drunk?
I say Sister
you've stayed in the palace for too long  and you heart has gotten smaller
I was just going along with His Majesty
After all, we are a family
You are his beloved concubine
I am his brother-in-law
aren't we close relatives?
Amitabha, fortunately His Majesty didn't blame you
and even let you escort me back to the palace before returning
I don't think he's mad
What's wrong with you?
Did the Empress do something?
How can the Empress do anything?
It's His Majesty's new Precious Smile who's acting clever
alienating and going against me
It's because of her
His Majesty took away my privileges to rule the inner palace
and never returned it since
A little Precious dare to offend you?
His Majesty favours her, what can I do?
I heard his father is in court too
What is his name?
Zhen Yuandao
Fine
If his daughter is against you
I will be against him
Fortunately there's Brother to watch out for me
If not...If not, how much grievance will I have to endure?
Brother is here, what are you afraid of?
Your Majesty, General Nian is back
Your Majesty
Sit down
I will obey
Great General, please have tea
Your Majesty
I informed you of the grand coordinator Zhao Zhihen
he is not qualified to be the grand coordinator
what do you think
Since you think he is useless
I'll dismiss him
Your majesty is wise
You and I are general and emperor outside, but relatives inside
If I were not a extraordinary emperor
I would disappoint your loyalty
Right
If you were not a extraordinary general
you would disappoint my promoting you
you and I
should set examples in history
I'll do my best
to live up to your majesty's grace
just set back
always thank me
I'm tired with it
Yes, I'll obey
I appreciate your meritorious service
so I reward you a hat with peacock feather
a suit with four dragons
yellow belt, purple rope, and a thousand taels of gold
you must be tired today
just go back and rest
come another day
I
thank your grace
Niangniang
Xiao Xiazi heard it clearly
his majesty called general Nian benefactor
Niangniang
Jianqiu
why does the weather get cold so quickly
because the northwestern wind start to blow
how about I bring you some clothes
the weather is cold, wearing more clothes is of no use
These days, every time his majesty came to the inner palaces
he only went to Princess of Glory
not even set a foot in our Palace of Benevolent Hope
The Palace of Benevolent Hope is always cold
Only his majesty come, it will be warm
But now, it really gets cold
Someday, his majesty think of paying a debt of gratitude
and give the Palace of Benevolent Hope to Princess of Glory
it will be truely warm
Your majesty is always accompanying me recently
why not go and see other sisters
Since you are so generous
then I'll go and see Princess of Regularity
Your majesty
I'm just saying
It is dark outside
you'd better not go out
I know you are grudging
I remember when you just came into Prince's House
I was always accompanying you
somtimes, I even desolated Yixiu, who had just become my legal wife
Before I came into Prince's House
your majesty had spent lots of time with Empress
Empress came into Prince's House early
your majesty should spend more time with me, that will be equal
I also want to spend more time with you
but now I am the emperor of the nation
I have so many affairs to deal with
and there are more people in the inner palaces
I can't desolate all the others only because of you
Saying like this
you must think about others when accompanying me
you are angry with me
before, in the Prince's House, you are my second legal wife
now your are the princess
it's more complicated in the palaces
you should be relieved and look out for me
Empress is physically weak, you should take more responsibility
I know
Sister is so interested in it
you have been working on the Baihe fragrance's recipe
for seven or eight days, but not tired
the night is long and lonely, I have to do something to kill time
His majesty didn't come to see you either
He came and had lunch 6 days ago
then never came again
Sister remembers it so clearly
I can't even remember
about half a month
but I shouldn't complain
I heard Princess of Regularity say
she hasn't seen his majesty since we came back
All the flowers have been killed since autum came
only Princess of Glory is standing out
she is happy about it, we should be happy about our own thing
Sister is feeling sick?
I cought a cold this morning. Just need rest for some days,
It doesn't matter
Actually, the process of making Baihe fragrance has lost
now it is rare even in the palaces
If everything is ready, it will be boring
to kill time, I have to find it myself
Besides, if I can make it
it is the best to use in winter
Put it into stoves
you'll feel like get into the sea of flowers
Yes.
Luckly, before my father became an official, he had been a fragrance merchant for many years
and got many recipes of making fragrance
I have thought it over for a few days
and finally I figured out there are several kinds of perfume that could be useful
Good, you say and I write it down
Your majesty likes listening to Lingering An's singing
I haven't heard her voice for several days
How about asking her to come and sing
so that I can enjoy with your majesty
It's too late, why bother to let her come
Your Majesty!
If you really want, then ask her to come
Zhou Ninghai,
Here
Go and invite
Yes
Sister,you have written all your worries on it
What?
sister is erudite,
why you forgot a part of this wordWhere did that part go
sister's heart has gone with his majesty
and this part also flew away
you're more and more smooth-tongued
I wish that his majesty ask you to go now
then you can be quiet
Who is smooth-tongued
sister is timorous yourself
look at it yourself
Respect to Precious Smile and Lingering An
wish you auspicious
Why is Zhou Gonggong coming
His majesty want to listen to Lingering An's singing
He's waiting at the Palace of Wings
His majesty is with Princess of Glory
What am I if I were there
How about tomorrow
His majesty is waiting right now
If you want to go against the order
you should reply yourself
don't give us servants hard work
Jinxi, bring me my zither
Young mistress
Acapella is monotonous, I'd like to go with Lingering An
and play the zither for his majesty
Will niangniang mind?
Young mistress is willing to play the zither and add to the fun
Niangniang must be pleased
Then, please
Respects to your majesty. Respects to Princess of Glory
Stand up
Thank your Majesty
Precious Smile
it's late at night, why are you here
Thank you for watching this episode with us!
Subtitles brought to you by The Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki