Meimei just came from Princess of Glory's place
and now is going to the Empress's to give my greetings
Not sure if Jie Jie would allow me to go first
Cai Yue, allow Promise Yu to go first
Let's go
She just became a Promise
Who does she think she is?
Talking about a young mistress behind her back.
That's not how you should behave
Your servant will not do it again.
She is favored by the Emperor
The more you gossip, the more trouble you'll get into
Be patient and stay out of trouble. See?
Yes
Let's go
Yesterday at Mother's palace
Ying'er sang "be together forever" very well
I granted her a name
"Lady of an exquisite voice". What do you think, Empress?
She earns it
Your majesty. It's time to flip over a name board
I heard that not every Princess Consort has served you
Lingering Smile has been sick
Lingering Chun is too young
She doesn't understand anything about the world. Is there anyone else?
There is a Promise An
Then I'll go with her.
Young mistress. You are back!
Young mistress. Where did you go?
I couldn't find you. I was so worried!
Where else can I be
I was just visiting Precious Shen
Didn't the Green House keep saying
that hey didn't have these precious flowers?
Why did they sent so many to us today?
Congratulations, young mistress
House of Respecful Affairs has delivered the good news.
Tonight it's you that will serve his majesty
What?
Today is your big day!
His majesty flipped your nameboard
As soon as the news came out,
servants from the Green House came and sent us so many flowers
The Imperial Kitchen also sent us some Ejiao
(a kind of collagen supplements, donkey-hide gelatin)
It's almost time
I'll help you clean up
I thought his majesty didn't even remember me
Don't get nervous, young mistress
His majesty is still reviewing the officials' memos
He will be a little late
In a bit, we will carry you inside
You can lie down and wait for his majesty to come
Young mistress. What's wrong?
Gugu. I'm scared
Don't be afraid
What's wrong?
I, I
I'm not a mean guy
The maids haven't taught you the protocols?
I don't like to force anyone. Another day.
Su Peisheng!
Yes.
Carry her out
Bring Promise Yu Here.
Yes
What the heck. I've never had to do such an ill-boding task.
The consort who was carried in is the exact same as when she's carried out.
It's so late. Who is still singing?
It must be the Lady with an Exquisite Voice
It's not appropriate to sing loudly in the Forbidden City in the middle of the night.
But still
His majesty has been busy with politics
he needs someone lively to serve him.
There is a Precious Shen...
Yes. We met her during the audition.
Modest and prudent
What his majesty needs is someone like her.
The empress will take care of the harem
The Empress Dowager should just enjoy life
The healthy way to live is to not worry
He is my son
The emperor has a huge harem
So long as they do not overstep the boundaries, everything would be fine
Otherwise I must still keep an eye out.
I heard that Meimei knows how to sing Kun Opera
The Emperor really enjoys listening to it
The Emperor is busy handling state affairs everyday
A song from Meimei would most definitely help him relax
No wonder Meimei gains the Emperor's favor
What songs do you know how to sing?
Peony Pavilion. I was taught by my father
Do you know how to sing "Return the jade intact to the Zhao state"? (meaning return something intact to its rightful owner)
That song?
Promise An must sing that herself
So that she can move her audience by telling them her own story
The Empress put so much effort into doing her this favor
Yet she made such a joke out of herself
The Empress must have grown many wrinkles from anger
How could she compare to Niangniang's youth and beauty?
Meimei, your words are really sweet
This jade wheel is from my brother
He sent through others from outside
It is top quality jade
Using it to massage your face could keep you looking young
I'll give it to you
Thanks, Niangniang
Promise An is of a lowborn family and couldn't win the Emperor's favor
Her life is finished
Such a pity
If I were carried out of the Emperor's palace like that
I would not be able to face anyone
Yet she's acting as if nothing happened
Yes
Servants should not discuss the matters of Mistresses
If there is someone
who belittles their mistress
I will report it to the Empress right away
and throw him/her out of palace! Understand?
Yes
I was wrong
Greetings, Precious Shen. Greetings, Lingering Smile.
Jiejie, sit down
Are you OK?
I'm fine. Thanks for your kindness
The next time will be alright.
We still have time in the future.
You two still have a future. I don't.
Young mistress, although it is February
you still need to pay attention to your health.
These days are even colder than in January.
Young mistress has been sewing all day
Hold this stove to keep warm.
It's still cold out,
yet the Internal Affairs Authority doesn't provide enough winter clothes.
We have to work on most of them ourselves.
This morning I followed your order
and brought some cakes to Young mistress An's place.
They were also doing needle work.
They said they're afraid that the money they receive monthly won't be enough
By doing needle work they can ask eunuchs to exchange them for money outside the palace
Both are ranked Promises
Why is Promise Yu living so luxuriously?
Don't gossip behind people's back.
Mei jie jie has already said
The Emperor wants to reduce the expenses in the palace.
which palace isn't doing some needle work to supplement their expenses?
Fortunately, we still have enough to spare
Huan Bi, bring some money to Promise An's place tomorrow.
She'll need to spend more on clothing when spring comes around
Yes.
Who is here this late?
Hurry up and go see.
Young mistress Chun, why are you here alone?
Please hurry come in.
Young mistress, Young mistress Chun comes.
Chun er, what happened?
Don't be scared...
Jie jie, I'm scared.
Bring her some tea.
Don't be scared...
Chun er don't cry...
Drink some milk tea and tell me what happened slowly
Don't cry.
Here.
Just now Lingering Xin and I were going back to our place
There was an unexpected gust of wind and
the lantern that the palace maid was holding caught on fire
and just then, Promise Yu passed by on the carriage
and the fire startled the horse in front of the carriage
and caused some shaking.
But I saw clearly
the palace horse is well trained
the shaking was insignificant.
But Promise Yu wouldn't let it go
Lingering Xin Jiejie wouldn't back down either
Lingering Xin has served the Emperor for a long time.
Her rank is also higher than that of Promise Yu.
She doesn't have to be humble before Promise Yu.
Promise Yu is in the Emporer's favor and has Princess of Glory behind her back
She's been acting aggressive and willful
Xin Jiejie has been unhappy about Promise Yu for some time
They argued and,
Promise Yu, in a fit of anger,
ordered that Xin Jiejie be locked in the Bureau of Cautious Punishment.
The Bureau of Cautious Punishment?
That's where servants who make mistakes are kept and punished
How can Lingering Xin be put in there?
The Emperor and the Empress haven't stepped in yet to take care of the matter?
Promise Yu said
If anyone informs the Emperor or the Empress about this
she would punish the director of the Bureau of Cautious Punishment.
Yu shi is so lawless. What she has done is unheard of.
Jiejie, what to do now?
Don't cry...
Xiao Yun Zi!
I'm here.
I'll let Xiao Yun Zi take you back first
You've been startled, you need to rest well.
Tomorrow I'll discuss with Mei jiejie.
Then ask her to notify the Empress to take further action.
Xiao Yun Zi.
Here.
Escort Lingering Chun back.
Yes.
Poor girl
At such a young age she has to stay in the palace and experience such frightening things
No matter what they are both ranked Lingerings
yet they are bullied by a Promise to this extent!
In the palace, not having the Emperor's favor is so pitiful.
Yu has let her blessings make her arrogant. Singing loudly at night,
and lawlessly putting Lingering Xin into the Bureau of Cautious Punishment at her own will.
In my opinion, this is a good thing.
A good thing?
Precisely
Her sudden favor from the Emperor has already angered many concubines.
And yet she behaves rashly with no decency.
Isn't she digging her own grave?
In this whole palace, only you can be so happy and carefree.
Outside is a chaotic mess
What happened?
The Empress Dowager has given the order
to release Lingering Xin and comfort her
by taking away Promise Yu's title of "Lady of an exquisite voice"
and restricting her to her own quarters to self-reflect for half a month.
The order came from the Empress Dowager?
Yes.
Why didn't the Emperor and the Empress take care of this
but the Empress Dowager instead?
The Emperor is busy with state affairs. He doesn't pay attention to these small things.
The Empress was at the Empress Dowager's palace when they received word of the matter
That's how the matter fell into the Empress Dowager's hands
The Empress Dowager is at once both strict and merciful.
She's using this small punishment for a severe wrongdoing to give her a warning
Yes, though Yu is still a Promise,
she lost her title,
her status is much lower than it was before
My calligraphy is nice and smooth today. (she wrote "Satisfactory")
Keep this one.
Yes.
Yu has been punished. She'll give it a rest for awhile.
Niangniang can do calligraphy smoothly with this peace of mind
The Empress Dowager cares for your wellbeing the most indeed
Promise Yu is at the peak of her favor with the Emperor
If I punish her at this time
the Emperor may request me to be more merciful toward her.
rather than putting myself in a difficult position where I need to compromise my authority or my relationship with the Emperor
the best way is to have the Empress Dowager take care of the matter. No one can question the outcome.
Niang Niang thinks thoroughly.
The weather is so nice now.
Young mistress no longer drinks the medicine as much
Look like your health is improving a great deal
So long as everything is peaceful
it's fine to not drink the medicine
Young mistress has been unwilling to get better
Now that you've finally stopped taking the medicine
you should take a walk under the sun.
This way your appearance can get brighter.
Young mistress said a few days ago that
you wanted to build a swing near the palace gardens outside Palace of Shattered Jade
Xiao Yun Zi has finish building the swing
That area is full of apricot flowers.
Why don't the young mistress go take a look?
"Sitting in the shade of apricot flowers, playing the flute until dawn"
You two insist on me going outside, huh?
Then let's go.
Liuzhu
Bring me my flute.
Hurry!
Who are you, royal sir?
Can you guess?
Is it possible that you are Emperor?
You are a Duke?
Have you heard of the Duke of Fruit (17th prince)?
Are you really the Duke of Fruit?
Have you ever seen..me?
Since I entered the palace,
I have never even seen the Emperor.
Then how can you know that I'm not the Duke of Fruit?
It seems that age doesn't quite match.
A person's age and appearance are often inconsistent.
If you say so.
I am a Lingering from the House of Zhen. Greetings, Duke.
You are the Lingering who has been sick?
How can Your Highness know the affairs of the Inner Palace?
I heard...from my royal sister-in-law (the Empress).
On New Year's Eve
His Majesty asked about you. I was present.
I see.
Are you feeling better?
Why don't you put on warmer clothing?
You are too kind
I am much better now.
Liuzhu, this is the Duke of Fruit.
Greetings, Duke.
Just now you played the piece "Heaven Image of Apricot Flowers"
It suits the surroundings very well.
Are you very familiar with this piece?
If you use a clay flute to play it in the evening of spring
the song will be even more charming.
By using the vertical flute to play just now
you have lessened the melancholy of the song
and have added some liveliness that takes away the winter wind.
I'm still lacking in skill. I hope the Duke will forgive the flaws.
You play very well.
But when you reached the line that sings
"the beautiful blossoms by the shore makes me unwilling to depart "
the sound of the flute became somber
sounding much like a suppressed sob
Is it that you are missing your home?
"The musician plays a subtle mistake, and Sir Zhou is aware"
The Duke's music ears are even better than that of Zhou Gong Jin (famous general and musician during Han Dynasty).
I haven't heard such beautiful flute music in a very long time
Not since..Empress Chun Yuan passed away
Never since then have I heard such beautiful music
I dare not accept such praise
I dare not compete with Empress Zhun Yuan.
I shall head back to my quarters now.
Please do as you wish.
Ok.
Young mistress, you are back.
Pei'er
Find out for me
if the Duke of Fruit came to the palace today or not.
Yes.
Young mistress is worried
that the person discussing flute music with you just now is not the Duke of Fruit?
What do you think?
It's best to be cautious.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Rise
Thank you.
Why did you come so early?
Your Majesty had people inform me early this morning
that you have an original artwork by Wu Dao Zi
I couldn't wait to see
so I came here immediately
No need to hurry. The painting cannot run away.
Oh, but you see, famous paintings are like beautiful women.
I cannot be late, even if it's just a second.
If you love beauty that much, why haven't you married yet?
I was planning to get married,
but just now at the door of your palace
I saw a pretty girl raining flower blossoms (crying)
and that was enough to frighten me out of my marriage plans
- Su Pei Sheng.
- Your Majesty.
Yu is here?
In response to Your Majesty, Promise Yu came early morning
crying, asking to see Your Majesty.
I informed her that the Emperor was not here.
She cried for a long while before she left
Just ignore her.
Yes.
By the way,
I remember there is a wonderful jade vertical flute
You find it for me.
Yes.
Where did you go, Royal brother?
I went to visit the Empress Dowager
and passed by the royal garden on the way back so I took a walk by myself.
unintentionally leaving you here to listen to a woman crying.
Love at first sight in the Garden of Winter Plums.
How does my Royal brother like this girl from the Yu family?
So So
Not as gentle and charming as that night
in the Garden of Winter Plums
Which is why they say, it's better to miss one another than to actually meet
Come, let's go appreciate the painting.
In response to young mistress, the Duke of Fruit did come to the palace early today.
Now he is appreciating a painting with the Emperor in the Hall of a Resting Soul.
I heard that the Duke looks very stoic...
and nearly 40 years old?
Not at all
The Duke was born in the 35th year of Kangxi's reign.
He should be around 25 or 26 years old now.
A Duke who is around 40 years old...
That must be the Duke of Perseverance (Duke of Heng)
He is down to earth
and loves to joke with us servants
How about His Majesty?
I don't know.
His Majesty rarely comes to the Harem.
When he does come there are a lot of people surrounding him
My status is lowly so I can't see His Majesty.
You're right. No matter where His Majesty goes,
there are a lot of people who follow him .
You can leave. I'm tired.
Yes.
I sympathize with what has befallen Meimei.
But this was the Empress Dowager's decree.
Even His Majesty can't do anything.
I have served in the palace since I was young.
I know that the Empress Dowager has a soft temper and is gracious to all.
She never gets involved in palace affairs
But why does the Empress Dowager not let go
of a small mistake I made
There must be someone instigating her anger.
Whether that's true or not
at least your half month restriction has passed.
The Empress Dowager cannot say any more regarding this matter
But... but His Majesty still refuses to see me.
That's true... and if this continues
I fear His Majesty will probably forget you.
Niang Niang, please save me.
I don't want to live isolated in the deep palace
I don't want to go back to the Garden of Winter Plums
and slave away at others' wills
Niang Niang, please!
Yes.
Since the person you want to see is His Majesty
If he refuses, Meimei should naturally
find other solutions so that he does not refuse.
"It's harder to be cold and detached when you look someone in the eye"
His Majesty won't be heartless toward you when you see him.
But... but I don't know what to do...
Do what you are good at.
Niang Niang, thank you for your advice.
Songzhi, escort Promise Yu out.
Yes. Promise Yu, this way.
Niang Niang,
This Promise Yu had gotten much attention from the Emperor
Without her, you would have one less person to compete with
Why help her?
It was the Empress Dowager who punished her, not the Emperor
If one day the Emperor thinks of her again
better that she is indebted to me
so that she will follow me without question
and help me split the Emperor's love away from Precious Shen
Niang Niang, this Precious Shen has just entered the palace not so long ago
She doesn't have stable footing here yet.
Niang Niang, I think perhaps you need not worry so much
Yes, she JUST entered the palace
and already she has somehow gotten the Emperor to allow her to learn how to manage the Inner Palace.
This is what makes me worry the most
Stop. You are all to go back to the Hall of a Resting Soul.
I'll take a walk by myself
Your Majesty, her Empress Dowager has just commanded me
to serve you attentively
If I don't go with you
then aren't I digging my own grave?
You are digging your own grave right now.
Uh...Lower the palanquin.
Don't mention this to anyone.
Yes
Go
Higher?
A little
I knew you'd be scared
Later I'll push you
Alright! I am not afraid of anything.
Liuzhu! You dare to play tricks behind my back
Your Highness...
If you're scared, step down
I'm not scared. You can push as you like
Higher!
Go higher!
Young mistress!
Greetings, Duke.
Young mistress, are you Ok?
Why are you shy now?
Were you not a brave heroine just a second ago?
I was improper.
I had not known that the Duke enjoys silently spying on people from behind.
Ah. You are blaming ME for being improper.
I was just passing by
and remembered Lingering's flute piece from that day
I hoped to run into you here again so that I might enjoy that beautiful music once more
But I did not bring my flute with me today
Then I can only wait for next time
This area is full of apricot blossoms.
Your piece from last time was also about apricot blossoms
Do you like apricot blossoms very much?
Apricot blossoms are not as vibrant as peach blossoms
nor as lofty as winter plum blossoms
they are particularly warm and serene
People are like flowers, just as flowers are comparable to people.
Only those who are warm and serene
would like warm and serene flowers
But I don't actually like apricot blossoms
Oh? Do tell.
Apricot blossoms are beautiful, yes, but the fruit is very sour.
what's more, it's kernal is extremely bitter.
if a person's character and life experiences are all beautiful in its beginnings but meet a tragic and downtrodden end
then what is the purpose?
if that were the case, i'd rather choose to be a pine or cypress
an evergreen tree that stays constant, despite being without blossoms and without fruits.
I've never heard of such insights
It is rather new and thoughtful
I spoke merely nonsense, apologies for my silliness.
I've disturbed you today.
I have two flute scores
five days later, at the same hour
I will take them here to appreciate them with you
I do hope Lingering will come to meet me.
"Obedience is better than politeness." (she agrees)
I have one request that I hope the Duke can agree to.
Go on
It's inappropriate for me to have met you like this.
please don't let others know.
To avoid damaging each other's unpolluted reputation.
Since it's a fact that our reputations are unpolluted,
who can damage it?
Your highness may not be aware
You and I are upright and honest
But in the Harem,
the more mouths, the more gossip.
I don't want to stir up trouble without cause.
Okay.
Thank you, Duke.
Who is on the outside?
There is no one.
Young mistress, is everything alright?
He and I are separated by our status.
How can he possibly be my soul mate?
Young mistress, you must be tired from reading.
Why don't you rest for a while?
Ugh, the paint on this table has come off too.
but Internal Affairs Authority doesn't bother to come repair it.
Xiao Yun Zi went to address this issue a few days ago.
I imagine they will come repair it in a few days
Your Majesty, please take a break.
Your Majesty, why did you stop playing?
I had been listening with respectful attention.
I don't play very well and so should stop playing.
The flute music of Empress Chun Yuan was the best in the Palace.
and now there is someone who plays just as well as her
Your Majesty means the 17th Duke?
17th Duke is best at playing the (horizontal) flute.
Su Pei Sheng.
Yes.
Go to ask 17th brother to come.
You were gone an entire afternoon,
why do you look so unfortunate?
I went to the Internal Affairs Authority,
and got a lot of mocking words for no reason.
We're just asking them to fix a table
not like we're requesting them for our monthly salary
how come we've gone so many times and still no success?
Princess of Glory has the upper hand in the palace
her followers, those dogs who do nothing but bully the weak
have made it a point to target the Palace of Shattered Jade
It's fine that they mock me
but they even insult the young mistress
and she has to unfairly bear the grunt of those ugly words
Those bastards in the Internal Affairs Authority dare to be so lawless?
In the winter they don't give us our goal
Now they don't even come to repair a table corner
shhhh...the young mistress is inside
if she hears you it will make her sad
What shall we do? we have a long time ahead of us...
Us servants can make do
But my young mistress...
young mistress, how can she bear this unfair treatment?
This Huang Gui Quan (eunuch in charge of Internal Affairs) relies on the fact that he's a distant relative of Princess of Glory
all he does is bully people!
my dear lady, my dear lady
please calm down and lower your voice
If the Internal Affairs Authority is busy, let's just make do with this table
it's not a big deal anyway
Yes
regarding what just happened, neither of us heard anything.
don't scold them a word
yes
Serving a young mistress like me
has truly caused you guys much pain
Young mistress, why say such a thing?
your servant dare not make you feel this way
I have never thought that serving you
has wronged me or caused me grief
In the Harem, flocking to the side of powerful people is a normal act
of course they wouldn't take a sickly consort with no favor from the Emperor seriously
My Royal brother must have heard beautiful flute music somewhere
to make you so obsessed with flute music all of a sudden
These days you've already listen to all of the court musicians
who can play a flute.
"like scratching an itchy foot when you are wearing boots" it cannot be compared, and cannot satiate my desire.
Is it that difficult for you to hear this person play again for you?
Can I ask...who this beauty might be?
You are too clever.
Promise Yu, the Emperor and the Duke are inside
and won't see any consorts.
Every time I come
you tell me that His Majesty is with the Duke
do you think I am that easy to lie to?
your servant speaks the truth
If young mistress won't believe me
I cannot do anything about it
Then Xia Gong Gong, please go announce me one more time
I've already informed young mistress,
The Emperor is with the Duke
and has commanded that he will see no consorts
what's the purpose of just making things difficult for us servants?
"Wake up from the dream by the chirrup of orioles"
"The spring sceneries pluck at the heartstrings everywhere."
I heard that Promise Yu knelt in front of the Hall of a Resting Soul for nearly the entire night.
That's why the heart of His Majesty became soft.
It's not because of kneeling but because of singing.
I heard that she's nearly lost her voice from singing all night.
Regardless, she has gained the Emperor's favor again.
Look at the airs she's giving herself.
We were the same palace maids once
she sings one song, and suddenly she's a mistress
and us?
we have to endure bullying and mocking just to
receive our monthly salary that is rightfully ours
We are all people but have different destinies. On that note,
Yu isn't even as pretty as you are, sister Huanbi.
Don't talk nonsense
Xiao Xia Zi, come here
young mistress, what can I do for you?
Since you're not doing anything, crack these walnut for me
Yes
Use your bare hands
In response to young mistress, the walnut's shell is too hard
I'm afraid even if I destroy my hands, I still cannot crack it
Are you being lazy?
Aren't you always the most loyal to His Majesty?
If the Emperor wants to eat walnuts
So what if you ruin your hands?
Xiao Xia Zi, what time is it?
It's 1:30 p.m, Your Majesty.
Fool! Why didn't you wake me?
But, Your Majesty, you normally always sleep until this hour
Slap yourself
Clothes, clothes
Your Majesty
You really are a fool
you had been so focused on cracking walnut for His Majesty to enjoy
you forgot the time His Majesty needs to gets up
look at all the blood on your hands!
how can you do your job later?
Alright alright, forget the walnuts, take your leave.
Yes
Go, go, go
I'll take a walk
Your Majesty, it's raining outside
If it's not, then what would be the purpose of the term "appreciating the rain"?
You! Go back to your place.
Your Majesty
Stop
Your Majesty,
Empress Dowager ask you to go to Palace of Health.
Thank you for watching!
Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team