Niangniang, Fuzi is already dead.
Dead?
How could she be dead?
When did this happen?
She was just retrieved from a well.
Her body is badly swollen.
You are in Niangniang's presence. How could you speak so freely of such things?
No matter.
It must have been the day you scolded her.
She ran out crying.
She was not watching her steps, so she must have fallen accidentally into the well.
So, it's my fault then?
That can't be,
it's all Fuzi's fault for having such a bad temper.
How can any servant not get an occasional scolding,
don't you agree, Jiang Fuhai?
This...your servant dare not comment.
What do you mean "I don't dare"?
If you won't believe me, then feel free to ask anyone serving at Yi Kun Gong (Palace of Wings).
Everyone saw her run out by herself.
Do you mean, Gonggong...
that someone pushed her from behind?
I would never dare to make such an assumption.
There is nothing you won't dare to do.
If you don't believe me,
then cross examine every single person from my palace.
Niangniang, it has not come to that.
But let me make one thing clear,
you came today by order of the Empress.
You asked what you had to ask, I answered,
and have witnesses to support my answer.
If you want to take anyone into custody, be my guest.
Otherwise, if you dare to bother me about this matter again,
don't expect me to be generous.
Excuse me, my Lady
Remember, all of you, this is what happened.
Fuzi ran out on her own free will
She misstepped and fell into the well, where she drowned.
Yes.
It smells so good. my lady.
Young Mistress had a bad fright yesterday,
she didn't have an appetite at lunch nor dinner yesterday.
At least eat something this morning?
It would be alright if it was only a one-time shock,
I'm only afraid that I will have to live with similar horrors from now on.
Why?
Xia Changzai picked a fight with us,
Meizhuang and I have evidently made many enemies.
Hua Fei is forceful, her methods are cruel.
Being so surrounded by enemies,
I fear for not only my own safety,
but once I make one wrong move
I fear that my whole clan will have to suffer for it.
What should we do?
I don't know yet.
Young Mistress, do you remember when we
made osmanthus candy at home?
These osmanthus are blooming beautifully,
How about I make some candies with them?
What do you say?
Your culinary skills are impeccable,
I will eat some if you make any
Okay!
I'll go get some help!
Pei Er, what are you looking at that's so interesting?
Look Young Mistress, the ants are moving in a weird pattern.
The ants are avoiding the tree root,
as if they are afraid.
Well I think the ants are just stupid,
taking the far way.
Xiao Yun zi, come here.
Dig up the spot where all the ants are avoiding.
What is this. Buried so deeply
Mistress, there is a jar here.
- Dig it up, let's have a look.
What is it?
Pull harder.
Here. Let me see.
Back off.
This jar is very odd, it has a strong fragrance.
Sui Yu Xuan used to be Fang Guiren's residence,
after her miscarriage she was banished to the Cold Palace.
But she still enjoyed His Majesty's adoration once,
what if there's some kind of rare perfume in it?
Our mistress likes perfumes, why not open it up and see?
Open it!
Let me see.
Open it up.
What is it? Such an irritating smell!
It stinks!
It's nothing but some cheap spices.
Huanbi, cover it up
You all are to keep your mouths shut
about what we dug up today.
We don't need any idle gossip.
Yes, yes.
Make the osmanthus candy tomorrow instead.
You can all go!
Go back to your duties.
Huanbi. Let's go inside
Take it away
Mistress, what's going on?
Why do you so pale?
I feel very unsettled.
Huanbi, go find Docter Wen, ask him to come see me.
Remember, it has to be Docter Wen.
- Okay.
Docter Wen. I'm glad you are here.
My mistress does not feel well
can you please check on her?
Is she all right?
Either way, she insisted on asking you to take a look.
Please hurry.
Young Mistress, you seem to have had a very serious fright?
I saw something I shouldn't have seen.
Then you have to find a way to forget about what you saw.
That day, what you said outside the Palace,
do you still stand by your promise?
Of course. I will forever place you above everything else.
"Forever"...is easily said,
but...not so easily done.
I know I don't have many merits,
but I always do my best to keep my word.
I will forever remember the debt owed to the Zhen family by my father.
Young Mistress, command me as you will.
I don't want to serve His Majesty in bed.
I don't want that to happen either,
but Young Mistress is already in the Harem,
sooner or later you will need to accompany His Majesty in slumber.
It would be advisable, for the sake of your future,
that you do so as early as possible.
But I can't help but be afraid,
if I serve him right now...
Docter Wen, I have something to show you.
Why do you have this Young Mistress?
The cherry-apple tree in Sui Yu Xuan.
Flowers have not bloomed this spring.
I dug that up from under the tree today by chance.
The Fang Guiren who used to live here had an unexplained miscarriage,
I suppose the real cause is that, or something like it.
It's apparent how much scheming goes around in this Harem.
Fang Guiren most likely doesn't know, even now, just what caused her downfall.
It's fortunate that you discovered this early,
otherwise, all the ladies who live in Sui Yu Xuan would have suffered the consequences.
I know I don't have the privilege of being your companion for life,
but if I can protect and keep you safe through the years,
then it is another way to honor my promise to you.
Is my condition serious?
Fear is the reason for your high temperature,
you must first calm your nerves.
If treated with care, you can recover in half a month.
But if you would like to be...extra cautious with your recovery,
then I will prescribe something that will allow you more time to make a recovery.
This kernel of musk is the strongest component of musk.
It would be best for Young Mistress to have no contact with it.
Let me take it instead,
I will use it as medicine, so that atonement can be found for the life that it took.
Doctor Wen. I am so scared.
Don't be.
Liuzhu, see Docter Wen out.
Wan Changzai has fallen sick? She was fine yesterday.
Wan Changzai is under an evil influence which,
combined with stress from a serious shock, has induced flu symptoms.
A shock?
Yes, she has suffered an excessive fright.
Right now she has a fever, and keeps muttering unintelligibly.
If that's the case then Chun Changzai should move away from Sui Yu Xuan for the time being,
to avoid the disease.
Yes. It's a dangerous season right now.
Wan Changzai's illness is caused by both internal and external factors,
I fear that should the other Young Mistresses be infected...
Then...
- So let Chun Changzai move.
Since you diagnosed Wan Changzai
and since she won't make a full recovery for quite a while,
why don't you continue tending to her illness.
I will do my best.
Starting today the new concubines will be available to serve Your Majesty,
do you still plan to visit Hua Fei's palace?
Are you prying into my thoughts?
I don't dare to pry into your thoughts.
Please flip a nameboard instead.
Please flip a nameboard over, Your Majesty
Where is Wan Changzai's nameboard?
To reply to your inquiry
this afternoon, the Royal Clinic sent someone to report
that Wan Changzai has had a serious shock,
which triggered the flu.
She needs to rest to make a recovery.
A shock?
Hua Fei gave Xia Changzai A Zhang of Redness
in front of Shen Guiren, Wan Changzai, and An Guiren.
Xia Changzai is already...paralyzed from the waist down.
What did she do?
Xia Changzai disrespectful etiquette,
she intended to hit another concubine.
But still, Hua Fei was too harsh.
She meant to use violence in the Palace, that needs to be punished.
Pay no more heed to her.
One of Hua Fei's servants, Fuzi, was found inexplicably dead in a well.
Wan Changzai chanced upon the event and saw the body.
Inexplicably?
What did Hua Fei say?
She said it was an accident,
but Jiang Fuhai thinks that there is something amiss.
Maids are at least from families belonging to the Eight Banners.
Hua Fei...
Look into this case.
-Yes
Wan Changzai is sick
but Shen Guiren and An Daying are still healthy.
Congratulations Shen Guiren.
Tonight, his majesty flipped your nameboard
You are the first one,
Among all the new young mistresses
Thank you, Gong gong. Cai Yue.
Thank you Gong Gong. You don't have to thank me
Young mistress, please get ready
for His Majesty's visit.
But... What should I...
Oh yes. This here is Liu Momo
She,
Will tell you what you should do.
Later, the Grace Carriage will come here to pick you up
and drop you off at the Hall of a Resting Soul.
Young mistress, take care!
Excuse me
Good bye, Gonggong.
Your Majesty, Shen Guiren is here.
Carry her in
Your Majesty.
His Majesty learnt that you like chrysanthemums so he sent you all of these.
He really has you on his mind.
What other flowers are there during the fall?
You are thinking too much.
It's true. You are His Majesty's favorite.
It's been a month since new mistresses entered the Harem,
His Majesty hasn't visited any of the new Daying,
and He is indifferent to the rest of the new Young Mistresses.
But he really likes you.
Not only has He summoned you the most at night,
He has also given you the most rewards.
What are you saying in broad daylight!
The white ones are Snow on a Sunny Spring Day,
The yellow ones are called Dragon Above the Clouds.
And that one, two blossoms on the same stem.
Just like His Majesty and Young Mistress!
You naughty girl.
The Emperor arrives!
Greetings, Your Majesty.
What were you talking about? Laughing so merrily.
Let me hear it too.
-Rise.
-Thank you, Your Majesty.
Do you like the flowers?
Yesterday I passed by the greenhouse and saw them in full bloom
so I told them to send you some.
I like them very much. Thank you, Your Majesty.
Replying to Your Majesty's inquiry, our Young Mistress really likes chrysanthemums.
So she's especially grateful for them Your Majesty.
I can see that. Your dress also has chrysanthemums embroidered on it.
Why do you like them?
They would rather die on the stem with scent still intact,
than be blown away into the sky by cold winds.
I like them because they symbolize honor and integrity.
You are well read.
I did not mean to show off Your Majesty, please forgive my slip.
I like that you are well read, knowledge can impart sense.
Chrysanthemums are symbols of honor and integrity,
but the reason I like them is because they alone belong to the fall.
They do not vie for attention like the others.
Only by enduring loneliness, can someone enjoy constancy.
Thanks for your advice.
If you like them,
I will ask them to pick out the most beautiful ones for your palace.
I heard there are green chrysanthemums in the greenhouse right now,
they took quite a while to cultivate.
You can have all of them.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
The name of your residence...
(Chang Xi Tang; Hall of Perpetual Luminance)
sounds like the name of an old schoolroom, not an ounce of romance.
Since you like chrysanthemums,
let it be called Cun Ju Tang (Hall where Chrysanthemums are stored).
I came today because I have a plan to share with you.
I want you to start learning about household management.
Some small, troublesome details,
notice them, give them some thought.
Learn as much as you can.
But I don't know any of these things.
Then you should try to learn.
You are smart. And you always consider the general interest.
I know that and I like it.
That's why I came here to remind you.
Managing the Harem is just like managing a family.
Pay more attention. And then you will learn how to do it gradually
Yes. I would love to give it a try
That's it.
As long as you put time and effort in it. everything will be easy to learn
Empress always feel sick.
Hua Fei is aggressive and impatient.
What I like about you is you are composed.
Learn more.
Then you can help me manage the Harem
Young mistress, Jianqiu Gugu is here.
Jianqiu saluting to you, Young Mistress.
Don't move.
Gugu, what brings you here.
How would I deserve your visit.
The Empress heard that
the Young Mistress is still unwell.
She is really worried
so she sent me to check on you.
Many thanks for the Empress's concern.
Why is the Young Mistress so skinny?
What did the Imperial Physician say?
Young Mistress, it's time for your medicine.
Young Mistress.
Our Young Mistress is frail, and she had a big scare.
She drinks the Imperial Physician's medicine three times a day,
but she is not getting any better.
The sickness of the body is easily cured,
but the sickness of the heart needs medicines for the heart.
Also, Xia Changzai's legs are now crippled.
The Imperial Physician said that she will live,
but she can no longer walk.
Hua Fei said that her living in the Palace of Lasting Fortune is now an inconvenience.
So she was moved to the Cold Palace.
It's a pity,
but it's her fault for not meeting the expectations
and also for harming you, Young Mistress.
I was cowardly. It was not Xia Changzai's fault.
Of course it was not Xia Changzai's fault.
But it is an unfortunate time for you to fall ill, Young Mistress.
Now Shen Guiren has an advantage.
She got the favour first.
I have no fortune,
unlike Shen Guiren.
It's my fault,
If I make Niang Niang worried
Please rest.
I'm returning to Palace of Benelovent Hope
I will visit you sometime in the future
Kang GongGong
Please walk gugu out.
Excuse me
That Wan Changzai is so beautiful.
But I didn't expect her to be such a coward
She only has a pretty face
She hasn't been in the Harem for a long time. She already saw that bloody scene
How can she not be afraid?
But that An Daying... she seems weak, but even after seeing that, she still seems fine.
You too have witnessed so many things that Hua Fei has done.
The other day she came here to say greetings.
Although you are the biological mother of 3rd Prince.
You still need to greet here first
Empress, are you blaming me for being a coward?
But his majesty is not fond of 3rd Prince
He also does not like me.
I am also old.
How can I compare with Hua Fei? She is young and beautiful. She also has the Nian family supporting her.
You should consider the future
At least you have a Prince.
My 1st Prince and Empress of Purity's 2rd Prince died early.
3rd Prince is the eldest son.
Your standing is much more higher than Glory who hasn't given birth to any child.
But...
But, the Emperor doesn't like 3rd Prince.
If His majesty doesn't like him, you need to find a way to fix it.
You are such a cowardly mother
No wonder 3rd Prince is not making any progress
His majesty hasn't stepped into my palace
for months already
Niang niang, look.
Although Imperial Garden has chrysanthemums all over the place.
But they are not as charming as those in our Palace of Wings.
Of course. Different places have different aura that will nurture different characters.
The niang niang in our palace is the most beautiful
Of course flowers there is the most beautiful
Did you put honey on your mouth? Full of sweet lies.
How would I say such disrespectful words
I made niang niang unhappy again
But Niang Niang, what I said is true.
Niang niang. Look at those chrysanthemums
In my lifetime,
I haven't seen any green chrysanthemums
It's indeed very special
Look. The guys from the green house is in a hustle.
They are definitely for our palace.
Since they are for me.
Then stop them
Let's take a closer look.
You all come over.
Greetings, Princess of Glory
- Rise
Why did you walk so slowly?
Is this green chrysanthemum so precious that you are unable to lift your legs?
It is hard work for you to have bred such a precious flower
Put it here
Princess of Glory,
The Chrysanthemums...
- speak if you have something to say
Is for Hall of Chrysanthemums
Then bring them there.
Princess Glory, pleae forgive me! Princess Glory, please forgive me!
Niang niang, forgive me! Niang niang, forgive me!
Slap yourself
It's all my fault! It's all my fault! It's all my fault!
Hall of Chrysanthemums
My lady, this sign is very pretty.
His majesty said he was going to change it, and changed it immediately.
He really has your ladyship on his mind.
Don't say things like this out loud.
People will laugh if they hear it.
Move quickly
It has taken so long to move a couple pots of flowers
From now on there will be no chrysanthemum in this palace
Quickly! Move them out!
It's still early to say greetings.
My lady, walk slowly
My bones are so stiff from sitting in the sedan chair
It's more comfortable to walk around like this
What's wrong with you? You dare to startle the lady!
I'm delivering water to House of Respectful Affairs.
I didn't mean to offend young mistress on purpose
All right, Cai Yue
Come home with me to change my clothes
Otherwise, we will be late.
Precious Shen is so early today
I am late for the greetings.
Please forgive me.
Greetings is about sincerity
Being late once in a while is not a big deal
Thank you, Niang Niang.
Give her a seat
Empress Niang Niang is as tolerative as always.
But I'm afraid your tolerance will spoil Precious Shen
and undermine the rules in the Harem
That's so right.
Don't take my words seriously,
But from now on, we can be absent from greetings to Empress
If we claim that we are sincere enough?
Replying to your words, Empress Niang Niang
We are not coming late on purpose
On our way here, an eunuch got our dresses dirty.
We have no choice but to go back to change.
Whether you are doing on purpose or not,
What you did is wrong. You should take responsibility for your own actions
Empress Niang Niang, although what Precious Shen did was wrong
But she is always cautious and dilegent in serving you.
Please forgive her this time
Pin of Respects is the main concubine of Palace of Whole Blessings
You are also responsible for Precious Shen's actions.
Let's not get other matters involved.
Meimei, what do you suggest I should do to her?
Shen Guiren has been arrogant and disrespected the Empress.
She should be flogged thirty times.
But I think we should be more flexible when executing the laws.
Since it's her first offence.
We should take 2-month stipend away as a token of penalty.
Pin of Respects is also responsible. Same penalty will be extended to her.
What do you think, Empress Niangniang
I admitted for being at fault.
But this has nothing to do with Pin of Respects.
Please reconsider.
Since Princess of Glory has made the decision for me.
I agreed. Only a little penalty is enough.
It's 2 months away from new year.
It is not convenient that they got stipends suspended.
1 month is enough.
Thank you, Empress Niangniang
I will keep this in mind. This will never happen again.
Rise.
Thank you, Empress Niangniang
You all must be tired. Go back to your palaces.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, then.
Actually we don't have to get into this matter so seriously
Then what do you think?
I see you as my sister.
As you always dedicated in serving me.
So I never cared whether you come early or late
You think I am embarassing Precious Shen.
You are always generous
However the palace is different from the prince's mansion.
Because the Emperor knew that you were generous
He asked me to help manage the harem
This way my strict way and your gentle way could balance out
If I do not act this way
Then I would be unworthy of the trust that the Emperor placed on me
The Emperor asked Meimei to manage the harem.
Because he believed that Meimei would be the role model of the harem
Therefore in the future
when Meimei come to my palace to show respect
Please come earlier
I will remember that.
However there are times that the Emperor treasures me
and insists that I not wake up early.
So I ask Niang Niang
At that time, who should I listen to?
Both you and I are the Emperor's women
Of course we will all listen to the Emeperor
Thanks for the Empress's clarification
Excuse me, then
I have something to tell Niang Niang
Speak
Fuzi was hit first and lose consciousness
then she was thrown into the well
For real?
There were scars for proof
There were severe damage to Fuzi's neck and head
Also on that day someone saw
the Emperor spoke to Fuzi in the Palace of Wings
The princess of glory became very upset right away
The princess of glory became more and more presumptuous
You tell the whole story truthfully to the Emperor
Yes
Bring me the general journals of House of Respectful Affairs.
Zhou Gonggong has brought it here.
This month, Precious Shen serves his majesty's night twice.
So did Precious Fucha.
Quite often
Not that often compared to you.
But his majesty only visited the Harem seven times
We should plan ahead.
Otherwise when they got arrogant in the future,
I can't control them anymore.
His majesty values the harmony between Han and Man.
Ask Precious Fucha to come here.
I will give her a good lesson.
Yes.
Precious Fucha.
His majesty often says, Man and Han are families.
You should know Han Chinese when serving his majesty
When he is writing something
You should be grinding the ink.
It's hard to grind ink.
You've got to spend more time practising.
Yes.
What I have told you can benefit you.
You think grinding for 2 hours is enough?
You still need more practice
Robzandanzing Tribe in Qinghai has risen in rebellation
Northwestern China is politically unstable.
Zhang Tingyu!
Who do you recommend that can be sent to pacify the rebels.
I think, when talking about military talent and trustworthiness,
Only one man is suitable
Nian Geng Yao
How insightful you are.
It's less than a year since youre enthroned
8th and 9th Prince's gang has not been eradicated.
Nian Gengyao is the elder brother of Princess of Glory.
He is in charge of Northwestern military affairs for many years.
That's why I think,
Nian Gengyao is the best choice.
Nian Gengyao indeed contributed a lot to my enthronement.
But now he seems to have autocracy in Northwestern China.
Yue Zhongqi, Left military governer, is the 21st descendant of Yue Fei (A famous general in history)
He is also familiar with Northwestern affairs.
People call him A General that never Loses.
He is cautious and smart. Why don't we...?
Then I will appoint Nian Gengyao
to General of Expedition.
Yue Zhongqi to General of Courage and Efforts. Also he will act as consultant for Nian Gengyao
Send them to Qinghai to pacify the rebels.
We will follow your orders.
Zhou Ninghai from Palace of Wings brought some dim sums to you.
They are from Princess of Glory.
They invite you to taste some.
Let him leave the dim sums here.
Yes.
I remembered that General of Jilin pay tributes to me and send me a pot of East Pearl.
Take it to Princess of Glory in person.
Tell her that it is a reward for her assistance in managing the Harem
Yes
It's late. Please go to bed.
I'm not sleepy at all
It's rare that you are so energetic
not sleepy at all
Ever since you fell ill,
except for Precious Shen, Promise An and Lingering Chun,
Nobody came here to visit you.
These few days,
I know that the servants and eunuchs are lazy.
I only asked them to do something trival,
even Little Yinzi dare to bicker with me.
It's understandable
We can't force them to do things they don't want to do.
Yes
Listen. Somebody is crying.
It's little Yunzi.
It's his night shift.
Let's go to see him
Why are you crying so sadly?
Sorry to bother you. Please forgive me.
Everyone has unhappy moments.
It's not a crime to be sad.
But tell me the reason
My elder brother is working for Imperial Warehouse.
He has been sick for over a month and does not get any better.
That's why I'm sad.
Everyone of us can be sick from time to time
Since I don't have anything to do these days.
You can go to attend your brother.
Thank you, young mistress.
Young mistress, it's getting cold.
Let's go back inside.
It's late. You can go to your room
Yes
Your majesty is tired because of the state affairs.
I asked them to make cubilose with lotus seeds.
It's nourishing and clearing.
Please have some
Thank you for this.
Fuzi's death has been reported to you by Jiang Fuhai.
Ladies in the Harem always get jealousy over little things.
I don't have a solution to it. Please tell me what to do.
I know who you are talking about.
Ladies get jealousy all the time.
But if they don't love me,
there won't be any problem
I don't want to blame them for loving me.
You should have more patience.
Yes
cubilose can moisterize the lungs.
It's winter. You should eat something more nourishing.
Thank your for your concern
How is Lingering Smile doing?
Docter Wen is known for his brilliant medical skills.
It's just Lingering Smile is still not getting any better.
But it takes time to recover from any diseases.
According to the doctor,
Lingering Smile doesn't have enough Chi. She is very week.
It takes time to build up her health.
Then tell her to be patient. Take good rest and nourishment.
Yes
Look at you.
Who do you want to impress with that upset face.
Shifu, look at Lingering Smile. (Shifu = teacher)
As a servant
Why servants of other Consorts can be so proud.
we are such a loss of face.
You think I am proud of myself?
Little Youzi from Precious Fucha,
Only because his majesty likes his mistress. He dare to call me his brother.
He should look into the mirror,
Who the hell does he thinks he is.
It's young mistress's fault.
It's been two months. She is still not getting any better.
I heard Doctor Wen said,
Maybe she still needs more time to recover.
Maybe it's pulmonary tuberculosis
Don't say that.
I think Young mistress,
can't have adoration even though she recoverd. Since the illness has destroyed her face
We became the servants of the servants all because of her.
Palace of Shattered Jade is such an unlucky palace.
It used to have Fang Guiren.
Now it's the unhealthy Wan Changzai.
No. We can't go under with her.
Please tell me what to do, Shifu,
Be smart.
Shifu, it's your shift today.
She is sick so she doesn't get around.
nothing can happen even if I am not on duty
But we should plan ahead.
about transfering to other young mistress's place.
Young mistress wants a cup of hot tea.
What takes you so long.
If she wants a cup of tea.
I need to start a fire and boil the water.
Tell her to wait a little longer.
One more thing, this month Internal Affairs Authority
hasn't delivered young mistress's regular tea.
She can only drink water then
Yesterday I saw you were drinking tea.
Why young mistress can't drink any tea?
Did you drink all the tea?
We are in the Harem
It takes proof and evidence to accuse me of anything
You think you are still in your maiden home?
Peier,
Liuzhu is the close servant of young mistress.
You have been in the forbidden city for a long time. Why you still don't behave like you are supposed to.
Boil the water as soon as possible.
If we ran out of tea, go pick some up in Internal Affairs Authority.
Lingering won't get any better.
Since Pin of Beauty likes you.
Please take me with you.
Gonggong has found a better place to go.
Why don't you just tell young mistress?
We can celebrate.
Sooner or later.
Come on. Let's go to see her.
Young mistress,
I'm telling you, young mistress
We can't serve you any longer.
What happened? Tell me about it.
Thank you for watching!
Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team