Episode 63
Looks like the friendship between Lady Xi and you
Is truly unusual
Mistress, you-
Feiwen, while you've been here in the palace
I never thought you would have those thoughts
I, the servant who serves you,
should I have any thoughts, it's of you.
Despite serving you in the palace,
I can only be loyal to the Emperor.
If I have offended you, please forgive me.
If being loyal to the Emperor means offending me
you're labelling me as disloyal and unfaithful.
Please allow me to ask her something.
Fei Wen, no matter how this turns out today...
you're not to return to Yong Shou Palace
and serve me again.
As long as I can work in this palace,
regardless of which mistress I serve
I'll go through fire and water for her.
Very well. We were master and servant once.
Since you're exposing my private matters today,
I assume you know this will be the last time
you serve me.
You should have done your errands prior to this.
Let me ask, before you came out today
my glass vase on the rosewood table in the main hall
did you clean it?
Yes
Nonsense.
When was there ever a glass vase on the rosewood table?
It's unmistakably a jade vase.
Oh right! It's jade.
It seems like Feiwen's memory is not very good.
It's hard for you
but you still remember the pattern on the cuffs of Dr Wen's robe.
I remember now. It was definitely a jade vase.
On my rosewood table
I've never had any glass vase.
You serve me
but you're not focused on important matters
rather, you're more concerned with the doctor's hands.
Take my hand
What's the pattern on my cuffs?
Details like this
other people don't dare to look at.
You seem to have some kind of suspicious motive
Day and night I only care about the important matters.
I don't pay attention to anything else.
If Dr. Wen and Xi Guifei are really having an affair
of course other people would oppose it.
Feiwen remembers everything
and remembers it so clearly
Could it be that Feiwei
has been observing Xi Guifei's every word and action, even when they don't concern her?
This girl really has.
You dare to watch her every day.
Empress niang niang,
This feels strange to me.
like someone behind the curtain is responsible
I don't believe what this servant is saying.
I'm afraid there is a larger plot behind all of this.
I have doubt
Qi Guiren lives in Jiaolu palace(?)
Feiwen is yongshou palace's servant
Since everyone knows
Qi guiren has never respected Xi Guifei
Why would Yongshou palace's servant
together with Qi guiren
bring forth this matter to the empress?
If Feiwen spoke the truth
and one day Xi Guifei were to harm her
then nobody would know about
this whole messy incident.
So it's understandable
that she would go to Qi Guiren about this.
I heard that those who pray have kinder hearts.
They wouldn't even kill an ant.
Noble Consort Xi was at Ganlu Temple
to pray for our kingdom.
With Guanyin Pusa's protection she bore children.
How would she do such terrible things.
The temple is a place for people to meditate and pray.
Zhen Huan has cheap personality by nature
Precious, Ganlu Temple is our kingdom's temple.
Precious says such insulting and nonsensical words
are you not afraid of Guanyin Pusa punishing you?
The emperor has arrived
Greetings, Emperor.
There is never a peaceful day in the palace.
We have disturbed you.
Please forgive us.
Tell me what's going on.
I'll inform you. Xi Guifei's affair is the cause of this ruckus.
Slut! That's nonsense.
I swear on my life!
I'm telling the truth!
Qi guiren took an oath in front of us
It seems maybe there is something going on
If there's some understanding, maybe we should figure it out.
If rumors get out
it could hurt Qi Guifei's reputation.
Ok, then I'll listen.
If you're lying I won't let you off easily.
I have proof
She's having relations with Dr. Wen Shichu
After Xi Guifei left the palace,
Dr. Wen went repeatedly to Gan Lusi to visit her.
A man and woman together in a room
If you don't believe me
Ask the women from Ganlusi.
The person is in the palace.
If you want to call for her it's up to your Majesty.
Send for her.
Huan Bi Jiejie, is the 17th prince's illness better?
Yes he's doing much better
Where is my mistress?
Why haven't I seen her for so long?
Servant Jiang took her somewhere
She still isn't back
Huan Bi it's so good that you're here.
I have something urgent to tell you
Qi Guiren asked the woman from Ganlusi
to come testify that Xi Guifei is cheating on the Emperor
What?
What should we do?
We should get someone from Ganlusi
to come testify that it's a lie.
How could my sister have an affair?
The Emperor is really confused.
We need to find Mu Yan from Ganlusi.
Mistress, we must go quickly.
Ok, I'll go with Xiao Yunzi.
You stay here in case anything else happens.
A lu, you work for Ning Guiren.
Wait by the palace doors to greet her.
Okay.
Hurry, Xiao Yunzi.
Yes.
What are you in such a hurry for?
Don't get in my way.
Something's happened to my sister. I have to save her. Let's go!
What's going on?
I am a nun from Ganlusi. My name is Jing Bai.
Greetings, Emperor and Empress.
Greetings Xi Guifei.
Long time no see.
I'm not sure if you still remember me.
Master Jingbai, you've made it to the palace.
It seems you're feeling better.
The spanks rewarded by Noble Consort Xi
has taught me to speak the truth.
I hope so.
JinBai what do you have to say?
You should hurry back so we don't hold you up.
Right.
When Xi Guifei first came to Ganlusi,
she ignored everyone.
We just respectfully kept a distance from her.
There was often an older woman
who came to see Xi Guifei.
There was also a doctor named Dr. Wen
who often came to see her.
Several times I passed by Xi Guifei's place
In the middle of the day her door was often closed
and there were two servants outside guarding the door.
It seemed inappropriate to me
so I wanted to tell Xi Guifei
but she would send me away
So I felt I shouldn't say anything.
Later I heard a rumor in the temple.
that Noble Consort Xi was ill and left Ganlu Temple
to live at Lingyun Feng with a serving girl.
From then on
I don't know if she had contact with him.
Priestess, the doctor Wen you were talking about,
is he in this room?
Ahmetuofuo. It is this man in front of me.
Priestess you wouldn't recognize the wrong person?
Men rarely come to our temple
Dr. Wen came often, I can't forget him.
Emperor, this is making my head hurt. I want to go rest.
Priestess meditates at Ganlu Temple?
Yes.
Those who meditate are peaceful.
It has been a rough journey from Gan Lu Temple.
I want to ask something from priestess.
I want to worship a wish lantern
at Gan Lu Temple.
I wonder, how many pounds would do it.
Amitabha.
Someone who practises Buddhism should never get involved with world matters...
Your humble nun, I, have only stepped into the Palace once two years ago,
to send a handwritten copy of the Diamond Sutra.
And have never stepped foot into the Palace.
Mistress receives the Emperor's love
The worship requires one of the Da Hai Lantern...
But My Lady's position is only at Noble...
Two to three pounds daily should be enough.
Thank you.
Emperor, I'm going now.
Emperor, Doctor Wen's frequent visits to Ganlu Temple
was that directed by you?
If it was your intentions
then this can be forgiven.
Emperor, Concubine Xi's place of residence is indeed deserted...
But there is Huanbi and JingXi
who can be my witness.
Niangniang and I are truly innocent.
Does doctor Wen think we are stupid?
Who doesn't know that Jingxi and Huanbi
are on Noble Consort Xi's side?
How can their testimonies count?
Wen Shi Chu and Zhen Huan have been childhood sweethearts.
After they came in the palace they shared secret glances.
When Zhenhuan left the palace Wenshi went to visit.
Both of them dated secretly.
Zhenhuan arranged to live Lingyun Feng by herself
so they could be like a couple.
Once Zhenhuan returned to the palace
the two in the main room
acted in disgrace.
Emperor, I have served in the palace for over ten years.
Noble Consort Xi
is not necessarily the first mistress I served.
Nor the one
I served for the longest time.
So, there's no need for me to be biased towards her.
I can calmly say
a fair and justified sentence.
There is absolutely nothing going on between Xi Guifei and Dr. Wen.
Did you have relations with him?
No
Emperor, Precious Qi and Noble Consort Xi
have the habit of harboring resentment.
They're merely cooking a story up.
Physician Wen has been paying Concubine Xi more frequent visits...
It is because he is a doctor.
If this is a reason for gossip
then us
consorts who have been healed by doctor Wen
won't we have to defend ourselves now?
That's enough. I believe Xi Guifei.
Emperor, if you want to prove that Xi Guifei is innocent
you should investigate further
to prevent rumors in the future.
Jiejie has born children for the Emperor.
And handles matters in the harem.
If she doesn't have accomplishments at least she has worked hard.
Emperor, you must investigate this further.
then it will prevent difficulties from us sisters.
This event will affect the relationships between us.
When Noble Consort Xi was at Ganlu Temple
you didn't even go see her.
We had to have doctor Wen go in our place.
Xi Guifei returned to the palace pregnant.
She got pregnant outside of the palace.
Your Majesty didn't go visit Noble Consort Xi that much
and according to priestess Bai
doctor Wen was the one seeing her.
Then Noble Consort Xi's children...
Precious Qi's words imply
that the prince and princess aren't of royal birth?
This has to do with our kingdom.
Precious Qi how can you say such nonsense?
Emperor, you mustn't listen
to Precious Qi's claims.
Precious Qi's statements are not backed up with evidence.
All of you love to parrot others.
I don't allow you to say such things.
Parroting.
You are saying that Precious Qi's assertions
have been circulating around the palace?
These women have too much time on their hands and nothing to do.
Often they hear rumors and spread them around.
You shouldn't worry about it.
Spread rumors
Tell me, what rumors are there?
If there are really rumors that threaten the harmony of the harem
As the head of the harem
why don't you take care of these issues quickly?
Noble Consort Xi came into the palace pregnant and gave birth prematurely.
Everyone says that where the babies came from is unknown,
and isn't necessarily of royal blood.
So I didn't easily believe it.
Noble Consort Xi's premature delivery was because of the scare she had with the cats.
Who could have predicted it?
Also, Noble Consort Xi's health has always been weak.
Longyue was born after eight months.
This proves the rumors are false.
I also think so.
The stray cats suddenly coming out to scare someone in the palace
and it so happened that it was Noble Consort Xi's sedan.
If someone wanted to frame her
then why would Noble Consort Xi not investigate it or say anything about it?
Unless it was Noble Consort Xi
who wanted to use it as an excuse.
I also think it is strange.
On the day that Niangniang gave birth
Before Niangniang fainted doctor Wen
asked her about saving the baby or the adult.
I was confused.
This question should be asked by the Emperor or Empress Dowager.
Why would he ask Niangniang.
I also heard something about "ten years of feelings"
and "giving up versus not giving up".
Empress is the head of the harem.
May I ask what the punishment is for having an affair?
Emperor.
Because Noble Consort Xi is sixth prince's mother
please adjust the punishment.
Noble Consort Xi becoming pregnant outside the palace and returning
already creates a lot of suspicion.
The people who stay at Noble Consort Xi's side
are only Jingxin and Huanbi.
In my opinion
a good beating will result in answers.
How dare you. Interrogation frequently involves innocent people
and there's no reason to use such a severe method of questioning.
Emperor, Empress,
At this point the only way is to interrogate Jingxin and Huanbi
or else
we can only let Noble Consort Xi and doctor Wen suffer.
People are made of flesh.
If we don't use interrogation how will we know?
If we can use the 72 method of interrogation
and the testimony doesn't change
then there's reason to believe them.
If they really suffer through the 72 methods of interrogation
then they will become paralyzed if not die.
Even if it returns their innocence what good will it serve?
Emperor, in order to protect Niangniang's innocence
I am willing to suffer any interrogation.
But, Noble Consort Xi has a precious body
and cannot be attended to sloppily.
So please don't punish miss Huanbi.
Jiejie.
I know that you care for Huanbi and Jingxin.
But if they aren't interrogated
then jiejie will be in a difficult position.
If your heart hurts, just bear with it.
But Huanbi is with jiejie all day long.
Why is she not here?
17th lord has been sick for many days.
Huanbi went to Guojin estate to care for him.
So she is not in the palace.
Your Majesty, if we force her to come back because of such matters
perhaps the lords and relatives will become alerted.
The situation hasn't been stabilized, it shouldn't be made known.
Don't spread it?
I already know.
Royal brother forgive me.
I came in to greet Empress Dowager
So I came to see what what going on.
Who knew that I would hear all of this from outside.
I cam here to represent the relatives
to say that I would like to on behalf of Noble Consort Xi, the prince, and princess
promise that since Noble Consort Xi arrived in the palace
doing my best and handling their matters personally.
So I would like to believe in Noble Consort Xi.
Baylor Sheng has upheld high moral standards...
You don't like to talk to the consorts in the harem.
Today
how can you say so many good things about Noble Consort Xi?
Handling matters personally and thoroughly?
It's as though the lord has seen it with his own eyes.
It doesn't have to be with my own eyes
Concubine Qi personally attended to various matters..
Look... Her status is low,
anyone could see how exhausting it must be for her.
On the other hand, Precious Qi looks well-maintained.
It's obvious she's someone who lives in comfort without working at all.
-You-Shut up!
It's nice to have Baylor Shen to speak up for you.
But the Sixth Prince is of royalty,
and the Emperor has just pinned high hopes on him.
This matter is important for many generations.
We have to be meticulous.
Then you tell me how we can be meticulous.
We have to use the blood recognizing method.
I heard the imperial doctors say this in the past
that using blood to recognize relatives
is to have two people's blood
pricked and mixed in a vessel
to see if they blend together.
If they blend together they are related.
or else they are not related.
This method is not difficult.
It just requires harming the precious body to gather the blood.
I fear using this method.
This method should not be used.
How can we hurt the Emperor's royal body?
Has my brother ever thought about
if Hongye and you use blood recognition
even if it proves he is your child
when Hongye finds out
it will hurt the father-son relationship.
Should Emperor bro really did pin high hopes on Hong Yan, people would want to know the truth.
It's exactly this, due to high hopes and expectations...
So we cannot not try.
Should there be anything amissed,
Emperor would be entrusting the kingdom upon a wrong person,
and letting it fall into the wrong hands?
I thought that my feelings for you were deep and loving.
Who knew that it would become like this?
If I knew earlier that you would suspect me
I would have willingly stayed at Liuyun Feng and be alone the rest of my life.
Huanhuan, if we test it
I can return you and the children's innocence.
You want to do the test, which means that you don't trust me.
Since you
You suspect that Dr. Wen and I are involved
Then Hongye
can just do the blood recognition test with doctor Wen.
This way it won't harm your precious body.
And it can give me and Hongye our innocence.
Subi Sheng, go bring sixth prince here.
Yes.
Go prepare the materials for the blood recognition test.
Sixth prince Hongye greets the Emperor.
Emperor, sixth prince...
Bleed a drop
Emperor, if you do this
even if you prove he is your biological son
He'd be despised later on in his life.
Because his father has doubted of his authenticity.
In the future... How does Hong Yan keep a foothold?
Sit down.
Subi Sheng
Yes.
Wenshi Chu.
Emperor, this isn't possible!
This is absolutely impossible!
How dare you not kneel down?
I'm innocent. Why should I kneel?
The blood came together, signaling the relationship.
What else can you say?
Come! Take off her Noble Consort items.
Throw her into the cold palace!
And take the bastard with her.
Wenshi Chu will be executed immediately!
Who dares to?
I treated you well.
Why? Why do you have to do this to me?
Emperor!
You've disappointed me too much.
You look yourself!
This water, there's something wrong with this water.
Emperor, there's something wrong with this water.
Emperor, there's something wrong with this water!
Anyone's blood can mix together!
Emperor, come look!
Emperor!
There's something wrong with this water.
Emperor, there's something wrong with this water!
Someone did something to it.
I'm innocent, Emperor!
Emperor.
This is impossible.
I cannot have the ability to reproduce.
How can doctor Wen and Jingxin be my children?
I know.
Emperor, the water has some acidic properties.
It's the result of adding alum.
Emperor, old medical records
say that if alum gets into water
then even if they aren't related the blood can mix.
If alum is added to water,
even if they may be father and son
the blood couldn't possibly mix, Emperor.
Emperor, the evil of someone's heart can be clearly seen.
Just now in order to be fair
The empress prepared this water herself.
There's nothing wrong with the water I prepared.
I remember that you have knowledge in medicine.
Even if I had such intentions
It's too easy to figure out.
It's too risky!
I'm not that foolish.
Emperor, the proverb says it well
"Nothing ventured, nothing gained."
Although the risk is big, the chances of winning are also big.
Once this succeeds, everyone would think that sixth prince was doctor Wen's.
Who else would test it?
Emperor, I'm innocent.
Please investigate thoroughly.
I am the Empress,
why would I resort to such tactics to frame noble Consort Xi?
Yes, you are already Empress.
What else would you be unsatisfied with?
Please look into this, Emperor.
Emperor, I was able to discover just in time
Even if Hong Yan is truly yours...
He'd still be pinned to death.
I have respected you as Empress.
And have shown you the utmost respect.
I don't know what I did to offend you
to want me to suffer such a terrible punishment.
Emperor, I've prepared a clean bowl of water.
There's definitely nothing wrong with this water.
Do the test again.
Yes.
Emperor, take a look.
The emperor has tested it. You aren't suspicious anymore are you?
Zhen huan, I was wrong to blame you.
I don't suspect you anymore.
I have finally been cleared of accusations.
Sit.
Precious Qi.
At this point, do you have anything left to say?
Even if sixth prince is your biological son
Noble Consort Xi and Wenshi Chu's affair
is witnessed by three people.
Are you just going to ignore it?
I am not lying.
Even if you don't believe my words
then you can't not believe priestess Bai's words.
She personally saw at Ganlu Temple
the Doctor Wen frequently visited Noble Consort Xi.
Ahmetuofuo, those who devote themselves to monkhood don't like.
Priestess Jingbai's words
would be enough for all the nuns and monks to die out of shame.
Sister, you didn't return to the palace after it's so late
I was so worried about you.
Sister, are you alright?
I'm fine.
I just wanted to go back to rest.
Who knew that on the way back
I saw second miss with a girl and gonggong
who were looking for Noble Consort Xi.
The gonggong she brought was Xiao Yunzi
Xiao Yunzi said
he knew someone from Ganlu Temple
and so I thought that
if priestess Jingbai's words aren't reliable
then another person would be better.
So I gave my pass to Xiao Yunzi
to ask him to find the person.
Who knew that second miss
and Xiao Yunzi
were pretty fast
and hurried back.
Emperor, you annulled my sister once.
Do you want to do it a second time?
Priestess Jingbai isn't the only nun at Ganlu Temple.
Emperor you should listen to someone else.
After a year
Niangniang's frostbitten hands
do they still get bad in the winter?
It's much better.
Except in the wintertime the pain cannot be avoided.
What?
You know about Noble Consort Xi's frostbitten hands?
When Noble Consort Xi was at Ganlu Temple she would have to chop firewood, wash clothes
and other hard work.
In the cold wintertime she would have to put her hands in the cold river.
How can she not get frostbite?
If she wouldn't do it, Jingbai would beat and curse at her.
Noble Consort would often be sick and in pain.
Once when it was snowing
she was framed by Jingbai for stealing bird nest (delicacy)
and shooed to Lingyun Feng.
She almost died a few times.
Emperor, if doctor Wen didn't frequently visit her
Noble Consort may not survive to be here today.
She is a nun, yet is so cruel.
You didn't die in Jingbai's hands
She isn't that vicious afterall.
The place Lingyun Feng is difficult to reach
and wild cats often hurt people.
If Noble Consort Xi and doctor Wen really had an affair
they could have easily left.
Why would they stay there and suffer?
Huanhuan, you have suffered.
Jiejie suffered through so much
Your majesty you should severely punish the nun.
I did not treat Niangniang badly, please think about it.
How do you think we should handle it?
I think that this nun has too cruel of a heart.
And she likes to lie.
Your Majesty you should pull out her tongue
to avenge jiejie.
We thought that Imperial Concubine An Pin was tender and gracious.
Who knew that there would be times when you can be cold-hearted.
Precious Qi, save me Precious Qi!
Precious Qi, save me!
Emperor, have mercy on me!
Emperor!
Jingbai said that it's been two years since she entered the harem.
Yet she knows a lot about what is going on in the harem.
It's been difficult for Precious Qi.
I'll have you all arrested, one by one!
Mistress, Mistress, I'm sorry.
Mistress.
I'm sorry.
But I don't dare to not come to the palace.
Or else Precious Qi
will have Chensi beat me to death!
Mistress.
Emperor
Although my mistress knew doctor Wen for a longer time
they never had any affairs.
Please look into this, Emperor.
Emperor... It was Precious Qi who instigated
Bin Er, Fei Wen and Jing Bai to slander me.
This was only made known now.
I wonder... who else could be instructing Precious Qi.
Otherwise she wouldn't be so brave.
And she wouldn't be able to think of this plan.
Concubine Xi is right.
If the person behind this is still in the palace causing trouble
I'm afraid in the future
there won't be peace.
Emperor, please get to the bottom of this.
Qi Guiren, if you tell us who made you do this
I may be able to forgive you.
It's up to you whether you want to live.
Nobody made me do it.
Xi Guifei, I'm out to get you.
Really?
Since the day the Gua Er Family rose to power,
your father has been jealous of my father, and you hated me.
This has nothing to do with my family!
My family background, my looks... which of them aren't on par with yours?
But why is it only you who gets all of the Emperor's attention?
It was all my idea.
How nice it is to have a biological sister by your side in the palace...
When I saw
Concubine Xi with her blood sister...
It reminded me of the old times,
with Elder Sister in the palace
when we served the Emperor, you.
With blood sister by your side,
regardless of blessings or misfortunes,
there'd at least be someone who trusts my ownself.
Emperor, if my sister were here,
she would trust that I'm innocent.
I really wish
your sister didn't have a sister like you.
I want to know about the water.
Emperor, I didn't do it on purpose.
When Empress went to get the water, I helped her a bit.
I have forgotten that I had handled alum,
and my hands touched the water incidentally.
It was a mistake and no ulterior motives, my Emperor.
Hui Chun have been careless with her duties...
Dismiss her to the Punishment Division.
Empress, save me!
Empress! Empress!
Get up.
There has been no news from Jing Ren Palace.
Dr. Wen still hasn't come back.
Cai yue, go find out what's going on.
See what is going on.
Niangniang, bad news.
Jingren palace is in a mes
and it seems like Noble Consort Xi suffered a lot.
An Pin niangniang wanted me to tell you.
What did you say? Noble Consort Xi suffered a lot?
What did she suffer?
It was all because of Precious Qi
who said that sixth prince was doctor Wen's child.
Mistress!
Prepare the sedan, get ready to go to Jingren Palace.
You cannot go.
If Bao Que was right,
you'd be risking a miscarriage if you were to go.
How can you say that at a time like this?
I will be careful okay?
If the Emperor listens to those despicable people
he believes that Zhen Huan and Dr. Wen are having an affair
Then I'd really have a miscarriage!
Go quickly!
Hurry.
Precious Qi... of the Gua Er Jia Family is guilty of fear mongering,
stirred troubles and disrupted the harmony within Palace.
Dismiss her to the Cold Palace.
Kang Chanzai, Zhen pin,
For spreading rumors, you lose your salaries for six months.
I'll let Concubine Xi handle the rest.
Jingxin
you take BianEr and Moyan back.
Yes.
Feiwen, Jingbai
Beat them to their deaths.
Xi Guifei, spare me! Emperor, spare me!
Since I've returned to the palace,
there are too many rumors about me and my babies
Before I didn't do anything
because I thought they would fade.
Who knew that my tolerance caused today's unfortunate event.