~ Episode 16 ~
Jiang Zhongmin is keen and quick in his work
He has got it ready in such a short time
Young mistress, have you told his majesty last night
Does his mejesty still suspect that you were involved in
young mistress Meizhuang's false pregnancy
Whether his majety belive me or not only depend on his whim
I just need to do what I'm supposed to do
There's no need to bother him
servant know
Only when his majesty is happy
will he care about
who make young mistress unhappy
and punished Huang Guiquan
Then his majesty must have no suspecion to young mistress
Probably
As long as he trusts young mistress
Your Majesty, Jiang Zhongmin from the Internal Affairs Authority is here
Tell him to come in
Reporting to Your Majesty
This slave requests for Your Majesty's instruction...
regarding how to divide these 3 pots of conch black dye.
You have to ask me on such a trivial matter?
The number of mouths exceed the amount of food.
To prevent dispute among the women,
if would be best if Your Majesty decided how much to grant.
Although you're new, you're quite perceptive
The Empress is the head of the inner palace. Her portion cannot be spared.
Precious Wan is best at painting black-and-white sceneries.
Give some to her.
In addition...
I believe that brows are darker when not drawn.
Your Majesty need not consider me
Yes
Actually, I should bestow you with one pot of conch black dye...
for telling me that Precious Shen's food was poisoned
and preventing chaos in the inner palace.
Your Majesty has already said this before. I've already forgotten all about it.
Why the need to thank me again?
Here's this year's Snail Eyebrow Pencil
It used to be 3 boxes
in the past years
Why is there so little this year?
The Internal Affairs Authority says
this year, Persia produced a little snail eyebrow pencil
only 3 boxes in all
Then what about the other two?
One was given to the Empress
One was given to Precious Smile
That slut Zhen Huan again!
Last night she bewitched the Emperor
so that
even that lowly Princess of Regularity ridiculed me today!
now she come to share my snail indigo
Never mind about the Empress
I ought to give her some respects
But what is Zhen Huan?
Niang Niang calm down, watch your health
Niang Niang, what's the use in getting upset?
Why not think long-term
Think long-term
I will definitely think of a plan for Niang Niang
to relieve your worries.
Zhen Huan is just a lowly Precious
but she can eliminate Huang Guiquan while protecting herself
how can you get a long-term plan
After all that effort you only managed to get rid of a Shen Meizhuang
Zhen Huan's standing is unshakeable
Instead she's moving up by the day
I dare not believe you
Niangniang, you know black from white
Ever since I joined the inner palace, Niang Niang has treated me very well
I was not being half-hearted
Of course I know that
Otherwise would I tolerate your existence here?
I put so much effort into gaining His Majesty's favor
I will not be harmed by them!
Why didn't Sister bring the princess to play today?
Princess only plays at His Majesty's?
Princess hasn't slept well
Other than going to His Majesty's in the afternoon,
she has stayed home the past two days.
Although you are her birth mother,
you are just a small Precious.
Princess is sick
It's inconvenient to keep her in your palace
Niang Niang
Bring her here. I will help take care of her sickness.
Niang Niang, Princess cries in the middle of the night
She will really disturb your rest
If Niang Niang likes,
I can bring her over anytime.
Quickly bring the princess over here
Leave the nurse here too
Yes
What? Afraid I'll harm the princess?
I dare not
I just feel
grateful that Niang Niang likes Princess so much.
That's good
Remember, if it weren't for me,
the princess would be raised in A Ge's department
without you to take care of her like this
Right
If princess were here
you would spare lots of time
take time to think
how to solve my problem
I understand
It's a little cool at night recently
I'm afraid Mei Jiejie's clothes is not enough
It is said put on clothes when it get cooler, though it is thin, warm because of your concern
if Mei jiejie recived this clothes
she must feel warm in her heart
Adding your embroidery on it
by your dab hand
makes it even better
Young mistress
Internal Affairs Authority just sent in a box of snail eyebrow pencil
His majesty gave to you
and ask you to draw the Distant Hill eyebrow
Keep it
Young mistress, have a try
the snail eyebrow pencils are very precious
I heared it is very expensive
if it were not the tribute
I couldn't even have a look
Jiejie, try it on
I can do this on my own
I've already handled the matter
of asking Auntie Fang Ruo for help.
Young mistress Meizhuang
asked Auntie Fang Ruo to bring you this.
She insisted you get this
Take good care of yourself. Help Lingrong.
Mei Jiejie is in such dire straits
but she still thinks completely of me.
Young mistress Meizhuang is right
Currently the only person you can rely on
is young mistress An.
Songzhi! The sun is so bright.
Why aren't you carrying an umbrella for the princess?
Isn't that an umbrella?
But the princess is still under the sun
Just a little bit. We will be there very soon.
Songzhi, Princess is still young and weak
Servant knows Princess is young and weak
Princess is fortunate to receive Niang Niang's care
Precious should be deeply grateful
Why are you instead so picky?
Miss Songzhi is too sensitive
To have Niang Niang dote on our princess,
Precious couldn't be happier.
It's natural for mothers to be concerned about their children
Enough, Niang Niang is still waiting for us
Hurry, let's go
Young mistress, we can't win against Princess of Glory
I've always done everything she told me to
and planned schemes for her.
But she won't even let me keep my child!
These days of no freedom, relying on someone else for charity,
when will they be over?
Young mistress don't be sad
Perhaps Princess of Glory will tire of it in a few days
She will definitely return her to young mistress
Will she?
This child cries all day and night
How am I supposed to sleep?!
Niang Niang calm down
Get the nurse here
I would like to see how they quiet down the princess
Yes
Don't cry
What are you two doing to take care of Princess?
Princess cries all night
I can't even sleep peacefully!
Servant has already tried everything possible to quiet her down
Perhaps Princess is not used to
leaving her birth mother and living in a different palace.
thus disturbing Niang Niang's sleep.
Have you really tried everything possible?
Servant is incapable
Give me the princess
Yes
Good Wen Yi, don't cry
This child is really difficult to quiet down
Songzhi
Yes
Bring the sedative drug that the imperial doctor prescribed me
then get a cup of water.
Yes
Quickly!
Niang Niang
Here, good Wen Yi, drink
Niang Niang, Princess is still young
I'm afraid she can't take drugs like that
If I can take them, why can't she?
If you dare utter a word to anyone,
I will take your heads!
We know
Quickly take her
Quick
Here
Don't cry
If the princess makes any more noise, just use this method
Yes, Niang Niang
Niang Niang doesn't know
Whenever the Emperor comes,
Princess of Glory is very affectionate towards Princess.
But when he's not there, she does not care much for Princess
As wet nurses,
we must not have salt in our diets
in order to produce good breast milk.
But Princess of Glory doesn't care
so others care even less.
That's not all
I can't produce good milk
Princess is unaccustomed to it
so she cries every night.
Princess of Glory actually fed her sedatives!
Princess taking these drugs at such a young age...
I'm afraid it will hurt her body!
But what can I do about it?
Everytime I go, she won't let me see the princess for long
If I ask too many questions she gets angry
saying I don't trust her.
If you hadn't told me this,
I would really be in the dark!
Precious, please think of ways
to bring princess back earlier.
Of course I want that!
But she is so pleased with herself right now,
how could she let go?
Servant will do everything to take care of princess
Precious, please relax for the time being
If princess can really come back,
servants will also be relieved
Alright
Lately your eye circles have darkened
Not sleep well?
No matter
I just went to see Wen Yi
She's a bit sleepy
Not as lively as before
Is she not feeling well?
I'm guilty for not having taken good care of princess
Wen Yi is young and not easy to take care of
Why don't you send her back to Precious Cao?
Precious Cao hasn't been feeling well lately
can't take care of princess, so she sent princess here
If I send her back now,
it will be difficult for Precious Cao to recuperate.
Your Majesty doesn't know
Princess cries every night
so she gets sleepy during the day.
Niang Niang can't sleep at night either
Even her eyes are red from lack of sleep
It must be tough on you, get up
Thanks Your Majesty
Princess is still young. It's natural and normal for her to cry.
However, I think
There are almost women in the heram, too much ying
so princess cannot sleep well.
If there was some yang too keep balance
Today is 16th,
I will stay to keep you company
Tell Precious Smile to go to bed early
Yes
Your majesty, try this tortoise and crane long life soup
I haven't heard Wen Yi cry
Didn't I already say
Your majesty's imperial flavour can dominate the ying flavour
so princess won't cry
What is that sound?
Your Majesty, it's thunder. Go to sleep.
Young mistress, what's wrong?
Young mistress has always been afraid of thunder
especially the kind with lightning.
At home, madam always kept you company
In the palace, His Majesty also kept you company during most of the thunderstorms
Today, let me stay with you, alright?
At this moment
Right now, Princess of Glory must accompany his majesty
Too many things have happened lately
I am really too tired
Servant understands
Go outside to sleep
I would like to be alone
Huan Huan
It's me
Dear 4th
Dear 4th!
I was awoken by the thunder
and remembered that you were afraid of thunderstorms with lightning.
There's thunder and lightning outside
Dear 4th really didn't need to come over
Exactly because of the thunderstorm
I didn't want you to be afraid
If you are elsewhere,
you won't be worried about me if you don't see me.
Even if eyes don't see, the heart sees
Then what about Princess of Glory?
Will you always be this good to me?
Yes
Even if you aren't,
with your word,
I feel much more at peace.
Niang Niang, His Majesty has already left for a while
Niang Niang, why don't you get some rest?
His Majesty has never done this before
He's never done this before!
Niang Niang
Niang Niang calm down!
Kill her!
Niangniang, his majesty has left Hall of Cool and Refreshing
and gone to Bitong Academy
Who knew Princess of Glory would have this day?
Even the old lover is good, but can't compare the new one
Today she experiences
the humiliation I felt back then.
In the past, when His Majesty was with Niang Niang,
she used schemes to coax him away.
But today, His Majesty left on his own will
If his heart's not there, what's the use in forcing him to stay?
I remember last year, the governor of Guangdong and Guangxi
gave me a screen with mandarin ducks and double He as tribute
Give it to Precious Smile
Yes
What fragrance did you light?
Servant saw it was raining outside, very humid
Niang Niang was also reciting Buddhist scriptures, so I lit some sandalwood
Loyaling to the Buddhism, not the sandalwood could represent
Even the most precious fragrances
are manufactured by man.
They're still unclean
How could they compare to the natural fragrance of flowers and fruits?
Get rid of it
Young mistress, Lingrong is here
Jiejie
Meimei
I spent several days
embroidering this silk brocade that Jiejie gave me.
I came to give it to you
I think rather than embroider a crow
to look forwards his majesty's favour
I prefer
the spring peach blossom in the Royal Garden
own the rain's favour
so the precious silk will not be wasted
(Poem) The peach trees are fulled of peach blossom
You will certainly make a harmonious and orderly home
Thanks for your compliment
Your clothes and ornaments are a little worn
let me make you up
Come
Finished, do you like
Jiejie's clothes are colourful and luxury
mine can't compare
Colourful and luxury clothes are not suitable
in such hot weather
cool colour is more attracting than warm colour
Lotus coming out of crystal-clear water, beauty coming out of nature born
such natural beauty is the most moving thing
Let's go
Young mistress
Look at the mandarin ducks, good sign
Jiejie, I'm afraid I can't do it well
how about change a plan
If i introduce you to his majesty normally
it will be fine
but in this way
even though you get the favour
his majesty won't put you in his heart
after several days, he will put you aside
it's not good for you
Ghost Festival's fete is a big event in the palaces
you have to prepare it well
Yes
I heard that princess Wenyi have always been sick and crying
I'll let the priest to pray for her
Who is singing
Perhaps it's a singer from the palace
Such a beautiful voice is indeed rare
Pick the flowers in time
don't wait until they fall
Jiejie
Intoxicating
Jiejie really likes to joke with me
Who's singing?
Respects to Consort Hua.
Get up
Yes
When did Precious Wan learn to sing?
You can sing and dance...you really surprise me
Niangniang praised the wrong person
I don't have such voices
It was Promise An singing
I was wondering who that was
So it's the daughter
of An Bihuai who the Emperor forgave a few days ago.
The guilty subject's daughter doesn't self-reflect on mistakes behind closed doors,
instead showing off everywhere. So indecent!
My father is not guilty
Promise An's father was released and restored to his original post
He was not found guilty
Being released doesn't mean he was really innocent
Precious Wan should know very well why
It's understandable for a lowly Promise to not know the rules
But why didn't Precious Wan teach her the four social bonds of propriety, justice, integrity, and honor?
It's just a song. What does it have to do with the social bonds?
Pick the flowers in time
the flowers are usually implicated women
By singing, isn't she trying to attract attention
and willing to be picked by anyone
This song called Golden Clothes
mean to persuade people to cherish
not what you just said
Precious Wan is so well-spoken
but usually, a submissive woman is more likely to be a virtuous one
but not the one excuse herself with sophistry
Precious Smile doesn't even abide by the female virtues
argue against your superiors
I dare not
Precious Smile didn't mean to offend Niang Niang
Niang Niang please forgive
Isn't it too late to ask for forgiveness when you've already offended me?
As the head of the harem,
I will see to it
that you two abide by the rules!
Come
Yes
Respects to your Majesty. Respects to Empress
This voice is really beautiful
You rarely wear such bright colors
Get up
What is it? Not very happy today?
On such a bright day
how dare she sing the decadent song
Tell me, what do you think of the song?
Promise An's voice sounds like nature
Empress praises me too much. I do not deserve it.
Only the chink of the Kunlun Mountain's jade and the weeping sound of the orchid
could barely compare
Lift your head
What a "pick the flowers in time"
What's your name?
An Lingrong
When you answer his majesty, you should add "concubine"
in this way, you would not be impoliteness
Many thanks for Niang Niang's advice
Seems like you and Promise An
will have many more chances to meet.
Meimei, take your time instructing her. There's plenty of time.
Of course
Empress has so many things to attend to in managing the inner palace
Of course I should help share your burden
Very good
The song is refreshing, the person is refreshing too
Your Majesty, I'm a bit tired. I would like to go back first.
Alright
Liuzhu, hurry. Take Precious Smile back to rest.
Yes
Then I will walk Jiejie back
I really enjoyed Promise An's song
Let her sing it again for us
Invite Promise An back
Yes
Jiejie, I'm going back now
Get some good rest. Wait for His Majesty to call for you at night.
Please wait Precious Smile, Promise An
What is it?
His Majesty invites Promise An
Hurry, go
Replying to Your Majesty, Promise An is here
Your Majesty
Walk with me
I have some things to discuss
with Princess of Glory about the ghost festival.
I can't stay
Do as you see fit
Princess of Glory, let's go
Young mistress wants to go back right away?
Let's walk along the lake
Young mistress's outfit today looks great
Normally you don't like to wear red
but red is so pretty!
It's also festive, like red clouds!
The begonia flowers embroidered on it are also your favorite
The palace's embroidery is naturally the best
Every stitch and thread, linked in countless ways
How much work must have gone into this beauty
Can't even miss a single stitch or thread
Liuzhu, tell me, the needle point is so sharp
When it pierces the silk, does the silk hurt?
Why would young mistress think of that?
In embroidery,
The material is originally supposed to be poked by needles
it's the destiny
This material isn't a person, so it won't know pain
Young mistress, look, the lotus flower is blooming abundantly
How beautiful!
Look!
Yes, the lotus is blooming so well
It's long past the Begonia's season to bloom
I urge you not to cherish the golden clothes
I urge you to cherish your youth time
Pick the flowers in time
Many thanks Your Majesty
Don't wait until they fall
Respects to Duke Guo
Quickly rise
Is His Majesty inside?
He invited me to play chess
At the moment, I'm afraid he's unable to see you
I heard he has got a lady with beautiful voice
better than the previous one
It's Promise An
Oh, I thought it was Precious Smile
Usually Precious Smile serves His Majesty the most
But from now on, that may no longer be the case
Then, seems like I came at the wrong time
Please take the trouble to inform him tomorrow
that I came.
Yes
Goodbye
Go well Duke
It's time to call the night duty
Young mistress is back
Congratulations young mistress
Quickly get up
Originally I wanted to wait outside the door for your return
but I didn't hear any sound.
I was supposed to return in a carriage
but I wanted to take a walk by myself.
So I walked back
Young mistress, why exhaust yourself like this?
Before, I would always walk around cautiously, with my head lowered
Now I am officially a young mistress
I didn't know what it would feel like to walk around now
so I wanted to take a walk.
How does young mistress feel now?
Before I only stared at the road
and hadn't noticed the scenery in the palaces
agreed with me so much
Promise An being favored
young mistress doesn't seem too happy about
I expected it, so I wasn't surprised
Young mistress, Promise An is here
Jiejie
Here so early in the morning?
I just paid my respects to the Empress
I missed you so I came over
Young mistress An is different now
You don't need to come over everyday
There is some tea outside
Bring some in for young mistress An
Do you blame me?
How could I?
I couldn't be happier for you
I helped facilitate it
Why would I want to blame you?
If Jiejie is the least bit unhappy,
I will stop seeing the Emperor.
You don't mean that
I am also half the matchmaker
How could the bride refuse
to see the groom on account of the matchmaker?
Jiejie always teases me!
As long as Jiejie doesn't blame me
Your clothes are a nice color
matches your complexion
This is new tribute, sparkling silks, from Suzhou
I heared walking in it, looks like the sparkling rivers
I only wore it because I liked the color
I remember there are only few pieces
His Majesty gave them all to you?
Yes, originally
but I dare not use such quality things.
I only kept one
I gave two to Empress and Princess of Glory
The remaining two, I brought them as gifts for you
You're so considerate
just what I should do
I heared in Tang dynasty, the sparkling silk clothes
were tributes from Gaochang
It doesn't even get wet in rain
Now we can make it ourselves
but I don't know
if it can also withstand rain.
Then I will wear it next time it rains
So strange lately
Young mistress Lingrong hasn't visited us
in two, three days?
It's so hot and stuffy lately
Who would want to go outside?
Even the Empress has canceled the everyday's meeting
That's true
But it's all good as long as His Majesty comes
That's young mistress's business!
Why are you longing for him?
Bad mouth! Who's longing for him?
You!
You're longing for him!
Be careful, young mistress will be unhappy if she hears!
Don't say such nonsense
Auntie
Maidens, young mistress is just inside
What if the Emperor comes later
and sees all this clamor? How inappropriate
Where is Auntie going with the food basket?
Young mistress wants me to visit young mistress An
She's afraid young mistress An will get heat stroke because her body is weak
so she let me send these Shijin water
and some medicine
Young mistress cares about her more than she does about me and Liuzhu
Don't be like this
Yes I know
She is now Lingering An
We're just a bunch of servants
The past few days
Huanbi's temper is getting bigger and bigger.
Even at home, young mistress would let her have her way
spoiling her like a younger sister.
Lately, she's been slacking off
Who knows where she sneaks off to
Later, I will tell young mistress about her
Auntie don't take it to heart
No need
I just mentioned it casually. You can go.
I have something to ask you
Has Lingrong somehow offended you?
Why are you always
giving her attitude?
Don't you think she's full of herself?
flaunting her success in front of us?
First the silk from Fuzhou
then the gemstone hairpin His Majesty just gave her
As if we haven't seen such things before!
Shut your mouth!
I only asked you one question
but you won't stop complaining about her!
She's the emperor's new pet
Whatever gifts the emperor gives her,
is she supposed to hide them?
Before, young mistress would get all the good things
What does she have?
It doesn't matter what she has
She is the emperor's wife!
You need to remember your own status
Don't cause trouble!
Yes
You are so moody
Lingrong gave me two sparkling silk clothes
I saved one for you
Remember, don't flaunt when you wear it
Yes
The crystal chestnut cake that the royal kitchen made today
I actually want some now
I will get it for you right away
Thank you for watching! Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki