Episode 54
Niang Niang, the emperor has returned from Galu Temple today
Oh? To return at this time
Let's invite his Majesty over for dinner
But the Emperor has already sent a message
stating that he is tired tonight
and does not allow you to visit
He is resting now
February 2nd is an important day
and the Emperor must stay in the palane
How come today...
Go and find out what happened at Gan lu Temple today
I already asked about it
they were tight-lipped;
I could not find out anything.
The more you cannot get any information, the stranger it is
His Majesty is most concern about your ladyship
On reaching the palace,
He has immediately ordered me to bring these gifts to you
Thank you for your efforts
regarding keeping His Majesty in the palace,
then that would have to depend on your abilities
Yes, I will try my best.
Then the problems regarding my father
Regarding this i know
This matter should not be raised by your ladyship.Otherwise it will raise suspicion with his Majesty.
He may catch on that it was all planned by you
So I already looked for a chance to bring it up
His Majesty will understand your concern
he naturally would care about your father
Although your father is still under sentence
His Majesty has already ordered his return to the capital for treatment
It should not be long when he is back
How should I thank you for your great kindness?
Your ladyship - you are a Consort .. I would not dare think of being rewarded
With my position today
even if you asked for something
I may not be able to afford to give it
Why are you refusing ?
Please your ladyship .. I am just lending my weak support
i've heard that
Recently the emperor often goes towards Ganlu temple
he says it's to burn incense
Ganlu temple...Don't you know who lives there?
But didn't she say that
Zhen Huan is no longer at Ganlu Temple?
I've heard that every time the Emperor goes to Ganlu Temple
he always go to Lin Yu peak where Zhen Huan lives
How did we let our guard down?
The Emperor is having such a close relationship withan abandoned concubine,
it will damage his name.
I wonder what you plan to do
Plan?
Let's first see if this is just merely gossip
then decide what to do
Then if the emperor goes to Ganlu Temple again to pray
why don't you, my lady, request to accompany him...
like that will make you feel safer
If His Majesty insists, I can't do anything either
I can see how it goes  and think of a plan as we go on
My lady, Su Gong Gong came
my lady, may i ask how are you?
Gong Gong, please have a seat
thank you my lady  the tea
although this tea isn't anything special
but the fragrance is wonderful
thank you my lady
My lady Miss
What happened to you?
Our madame has been nauseous for days
Congratulations my lady, congratulations!
Gong gong, you are the first to find out
Am I?
Forgive me for being nosy to ask
But how long has My Lady been pregnant?
About a bit over a month
Isn't that precisely when
His Majesty visits this Ling Yun Temple for the first time?
I really have to congratulate you, My Lady
Your pregnancy is just the right time
you can use this to return to the palace
and everything will be fine
When The Emperor knows of my pregnancy,
he might be too occupied and happy...
so I have to ask you to please remind him from time to time
Yes yes yes
The Empress hasn't been well lately, and already preoccupied with many palace issues...
there is no need for my pregnancy to be known to others
Yes, this I understand
Only the emperor needs to know.
But with My Lady's pregnancy
why didn't you call for a doctor?
Our Lady does not have a title as of right now
a lot of things may seem awkward
It's better to lay low.
But Imperial Doctor Wen
has some acquaintance with our Our lady
Why don't we ask him to come help  our Niang Niang do a check up
It's more appropriate that way.
Jing Xi has a point, being so thorough in her thinking.This is good as well...
His Majesty has always been full of praises for Imperial Doctor Wen's ethics.
He will definitely agree to this arrangement.
Gong Gong has been by Huang Shang's side for so long
you would know how to ask
Yes.
All I hope for, in this wilderness...
is to quietly expect my labour here.
Niang Niang you must be joking;
how will the Emperor let you give birth here?
You must return to the palace
I am a disposed concubine
How can i return?
I just hope for my child to grow up peacefully
and it will be fine
How can you say that?
Your child is of royal blood
how can he be just outside?
Pus the Emperor always takes care of his children
he will treat yours the same.
The Emperor already treats me this way,
it is already my greatest fortune
How can i ask for more?
If Huang Shang
gives my child a tite
it is a given they will return to the palace
then i will be lonely
Niang Niang, you are pregnant
you can not be depressed
Your majesty and your royal baby is the most important.
i will think of a way to talk to Huang shang
you must be very careful
no one can know
our Niang Niang is outside the palace
and if someone finds out about the pregnancy
i don't know what mess will happen
i understand the circumstances  you take care of Niang Niang
I will return and talk to Huang Shang
to send the Imperial Doctor to come see Niang Niang
Thank you Gong Gong
I'll take my leave
Wen Da Ren,
I wonder what bring Gong Gong here
Wan Da Ren, let's go straight to point.
today i came here by Huang Shang's command
to give you an assignment
huang shang would like you
to help someone perform a check up
Thank you,
may i ask who?
Speaking of this person, you know of them too
I know them?
today this person
is living in Ling Yun Feng
could it be...?
this task was personally given by Huang Shang
no one must know
do you understand me?
I understand
Wen Da Ren!
Look at all the sweat on your forehead
Have a seat and drink some tea
i am not in the mood to drink tea
Your father has gone back to the city,
Xu Pi Xing asked me to
ask the Royal Doctors to take care of him
Xu Pei Xing is the King's man,
why would he suddenly bring your father back?
now that you already know
why do you still waste your breathe to ask me?
Did he tell you,
I am pregnant
and you are to help me do a check up
but my pregnancy
isnt at the 2 months that you know of
but only a little over 1 month
how did this happen?
because i saw huang shang
my child is huang shang's child
That's why Xu Pei Sheng is asking you to take care of me.
but this child is obviously...
whose child it is is not important
it is important that huang shang believes  that this child is his
believes that this child is only one month
you're crazy
this is treason. what if...
there is no what if.
the only 'what if' is if you won't help me
You go tell the Emperor
the baby that I've had for over 2 months
is not even his!
You know I will not
i already told you
If you give birth to this child,
I will take care of you and your child for my whole life,
you can rest assured now.
You can take care of my child and I for your entire life
but can you take my sick father
from Ling Gu Tower and bring him back?
Can you protect my family members
from being harmed by others?
Can you find out Yun Li's real cause of death,
help him get revenge?
Either way it's because I am useless,
I cannot help you
It's not that you cannot help me
I just have a hard life.
it was so hard to leave the Forbidden City
but now I must return,
because this world is the Emperor's.
Nobody could help me that much.
If there are other options,
I also am not necessarily willing to take this step.
If you are willing to help me, then help me;
if you can't, I won't force you to either.
The path my child and I must take is very hard already,
No matter how tough...
Step by step, even if I were to die
I must protect the child.
But if I lead you down the way,
I can only lead you back onto your old track.
this road is too bitter
Outside the palace I have no one to rely on
i can only wait
life in the palace is horrible but
it is better than
being killed without putting up a fight.
Shi Chu ge ge, there are things you are not willing to do, but
I am also not willing.
but in the end
i am not a carefree person
and just not care
if we already know of this day
i wish you never found about
__ 's death
Fine, Huan-er.
I can do anything about you, like always.
Besides helping you and listening to you,
I have no other way to help you.
Since you want to protect others,
I must protect you with all my power.
Your humble servant greets Your Highness.
whats the situation
Huan Bin Niang Niang is 1 month  into her pregnancy
only...
Only what?
Only that... her pregnancy is unstable and thus,
must rest
To stabilize the child, I'm afraid she can't have close contact.
you work hard to take care of Huan Bin
As for the Imperial Medical College, go whenever you can.
Yes
you may get up
Thank you Emperor
Jin Xi, get me some water
Emperor
Now... and you're still full of formalities.
When did you arrive?
i didnt know
Jing Xi didn't even wake me up.
The Emperor has already been here for an hour,
and seeing that you were sleeping, he did not want to wake you up.
i told them not to wake up
to let you sleep some more
When Su Pei Sheng informed me of your pregnancy,
I was overjoyed.
Emperor, you shouldn't have...
Despite your joy,
you could come by any day you wish.
It just rained, and the road isn't easy for walking...
why'd you rush here?
Your pregnancy is a joyous event
I am very happy
You're blessed indeed,
I visited you for the first time, and you got pregnant then.
Emperor
I am worried about you
Imperial Doctor Wen said your pregnancy is unstable
he said you can't do this or do that
i am so worried
To have my lover be this worried over me, I am...
If not for your pregnancy,
there's too many things in the palace to worry about...
I, can never find another reason to be this happy.
here, i told them to make
bird's nest with yogurt
this was your favourite
Chang Xiang Si (the longing) is still with you...
since you left 3 year agos, no was has been able
to play such a nice song
You were fine just now, why the sudden tears?
Huan Huan, I, have not played it for a long time.
It feels like centuries...
To have you back by my side, it already feels that way.
come with me back to the palace
i am a disposed concubine
now that i even have your child
i don't want to think about returning to the palace
disposed can be re-titled come with me
would the Empress Dowager allow it
now that you are pregnant
she would not prevent this
i will plan everything for you
what did you say? she is pregnant?!
it is certain
i personally saw imperial doctor wen
prescribe medicine for pregnant women
and in the palace no one is pregnant
Able to be under the care of Imperial Doctor Wen...
it could only be the one at Ling Yun Mountain.
go out
yes
no matter how we tried
we couldn't stop that fox's stomach
if she wasn't pregnant, it would be easier
pregnant so fast! this isn't good
Niang Niang
it was so hard for the Palace to be peaceful
if we allow her and the child to return
the palace will have drastic changes
Empress, think of something
even though there isn't any rule banning disposed concubine  from returning to the palace
but not matter what  i can not let her return!
right now, we can only keep her outside
To eliminate her completely, and rid of further complications.
Your Highness, bad news...
the empress dowager is sick and fainted again
Quickly order Bao Hua Dian (a temple),
to pray for the Empress Dowager.
yes
Make other preparations.
I'll go over, and personally pray
for the empress dowager
Missy, by constricting your tummy... Will the baby be harmed?
it shouldn't
Imperial Doctor Wen said, Concubine Wang in the past...
is scared of the empress' power
is pregnant but too scared to say anything
And she constricts her tummy daily until labour.
Besides, I'm only doing it once every few days.
only doing it for the next few months,
and not constricting it too tightly.
Imperial Doctor Wen has sent some tonics over as well.
and after donning this baggy top,
it does look like you are only one month pregnant.
As long as the Emperor doesn't come too close,
we can hide this
Imperial Doctor Wen, do you have news of Huan-er?
she does have something she told me to tell you
what is it?
she is pregnant
huang shang will probably bring her back to the palace
really?
but returning to the palace
isn't something huang shang can say for himself
we still need the empress dowager's approval
you are always at the empress dowager's side
if the empress dowager mentions anything
would you please help add some good words?
yes yes of course
returning to the palace is only the beginning
the rest of the road is endless
niang niang you must be prepared
If Empress and Concubine An were to know of your return...
they won't let you go easily
huang shang has made up his mind to bring me back
the empress may not be able to prevent it
She could only do the Emperor a favour and grant it, while welcoming me with much sinister plans.
And when I finally go back to the Palace,
she will use her power against me
that would be hard to face
who would know after these couple years
no one in the palace is able to face her
She might be arrogant,
but whatever she does,
it is of no use.
If you return to the Palace with a Title,
and give birth to a royal baby in a few months,
then you're settled down.
Even if she picks a fight with you,
you might not lose.
I just hope that even with all the lust around you,
you will not forget our purpose.
Lady, help!
Tai Fei
heard about ____'s death,
and she hasn't eaten or drank anything for three days.
She wouldn't listen
Bring me to her.
Please give us some time,
The dead has died,
should the Living follow?
I want to follow him as well,
and just end everything
and leave behind all the troubles.
Do you just want your son,
but not your grandson?
The baby I am carrying right now,
is still waiting to call your Granny.
The baby doesn't have a father already,
he doesn't wanna lose his grandma too
I only have this one son,
I didn't take good care of him
Now I am watching my own son leave,
Yun Li, you were going to be father soon,
but you will never see that now.
Huan-er, you're pregnant.
Don't get too worked up or grieved. Don't cry anymore...
Royal Concubine... eat something.
Yes... I'll just eat something.
Ji Yun. Ji Yun, bring in some dishes.
Coming.
Royal Concubine, in the future... I'm afraid,
I can no longer come by An Xi Guan anymore.
Why?
The Emperor means to bring me back to the palace.
And I have agreed.
No harm doing so...
You cannot defy the Emperor's orders anyway.
But, the child in your tummy...
The Emperor thinks it's his.
That's why he insisted on my return.
My son, Chong Li, has just died...
and you want my grandchild to
address someone else as his father? You...!
Royal Concubine, do you know that...
Chong Li's death was no accident.
He was murdered.
The boat he was on, was tampered with.
That's why he died!
I've never thought that his death was by accident.
Chong Li did not die in peace.
I must avenge him.
But regrettably, I am merely a woman.
But do you
have to bring my grandson into the palace?
I didn't want it to be this way
but this is the only way
I can seek revenge for Yun Li.
The only way I can keep our baby.
And the only way,
I can protect my family.
Tai Fei, did you know
rather than living like this,
I would rather die.
But for Yun Li, and for our baby,
and for the Zhen's.
I still have to do it no matter how difficult it will be.
Let's leave.
What happened back there is too unlucky,none of you should tell anyone.
Your majesty should take a walk,
since you're not in a good mood.
Let's go look at fishes.
Empress Dowager is seriously ill,
how can I relax?
Let's just reutrn to the Palace.
Yes.
are you alright your highness?
quick get the doctor
Your Lady!
Fire! Fire! Fire!
Fire! Protect her majesty!
quick come
help
Fire!
Fire! Fire!
The Queen has always been mannered and had good posture,
why did she fall?
It must have been you guys' ignorance,
Its not their fault.
I was just careless,
Thank goodness I wasn't hurt badly.
What did you find?
The concrete was unstable,
that's why her Majesty fall.
It's just my carelessness then.
But just now when you were at the Temple,
you dropped the incense twice, that is so unlucky
Don't say useless things.
Your Highness! There was a fire!
What happened?
Is the Empress Dowager okay?
she is alright
and she wasn't injured.
Thank goodness that the fire wasn't big, and it's been taken care of
That's good, I must head to her Majesty now.
Your Highness,
please allow me to speak
both the dowager and her majesty suffered from shock today
Empress and the Empress Dowager met with such unfortunate events in the same day.
one sprain her ankle and the other faced a fire
I am wondering
if we should invite Zhen Tianjin here
I will visit the dowager
invite Zhen Tianjin to see me later
yes
Yes.
greetings
stand up
the dowager and her majesty suffered shocks today
fire or sprain ankle
is it heaven's will?
I came to report
after observing the sky
found that
normally stars that shine in October
is specially shining today
it has a "tail" star and could outshine the moon
really?
yes
Danger, immense danger.
it could mean clamality
the moon is represented by the dowager and the majesty in the palace
the star with the "tail" implies someone who is pregnant
this person is likely in the north
can could harm the health of both ladies
is the person in the palace now?
no
the person should be outside the palace now
she is getting nearer though
if so
the two ladies will definitely suffer
a lay who is pregnant and is outside the palace
north
Su Peisheng
delay your preparation for Zhen Huan to return to the palace
yes
lady,Su told us
the king is worried about observations done by Tian
looks like you can't return to the palace
I knew it already,
it will be difficult for me to return
That's good too,
at least we now know what they're doing.
Ask Xu Pei Sheng to tell Mei Jie Jie,
everything will only work if she is ableto convine the Empress Dowager
Yes, I should go do that.
Your majesty was injured a few days ago,
thank goodness that you look very well today.
Please be careful and take care of yourself,
or else I will not be able to sleep well.
Thank goodness I wasn't injured seriously,
Resting a few days is enough.
But these few days,
I miss you a lot.
Thank you for your care,
Good that your lessons finished early,
then you can spend some time with Mom.
So, did you study?
Yes
That's good, as long as you're hardworking,
your Father will like you a lot.
Ethics lie in big knowledge...
someone chanting phrases from the ancient books
In the past, those who wish to rule...
must rule his family before he can rule the country.
Who is looking after 4th prince?
a few of the nannies from Yuanmingyuan
did the king visit the 4th prince?
I don't think so
3rd prince
you study with him
what do you think of his progress
the teachers said he started lat
but he is smart so he learnt fast
then what did the king says
king doesn't speak with him
if you compare with him
he is hardworking
he is still learning
and can't compare with my progress
for now
if he continues to be hardworking
and serious
he will be successful
in future
...
4th prince, you ate very little tonight
you started studies again, your eyes must be tird
leave me alone
I feel sorry for you
you will spoil you health
I am very lucky to be back here
every time dad sees me
he only asked about my studies
if I don't do well
no new will think well of me
the supper is here
put it here
this is green bean soup
it is good for improving eyesight
drink up
no, you drink it
I asked them to cook it for you
you drink it
keep quiet
I can't sleep if I can't memorize the notes
ai...
drink it
yes
are you alright?
mama
what happen
4th prince are you alright
don't be afraid
I am Huping
Huiping, someone wants to kill me
..
don't say nonsense
my mama has died
in my room
Hui lady, save me
don't be afraid
if you trust me,let me think of some ideas
greetings
why are you here
don't cry
come
don't blame him
he was frighten
his mama
drank his soup and died
on the spot
what
I am no one like me
why does someone wants to kill me
why
I think
he doesn't have his birth mother here
no one to protect him
for his safety
can he
stay with you
for safety
sure
good boy
you saw something you shouldn't see
and frighten yourself
do we want to investigate
..
it will be difficult
one bowl of green bean soup
many people were involved
it will be a big
issue if people know
I understand
because of the sky observations
it affected the dowager and her majesty
Wanping is pregnant and can't return to the palace
only able to stay outside
in the long run
not sure if this affects the "moons" or the entire dynasty lineage
shift his things to my court
..
let him stay here
see who dares to hurt him
yes
I will pack his stuff later
my grandson
go back
yes
what do you think
who did it
you know it in your heart
I don't dare to say more
to hurt your feelings
besides her
who would dare to do it
she ha 3 sons
don't think she will do it?
because of her sons
she needs to give them a smoother path to the throne
she is getting bolder
there is no one who can control her
in the long run
our lineage may be ended
invite the king here tomorrow
yes
4th prince?
his mama died
useless
forgive me
clean up all evidences
be alert