Queen is also here
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Yes.
Peace upon you, Mother.
Mother, are you feeling better today?
I feel better now
The floor it's cold, stand up and take a sit
I asked you to come to tell you something
I will listen to your instructions.
I've heard that Wan concubine was pregnant
but due to astrological forecasts, the King dares not bring her into the palace.
This matter affects the harem. I dare not make the decision on my own.
I worry more about your health.
I'm old, body is not strong
nothing is more important than descendants
Empress, is that right?
yes
I think
the May Yan  (constellation)  crisis is not an urgent issue.
Me and Empress are not afraid of that
But do you know
that Fourth Prince was almost poisoned by someone?
He was so shocked by that incident that he has refused to return to the palace.
He can only live beside me, only I can take care of him
If anything bad were to happen to Concubine Wan's child,
the Emperor and I will not forgive her.
I want bring Concubine Wan back to the palace immediately.
Madam Zhen is really fortunate.
She was pregnant right after one visit from the Emperor.
I'm afraid that many people would envy her.
It's just that previously, Madam Zhen's position was taken away from her. Technically, she's a deposed concubine.
Everyone knows this in the palace.
And there's no precedent of any deposed concubine returning to the palace.
If a position is taken away, it can be given too.
As such, all I have to do in confer a new title on her.
I'm afraid such a huge action may cause rumors outside.
Mother, what Wan Pin has is the royal family's descendant
We can't leave her out in the wild on her own.
She should be brought back to the palace and given proper care.
How are you going to bring her back? And when?
You're the Emperor. The decision is all yours.
It's just that I know that my illness is severe. I won't be able to take care of Fourth Prince for long.
I hope Your Majesty can arrange for him to have an adopted mother.
Don't leave this child alone and without any support, like a frightened bird.
I understand.
You should also remember...
even if Concubine Wan has offspring,
you cannot favor her excessively, and allow her to become arrogant again.
I think the Empress won't object either, right?
If Zhen Meimei could come back, it will naturally be great.
I miss her pretty much
The process of creating the middle notes of this goose pear tent is truly unique.
A sliver of sandalwood paste.
Then remove the core of the goose pear,  and pour the fragrant paste in.
Continue to replace the cover of the goose pear.
Then use this silver pot to steam the pear over fire for thirty minutes.
Tell me after you've finished.
Yes.
I didn't know you were coming, Empress.
I didn't welcome you from afar. Please forgive me.
Get up.
Yes.
I'm just here to see how you mix the fragrances.
I didn't have anyone announce me, and came in on my own.
Empress, if you need any incense, just send a servant to notify me. I'll send it over to you personally.
I'm afraid the servants may not be able to convey the message clearly...
resulting with you not only being unable to concoct the appropriate scent, but knocking yourself out in the process.
I'm unintelligent. Please explain, Niangniang.
His Majesty is adamant on bring Concubine Wan back to the palace.
What fragrance do you have that can change the Emperor's mind?
I'm useless.
What are your plans, Niangniang?
What plans can I have?
If the Emperor insists that she come back, I'll just let her come back.
If she's right under my eyelids, I'll feel a lot more assured.
Previously I have spoken to you about constructing a new building for Concubine Wan -- has it been approved?
It is an inconsequential issue,  but just thinking about it makes me angry.
How is that so?
Today, I raised this matter at court.
It was as if all the ministers had discussed it beforehand. All of them stood out to object to it.
They talked about the South-West flooding and  how the stores are being stretched.
To make such large-scale preparations for a  mere concubine's welcome.
may cause the people's hearts to lose the sense of security, and create a mountain out of a molehill.
The ministers have always been like that. They always make a mountain out of a molehill.
Your Majesty, just make your own decisions.
With blanket opposition from the ministers, it is not appropriate to go ahead with the plans.
I've already thought it through.
I'll have the housekeeping department renovate Yongshou Palace. I don't think they'll have anything to say.
That's good too.
As long as Concubine Wan doesn't feel slighted.
But now that they've brought it up,
I feel that this matter needs more effort to solve.
They opposed my welcome of a banished concubine back, indirectly also labelling her as the daughter of a condemned minister.
Born of the Han army's lower five banners,
her birth is neither noble, nor has she given birth to a male royalty.
Even the child in her womb is of an unknown gender.
So many reasons...
it looks like it'll indeed be a challenge to bring Concubine Wan back to the palace.
Then how about...
I've already made up my mind.
Since she is born of a Fifth Han Banner's status,
I will raise her banner...
and make her status that of a Third Manchu Banner.
Her family name will be 'Niuhulu'.
You have to consider this matter in detail, Your Majesty.
If my king truly wishes to raise the status of Zhen Shi,  to give her a new family name,
can add a character 'Jia' at the back of the family name 'Zhen',
and thus raise it to the family name of 'Zhen Jia'.
After she's given a new family name, she will no longer be the condemned minster, Zhen Yuan Dao's daughter.
Even if she doesn't have a son, there are many princes in the palace without mothers.
Your Majesty, you are referring to Fourth Prince?
But Fourth Prince is of a lowly birth.
It's precisely because he's of lowly birth...
that he needs a mother with significant status.
From today onwards, Fourth Prince's biological mother will no longer be the servant girl, Li Jingui...
but my concubine, Niuhulu Zhen Huan.
But Concubine Wan is only 22 years old!
The age difference with Fourth Prince is only 7 years! How can she be his mother?
That's not difficult.
We'll just treat it as Huanhuan gave birth to Fourth Prince,
then left the palace to pray for the country.  Thus, she will not be regarded as a banished concubine.
The age is a small matter. We'll just add 10 years to her age.
What's wrong with saying she's 32?
If that's what you want to do, Your Majesty, I have nothing else to say.
But I'm afraid we may not be able to stop the rumors.
What is there to fear from people's words?
Regardless of whether they are willing to talk about it,
or if they are not willing to do so. I'm determined to give Huan Huan the position of a consort (fei).
The character 'Huan' is not good.
Many troubles were raised by past issues.
I'm going to change her title.
The past is too heavily dark to be pursued.
The future's path is bright and brilliant.
I'll choose the character 'Xi'.
to bring across the meaning of light and brilliance.
I think that it's great.
Everything in the palace has been prepared accordingly.
We will receive my lady back to the palace soon.
The Emperor said that he wants to title your ladyship as 'Xi Fei', for you to live in Longevity Hall,
and for your to raise the Fourth Prince.
The Fourth Prince?
Yes.
Your ladyship was originally a banished concubine. To return to the palace may cause a lot of rumours.
I suspect the Emperor has given your ladyship  a new surname of 'Niuhulu',
to take the guise of the Fourth Prince's birth mother.
Even your age has been raised by ten years, to become thirty-two years.
Thirty-two.
How does our lady look like she is thirty-two years old?
Of course she doesn't look the age.
That's only to minimize the possible rumours.
This is all a small matter
The Emperor's decision is the best
The Emperor also says, it's not suitable for your ladyship to continue to live in Ling Yun Feng,
for your ladyship to bear travelling to and staying in Gan Lu Si for a few days, before we receive you from over there.
We'll just follow to what the Emperor arranges.
Forgiving those at the Dewdrop Temple won't result in any controversies.
If we go back now,
I wonder how those detestable people at Dewdrop Temple will react.
Just thinking about it makes me satisfied.
Mistress, why aren't you dressed up yet?
Soon Su Peisheng will arrive with the imperial decree to bring you back to the palace.
Huan Bi, help me dress up.
Mistress, this time's return,
some things you must let go of them.
For example...
Heart
But not a cruel heart.
A cruel heart is still a heart.
You need to be just cruel
without any heart.
Jinxi, besides you,
no one else would say this to me.
According to Heavenly will, the Emperor declares,
Niuhulu Zhenhuan, of a well-known clan, gentle, respectable, and great
By the Empress Dowager's decree, is canonized as Xi Fei.
Thanks to the Emperor's grace.
Congratulations to Niangniang.
The emperor means to tell you,
the ceremony will be held three days from now.
At that time, the Official of Canonization will escort Niangniang back to the palace.
Thanks, Gong Gong.
Empress Mother, I want to take Zhen Huan back to the palace in a few days.
I only need to decide on the Official of Canonization.
Just have the Ministry of Rites find a capable person.
I gather that she is already three months pregnant.
It's about time to have her return to the palace and rest up.
Emperor, Emperor, he's back, he's back!
So panicky that you can't even speak properly.
Who is it who has returned?
Who's there?
Master!
Is it really you, Wang Ye?
Is Mother in?
Imperial Concubine Dowager, look who has returned!  Mother!
Mother, I have come to greet you.  Yun Li!
Yun Li!
Is it really you?
Yes, it's me! I came to see you as soon as I got back!
Yun Li!
They all said that you have died in the Yellow River!
I cried my eyes out!
Mother, don't be sad.
Look, am I not great right now?
Yes, I'm not being sad.
I'm being happy, happy!
Right,
have you met the Emperor and the Empress Dowager yet?
I heard that the Empress Dowager has become more sickly each day.
I sent Ah Jin to the palace immediately when I got back so that I can have time to see you.
Yun Li,
You are back,
but Huan Er, she's not here anymore.
Mother, what are you saying?
Yun Li, Huan Er she
she's returning to the palace.
Yun Li, you have to understand.
Huan Er also has her own grievances.
Huan Er is the same as I.
We both thought that you had died!
But even if there are numerous rumors,
even if she has her grievances-  Huan Er, she...
Yun Li, we all have our own ambitions.
Please don't hold a grudge against Huan Er.
One day,
you will understand her difficulties.
Mother,
I must go find her.
I must go find her and get an explanation from her.
Yun Li, Yun Li!
The imperial decree has already been passed.
I can never see the blue sky outside the palace ever again.
Huan Er!
Huan Er! Huan Er!
Wang Ye!
Huan Er, are you waiting for me?
Look, it's Niangniang's wedding day.
It would be terrible to get your clothes wet. Go in and change into more festive-looking clothes.
Master is alive and well. I will immediately go give thanks and sacrifice to the gods.
Once the edict has been passed, nothing can be reversed.
If you use your emotions on this matter,
I'm afraid the consequences will be disastrous.
Niangniang?
You're really going back to the palace?
I never thought that in this lifetime,
I would be able to see Wang Ye back in peace.
Wang Ye?
We were only apart for four months, and the changes happened so quickly?
You're a Niangniang again?
It must be because I haven't heard that title in a long time.
It's foreign.
It's good that you've come back.
I'd rather die in Dianzang and never return!
Huan Er.
I was only able to make it back because I was thinking of you!
But the moment I'm back...
I have to watch you being welcomed back to the palace...
-and return to my brother's side?-If you didn't return,
did you think that I would spend my life thinking of you and missing you?
If you didn't return, you would never have realized that I'm such a heartless woman!
I have always been a heartless woman!
Heartless?
I'm apologetic towards Wang Ye. Saying anything more would be futile. I ask you to leave now.
Grand Concubine, Miss Huanbi has come.
Peace upon you, Grand Concubine.
Why have you come?
Mistress asked me to look for Wang Ye.
What did Huan Er say?
Is everything ready?
Please don't worry, Wang Ye.
Alright.
I will wait for her at that time.
Wang Ye.
Take care.
Mother, I have something up.
Just go
Grand Concubine, Wang Ye is so upset. Why won't you tell him the truth?
How could I have guessed that he would be in this much pain?
If I tell him the truth, by his temper,
he would want to ignore everything and runaway with Huan Er.
Then the Emperor would also realize that Huan Er's unborn child is not his.
But if so, Wang Ye would hold a deep grudge against Mistress.
It has to be this way. Everyone's life is on the line.
For now, we can only take the lesser of the two evils.
You're finally willing to see me.
Seeing you return peacefully...
I can also return to the palace in peace.
Only for this?
Then what did you think?
We haven't seen each other for so long.
-And you're not even asking where I've been?-Is that important?
Seeing you alive and well in front of me,
I have no more regrets.
So you only have no regrets when I'm well?
Then during the times when rumors of my death abounded,
you must have thought of me day and night.
I've often heard that Wang Ye overthinks.
It really seems to be the case here.
Our hearts have long mirrored each others'. Today you are returning to the palace so that's why you've been so cold to me!
Our fates have already ended.
Fates?
Before, you said that there's no fates involved in love.
You said only weaklings who refuse to fend for themselves would use fates as an excuse.
Great fates is an excuse for intimacy while ended fates is a pretext for breaking up!  I also said,
When the end of the road has been reached with nowhere to go,
that's when I say the fates have ended.
I only want to tell you right now,
that I want to end our relation.
I'm sure someone has already told you
that I have been pregnant for three months.
Three months.
You must know that this child is not yours.
Right, three months.
When I have left for only one month.
you were with my brother.
Everyone spread rumors of my death, but that's alright.
It's also ok that you did this for your survival. But my heart hurts.
Huan Er,
You walked out of the palace because of a broken heart,
why must you go back to that brokenhearted place to torture yourself?
I really can't hold this in.
I would rather, I would rather have Wen Shichu take care of you for the rest of your life! At least he was true to you.
Only your brother can give what I want!
My father's live, my whole clan's survival, and the riches!
I was in the Dewdrop Temple for years. I have had enough of insults!
I wanted to live that life of glory!
I don't believe it.
Fortune and glory?
Since when were fortune and glory even in the line of your sight?
If you are really gonna use this to degrade yourself,
then you are also degrading all my feelings toward you.
The woman I love and cherish,
how can she be like this?  Wang Ye met the wrong person.
I am that type of mortal.
I want to live well. I want the people around me to live well.
I don't want to be stepped on again!
That day,
my boat was sinking in the Yellow River. Everything was washed away!
If I had not been familiar with the water, I would have been a corpse in the river!
I finally reached the shores.
Yet I walked into the trap of Zhun Ge Er, who capured me and took me to their land.
Do you still remember that snake-bitten man whom I rescued that day?
He was Zhun Ge Er leader's eldest son, Mo Ge.
I walked right into his trap.
When he found out who I was .. he did not mistreat me.I escaped. I was concerned you were worried.
I rushed back to see you and mother
Yun Li
Huan Er
It's not too late
Let's run away. I can give up my royal titles
We can marry without honor
Your child will be like my flesh and blood
It's too late
Yun Li
Man do not just live for love
Consider this ..
if we run off all the people around us will be held responsible
We cannot be selfish and sacrifice them
I cannot do it and neither can you
If I could ..
I would give up everything to be with you
But we know our parents and those who are dear to us will pay with their lives
There is no where we can hide
We have no choices left
Huan Er
From the beginning ..
if you had rejected me
I would never believe
Your rejection today ..
I understand
You will never be by my side again.
When you left - our fates were sealed
Huan Er .. let me embrace you
Even if for a moment
From today on
I can embrace anyone
but I will never have you in my arms again
Yun Li
Being with you is like a dream
I do not want to wake from this dream
The happiest days of my life was living this dream
you gave me those moments
it's the same for me
Alright, Huan Er.  With your words,
I have not wasted this life.
With her, you will support and guard  each other into your old age.
You will live a very good life.
You will be in bliss for the rest of your life.
Are you saying such things to make my heart hurt?
My everything,  has been summarised by that marriage contract.
There is only you and no one else
My king, Duke Guo has come back.
Greetings to my king.
Rise up quickly, quickly.
Sit.
It's good that you are back.
Good that you're back.
When I heard that you died in the Huang River,
I was heartbroken.
Mother, who is sick in bed,
is also having restless days and nights.
That you are able to come back  must be a blessing of the gods.
It's the prayers of my brother,  that enabled me to salvage my life.
You have returned at the right time.  I have an auspicious task,
and I have been wondering who to assign it to.  - Please instruct me, brother.
I want to welcome Xi Fei back to the Palace.
That Concubine Wan.
Other people tends to refute mewhen I start talking about this.
Your Majesty.It's only reasonable for you to bring back your loved one back to the Palace.
Furthermore, I heard that Xi Fei is pregnant.
I must say you're quite informed.
Xi Fei is coming back after being banished.
People are talking about it outside.
I plan to find a someone with a respectable status to be the Canonizing envoy, to welcome Xi Fei back to the Palace.
But several Princes have been tactfully declining.
Is it because if I become the canonizing envoy, I would add on to Xi Fei's glory?
If it isn't so, I wouldn't have sought for your help
I know what to do. As long as..
it's for Brother, I'm willing to go forward.
Truly worthy of my brother.So tomorrow..
You will use half of the empress's ceremonial devices to welcome Zhen back to the palace.
Edict obeyed.
I heard that the Emperor will use half of the Empress's ceremony to welcome back Zhen.
She is already given family name of 'Niuhulu'.
In order to prevent other people from gossiping,
the Emperor has raised her status to the Embroidered Yellow Flag
and given her the great Niuhulu name.
And even calls her the birth mother of the Fourth Prince,
who has been praying for the country's wellbeing in the Dewdrop Temple. She got a son for free
and also entered the top three flags.
And her Palace of Longevity is so luxurious that people gape at the sight of it.
But the Fourth Prince is already so old, how can they be mother and son?
The Emperor can falsely credit that boy as her son,
what's falsifying her age by ten years?  Is there really no way to prevent her from coming back, Niang Niang?
What's so bad about her return?
Though all land graced by the heavenly dew is the King's land,
the Harem is entirely under my control.
Let her return if she wants to.
Niang Niang's intelligence makes me realize my own lacking.
But for An Pin, you've always known Zhen Huan's personality so you should take this opportunity.
Edict obeyed.
Qi Pin, you must have your father keep mentioning Zhen Huan's return to the palace in the courts.
He must stain her name and ruin her reputation.
You asking the Emperor to refurnish the Palace of Longevity has been interpreted as outsiders as the Emperor favoring Zhen Huan.
This rumor has been widely spread.
You must complete this task well.
These days, An Pin will be in charge of serving the Emperor.
Yes
To me, this gaudy wedding attire
is like heavy chains,
locking away all my life's happiness.
When you're used to it, it won't be uncomfortable anymore.
Let us go outside.
Wang Ye,
Prince Guojun greets Consort Xi. The carriage is already waiting outside the palace.
Please rise, Prince Guojun.
Wang Ye has fallen flowers on your clothes.
Fallen flowers wither.
Wang Ye shouldn't have gone near them.
Fallen flowers also have feelings. Why remove them?
Huan Bi,
I think we have forgotten Niang Niang's Ornament of Good Wishes.
How about you go find it with me?
Huan Er wishes Wang Ye to have an abundance of children
and longlasting fortunes.
Without you,
this longlasting fortune is only a complete defeat for me.
This official respectfully welcomes Consort Xi back to the palace.
To show the great imperial mercy,
Servant Su Peisheng greets Consort Xi Niang Niang.
We respectfully escort Consort Xi Niang Niang back to the palace.
Niang Niang, please.
Su Gong Gong please wait. I still have some trivial matters.
Jingbai Shitai.
Niang Niang,
I have meditated here for numerous years
thanks to Shitai's care.
Nuns should naturally embrace kindness.
Niang Niang, Niang Niang doesn't need to thank me.
Shitai's care for me in the past days,
I will never forget.
I will definitely repay you.
Jingan Shitai  Here.
I have always separated my goodwill from my grudges,
Shitai's care for me in those days I thank you greatly.
Jinxi,
get two of my handcopied Peace Scripture
to gift to Jingan Shitai.
I know that you have never liked gold or silver.
These two scripture books are just small tokens of my appreciation.
Thanks for Niang Niang's gift, but I've alway had one wish that I hope Niang Niang can fulfill for me.
I understand all that you have said.
I will let her filthy life live.
In hopes of her repenting and directing her heart towards Buddha.
Thanks to Niang Niang's great mercy.
Thanks to Niang Niang's kindness.
Our Buddha will definitely protect Niang Niang.
Where's Mo Yan?
I am here, what does Niang Niang want?