Episode 44
Meal delivery
Vegetarian meal again!? You guys...
Quit complaining
To eat or not, you choose
Not eating? I'm going to feed it to the dogs then.
Don't Don't Don't
Having something to eat is better than nothing
Come back an hour later to collect the utensils
Let's go
This bunch of lowly eunuch, only know how to take advantage of others.
They must have taken a portion of our share
to get favour from their master
lower your voices
without the higher up's backing
they wouldn't be so daring
liu zhu
take these two to heat it up
and our charcoal are almost used up
Imperial Household hasn't send us any supplies for a very long time.
looks like the wind is picking up
our master is still hungry
lets heat it up and fill our tummy first
lets go
your highness, this few dishes still can be eaten
your servant, has just asked of liu zhen to heat it up
eat it while its still hot
i'm not hungry
share it among yourselves
your highness, if you continue to starve yourself
you will eventually collapse
then the servants of this household
will have nobody to rely on
save me half a bun
the rest split among yourselves
I will do as you say
your highness
you become weaker and weaker by the day
where exactly are you not feeling well?
I feel so languish
I cant even exert any strength
and my waist feels so very sore
what should we do
your servant has to think of ways to get the imperial physician over
forget it, they will never come over
the day before, Xiao yu zi had a high fever. he wanted to go over to get some medicine
but they refused to spare any
thank god, Xiao yu zi had always has a strong constitution.
otherwise he wouldn't had made it
your highness has always been weak
Xiao yu zi can make it through, but your body constitution is different from his
your servant has got to think of a solution
to get the imperial physician here for sure
hun bi, take good care of our master
sister, rest assured I will definitely do my best
alright, liu zhu come with me
Mr guards Mr guards (calling out to the guards guarding the door~)
open the door open the door
wan concubine is sick, please open the door brother
i'm begging you
Mr guard
wan concubine is really sick
his majesty only grounded her highness
he didn't ban her from seeking medical attention didn't he?
what if her highness had any mishap
how are your guys going to answer for that
I have some money here
how about you guys going for a little drink
please i beg of you
his majesty had given the edict before
no one in this household is allowed leave this mansion
anything other than that, we couldn't be bothered anyway
close the door
please don't close the doors please~
I beg of you please open the doors
your highness...
your servant is so useless, I failed to get the physician here
forget it, don't make things difficult for the guards
I can still bear it
liu zhu, help me up to move around
your highness, what are you going to do?
I want to get some fresh air
your highness your highness!
guards open the doors!!
open up!!!
guards open up!
open the door! her highness has fainted
kick open the door
what are you guys doing?!
don't stop me. what are you guys doing!?
get out of my way
back off. insolenece!
her highness fainted
let go of me, let me out, let go of me
let's see who dares to move
let me out!
let go of me, let me out
liu zhu!
liu zhen liu zhu~
get ..
the imperial physician
hurry! report back to the supervisor
get the imperial physician
imperial physician! imperial physician!
your majesty
chief of imperial guards has a matter to report
your majesty, your subject has an urgent matter to report
speak
your majesty
the servants of sui yi mansion wants to barge out of the household
the guards faithfully doing their job
in the commotion a palace maid was injuried
how dare they have the audacity to disobey my orders
do you know why?
your majesty
I heard from the guards, its because wan concubine fainted
they wanted to get the imperial physician
the guards followed their orders
refusing to let them leave
outrageous
I only order to ground her
you guys actually refuse to let her seek medical attention
what if anything happens to her
are you going to bear the blame?
your servant deserve to die!
send the guards on duty to the division of punishment
yes your majesty
at your service
get the imperial physician over immediately to wan concubine
report back to me of any situation
get wen physician specifically!
your highness is awake
don't move, your hand has just been applied frostbite medicine
recuperate first
you must be hungry
come send it over
wen physician has left instruction
to use frozen donkey-hide gelatin stew bird nest
your highness, please drink it while its hot
wen physician
your highness, your servant congratulate your highness
congratulation your highness
your highness, wen physician said
you are one month pregnant
jin xin
you and the physician stay behind
the rest of you leave
your highness, your servant has just taken your pulse
you are emotionally unstable, the fetus is unstable
you cannot afford to be emotionally unstable anymore
how do you think things are looking?
this is your highness only chance to turn things around
your majesty has already received the news of your highness pregnancy
he has order me to personally take care of your highness
her majesty has also ordered me
to take special care of your highness diet
your highness, you can set your mind at ease
is that so?
do you think that
this is my chance to turn things around
if that is so
what you have said previously
why isn't there any orders to revoke the grounded edict
your majesty also didn't said any words of comfort
this so call babysitting
is also because of the child in my stomach
its not because of me
your highness
don't worry
I will not take my life
for the child's sake
that's good to hear
your servant and lady hui
are afraid that your highness will do injustice to yourself
with your word
your servant will do his very best to take good care of your highness
you and I have known each other for so long
when have you ever seen me doing injustice to myself
i only know that me and the baby inside of me
are in your care
rest assured
your servant will give his best
to take care of your highness and the baby in you
this isn't only just for your highness
its also for lady hui
gratitude towards your highness
the days that I have been grounded
sister you must had been worried
yes, restless sleep and any food taste bland
all together was refuse entry
her lady was so anxious
tell my lady hui to rest assure. i'm fine
your servant understands
your highness rest well for the baby
your servant shall take his leave
jin xin
this time with a child is also not too bad
his majesty wouldn't be so heartless then
its also a blessing that its wen physician looking after you
your servant is rest assured
you also feel that his majesty is too heartless?
so many children in this palace are not able to be deliver safely
her majesty is very wary
your highness has to be careful from now onwards
jin xin get me the brush and ink
your highness is still weak
if theres anything, wait till you get better
go get it
i got it
now that i'm pregnant
his majesty will be oblige to read my letters
you must think of ways to send it to him
what has your highness wrote?
i beg his majesty
to get her majesty to personally overlook my pregnancy
her majesty, the empress!?
your highness has always been wary of her
you been grounded, isn't that the doing of the empress
why would you want the empress to overlook personally
only because in the palace the empress is high above all
if i want to keep this child
with only myself its will not be enough
her majesty set up this trap to do me in
she must have hated me to the core
naturally she will hate the child in me
i want her to take care of everything
if there is any mishap
she will have to take reponsibility
she will nonetheless do her very best
to keep this child
for every thing to be smooth
this is the best plan
if your highness wants to regain his majesty favour
all of this will have to be pin on this unborn child
i just hope this child can grow up well safely
take it
im afraid the bird nest has already turn cold
let me go get you some milk instead
do that later
my taste bud feels bland
let liu zhu give instructions to the kitchen
to make a bowl of shrimp congee
separated this period of time, do you feel more at ease?
i cant seem to settled down
the news from wan concubine keeps bothering me everyday
but i cant go closer to get a better look
you have to know the son of heaven is angry
so I advise you
don't rub it on, in the teeth of the storm
even if its the peak of the storm
wan concubine days would be like hell
this times wan concubine should be living in hell
she should struggle
if these times, the emperor
still protect and shield her
I would be so worried
but wan concubine only worn a wrong clothing item
his majesty does not have to go to that extreme
althrough i won't ask more than i should
but there must be other reasons
I beg of your majesty, empress dowager to sae wan concubine!
now is not the time yet
i cant promise you
your majesty
you don't understand
the emperor has to get his angry off his chest
only then
wan concubine will have a chance to find favor
otherwise even if she is release
do you think she will have good days ahead?
more ever this issue involves the empress
if the emperor don't want to budge, nobody can do anything about it
your highness
your highness is now a pregnant mother
one person eat, two person nourish
drink more
where's liu zhu
when you guys came in to gave your congrats
did you see her?
your highness looks that your servant doesn't serve you good enough?
why do you keep thinking of liu zhu?
where's liu zhu?
nothing's wrong
its just that these few days she didn't rest well
caught a cold and is resting
i shall go take a look
your highness
she just fell asleep
you have just woke up
why not go visit her later
don't try to stop me. i'm going to take a look
your highness!
don't bother
liu zhu...
shes no longer around
what did you say?
how did you think wen physician came in?
the people outside didn't listen to our plea
liu zhu sacrifice herself by the blade
the other outside were afraid of the higher up blaming them hence
wen physician was able to come over
fortunately its wen physician that came over
but liu zhu
she's no longer alive
you...
i already said earlier not to let your highness know about it
afraid that it might harm the fetus
your highness, your servant knows your upset
but no matter how sad your highness must understand
the most important issue at hand is to preserve yourself
liu zhu died for your highness
your highness must not let her death be in vain
only with your highness well
then can you exact revenge for liu zhu
liu zhu and I have grown up together since young
shes like my blood sister
your highness!
no don't!
your hand has only just been bandage
what to do if you made the wound worse
has your highness forget that day how lady chun died
at that time you can endure
why not now!?
if your highness injure yourself
in future
how would you exact revenge for liu zhu
you are right
i can only continue living on
liu zhu's sacrifice then would not be in vain
greeting royal mother
get up
yes
whether im at ease or not, things are still how it is
whether the children of the emperor is good and well is what that has me worrying
are you referring to wan concubine's unborn child?
from what i heard from the emperor
wan concubine would like you to protect this child
i am not that capable
even my elder prince i couldn't protect
you have the capability, this i believe
since you have put it this way
i shall not refuse
looking after all the concubines and ladies is the empress's duty
its good that you know your own duties
being in your position, if you want to protect it
you must overcome the hard with the soft, and be generous
you are the empress of the qing dynasty
also the emperor's empress
your every action affects everybody
even more so to reputation of our family
you are my niece
I hope you will protect the reputation of the empress
protect the honor of the royal family
i got it
protect others which in turn is also protecting yourself
what a surprise that you came to see me on your own initative
after recovering, i have been weak ever since
render me unable to serve your majesty, i seek yourmajesty's understanding
you came over not to just tell me this i guess
i have a request, please forgive wan concubine
I accepted your audience not because i want to hear this from you
since your majesty is willing to see me, you should have known
i am going to request this of you
say your piece,the final decision still lies with me
I beg your majesty on behalf of the unborn child
right now wan concubine is unsettled, no appetite
how can she be able to peacefully nurture the child
I have already instructed steward gou
and i have read wan concubines letter
permitted the empress to look after the unborn child
and issue an edict
to reinstate her royal concubine's treatment, but lady wan is still unsettled
without your majesty's forgiveness she keeps being paranoid
why not let me go over to take care of lady concubine
to look after her with due diligence, i have given whatever that is possible
its just that i have spoil wan concubine
so much that she doesnt know limit, doing whatever that she wants
she deserve to be punish, alright end of disscusion
your majesty, her majesty seeks an audience
summon her, right away
take your leave now
greeting to your majesty
hundred thousand blessing to your majesty
I just met hui concubine on my way in
she must have been here for the same issue as me
your majesty, wan concubine is pregnant
at least pay her a visit
forget it
might as well dont go
once the child is born, we will have to meet eventually
wan concubine so far is still under house arrest
I wonder wherethe your majesty can revoke your orders
there is no need for that
just let her stay in there and nurse her child instead of running around
then I shall send physicians over regularly to check up on her
to look after her well being
if she wishes to go to the royal garden, she must be accompany.
sure. in future
this kind of trival issue, do as you deem fit
dont bother asking me
i shall do as you ask
hui concubine got wen physician to send over this inner shirt
is so exquisite, little kids wearing is
will look so cute
it has already been five months
his majesty doesnt even drop by
he must have been sick of me
if he doesnt drop by, there is nothing we can do
on the other hand, dao concubine and jing concubine
always send their regards on behalf of wen physician
but an concubine has never ever ask of you
its just so sad
in reality
since when do people stick with you through good and bad times
people are like that
why should i feel sad
your highness
wen physician
concubine hui has send your servant to bring over this snack
right now i am free
she still thinks of me
your servant has also bought a good news to your highness
your highness feel much better after hearing this
speak
since your highness was grounded, your highness has always been worrying about your family outside of this forbidden palace
this your highness need not worry
from what I heard, your family has not been implicated
but they are very worried about your highness precadiament
your news
indeed has set my set my mind at ease
please send my regards to my family
everything is well
there is no need for concern
i will do as you say
wen physician has just came over
the child is stable
everything is fine
the child is safe
looks like
in a few more month she will give birth
your majesty, shall we?
his majesty has personally instructed me to look after the child
how can i disappoint him
as long as im involved
nobody shall stir up any problem
what if she loses the child herself?
from what i have been hearing
concubine wan has been emotionally unstable
she cannot afford to break down
otherwise it would affect the child
not only that, once she comes to due,if shes not careful
both the child and her will be in danger
I have already stripped him of his rank and sent him home
The officials in the capital,
are still going to petition against him?
hence i compile everything
and distributed it over the empire
has it been seen to?
your majesty
your servant has went over the details
coming to this kind of issues
only then will will you find out whether the subordinates below are loyal or not
I
since my ascension, I have been worried about fractions
but that has yet to be resolve
this is a good time to see whether the officias has any other ulterior motive
Since
Chen Ban Yan is corrupt
then
strip Chen Ban Yan of his title and rank
wu xiao ge is to be exiled
I shall do as you instruct
But there is something that I have to report
King: Speak  Servant: It involves zhen officer
Speak
Give him three days
If he is willing
otherwise I will also deal with him
but
zhen yuan dao is wan concubine, paternal father
I'm afraid
this will alarm concubine Wan and her unborn child
that would not be good
I have my own ways
You go and persoanlly speak Qian Ming Shi
Zhen Yuan Dao
Why is he involved
Yes
sorry to trouble you, please announce our arrival
what a coincidence, our master has just fallen asleep
Now that her highness is pregnant,
of course she has to rest well, we shall wait
Oh, right, Miss
has her highness's cramp condition any better?
there hasnt been any improvement
she has problem sleeping at nights
Then she should drink more bone broth
with a dash of vinegar
give her more tofu and fruits in her daily diet
only then can it help to alleviate her cramps symtoms
er drink some milk before sleeping
this will help counter insomnia
I understand, from now onwards i will make bone broth daily for my master
Is wan physician outside?
Let him in, Yes I understand
After Physician Wen
Please heed my advise, Since your highness has insomnia
Its mainly because of worrying too much
This is not something that medicine can helpl relieve
Since you are well aware of this
Why mention it anyway
LAter when you report to the empress
Please send regards on my behalf
that everything is well
I understand, His majesty has request of her to take care of you
You would not dare to do anything to your highness and the unborn child
She often summon your humble servant for questioning
Im relieve that you know how to deal with her
I understand
Please come with me to get the medicine
Then bring it back to prepare the medicine
Remember to personally give it to her highness
do not allow anyone else to interfere
I understand. Wen physician is indeed understanding
Is my sister's hui concubines hand recovering?
It has been much better now
Even through her wound is slow to recover
But it will be completely healed before autumn
Just that there will be a minor scar
Scar?..
My sister didnt use scar relieve gel?
I still have duties to attend to.
I shall take my leave.
your highness
If an concubine has anything to pass to you
Please let me screen it through before consuming
Sir wait a second
If you want me to nurse my child in peace
Please be frank with me
You are making me uneasy on purpose
what is it? please dont hesitate to tell me
Inside that scar relieve gel...
There is something else
inside the scar relieve gel
musk?
there is musk inside the gel. isnt it?
Yes...
Yes
There is an unknown amount of musk inside the gel
entry into the body through the wound
will be the eqivalent daily dosage
the gel is to cover up the musk's scent
Unless it s a specialist
that person wouldnt not be able to concoct it otherwise
actually, it might not be concubine an's doing
after all the pain relieve gel in your palace
is accessible to anyone
your highness
are you naseous
human true nature makes me feel even more disgusting
does sister mei knows about this?
I do not dare rave about this
she must be kept in the dark
if this is indeed concubine an's doing
she must have held a grudge
now that I have lost favor
my sister must have been in even worse shape
dont forget to tell mei sister
do not by all means offend the empress and an ling rong
do you get it?
you may go
your highness should be happy instead
an's concubine dedication
if she is a spy before
then now she is a famous spy
isnt this even better for us to be prepare against?
you are in the light
of course the lesser enemy you have
the better it is
are you
hurt about the relationship with your sisters?
looks like she and me
can still be consider sisters'
your affinities and concubine hui is a rare thing to come by
but you cannot expect everybody to recipocate
I dont understand
Is this how she repay me
even if one day the truth is reveal
it will be an ugly truth
You may be true and good to an concubine
but not everybody will reciporcate
I know that the current me
does not have any means to retaliate
what you said is true
good and bad
its all for personal gains
I was once panariod
liu ru might be acting under another's instruction
but whether she's willing or not
it is still her doing
yi xin, im here
you made me realise in time
your highness values this relationship hence your upset
but you must remember
in this harem, even if its blood sister
you would still turn against each other
You're right
Master and subject relationship is indeed so
this so call sister
Last night
you didnt get to sleep well
why not go back to sleep
you may leave
get su bi to serve me, I understand
Yes, your Majesty
I shall take my leave
how is it over at her side?
Your majesty
You seal the palace to forbid entry and exit
you are getting over your head
forgive your humble servant insolence
I'm afriad once you know you will be worried
is she not feeling well anywhere?
I thought she has already past her third month phrase
what your majesty knows
her previous pregnancy, she had a miscarriage
now that she is under house arrest, she must be feeling pent up
from what yin xi said, her highness couldnt sleep well
Think about it, if her highness cant sleep well, then the royal child
also cant sleep well
what you said is the truth
its too hot i cant sleep either
accompany me to take a walk outside
let me summon a sedan
what if your majesty collapse from the heat, then your humble servant deserve a hundred thousand death
no need for a hundred thousand death, you being like this
dying once is enough
I have somewhere that i want to go
then I shall get an umbrella
hundred thousand blessing to your majesty
does she often sleep in this uneasy state?
these few days her highness felt the movement of her child
hence unable to sleep well
thus she appear to be worn out
how is her appetite? does she finish the food that is send here?
she is upset
her appetite is decreasing
everything taste bland
that is her fault then
for the sake of the child, she should at least eat some
its not that her highness doesnt want to eat, i know
its starting to get late, your majesty
it wouldnt be nice if other hears of this
serve your master faithfully
you will stand to gain
i understand
I seek your forgiveness your highness. i did not mean to intrude
its just that his majesty had instruction
to accompany your higness wherever you go
to take care of your well being
being look after
under survelliance
to me
his majesty edict means the same thing
if your highness is tired, you should take a rest at the pavillion
to catch your breath
as you progress further into pregency, it cant be help to feel tired easily
this incident
if only back then your servant had groom your highness better
to prevent such injustice upon entering the palace
to suffer this injustice
both me and you sister, are not saints
how would we know what is going to happen in future
actually his majesty is still concern about your highness
is that so?
is he worried about me
or my unborn child?
His Majesty,
greetings to your highness
its just a royal concubine that has lost favor
whats more she is a sinner
why bother to show your respect towards her
her highness is still an upright person
women in the palace are like flowers in the garden
once it withers
it will blossom again
this batch withers
and in comes another new batch
just like endless spring blossom