Go.
My status is lowly.
I'm afraid of touching these auspicious objects.
Us servants shouldn't follow the Empress into the room
We don't want to offend the Gods
That's true.
It's better to be more cautious regarding such matters.GIve it to me.
Niang Niang.
You haven't drunk your pregnancy medication.
When I sent it to you just now, you said it was too hot.Now it's just warm.
If we leave it any longer, it'll turn cold.
Your Majesty.
The Empress, the two Jiejies, and I will be out soon.
When Empress Niang Niang is virtuous, she really is virtuous.
In the past, she didn't like Imperial Concubine Xi.
But now she accommodates to her needs.
Don't second guess the Empress.
I thank the Empress for fulfilling my wish
of personally tying the fortune pouch for me.
I'm the Empress. It's only right.
Logically, it's right, but emotionally speaking,
Empress must really hate me.
I gifted you the Childbirth Guanyin
in the hope that you would be at peace
and not become distracted. The most important thing right now
is to bear a child for the Emperor.
Whether or not I'll be able to give birth,is all in the hands of the Empress,
not me.
What do you mean?
Isn't that the case?
According to Niang Niang's wishes, the child lives. Against Niang Niang's wishes, both the mother and the child are ruined.
For so many years,
Empress Niang Niang has used this method to rule the six palaces.
I really am afraid.
I won't be able to keep the child in by belly.
if I somehow anger Empress Niang Niang one day.
Presumptuous! You dare to slander me?
Slander?
Let go!
Do you dare to swear to the gods that you have never harmed any of the Imperial offspring?
That you have never harmed anyone in the harem,that you have never harmed me?
I'm the mistress of the six palaces.
How can I swear at your whim?
Let go.
You don't dare to, do you?
Why did Consort Qi die?
Why is Ning Pin infertile?
Precious Fucha's miscarriage,
and my unborn child that year.
You've done so many evil things.
You yourself know clearly what you have done.
How did it turn out like this?
Niang Niang!
What happened to Niang Niang?
What happened to Niang Niang?  Summon the Imperial Doctor!
Niang Niang! Niang Niang! Huan Huan!
Huan Huan! Summon the imperial doctor!  Yes!  Niang Niang!
Imperial Doctor!  Huan Huan!
Imperial Doctor!  Get someone!
Get someone!
Hurry and summon the imperial doctor!  Niang Niang what happened?
Wake up Niang Niang!
Niang Niang,
reply to Emperor, Niang Niang is awake.
Noble Consort Xi, you have woken.
Noble Consort Xi, please suppress your sadness. You will still have children.
"You will still have children"?
Empress Niang Niang's simple words,
are you equating my child's life with that of a piece of grass?
Empress,
No matter how much you hate me,
why did you have to harm my child?
Ridiculous! When did I harm your child?
Emperor, Emperor.
My child is no more.
It wasn't because of my carelessness.
It was Empress Niang Niang.
She and I started an argument
and she pushed me!
Emperor, Niang Niang's abdomen area
does have signs of heavy trauma.
The imperial doctors can also testify
that there must have been a person who strongly pushed Niang Niang.
Besides, the fetus has always been healthy.
I'm sure the Emperor had also often heard of the fetus's movements.
If it wasn't for an accident,
miscarriage definitely wouldn't have occurred!
Empress, at that moment in the palace,
you were the only one present with Noble Consort Xi!
Emperor!
You,
and you.
At that time in front of the palace entrance,
did you guys see anything?
At that time I was talking with Imperial Noble Consort outside and didn't see anything.
But,
but imperial noble consort and I did
hear from inside the palace that Empress Niang Niang and Noble Consort Xi seemed to have started an argument.
Because they started a dispute, we dared not to intrude and intervene.
Though I did hear Noble Consort Xi saying words like "fear", "afraid", etc.
Empress also told Noble Consort Xi to know her place and be content with what she has.
The rest, I didn't see anything.
But my eyes and the eyes of many others saw
when Noble Consort Xi got hurt and fainted, only you were by her side.
Emperor, Empress hates how I get all your favor and love
and always thinks that I have a non-respectful heart so she rebuked me.
In her fury, she pushed me.
At that time Noble Consort Xi
I had to struggle just to get her grasp off me
But I didn't push Noble Consort Xi
According to what you're saying, then Noble Consort Xi pushed herself?
I don't understand either
Why would Noble Consort Xi have been unreasonable and disrespectful? She's normally so prudent and cautious
Even when taking her medicine, she never forgets to drink every bowl on time.
All these years, Noble Consort Xi has been nothing but polite to the Empress
Even if Noble Consort Xi said something to offend the Empress
the empress should have forgiven her
At least, the empress should remember that Noble Consort Xi is carrying the Emperor's child
You said that Noble Consort Xi was being unreasonable, so what did she say to offend you?
At the time there it was only the two of us
I know that there is nothing I can say for you to believe me
The only way that I would be implicated in this is if someone is trying to set me up
You may feel that there is nothing you can say to change my mind
But I cannot even understand why or how something like this could happen
There were only two of you in the room, and there was an argument
and you have always disliked Noble Consort Xi. I have seen all of these factors
Yet, Noble consort Xi has been constantly pleading for forgiveness and peace
She has been thinking in your shoes this whole time
I have no reason to harm Noble Consort Xi
All these years that I've managed the palace's affairs, have you ever seen me harm anyone?
Only you know the answer to that.
Emperor!
During the Tang Dynasty, in order to gain the emperor's affection
Consort Wu got rid of Empress Wang by murdering her own baby girl
and setting up Empress Wang for murder
My fate today is the same as the past Empress Wang
Emperor
From the empress's accusations, even my death would be nothing.
But my child,
my child didn't even get to open its eyes and look at the world
my child is so blameless
Long Yue, why are you crying?
I didn't see anything
I didn't see anything!
Come over here
What did you see? Tell your father.
Your dad is here, there is nothing to be afraid
Your Empress Mother is here too. Tell us what happened. Don't be afraid.
Tell me what happened
Empress Mother pushed Noble Consort Xi. She pushed her!
You're lying! You coached her!
Tell me! You coached her!
Or it was you!
Empress!
Emperor! I'm innocent
Everything happened so fast. How could I have know what was going to happen?
And then coach her?
She's only 6 years old
She can't even lie yet
Plus, Noble Consort Xi only just woke up
who could have coached her?
Emperor!
I'm just like Empress Wang; we're being set up!
I am not Emperor Tang
I am not easily fooled like him.
But you, you've always treated Noble Consort Xi as an enemy. You've been trying to get rid of her all this time
I swear upon my ancestors
I didn't do anything to harm Noble Consort Xi's fetus
This kind of swear
you may as well do in front of the Tai Hou's grave
You are cold and calculating
and have harmed royal children
From this day onward,
you are not allowed to leave your palace
Su Pei Sheng
take her away
Empress
Let's go
Forgive me for speaking out of place,
but is the matter about the Empress true?
You are an old counselor
You are allowed to ask
I have thoroughly investigated
It is irrefutably true
Emperor
Although the Empress is not as gracious and loving as the past Empress Chun Yuan
But she is not an evil doer
Regarding many matters in the past,
it's not that I wasn't suspicious.
I just didn't want to pursue it.
But regarding this matter,
the Empress has no way of denying it.
The Empress has been fine all along.Why would she suddenly do this?
When one has too many desires, it is impossible to make all of them come true
She wanted too much
Being Empress wasn't enough.
She still wanted to be the legitimate Empress Dowager!
I put Third Prince under her care.
But that only made her have delusional ambitions, beyond her place
The emperor is wise
In the future, whoever takes the throne
the empress will always been the Empress Mother
But the one holding power would be changed. How could she willingly watch that happen?
Then how do you plan on punishing her?
I've recently heard that there are many rumors
that many other children have died in the hands of the Empress
But rumors are just that, rumors.
Just like the Empress can only be the Empress.
If the Empress is removed, it will create mass chaos
I haven't thought that yet.
The position of the Empress must be stable in order for the country to be prosperous
I will have the Empress reflect upon her mistakes
and severely punish
Niang niang, drink some tea. Rest a little
No matter how much I repent right now, I can't shake the guilt I feel towards my unborn child
You had no choice
The child is gone
You were not fated to spend a long time with each other
Right now the most important thing is
Although the Emperor has put the Empress under house arrest, he hasn't punished her.
The Empress is Third Prince's adopted mother, and the Dowager's relative.
You need to get rid of her roots and ties
that way, she will have no support and help
Mother. The night is cold.
Don't keep kneeling at the expense of your health.
I've gotten someone to brew some bird's nest.
Get up and drink it.
Such a filial heart is hard to come by.
I know that you are upset over my yet-to-be-born brother, Mother.
I got some auspicious papers from Consort Fu
We should burn some for my unborn brother
so that he may rest in peace in heaven
You and Consort Fu have worked hard
You are sick, and I can't even help
I've been really worried
I know that you are filial.
How has Third Prince been lately?
I heard that Third Brother is begging Father regarding the Empress.
In the end, he got lectured by Father.
Third Prince was brought up by the Empress.
Now that the Empress is out of favor,
lessen your contact with him.
Yes.
The Third Prince relies on the Empress for support
They rely on each other
Naturally.
Everyday that the Empress is around,
Third Prince will have a chance to ascend the throne.
Everyday that Third Prince is around, the Empress will have a source of support.
Yes. I understand.
Fourth Brother has always been the most hardworking.
Even after getting married, you don't let up.
How are you so free to be standing here today?
It's Eighth Uncle's birthday today. I went to the dungeon to visit him.
You dared to visit Eighth Uncle?
Weren't you afraid of being seen by others?
If other's had asked, naturally I wouldn't say a thing.
But you're my Third Brother, as your younger brother, I wouldn't hide it from you.
How is Eighth Uncle then?
What do you think? He's under arrest, and he's better off dead.
Third Brother, there's something I've always wanted to say.
I don't know if it's appropriate, though.
We're brothers. There's no need to stand on ceremony. Say it.
Due to matters regarding ascension, Father had countless kin locked up.
This was the case with Eighth Uncle, Fourteenth Uncle...
These were all Father's closest kin.
If we can intercede on behalf of Eighth and Fourteenth Uncle,
and allow them to receive Father's mercy,
wouldn't that protect Father's reputation?
It will prevent people from a hundred years from now, thinking that it was kin killing kin
Plus, this will let the Dowager rest in peace
Next month is the birthday of the previous Emperor.
If the opportunity arises,
I want to beg for Father's mercy on behalf of Eighth and Fourteenth Prince.
This is the most filial thing I can do for the previous Emperor and the Empress Dowager.
You've thought long and hard about this. I didn't even think of it.
Ok, if I get a chance that day
I will definitely beg our father
and try to persuade him
Niang niang, drink some tea
The emperor still will not let you go outside
You've been with him for so many years
and you've never been house arrested before
Consort Xi is in favor right now, and she's been house arrested many times
I'm the Empress. I can handle it.
Oh yes, I heard that the Third Prince begged the Emperor for you
But he was lectured by the Emperor
Third Prince is so stupid. At this moment he should be protecting himself
He's just trying to be filial
When filiality is not used correctly, it can cause harm instead
Now I can only hope that on the past Emperor's birthday
Third Prince will meet my expectations
If Third Prince has a good future
then all this suffering will not have been for nothing
You have performed your duties well
My father's ceremony was performed very well
Thank you father
I have seen all of your good work
That's right, I've heard that
you've been to prison to see your uncle Yin Ci many times
Yes
Eighth Uncle is very miserable
Wow, you are so gracious and loving
Eighth uncle made a big mistake
No matter how much you punish him, he deserves it
But in the memory of your father
Eighth prince is your brother after all
I would think that if grandfather was alive, then
he would want to see all his sons getting along
What else?
Also,
Fourteenth Uncle
Father,
Fourteenth uncle is my blood uncle
he's your pure brother
but he's been under house arrest this whole time
I remember when grandfather was alive, Thirteenth Uncle was also under house arrest
And father, you begged grandfather for Thirteenth Uncle's release
It would be nice if, in the memory of grandfather,
you could let Fourteenth Uncle free
I see you've been thinking about your uncles quite frequently
I don't dare
But I heard that when the Dowager was ill, she kept asking for Fourteenth Uncle
I was thinking...
If at the time, Fourteenth Uncle could have been there...
If your Fourteenth Uncle was free,
then the Dowager's illness would have been cured?
You think I've been unfilial towards the Dowager?
I don't dare
You don't dare?
Weren't you just talking about brotherly love?
About how my lack of brother love
resulted in my brother's disrespect towards me
Filiality
You were saying how I am not filial
so there is no need for you to be filial to me as well?
That's not what I meant
Father
I was thinking for your legacy
Father,
Even if my uncles have mistakes
they are still your brothers
Though Empress has made mistakes
she is still your wife.
I can withstand your momentary anger
but I must think for your legacy
You house arrested your brothers and wife
I am worried
how others will guess...
How the people will think?!
What I think you really want is to be my ruler as well
Though I am your father
you have not gotten the facts right
and have already accused me of crimes
In your eyes, am I such a terrible Emperor?
Or have you long watched my "mistakes" and have been wanting to replace me?
I don't dare! I don't dare!
Since I ascended the throne
your Eighth and Fourteenth uncles
have done nothing but createdtrouble and disrespect me. You have seen all of this.
Yet today, you have switched sides
You want to beg for those that wish me harm
You have joined forces to besmirch my name
As for your Empress mother, why I have chosen to house arrest her,
is not only for Noble Consort Xi's unborn child
All this time, your Empress has created trouble
just to make sure you ascend the throne in the future
Father  You still dare call me father?
You are my oldest son, but you are weak and useless
Yet I have always spoke up for you, cherished you and forgiven you
Unfortunately fate wouldn't have it
somehow I have taught you to become someone else's son!
To the point that you beg for your Eighth uncle! Why don't you be his son instead!
Father
You can be angry
but you don't want me as a son anymore?
It was you that didn't want me as a father, not the other way arround
Su Pei Shen!
Enforce my decree: Third Prince is not allowed in the palace anymore
He has empathized with Eighth Prince
Let him be Eighth Prince's son
Eighth Prince made mistakes, so he was stripped of honors
And is no longer in the family tree
Since Third Prince is now his son
He must also be stripped of honors
Remove his honors right now
And give it to Lord Heng
I do not have this son
Emperor...  Do it now!
I obey
Niang niang
Something terrible has happened!
Third Prince
he...
said something wrong again?
It's ok if he couldn't convince the Emperor to release me
Most important is that he still cares for me
which means that I can rise again in the future
The emperor stripped him of his royal honors
and made him Eighth Prince's son instead
What did you say?!
The decree was already given to the officials
You're lying!
Third Prince is the Emperor's son! This is not possible.
I don't dare to make this up. Third Prince spoke up for 8th and 14th uncle, and you. So the emperor accused him of treason
Everything was fine. Why did he speak up for those criminals?
All my effort these past years has been for nothing
It is all wasted
Niang niang, think of something to save him!
Useless!
The emperor has always been cold. So little and he has broken this father son bond.
Niang niang
If Third Prince can't ascend the throne...
If there's no 3rd prince, there is always 4th and 5th prince, and so on
Plus there is also a 6th prince now
6th prince?
Just like how Consort Qi died. If there wasn't Zhen Huan
then I could have raised 6th prince
It's all ok
as long as I am still Empress, I can still rise again
No one's child matters!
If my child was still alive, I would be the only Dowager Empress
Have you prepared the object that I asked for?
Yes, everything is ready. But the Empress doesn't know. Should I tell her?
If a master suffers humiliation, it is only because the servant was useless.
I've been with the Empress so many years. She's never suffered this kind of humiliation
A royal Empress house arrested after being set up by a lowly consort?!
She even caused the Empress to lose 3rd prince as support. This cannot be the law of the land.
But this is too big. If anything goes awry, then both our lives will be in danger
It doesn't matter if I lose my life. As long as Noble Consort Xi is gone, then the Empress can rest easy.
Give it to me
17th brother
Our father's ceremony is over
I've remembered the times when he was still alive
the things I taught you
It was such foresight
Thus the tears today
As a family, we should remember our brotherly love
I thank you for your love and concern
Sit down, Sit down
Family members don't need to be so polite
If our father was alive
seeing that you have a family now
and almost a child
he would be very happy
Everything that I have was given to me with your blessing
I have not forgotten our father's teachings
You have respected your brothers
and respected your place and title
We are
merry brothers and good court members
Yes
A little brother is in my stomach. 6th prince, do you like him?
I want a little sister
What about you my lord?
Both are good
6th prince is so little and he likes your child
They must be fated to be together
Of course cousins are fated to be together
6th prince
Come and drink some soup
Don't bother your aunt
But I want my aunt to feed me!
Ok, your aunt can feed you
What's wrong?!
Get the doctor!
Doctor!
What's wrong? She was fine earlier!
Yes,... it looks like poison
There's poison in the food. Guards! Protect the emperor!
Emperor, if her Ladyship is truly poisoned, then this place is not safe. You should go back to your palace
I am not leaving. I want to see who dares
to poison in front of me
Move her to the back room
My Lord
I'm here
My lord
Hurry
Silver needle?
It's poison
Poison?
Oh no, she's already 8 months pregnant
Get the medicine to induce labor
Hurry
My lord, let me feel her pulse
It is fortunate that she did not ingest too much poison. It did not harm the fetus.
My lord, rest assured. The doctors will take care of her.
I will go and report to the emperor
Hurry
My Lord,
who would want to harm me?
Emperor,
Her ladyship was poisoned
Why would there be poison at a royal feast?
What was the last thing she ate?
She was feeding 6th prince's food to him
Jin Xi
The needle turned black. Indeed there was poison
What about this bowl?
This bowl has poison too
Because someone wants to kill me and 6th prince
Her ladyship was collateral
I am here
Investigate!
How could these dirty things
get into Noble Consort Xi and 6th prince's food
My Lord
Am I going to die soon?
Don't think too much. The doctors are all here
My lord, I let you drink too much
and that's the only reason we had this child
Don't say that
I will stay by your side
I will always stay by your side
I have investigated
The royal kitchen prepared the food and the servants brought it over
The servant that brought Noble Consort Xi and 6th Prince's soup say that
on the way she ran into the Empress's servant, Jian Qiu
Jian Qiu opened the food to see what was inside
Other than that, no one else has touched the food
I have brought Jian Qiu with me
Bring her in
Who told you to do this
Who. Told. You. To. Do. This?
No one
It was all my idea
Was it the empress?
She is house arrested
She doesn't know anything about this
It was all my idea
She wants to commit suicide!
Emperor
Why can't you believe the empress?
She is your wife! She truly loves you!
Take her away and punish her severely!
Make her tell us the truth!
She is your wife! She is the empress!
Emperor
Why can't you believe her?
Take her away
Noble Consort Xi, aren't you afraid of bad karma?
You will die horrifically
Noble Consort Xi, you are an evil person!
Evil person!
Emperor, she has given birth to a boy
But her ladyship was weak after labor
and the poison too effect. She has just passed away.
Jian Qiu
niang niang
Where is Jian Qiu
Why haven't I seen her?
Also where is Jiang Fu Hai?
Would you like some water? I can get it
I am asking you a question!
Why are you changing the subject?
What could it possibly be that I can't handle?
Jian Qiu has not returned
Eunuch Jiang has also been taken away
Who dares!
How could anyone just take my people away?
No one even asked me
It was the corrections facility... they were obeying the emperor's orders
They said it was unnecessary for you to know
What happened?
I do not know
I just heard that
Jian Qiu tried to harm Noble Consort Xi
and poisoned her Ladyship
We've tortured you. Are you ready to tell the truth now?
The empress never did anything
There is nothing to say
You can't just torture me until I lie
The Emperor will not believe such confessions
In the future
The Empress will not forgive you stupid lot
I are obeying the emperor's orders
To use all means necessary
to get the truth out of you
Even if your body is made of steel
you can't withstand all the torture
If you don't want to tell the truth
then let's use the needles
You don't dare!  Whether or not we dare is not up to us,
It is up to this needle
If this needle dares to pierce your fingers
You will not confess? Let us do this first.
Let me go!
We told you to tell us the truth!
What about you?
Will you speak?
Speak!
Who knows if those servants will speak?
Don't they say that the servant in charge
is more effective than prison guards?
But Jian Qiu has always been loyal to the Empress
I'm worried she won't tell
If not Jian Qiu, there is always Eunuch Jiang
If not Eunuch Jiang
there is always the servant Wei Chun.
At least one of them will give it up
Once one hole has ripped open
the rest will come falling out
Hearing you say this, I feel a lot better
The drama has gotten so big
If we don't continue to poke at the Emperor's emotional scar even more
then, it will be truly out of hand