The Legend Of Zhen Huan Episode 73
Your Majesty
Huangshang
Xi Guifei has been waiting inside for a while
call the 17th Prince waiting here
he can't go in without Zhen's call
Huangshang are back
why look at Chenqie like this, Huangshang?
since when?
Chenqie are slow
don't know what Huangshang mean?
Zhen has been favoring you
but at this moment
Zhen hate this face of yours
someone just told Zhen
the story of Zhaojun
is Muoge
Muoge came to see Zhen on a special purpose
ask Zhen allow you to marry him
when did he lay his eyes on you?
Chenqie is a concubine of the Heavenly Emperor
how could I marry someone for such purpose?
Muoge is ridiculous
How could Zhen not know he's ridiculous?
Zhen used you words to block his mouth
but he brought up the precedent of Han Yuan Emperor
compare Zhaojun to you, and asked Zhen to give my own favor up
this face of yours attracts Zhen so much
can attract others too
Zhen should not have you seen him
Ming Fei (zhaojun) going to the West
was the hear break of Yuan Emperor's life
chenqie is Huangshang's concubine
if this happens
how could the royal son and the princesses
spend their lives with their heads up?
he told Zhen
he doesn't care these
as long as he likes
he can accept anything, not mention it is you
if Muoge had the evil thought because of Chenqie
Chenqie is willing to destroy my face to preserve my integrity
it is not that important if it is only about face
though Qing forced back Zhungeer with plaque
it is not certain that
they won't find the antidote against the plaque
furthermore, the war is continuous still
the vitality of Qing has been undermined greatly
Zhen have asked the Treasure
gathering all grains to one place
it provides the military for only three to five months
if the stalemate lasts
it is only getting worse, not better
Muoge told Zhen in a way that couldn't be more clear
if allow you to be Zhungeer's concubine
and provide the prescription to cure the plague
the big army of Zhungeer will withdraw
and each year
pay him 3000 jin grain,
and 100,000 tael of silver
and never have war with Qing
Chenqie see
Chenqie as a Guifei
have Huangshang's favor for many years
this is the time to repaying Huangshang's favor
Chenqie won't dare to protect myself
I'll do what Huangshang wish
Zhen is the Emperor of the country
let...
let you decide yourself
Chenqie
wouldn't dare to forget Huangshang's favor
Guifei Niangniang think again, you can't do this
though Xi Guifei niangniang doesn't protect herself
that could put the royal brother in a position of injustice
Prince,
Huangshang hasn't called, and you couldn't come in
Guo Junwang would feel bad if he couldn't finish his words
Guo Junwang worry too much
Bengong is voluteered
Huangshang didn't force me
Niangniang don't want to make it difficult for the royal brother
but once Ninagniang marries Zhungeer
Royal Brother would be like Han Uuan Emperor
a laughing stuff of the future generation
but how to reply to Muoge?
Roral Brother, Xi Guifei is the mother of three children
her position is high and glorious
if send Xi Guifei to marry other
the princes and the princess
ask about their mother in future
how Huang Xiong reply to them?
furthermore
zhungeer is tens of thousand li away from here
if the royal brother miss Xi Guifei
it won't be possible to see her again
Huangshang loves Guifei
certainly won't want to use Niangniang's life to maike peace at the border
if Zhungeer really wants to use marriage to make peace
why don't Huangshang choose another beautiful and talented woman to marry Muoge?
that would save Niangniang
and save the face for Muoge
you know
once you love someone, it is extremely difficult to change
since Muoge dares to ask for Xi Guifei
he must've determined to get her
you thought that another woman
could make Muoge happy and withdraw?
nothing for you here. go outside
either another woman
or Guefei
it is to sacrifice a woman to protect homeland
what's the difference?
if Zhungeer uses this precedent, asking bribes and women year after year
wouldn't it make women accept cruelty?
where is the integrity of Great Qing?
Chendi thought that this is umproper
it is Zhen
who was deceived
I didn't even know
when Muoge noticed Xi Guifei
that put me in a position that no matter what I do would be hard and lose face
huang Xiong, it is not that we couldn't beat Zhungeer
do you think Zhen want to give up Xi Guifei?
it is not that we can't fight
but we can't fight like this without ending
the situation now
you thought how many good generals Great Qing still has?
in the History of Han, use marriage for peace was the worst strategy they had
if Huang Xiong don't think your younger brother useless
I'm willing to lead army to the West
I won't be back without defeating Zhungeer
you told Zhen
what you ask is for Great Qing
or for her?
Huang Xiong tried so hard
was to make your brother
to say this?
you had been cautious
yet heard that
Zhen would allow Xi Guifei marrying to Zhungeer
you ran into the palace boldly
in general
you had paid little attention to the politics
you knew also that
Zhen don't like to have princes to be in charge of army
but for her
you asked Zhen let you lead military to against Zhungeer
Zhen hate self blind before
didn't find out the secret affair between you two
Huang Xiong is mistaken
if it is not for your running into the palace
Zhen would never
believe what others said
saying that two of you met secretly outside the forbidden City
and Zhen didn't know anything
you...
you are really good
Huang Xiong
Xi Guifei has been following the rules of the harem
Chen Di was careless and impolite
to enter the palace without calling
but Chen Di is a person of Great Qing
couldn't stand the insult imposed
by Zhungeer humiliating us with the demand of the marriage
though Chen Di is useless
I am paid as Qin Wang
I should make my contribution to the country
until death
you continue
Chen Di understand what Huangshang suspect
that's all because Huang Xiong care Xi Guifei so much
congratulate to Xi Guifei
yet last tow years
Zhen heard many gossips
saying that since you married Yu Fujin
you two are not getting along
even Huang Xiong have to be bothered by the things in the harem
certainly can understand that
it is not easy to stand between Yuying and Jingxian
deep feeling causes jealousy, and jealousy causes suspicion
not getting along
is really feelings too deep
the worst between husband and wife
is suspicion
Chenqie is not afraid to suffer for Great Qing
there was the thing of Doctor Wen
Wangye got implicated today
Chenqie couldn't help but feel disheaten
dishearten?
Zhen had a moment of suspicion
the 17th brother
married Yuying because of the little portrait
that little portrait
had really resembled Yuyin
but it is okay if saying it resembles you
Zhen won't dare to think further
Huang Xiong really thinks too much
it is Zhen that thought too much
Xi Guifei is either intentional
or not
she is between our brothers
and caused the attraction of outsiders
is a real evil flood
Zhen will allow the request of Zhengeer
sending her far away from Great Qing
marry Zhungeer to make peace
please think over more, Huang Xiong
Zhen have decided, and
won't change
banquet in a Spring day
a cup of green wine and a song
bow again to make three wishes
first is to wish husband living one thousand years
second wish is for me be healthy
third wish is to be swallows on beam
see each every year
Chenqie is a deserted woman
today I can use my body
to serve Huangshang
Chenqie couldn't refuse
even if couldn't see Huangshang every year
still hope Huangshang healthy
and living forever
you go out now
Yes.
Zhen ask you
what is you plan
after allowing the marriage?
Chenqie couldn't take the insult of others
and damage the reputation of Huangshang
Zhen is not Han Yuan Emperor
I don't want you to be Zhaojun who went and never came back
even the 17th Prince had some bad intention to you
Zhen wouldn't be really angry with him
everyone likes beauty
no wonder they are longing for your beauty
yet
no matter how others admire your beauty
your heart can only be here with Zhen
Huangshang gave an edict last night and said Sister is seriously ill
but not allow to visit
not only claim she is ill but not allow visit
what Huangshang has done is like house arrest
Huangshang intends to use marriage for peace
once Xi Guifei is sent out of the country
Huangshang will held funeral ceremony for Xi Guifei
after that
she won't exist in the world
here is Yuanming Yuan, everything is inconvenient
if the 17thi brother's news is accurate
we go back to the House first
discuss there
Huangshang is going back in a few days
we should go back immediately
don't know how he is
Niangniang is locked up here and don't know what is happening
still worry about the 17th Prince
I'm afraid that Yunli can't hold back any longer
I bowed Huangshang farewell yesterday
bid Huangshang living thousand years
only hope Yunli
doesn't lose control for me
it doesn't matter what happens to me
don't want to hurt him more
this Huangshang
is too cruel
nurture into jade color, sell to royal house
everything including life belongs to Huangshang
so called favor and love
can't compare with the future of the country and the crown
if I asked Huangshang to pity and protect me
I didn't know how much I was worth
Nubi saw that
Niangniang seems giving up
Huangshang has suspected me
between him and me,one person can't be saved
if it is him,
I'd rather be me
Niangniang shouldn't believe such a foolish idea
if fear death
house of the 17th Prince won't be survived
it's better to let me die
Huangshang still cares those children
won't kill them all
and you thought
if he dies
could I live?
if Niangniang ends as such
Wangye would get the same
I'll try my best to protect them
Wangye
don't go
my heart has gone
Huangshang is so suspicious
and you have endured for so long
why at this most dangerous time
you want to risk everything?
you have know and no more questions
you know.
you cares the older sister so much
that not care about your own life?
to protect me, she can sacrifice herself
me, too
how could what she did is to protect you?
it is to protect herself
there is only death without the marriage for peace
she could be live with the marriage
Wangye, didn't you know the temperament of the older sister?
not long after she got the news of your death
she went back to the harem
why don't you for her
still give up your safety and prosperity?
there were difficulties at the time for each of us
don't talk about it
between me and Huaner
we don't give thought about such things
if something happens to her
you won't have a good time for the rest of your life
I never begged you before
I beg you this time
I beg you with my life
though the older sister is my real sister
and I'm grateful to her
you are my husband
you are the only man I love in my life
I'll hurt anyone for you
and not have you been hurt
Yuyin
I know I owe you
but I can't listen to you
do you think that Huangshang will forgive you if you can get her out?
wake up, Wangye
from the first moment I laid my eyes
on her
I knew there would be a day like this
I can't save myself
but I want to save her
everything has arranged
the news went out
and the 17th Prince Household thought that Xi Guifei had sent to the marriage for peace
nobody knows
in the carriage
there is only a prescription
for the plaque
this Muoge is really audacious,
dares to ask to marry Xi Guifei, and looks down upon the Heavenly Dynasty
the people that can accomplish great things don't sweat on trivial things
and won't be drown in a love affair
Zhen said only to give him a prescription for the plaque
he understood
but Muoge has been denied that
there is any secret affair between Guo Junwant and Xi Guifei
Muoge takes side with Xi Guifei, couldn't Zhen see it?
the most outrageous is Guo Junwang
who dares to eye on his royal sister-in-law
a disloyal heart
Zhen know you are effective; now it is up to Yunli
whether he'll pursue her to the West
if he does
that would be true that he pursued Zhen's woman
Nucai will have someone watching Xi Guifei
there won't be any leak
good
for Muoge leaving the capital
sent out the order.
going back to the Palace tomorrow
the 17th Prince,
you go without worry
every here Yurao and I won't tell anyone for now
hide now, can't hide forever
it will get you in trouble
17th Brother, take care
brothers
you are my close soldiers and guards
this trip to the West is dangeous
I'm afraid that I may not come back
but I still ask you
to help me
it is me
that owe you all apologies
Nucai want to follow Wangye
protect you with all we have, live or die
what has happened?
a person down there reported that
the 17th Prince with his people is pursuing out of the capital
Longyue is taller
come over, let Royal Father take a look
what is going on?
the Princess grows up, and has ideas
she heard that Hongyan and Lingxi are ill the day before yesterday
she wanted to go to see the brother and the sister
who would know that she couldn't sleep and worried after she came back
Zhen had seen Hongyan and Lingxi
doctor said that the illness were caused by upset stomach and worries
where are the worries from for such little person?
it must be the people there that didn't serve well
Zhen had scolded their wet nurses
Hongyan and Lingxi haven't seen their mother for a long time,
they miss her very much
I heard that Mother is seriously ill and couldn't get out of bed
Longyue couldn't ease the pain of brother and sister for missing Mother
could neither do my filial devotion at Mother's bed
that's why I am sad
Jing Niangniang and other mothers
love you very much
Longyue know
yesterday Lingyue read "Mencius"
Mengzi said that
first happiness is that parents are alive and brothers have no problems
second happiness is that being worthy of Heaven and others on Earth
the third happiness is to educate talents
Longyue wish to be Junzi, be fijial to Royal Father and mother, take care of younger brother and sister
something bothers Huangshang?
you haven't slept well for a few days
nothing. go to sleep
Xi Guifei is recuperating at Bitong Study
Huangshang have been worrying about her
let's take Sister Xi back
Chenqie know that
Huangshang care Sister Xi very much
go to sleep
though Huangshang let Niangniang back
that the 17th Prince went to the West for Niangniang is not over
I'm afraid that Huangshang will blame and question Niangninag more
even he let me back to the harem
look this Yongshou Palace, not even a ghost here
everyone thought that I was still at the Yuanming Garden
if I died at this moment
who would know?
Huangshang must've wanted to hear Niangniang
that's why he calls you to Yangxin Palace
Niangniang have to prepare for it early
Huangshang, Xi Guifei is here
Chenqie is well now,
special greetings to Huangshang
it was not a big deal that you were ill
but Guo Junwant thought that you married for peach
and dared to take his men to the West
Xi Guifei
his feeling to you is really not shallow
Chenqie should be died for ten thousand times for the crime,
and didn't even know that such thing happened
you deserve to die
can you say anything to defending yourself?
Guo Junwant was reckless to go to the West
but he did it for preserving the integrity of Great Qing
yet chasing the root
it was still caused by Chenqie
Chenqie is willing to take punishment by Huangshang
Zhen will punish you, of course
Chenqie submit to the order of Heaven
it is not only this one thing that Zhen want to punish you
several crimes, that make difficult for Zhen not to know where to start
Zhen saw you got leaner
you must've thought over your mistakes at Yuanming Garden
alright,
Su Peisheng
take Xi Guifei back to her palace
go to see your children
they miss you very much these days you were sick
Chenqie leave
Niangniang
go to greet your father
Huangshang, use some almond tea to moist your throat
Su Peisheng
Zhen forgave Xi Guifei as such
whether or not that would spoil her?
Huangshang, forgive Nucai to say something that I shouldn't
this has nothing to do with Xi Guifei
this is the fault of Yunli
he had his eyes on the concubine of Emperor, and went out of the capital without order
rebelliously amoral
Guo Junwant won't dare to be against Huangshang
Junli had submit his memorial
admitted his crime of leading a troop without permission
asking the punishment of guarding the border and enduring the harsh life of wind and sand
it is good that Guo Junwant doesn't come back
so that it won't cause the anger of Huangshang if Huangshang don't have to see him
what do you know
Zhen have to endure gossip if I punish him for this
and cause speculations on the harem
he wants punishment, Zhen want to award him
send my edict
Guo Junwang and Shen Beile are loyal to Emperor and defend the country
promote Guo junwant to Guo Qinwant
Shen Baile to Shen Junwang
Guo Qinwant stations outside of the Yanmen Pass
can't come back to the capital
without Emperor's order
obey the order
Three Years Later
beautiful flowers and full moon is easy to have
people cannot be together for long
Huan'er, at this moment
I hope, under this bright moonlight, you are safe and happy
these letters are true?
is it confirmed that is his handwriting?
it's confirmed
it was when Cucai greeted Yu Fujin that I stole
from the lower drawer of her dressing table
are these all?
Nucai were afraid to be discovered that were all I took
How is Guo Qinwang?
Huangshang, Guo Qinwang stations in Yanming Pass for three years, and
Zhunge'er didn't invade at all
Wangye guards the border, runs the army with strict disciplines
eats and sleeps with officers and soldiers, and didn't show any arrogance because of royalty
officers and soldiers all love him without exception
he wants to bribe for love of mass?
Chen guess that
maybe Wangye doesn't want to be the talk of others
Zhen have seen his memorial
saying that Spring wind won't across Yumen Pass
life in the Pass is harsh and cold
ask Zhen to care about the officers, soldiers, and the people at the border
reset Hu shi
let the people prosperous
what Guo Qinwang said is reasonable
it is reasonable though it is unnecessary for him to say
Zhen want him to guard the border, not involve in local politics
don't be angry, Huangshang
the medicine the doctor gave you
you have to avoid anger if taking it
three years
call him back to the capital
Mother, Look, dragonfly, red dragonfly
Lingxi, look
the lotuses on the lake are blooming
why do there only lotuses on the lake not other flowers?
because
the fragrance of the lotus is pure and sufficient
the fragrance of other flowers would make it worse
Lingxi, this is your 17th uncle
hello, 17th uncle
Lingxi grows so much
heard Wangye was coming back, didn't expect you were back so soon
I haven't been in the capital for a long time
my heart was like a flying arrow, and I came back nonstop
hadn't seen Xi Guifei for a long time
how are you doing?
with Wangye's blessing, I am doing well
have you seen Yuyin and Yunche?
I rushed to see Emperor to report my job and haven't be back to my house
I'll arrange someone to get them here immediately
the wind, the bitterness, and hardship at the Pass
every time Yuyin talked about it
we worried
thanks for the concerns of Xi Guifei
I had been written to Yuyin
so that she would worry less
everything is fine
Wangye
Nucai found you finally
Xi Guifei is happy
Wangye is happy
Huangshang is waiting for you
he waited, and waited, and worried, hurry up
I am going
Huangshang cares about his brother, send Nucai to have a look in particular
come
the 17th
give Zhen one true word
be blown by the wind of the border for three years
whom did you miss the most?
Mother
your brother is not a filial child
you dared to let a troop to leave the capital
you remembered your mother?
Chen Di have filial devotion, royal brother have, too
Huang Xiong is a wise emperor
certainly wouldn't blame Mother and Yuyin
for Chen Di's fault
go out, all of you
the 17th
you tell Zhen one true word
did you do anything improper with Xi Guifei?