Episode 51
What a clever woman
Do you know what I do
to clever women?
Kill me?
but people who were saved do not kill their savior
I never thought of killing you
Smart women who are also beautiful
It's very easy for people to like them
This brother here
Your comment is a little out of bound
When we like something, we like them
Not only like them
We want to own them
Don't forget
this is my country
There
will be a day, that it can be ours as well ours
We just saved your life
We can also kill you
With your ability?
It won't be that easy
Your Great Qing had a general named Nian Geng Yao in the past
but recently you don't even have anyone near his ability
not one that is comparable
I won't even bat an eye
but you're lucky
because you're hurt
Sir!
You made us search for you so hard
What happened?
Just now, i was bitten by a snake
Luckily they saved me
Thank you sir and miss
for saving our master
This master better becareful the next time he goes out
Maybe next time, you won't be so carefree like today
I understand the meaning of your words
Of course as I can see that you're someone who values your life
Judging from what you say
you know half about me already
You think that I know half about you
but it will be my fortune not to ever bump into you again
Please excuse me
Come, sir
Master
Slowly
Let's go
Thank you
Why did you bring so many books? Where did you get it from?
I brought those that Wang Ye liked
He asked them to bring it over today
I only need a few books
Why do you want so many from him?
Miss...teach me how to read and write can you?
Did you not want to learn before?
why the change of mind?
Isn't it better for me to know a little reading?
Missy always loves these
so i want to understand it as well
I can keep you company and kill boredom
Missy now has Wang Ye
You're like a pair of celestial lovers
Don't you want my company anymore?
Don't argue with me
Let me ask you
These two past two days
you've heard everything didn't you?
Since you guessed it already
I won't hide it anymore either
Missy and Wang Ye are so knowledgeable
Your conversations flow so smoothly
I don't even know anything
The other day, the both of you were creating poems together
I felt like a block of wood standing there
It was so embarassing
It's great that you're motivated
as long as you want to learn, I am willing to teach you
but as a girl, to know a book, the smarter you become
and this will create more headache in the future
But that's ok
Go and ask your little master out
Also Sun Gong Gong
you don't understand him. He doesn't trust anyone
Now it's only her new horse
she refused to come out
If you want to wait here, you will be waiting about two to three hours
then you won't do your big duties
Haiyoo...my dear grandma
She can escape out of it, I can't
I have to serve the Emperor
Sun Gong Gong! I know you're scared of horses
Don't be afraid, the horse is dangerous
but with little master around
it will not hurt you
Your Majesty, why do you fancy such a woman?
Little Master, you're finally out to receive the edict
If you have something to say just say it!
Emporer has an order
Little Master, sorry
You should kneel to recieve the order
By divine edict of the Emperor,
Ms. Ye of Yuanming Garden is intelligent and refined.
She's to be conferred the title of Promise, and taken into the palace to reside. End of edict.
Young Mistress, you have to express your gratitude.
Thanks.
Congratulations, Young Mistress Ye.
You're really fortunate.
All the females in the palace start from being an Official Lady.
Your first step, and you're already a Promise.
If I gave this fortune to you, would you want it?
Young Mistress, you're joking.
You should start packing quickly and get ready to enter the palace.
Where will I be staying in the harem?
The Internal Affairs department will make the arrangements.
What the Internal Affairs Department arranges is their own problem!
Since the Emperor likes me, why is the Internal Affairs Department getting involved?
By nature, I don't like noise and excitement.
Gonggong, please tell His Majesty to arrange a place for me that is quiet and far away from everyone else.
Yes.
His Majesty will definitely make the arrangements.
Young Mistress, please enter the palace quickly.
You still have to express your gratitude to the Emperor.
I won't be able to wait for him to come anymore.
I still promised to perform for him.
Young Mistress, whom are you referring to?
Why do you care who I'm talking about?
Look at this fish. Its eyes are protruding out.
This fish is pretty.
Greetings, Empress Dowager, Empress, and Consort Qi.
Get up.
Thank you, Empress Dowager.
I had no choice but to call you over despite how busy you are.
Your servant doesn't dare.
The matter has been done secretly.
But sooner or later, she'll have to stay in one of the palaces.
How long does His Majesty intend to hide it from me?
I'm asking you.
Has the new girl entered the palace yet?
What new girl? How did I not know of it?
His Majesty finds you magnanimous and of good character.
Always approving, never rejecting.
So he dares to pull all kinds of people into the palace.
Empress Dowager, don't be angry.
It's just her status that is a little low.
It's a bit similar to Lady Miaoyin in the past. That's all.
At most, it'll be like the previous Eight Prince's mother.
Only a lowly slave.
That lowly slave was at least a servant official
The one His Majesty has picked this time...
is a horse trainer from Yuanming Garden...
who performs shows.
Empress Dowager,
she has already entered the palace.
Because she was at Yuan Ming Yuan and couldn't enter the palace
The emperor was worrying day and night
He titled her as Promise, and had her brought into the palace.
Has it been decided where she will be staying?
Not yet.
But Promise Ye said...
that she wants to stay somewhere quiet with few people.
Hear that, all of you.
She's just entered the palace,and she's already making demands.
Exactly.
Has His Majesty mentioned where is to be given to her?
We have to wait 2 days before they clean up the room
His Majesty said for her to stay at Yang Xin Hall's side wing for the time being.
How can that be allowed?
Tell the Emperor...
Chun Xi Hall in Shou Kang Palace is empty
Get someone to clean it up immediately for her.
Yes
Chunxi Hall is to be given to her?
Isn't that too much of an honor for her?
Naturally not.
In a situation like this,
I'm afraid that she will be promoted again
She likes the quiet.
There are no place more quiet than Shou Kang Palace
Let her live right under my watch,
and she won't be able to play any tricks.
Dispense with ceremony. Sit.
Why?
You're not happy?
Are you not used to living here?
It's the same everywhere.
You've been here for a few days now.
I haven't seen you smile once.
If you feel that the palace is constrained,
I'll take you to Yuanming Garden for a few days when I'm free.
Your Majesty is busy with Court.
You don't have to worry about me.
Furthermore, not smiling...
is because by nature, I do not like to smile.
No other reason.
Actually, when you don't smile, you're even prettier.
Niangniang, how did His Majesty title such a lowly lass as a Promise?
Empress...
The ancestral rules state that when a courtier is titled,
they have to start from a lady official
Ye Lanyi is not a courtier. Moreover, the Emperor likes her. What's impossible?
She was titled in the afternoon, had dinner with the Emperor
And at night she was sent into Yangxin Hall to attend to consummate the union.
For these few days, His Majesty has only had relations with her!
I have never seen His Majesty like that before.
You've never seen it? I've never seen it too!
This is what deviousness and cunning means
Today, when I went to Yangxin Hall to pay my respects,
I saw Promise Ye's appearance.
Her aura so uncouth.
What on earth does His Majesty like about her?
If Concubine Qi has the ability,
why doesn't she display that aura too?
His Majesty will like it too.
For Ms. Ye to receive this much favor...
is worrying indeed.
If she were to spawn some lowly creature someday,
who knows what would happen?
If Heaven were protecting us,
may she never give birth.
Promise Ye.
Seventeenth Prince?
You're here?
I haven't seen you for some time,
and you're now a Promise.
No one ask if I was willing to or not.
And here I am in the palace.
And I'm a Promise.
I heard about what happened to you.
You seem depressed
Everything here is so dirty.
My Hundred Horse Garden is still the cleanest
Do you still remember that year?
You had a high fever.
I remember.
That was seven years ago...
I was ill and almost dying.
No one would care about a lowly slave like me.
It was you who saw me by chance,
and had the Imperial Physician save me.
When I first saved you then,
it wasn't to see you...
so filled with despair today.
But what else can I do?
I can't go where I want to.
And where I'm staying...
makes me feel disgusted.
and fills me with utter hopelessness.
You have to take care of yourself
My memory of Ye Lanyi...
has a beautiful smile, and a strong character.
No matter bitter it is, she'll find a way to find the sweetness in it and be happy.
I have never been able to repay...
you for your kindness many years ago, my lord.
Since you want me to live well,
I will definitely listen to you.
That's great.
Huan Er.
Why did you come so suddenly?
When I was done with my errands, I rushed over to meet you.
Before..didn't I say that my heart was unease?
I've thought of something that will allow both our hearts to be at ease.
A marriage notice?
Yes, a marriage notice.
I'm a person your imperial brother threw out.
Furthermore, I'm a guilty woman...
whose future is unknown.
Why are you doing this?
A contract for a lifetime.
Forever binding.
Huan Huan.
In this whole world, I only want you.
Zhen Huan.
I pray for a live a peaceful and quiet life with you
Huan Er.
I will definitely do as you wish.
I know
It's just a foolish dream of mine
that's ultimately futile
Believe me
After Imperial Brother has slowly forgotten about you,
I will get Abbess Jing'an to announce your death
We'll change our names, and go far away from here.
And live the rest of our lives out together
Huan Er, what are you doing?
You and I, husband and wife, will be one.
One forever, never to part.
Your Majesty seldom lets me interfere with Court matters
There is some unrest in Tibet
A'er'buba intends to escape to Zhunge'er'bu
Although Poluonai moved his own troops to settle the matter,
I think
that for every day of unrest in Zhunge'erbu
The matter of Tibet cannot be resolved
If it cannot be resolved,
the Mongols will be suspicious
And these two parties may pose a worry for our country
Although I have titled some officials
and made plans to gather troops for Zhuge'erbu
But there are many matters that have not been clarified
I need you to make a trip to scout out the information
Although Imperial Brother wishes to give me this task
But I am not talented
I want to use you
Precisely because you don't have many ties in Court
If you go in plain clothes, most people won't recognise you
Now the stretch along Yunnan
is filled with spies from Zhunge'er'bu
I'm afraid of alerting the enemy
Also,
if we do end up raising the military against Zhunge'er'bu
It'll be faster to move the troops from Gansu, Yunnan
Imperial Consort Shu is from Yunnan
For you to make a trip to Yunnan is more appropriate
Although your brother is untalented, since Your Majesty has asked, I cannot decline
I will do my best
Good
Go and get ready, leave and return early
Your brother takes his leave
Su Pei Sheng
Your Majesty
Call for Minister Zhang Ting Yu
Yes
Your Official pays his respects to you
Get up.
I summoned you here today...
because of the matter regarding Prince Guo advancing to Yunnan.
You must send some trustworthy people to protect him in secret.
At the same time,
prevent him from getting too involved in politics.
Every time he reaches a location,
whom he speaks to, what he does...
investigate it closely and report it back promptly.
Yes.
Physician Wen.
Is the medicine ready?
Yes.
Be careful when you use it.
Many thanks.
Don't thank me.
I'm just afraid for Huan Er's wellbeing.
Still, many thanks.
Why were you so careless when you dismounted your horse?
Such a good cloak, needlessly ripped
I thought about the fact that I hadn't seen you for four days already.
So I hurried when I got off the horse.
It's just a clothing. It isn't worth much.
The mountain roads are slippery in the snow and it's easy for the horse to slip
What's the point of you rushing over here?
This time you cut your clothing, what if the next time you hurt yourself?
Are you intentionally out to make me worry?
I'll just promise you then.
I don't want to hurt myself either.
If I'm hurt, how will I come to see you?
What a slippery tongue.
If you tear your clothing again next time,who's going to repair it for you?
I'll just leave you to wear a torn clothing all over.
You're leaving tomorrow?
23rd of the 12th month. In about a month.
I can't delay any longer. Looks like I won't be spending the New Year's in the capital
In 40 days will you be back?
I will definitely be back within 40 days.
40 days.
Another full cycle of the moon.
40 days are very short!
I've already made all the arrangements.
When I come back this time,
I will take you to leave this place.
Really?
This is...?
It seems like fragrance powder.
It's a medicine from Physician Wen
to fake death
It's called the "7-day Unconscious Powder"
Made from Datura flowers
After taking it, it'll be like you've stopped breathing
Exactly like a dead person
7 days later you'll be able to wake up
In the end, he's still willing to help me
Physician Wen has indeed put in a lot of effort for us
We should really thank him
I've made the preparations
Once everything is in place
Huan Er.
When that time comes, we'll be together forever.
I'll wait for you to come back, and wait for everything to be resolved
Only then can I rest easy
Huan'er. This is a matter of governance
I can't not go.
It's just 40 days.
I will definitely wait for you.
In the past, my aunt from Jiangnan
There's a bridge on the west lake in Hangzhou called the "Long Bridge"
Long Bridge?
Is the bridge very long?
Actually the bridge isn't very long
It's called the Long Bridge
because the locals always say
that Liang Shan Bo bo Zhu Ying Tai (famous historical lovers) said their goodbyes there
Unwilling to let go of each other
So the short bridge seemed like a really long one
The pain of separation
has been the same since the ancient times
I don't want us to be Liang Shan Bo and Zhu Ying Tai
She married crying and he died young throwing up blood
In the end they could only leave the Earth as butterflies
We're much luckier than they were
What was I thinking? Making an analogy out of them...
I'm thinking too much today
So I can't really stomach any inauspicious words
It seems like a man's heart
that is in the hand's of his love
can no longer be free and easy
Go and be free and easy
Prince Guo is suave
Is he afraid that no other beautiful ladies would pine after him?
You, really! Bullying me this way
You're trying to make me angry
Who asked you to speak nonsense?
Although the flowers are blooming
But please hurry back
because I will wait for you here
With you here
I will return home as expediently as possible
Huan'er!
Huan'er
I will return very quickly
I wait for your return
Wait for me
I wait for your return!
I wait for your return
My lady.
I've sent the blankets to Anxi Hall as you've instructed
Imperial Consort sends along her regards
and said that Wang'ye will be home soon
At that time, the both of you should go together to pay your respects
These two days I've been feeling lazy and sleepy
But Yun Li will be back within 10 days
I can always go with him then
Priestess Mochou, an esteemed guest from the palace has come.
Jiejie!
Huan Er!
It's all my fault!I waited till today to come see you.
Sit.
This is our first time seeing each other in a few years, why are we crying?
Out of the blue, how could you let my sister stay in such a secluded place?
When I came over from Ganlu Temple, even on a sedan, it took a whole hour!
Is this how Ganlu Temple looks after women from the palace who come here to pray?
I've been sick recently
That's why I moved here to recuperate
It's not the abbess' fault
Mochou is kind
Yes, yes.
Mochou was sick, that's why she was moved here
All of you go out and wait
I have private words to speak to Mochou
Yes.
Other people aside,
Priestess Jing Bai is hale and healthy
Go and sweep the snow off the path towards the palace
In order to show your sincerity to my lady, please complete this task alone
Yes.
Why are you making things difficult for her like that?
You've been thoroughly humiliated at Ganlu Temple!
Not at all.
You're still trying to hide it from me?
Do you think I really don't know?
You were dismissed from the palace under disgraceful circumstances
Which person on this earth doesn't look down on the disgraced?
Even if one is a nun, they may not be able to look past it
When I wanted to come see you
that Jing Bai continuously tried to rebuff me
First she said the weather was cold. Then she said the road was slippery.
I just said a few sentences to you, and she already looked so guilty!
Obviously, she has been bullying you all these days.
I punished her in front of you.
On one hand, it is to punish her
On the other hand, it is to show that you weren't the one that put me up to punishing her
You're so thoughtful.
It's fine. It's fine.
I just think that you're suffering so much here
And the Priestess said that you were heavily sick and moved out of Gan Lu Temple
During the journey over here, I was so worried!
Now that I see that you're well and healthy
I can be rest assured too.
I heard that you got promoted to be a Concubine.
I was so happy for many days!
What's the use of being a Concubine?
That doesn't matter to me
Why do you do that to yourself?
For these two years, it seems like His Majesty is punishing himself.
He only buries his head in Court affairs.
After you left,
His Majesty's attitude toward the harem has cooled a lot too.
Although there is also Concubine Qi,
and a Lingering Kang and Concubine Zhen
But it's hard for one to say that he really likes any one
Until just recently, Promise Ye entered the palace and things got a little bit better
Now His Majesty treats me courteously
That's good too. Now with the status of a Concubine,
it's easier to do some things too.
Fangruo Gugu being able to visit me frequently...
it's thanks to you asking Empress Dowager for permission?
You're doing so much for me.
If the situation were reversed, and I were the one suffering,
you would do the same for me.
Huan Er, I listened to you.
I kept my head down and out of the Empress' notice
I just spent my time dutifully serving the Empress Dowager
And helped Consort Jing look after Long Yue
Just so that the day will come when I can clear your name
But after so many years, I haven't been able to get anything useful
It's not easy to leave the palace, especially not at this time of the year
How were you able to come out?
A few days ago, Princess Wenyi fell sick.
Although the physician saw her,
But the priestess at Bao Hua Temple said that there's a spiritual disturbance
So all the tablets of executed court ladies have to be moved to Gan Lu Temple
But to do this in the Zheng month (12th month) is inauspicious
Why was it handed to you?
The Priest said
It has to be done by a woman that hasn't been with the Emperor for a long time to perform such a peaceful task
Of course, I'm not the only woman who fits that criteria.
But the others found it taboo.
That's why I had the chance.
You've always been circumspect about such matters
and would never get involved with these sort of spiritual things
Sister Mei
Are you sure that you're only here to see me
as a convenient aside from that task?
Since you've discovered it, I won't keep it from you.
I had Physician Wen give Princess Wenyi some medicine to increase her temperature.
And then bribed the Priest from Bao Hua Temple to mention the cleansing of the spirits
That's how I got the opportunity to meet you.
You put in so much effort...
Something severe must have happened?
Has something happened to Longyue?
No, no. Not Longyue.
She's fine. Nothing's wrong with her at all.
It's...
Your father. He's fallen gravely ill in Ninggu Tower
Father was fine.
How could he be ill to the extent that it's life-threatening?
Yes. Although Uncle was exiled, his body has always been healthy.
I was hesitant for many days regarding telling you about it.
I was afraid that if you found out, you'd just be upset over it.
But... after thinking it through,
I'm worried about Uncle's safety, and could stop myself from telling you about it.
Father has always been healthy.
What on earth happened?
That's exactly where the problem lies.
If it is heaven's will then it is alright
If it is a human's will
then it's really frightening
Jie Jie thinks
that some one was deliberately out to harm him?
I'm afraid that it may be from the Empress' camp.
Otherwise it's people from the Gua'er'jia clan
To think that even after so long,
that they'll keep persisting without letting go
Then Zhen clan has been imprisoned in Ni Gu Tower
I've even left the temple to come here
Why won't they let us off?
Huan Er, now is not the time to be sad.
Uncle was targeted
Who knows whether the next target will be you?
You have to think of a way to get Uncle sent back to the capital to be treated.
With careful treatment, he may still be able to recover.
What you said is right.
At this point in time,
The most important are those who are alive.
Regarding Father's treatment,
I will do my best to think of a way.
Yes.
Niangniang, the time is up. We must return to the palace before it gets dark.
Alright. I understand. Have the sedan waiting.
Yes, Niang'niang shouldn't miss the auspicious hour
Huan Er.
I'm leaving now.
Just remember one thing.
Take good care of yourself.
That's the most important thing, alright?
The palace is dangerous.
You have to be careful too.
When we'll meet again...
is anyone's guess.
As long as we're both safe and sound,
why does it matter whether or not we meet?
You must take care.
You as well.
Why hasn't mistress eaten dinner again?
Something happened to His Lordship. I'm very upset too.
I just hope His Lordship can return as soon as possible
So that he can help
Mistress, what's wrong?
Did you eat something bad?
Could it be...?
Congratulations, Mistress.
It's not even been a month. Lower your volume.
Mistress, you should tell Grand Concubine. It'll make her happy.
Something just happened to my father.
I can't bring myself to be happy.
I'll wait for Yunli to return.
We'll tell Grand Concubine together then.
Huanbi.
The one in my womb is your little nephew.
Yurao and our parents are in Ning Gu Tower
I'm afraid for the rest of our lives, we can only rely on each other as sisters
My child is also your child
From now on we'll raise him together
Is that okay?
Is that really true?
Elder Sister and His Lordship's child
is also my child
Some things have already been decided, and can't be changed.
If there are changes, it would only hurt people
What I can give to you, I'll give it all to you.
I understand
Somethings that are not destined to be mine...
can't be forced.