~ Episode 23 ~
We wish the Empress Dowager health and fortunes for ten thousand years
I haven't seen Lady Wan in a while
Raise your head and let me see your face
Get up now
Thanks Empress Dowager
Lady Wan is very sensible
and her personality is easygoing
Courtier Concubine Zhen Huan bows to the Empress Dowager
Empress Dowager please accept my formal bow
Courtier Concubine is delighted beside myself
Very good. Really are quite sensible.
Courtier Concubine was young and rash
it's all thanks to Empress Dowager's grace and protection
Empress and all the Jie Jie (older sisters) are also willing to teach me
so that I don't lose my manners
I don't blame the Emperor for liking you, I also like you
Zhuxi
Yes
Get two rolls of cloud brocade and grant them to Lady Wan
Thanks Empress Dowager
Can you write?
Lady Wan has a nice personality and is literate
Courtier Concubine is somewhat learned in literary works, but my calligraphy is messy
I fear that it's not fit for the Empress Dowager's eyes
it's good you can write
Come to the Palace of Age and Health often to be my company
Copy verses for me, ok?
As long as Empress Dowager doesn't mind my clumsiness
Courtier Concubine will serve the Empress Dowager with all my heart
Having you come here everyday to copy verses
really take up your free time
To be able to copy verses for the Empress Dowager
is my fortune
The snow is falling so hard that even branches are broken off under the weight
You are a child with a quiet heart
I see that you don't talk much
My heart was originally not calm
but after copying verses for the Empress Dowager,
my heart has slowly becomes quiet and calm
Therefore to have a calm and peaceful spirit
is to copy the true words of Buddha
Are you done copying?
Almost done.
Does Empress Dowager also like sandalwood?
Followers of Buddha mostly use sandalwood scent
The harem rarely uses this scent, how did you recognize it?
Courtier Concubine sometimes uses it for calming the heart
it works better than Peace Scent
That's right, life often has moments where it doesn't go your way
It's good you learn how to get rid of that discontentment
Didn't I say that I would come?
Why are you asleep so early then?
Maybe because in Mother's palace
I got tired from copying the verses
Then you are quite weak
But I did wait for the Emperor for a long time
I fear the cold and I was sleepy
I was dictating some proposals and time passed by quicker than I thought
It's my fault
The weather is cold and the snowfall is heavy.
Courtier Concubine thought that Emperor would go to the closer palace
to Empress Niang Niang's palace for tonight
I just visited the Palace of Peace and Righteousness a few days back
and you are telling me to go again?
The days are cold and matters for the New Year are plentiful
Empress Niang Niang's body may not be strong
Emperor should go there often to accompany her
Yesterday when Courtier Concubine visited her palace
I saw Empress Niang Niang drew a picture of samuume
Emperor did you see
No I didn't.
I'll have lunch with Empress tomorrow then.
and look at the picture there.
Emperor only eats lunch there
and Empress Niang Niang puts her whole heart into preparing it.
You should go eat dinner there.
That way you can also rest at the palace
My Huan Huan is certainly very generous
Empress Niang Niang is the mother of the whole empire
Emperor should go be with her more
Since you are so moral, I'll go there tomorrow
Greetings to Empress Niang Niang. To Niang Niang be ten thousand fortunes and golden peace.
Rise and grant her seat.
Thanks Empress Niang Niang
What's with you guys today? It's like it's planned
The arrival times are all pretty similar.
Today really is a coinicidence.
These few days are cold
Is your body better?
It's better. Thanks for Jie Jie's caring
I've made a joke of myself
It's only the cold
I don't know why it's been dragging on for so long
Did you guys hear that? Just a cold
has caused An Changzai's voice to worsen
it's not like before
Wan Jie Jie only cares for An Jie Jie
and ignores me. I'm also your Mei Mei
Yes. Of course you are my Mei Mei
Everyone here are all sisters
Wan Jie Jie, look at me, I got fatter today.
These newly made clothes are already tight at the sleeves
Well yes. Breakfast is two bowls of rice porridge and three sugar buns.
Lunch is fat chicken and fat duck
Before dinner you also eat snacks
If it weren't for me stopping her at dinner
that whole bowl of ham stew
would have been in your stomach
And even then she still complains about her hunger
so then she eats a midnight snack, but she's still hungry!
Your stomach
will probably become more and more round as you eat
Jie Jie likes to make fun of me more now
But Jie Jie is right
I can't eat like this anymore
Even Emperor said that my clothes
have to be remade every two months
I either grew taller or grew fatter
But I envy An Jie Jie
and how she can remain so slender
It's fine if you are a little fat
as long as Emperor likes it
Your An Jie Jie probably envies you too
being able to eat so much
Look at how skinny you are, it's not good
You have to eat medicine.
but you also have to balance it.
Thanks for Niang Niang's care
I don't have as much as fortune as Chun Mei Mei
Being able to eat is fortunate, being remembered by others is also fortunate
Just look at your Wan Jie Jie
and even how much you eat everyday
she's noted in her heart
Alright. Sit down now.
Yes
Lady Fucha, are you ok?
Did you eat unsanitized food during breakfast
that caused your body to be unwell?
Reply to Empress Niang Niang:
It's not that Lady ate bad food; she's pregnant
Don't lie
Is that true?
That's great! It's an event worth celebrating!
We have to congratulate the Emperor
Really? Did the Imperial Doctor inspect it?
Two imperial doctors have already inspected
I'm not the type to do anything just to gain favor from the Emperor
If I have it, then I do. If I don't, then I don't.
How I can falsify things about imperial descendants?
Isn't it enough to have Shen Daying as an example?
Lady Wan, don't you agree?
Fucha Jie Jie is really fortunate
Just three to five days and she's already pregnant
I remember that the Emperor
hasn't visited Lady Fucha for a while
He only orders you to serve him once every few months
and Mei Mei still gets pregnant
Mei Mei really is a fortunate person
Of course, this is fortune sent by heaven
It might even be a little ah-ge (or prince)
Xin Changzai, do you agree?
The heaven destines whether you'll get a boy or girl
The fortune of bearing a son
is not possessed by just anyone
Ok ok, it doesn't matter whether you have a son or daughter
Lady Fucha, now that you finally bear the dragon's seed
you need to take care of your body
there can definitely be no mishaps in this matter
Thanks Empress Niang Niang
Lady Wan
I am foolish as an older sister
I have something to ask Lady Wan
Please ask, Jie Jie
I really feel regretful for Mei Mei
The Emperor favors and loves Mei Mei the best
The number of times Mei Mei served the Emperor would, of course, be the most
How come you are still not pregnant?
Now that Lady Fucha is pregnant
The emperor would look after her more
Mei Mei you get free time now
so take the chance to recharge your body
Lady Fucha bears the dragon's seed
so of course the Emperor would look after her more
When Mei Mei (I) have free time, I will condition my own body
Jie Jie should also take care of your body and Princess Wenyi's
The Princess's body is worth a thousand gold
there can definitely be no mishaps
Yes, Lady Wan
Lady Cao's words offended Niang Niang
I'll ask for forgiveness on Jie Jie's behalf
Niang Niang, please forgive her
What is it?
Lady Cao just said that
I serve the Emperor the most and yet am not pregnant
Isn't she using these words
to insult Niang Niang?
Amongst the concubines, it's still Niang Niang who gets favored the most
I shall confess Jie Jie's shortcomings for her
Does it matter whether you are pregnant or not?
Niang Niang
If the heaven cares about me, it shall grant me a son
if the heaven doesn't remember me, I shall still get a daughter
anything better than nothing
Niang Niang is right. Whether you have children or not
being favored is still favor. Even if the mother rises in stature because of a son
you still have to see if the child is liked by the Emperor
I escort Hua Fei Niang Niang
Lady, it's late, sleep now
Lady Fucha got pregnant by serving the Emperor only a few times
but there's not even anything within me
I have to admit my fortune is shallow
How can it be so? Lady is a very fortunate person
Pregnancy will come sooner or later
Lady doesn't need to worry about it
But I heard from the city guards
that Jing City is infested with plague
it's hard to say it won't spread inside the palace
Lady must be very very careful
Quickly go to sleep now
Lady Fucha is pregnant
I've been goodhearted enough to let Songzhi send over a plate of date and yam cake
who knew that Lady Fucha would rely on her pregnancy
and not even rise to thank me. She is certainly bold!
Lady Fucha is only rebellious this one time
She doesn't really mean disrepect to Niang Niang
She just got pregnant and she's already defiant to this point
If she gives birth to a son
wouldn't she think she's risen to the heavens?
That's not always true, just look at Qi Fei
Lady Fucha is young and beautiful
When times passes, it's hard for the Emperor not to change heart
Yes
If she gives birth to a princess it's fine
but if she gives birth to a prince
it's been a while since there's been a prince born in the palace
we don't know how happy the Emperor would be
I remember that the Emperor only went to your place once this month
Now that Lady Fucha is pregnant
he probably won't even visit you once now
I only wish that Wenyi grows up peacefully
I have no other desires
You can't tolerate people. People might not tolerate you.
Good thing that Lady Fucha isn't a fortunate person either
She got pregnant
just when there's plague going around outside the palace
The Emperor is really worried right now.
Niang Niang, bad news! The plague has reached inside the palace!
What?!
Did the mugwort get delivered to every palace of the harem?
It's already been delivered over the night
Lady Fucha is pregnant
so put more in her palace
Hua Fei's Yi Kun Palace got infected first
so you must clean it more
Everyday in the morning, noon, and dusk
burn the mugwort once to drive out the plague
Also, instruct the Imperial Hospital
to be ready with antidotes for the plague
tell the maids of every palace to make scented pounches through the night
and wear it on the body and hang them inside the palace
Yes
Imperial Doctor Zhang
Here
You are the head of the Imperial Hospital
In your opinion, how did this plague come about?
This disease is caused by abnormal air
the first symptoms are fever and headaches
then, the plague clogs up
if one person has it, he or she can spread it to the whole room
then that one room can spread it the whole palace
We must take precuations to prevent bigger accidents from happening
It's this serious?
Courtier does not dare to exaggerate in this case
The laborers of the harem have already been infected
the furious force of this plague can be seen
The Imperial Hospital will have to start the precautions
Empress Niang Niang, please inform each palace
not to wander around outside
Everyone only cares about their own safety now that there's news of the plague inside the palace
The words of the Imperial Doctor should be obeyed by everyone
Everything will have to taken care of by the Imperial Hospital
Yes
Report to Niang Niang: the laborer in our palace
Little Dezi got the plague
The Imperial Household Dept. is moving him out
What are you doing standing there?
Burn everything he's touched and all his clothes!
The cup he used, the tea set
all go break them outside
spread ashes in his room to remove the bad air
No need for Niang Niang to be panicking
Servant already instructed people to do it
How can one not be panicky in a matter as big as this?
Luck to Hua Fei Niang Niang
Report to Niang Niang: Empress Niang Niang said
that the plague is currently spreading around the palace quickly
and asks that Niang Niang also helps to take care of the matter
The eastern six palaces have already been spilled with boiled soju
they're currently burning mugworts
The western six palaces will be given to Niang Niang to manage
Ok
Empress Niang Niang also said that though there are not many people in Xianfu Palace
but the Palace of Perserved Chrysanthmum where Shen Daying lives
must also start burning mugworts
no places must be left out in the six palaces
Report back to Empress Niang Niang: I'll do it well
Servant will leave
Liu Ben didn't get captured
is still one of my biggest concerns
But if Shen Daying dies
even if Liu Ben is captured
it would still be a dead witness with no cross-exam
I couldn't sentence Shen Meizhuang's death in the first place
and she got away
Now I might as well let her die on her own
Are there any usable objects in Little Dezi's room?
There's still one more tea set that Little Dezi used
If someone wasn't careful and drank from that set
she would probably get the plague
A good object like that would be wasted if we just threw it away
deliver it to the Palace of Perserved Chrysanthemum
Servant understood
The Emperor's heart is with Lady
he specifically instructed Servant to come clean Palace of Perserved Chrysanthemum
so that Lady won't get the plague
If we created any disturbances, we ask Lady to please be tolerant
You guys do your thing. I'll manage on my own
what talks of disturbances?
Servant understood. Go outside and sprinkle some soju
Come in
Lady has been imprisoned for so long
all the stuff here must be old
Imperial Household Affairs Dept. specificially ordered servant
to deliver you this new tea set
the tea's already been boiled. Lady please try it.
Finally got heart?
Lady, the outside's already been cleaned
If you don't have any other orders
servant has to go to other palaces
Servant shall leave now
The last few days you kept on coughing
you must be extra careful in taking care of your body
Thanks for Jie Jie's care
Thanks for Lady's care
We've already burned magworts three times a day according to given orders
The Imperial Hospital delivered some medical scented pouch
I was thinking that since your body is weak, I would give you some of mine
To protect your body
Shattered Jade Pavillion has Jie Jie and Chun Changzai
naturally all the good stuff are there
What are these?
Imperial Hospital said those
are some newly delivered herbs
that would better if burned with magworts
They're for Palace of Everlasting Fortune
Deliver all of them to my place
Aren't those for our palace?
Why doesn't our Lady have the same thing?
Lady Fucha forgive my sin
The stuff are already going to your place
what will happen to our Lady?
An Changzai's body is strong and well
she naturally doesn't need these
I bear the Dragon's descendants
so I naturally have to be more cautious and careful
when someday An Chanzai is pregnant
I would give my portion to her
Lady Fucha and the imperial descendant's lives are lives
An Changzai's life is also life
Imperial Hospital will still send out more herbs
why must Lady Fucha get it all?
and not care about others?
Well well who is this?
it seems that the great Lady Wan has arrived
No wonder even An Changzai dares to fight for stuff
Jie Jie has misunderstood. Mei Mei doesn't dare to.
An Changzai has a good temper
but I must say something
Today no matter what, your opinion won't count
If you are not satisfied, why don't you go talk to the Emperor?
The Imperial descendant is the most important
I think the Emperor won't help you either
Actually why disturb the Emperor?
Lady can understand this principle as well
If these herbs are only used in Lady's palace
and An Changzai gets the plague
then wouldn't Lady be in deep trouble?
Aren't you cursing me like this?
I'm gonna go tell the Emperor
It's Lady's choice whether to tell the Emperor or not
I only fear that after Emperor hears about this
he will feel that Lady was shortsighted in the situation
then I won't listen to you deliberately
Move it in and close the door
Jie Jie's arguments are useless
and you might even get in trouble
I know it's useless, but if I don't say it to her
today she'll snatch it away once, tomorrow she'll snatch it away again
then An Mei Mei would have to endure her everyday
Let's go inside first
Later, I'll get some more herbs from Imperial Hospital
How can it be that easy?
If it's that easy to get this stuff
I wouldn't have to argue with her
Let's go
How many today?
two have deceased this morning
This illness comes full forced
even Imperial Hospital has no way to stop it
Empress Dowager, Empress, Qi Fei, Hua Fei
have already prayed in the Precious Glory Temple for two days
The plague is prevalent inside and outside the Jing City
Imperial Hospital's solutions are only temporary
Emperor's been anxious for many days now. He's gotten thinner
The smell is too strong
Yeah. These few days the maids
have sprinkled vinegar everyday to drive away the plague
vinegar smell is also strong
I can get used to the smell
Lady Lady bad news!
Say it slowly or else you'll bump into Lady
Full Blessing Palace has reported
that Lady Mei Zhuang got the plague
Lady, you can't go!
How did this happen?
Mei Mei don't panic, sit down first
I'll tell you slowly
It's like this
She was fine yesterday
but this morning when she woke up Fang Ruo reported
that she threw up everything she ate
she also got a high fever
at noon she started mumbling nonesensical stuff
What about the imperial doctor? Did you guys get the imperial doctor?
Don't mention the imperial doctor
Shen Daying has been grounded for a long time and have been neglected
and now the plague is also easily contagious
which imperial doctor dares to come?
I already sent people to get the doctor three or four times
not even one dared to come and take a look
Tell me, how can she get well?
Servant has already tried my best, I wanted to plead with the Emperor
but the Emperor is still discussing state affairs and won't see anyone
Empress Dowager, Empress, and the several Niang Niang
are all in Precious Glory Temple, praying for blessings
there isn't anyone who can decide what to do!
I'll go see
Lady you can't go, can't go
Mei Mei, if you go into Perserved Chrysanthemum Hall you will be in danger
The plague is very contagious
No matter what condition, I must go see first
Mei Mei, you can't
Lady Lady Lady
Lady cares for Lady Mei Zhuang
but you must also take care of yourself
Yeah
I'll just take a peek through the door
I'll just take one look, just one look
Lady you can't!
Lady Mei Zhuang is already like this
Lady must think of yourself
I'll just take one look
or else Lady Mei Zhuang won't even have someone to talk to
Lady
Lady, Lady!
Aunty, I'll have to trouble you with taking care of Mei Jie Jie
Su Gong Gong
Lady, don't take it to the heart
the plague is spreading among the commonfolks
Emperor is very anxious for this matter
and is currently discussing this with the courtiers and officials
he really doesn't have time to see Lady
then how long will it be before Emperor can see me?
This matter is big. Servant doesn't dare to give an estimate
If Lady has urgent matters
then how about you go the Empress?
That's the difficult part
if I plead with the Empress for this matter
Emperor must first give his approval
Lady is talking about Shen Daying?
Forget it. Lady
Servant advises Lady just one word
Emperor is extremely worried because of the plague
why must Lady mention Shen Daying's matter at this juncture to annoy the Emperor?
Why not think about alternatives?
Many thanks Gong Gong. If Emperor is available
please trouble Gong Gong to report to me
Servant understands
Courtier Wen Shichu greets Lady Wan
Please get up, Wen Milord (lol not sure if this is exactly correct)
Thanks Lady
Let's step aside and talk
Is Wen Milord still busy with matters relating to the plague?
and has no time?
Yes
If I have a matter needing Milord's help
can Milord help me?
I can tell Milord
there won't necessarily be a reward for this task
if discovered by others it might even be a felony
but if I don't do it
my heart will probably never be at rest
then may I ask Lady
if courtier agrees to do it
will Lady be more assured?
If Milord is willing to help me, I would naturally be more assured
For Lady's peace
Courtier is willing to do my best
but all according to Lady's commands
Perserved Chrysanthemum Hall's Shen Daying is currently plagued
and her life is endangered
I want to ask you to help her
But the only thing is...she's a grounded imperial concubine
No matter who she is, as long as Lady commands me
Courtier shall do my best
Will Lady be more at peace now?
Many thanks Wen Milord
then Courtier shall go now
Wen Milord
you be careful also
Donkey-hide gelatin is very dollars
Jing City's plague has caused madness
Emperor won't even eat anything now
You guys hurry up and find a cure
Yes, courtier understands
Niang Niang don't be impatient
the cure has never been created before
we're like blinds touching an elephant
we must try one bit by one bit
what is this talk?
I can't stand seeing the Emperor being worried
Courtier shall do my best
"do my best, do my best" you guys already read through medical books for several days
and still didn't find anything
how about I do it myself?
Niang Niang, you've already pulled several all-nighters
If you become unwell
courtier can't take up the responsibility
Milord, you are still not gonna sleep?
It's about time. This cure is almost ready.
Milord, these fews days because of the plague
you have been worried day and night. It really has troubled you
Entrusted by others a righteous matter
No talks of tired or not tired
Yeah
Wen Milord has worked hard, why don't you go rest?
Jiang Milord
These days Wen Milord
has to take care of the imperial concubines by days
and try to create a cure for this plague by night
you are certainly tired
any progress for the cure?
there still hasn't been a clue
but I'll do my best to create it
Ok then you do your thing
Lady Meizhuang being plagued
even the garrison guards are scared and avoid her
security is very loose
Servant has secretly ordered Imperial Doctor Wen to cure her
Are Cai Yue and Cai Xing still doing their best?
They're very diligent, but
Imperial Doctor Wen is curing her in secret
medicine is lacking and food is not good
so Lady Mei Zhuang's illness still hasn't gotten better
As for now, he must diligently treat her
Yes
Congratulations Lady, your wish has been fulfilled
Su Peisheng
Servant is here
Is the plague inside the palace raging?
Emperor, the palace laborers have died one by one
Everywhere, people are panicking
It's already like this inside the palace, needless to say outside the palace would be worse
Yeah. I heard that affluent individuals in the Jing City
all way to escape out of it
But who would've thought that out of Jing City
all you see are plagued commonfolks
so they were all scared back into the city
I heard that the Jing City is not even the worst
The villages in Yongping are even worse
Yeah. whenever the commonfolks there
hear someone gets plagued
they would lock up and separate the person from the rest
Those who were separated
have no other alternatives except to die
Emperor, Lady Wan outside wants to see you
How is she here when it's so late?
Could it be of some urgent matter?
Let her in
Yes
Ten thousand peace to Lady
Ten thousand fortunes and golden peace to Emperor
What happened that caused you to be come here so urgently?
You guys can go out
Yes
Say it
Little Yunzi
Aren't you gonna lift up your head in front of the Emperor?
Courtier Liu Ben greets the Emperor
How is it you?
Courtier Concubine still doesn't believe
that Shen Daying would fake her pregnancy to gain favor
so I've secretly ordered people to investigate Liu Ben
Finally the hard work paid off
and we found him at the border of Yongzhou
Fu Lin has already been hit to deaeth
Liu Ben was responsible for anchoring the fetus many times
he knows the inside details better than anyone else
I won't torture you to make you confess
but if you utter any lies today
I'll make you suffer greater things than death
I heard that when he was discovered
he's already disguised himself as a beggar to prevent being killed
Imperial Doctor Liu, you can say nothing right now
but if you don't say anything now
I'll expel you from the palace
I think that before you get out of Jing City
your body and head would be in different places
So embarrassing. If you don't tell the truth
you would be digging your own grave
Emperor, Lady Mei Zhuang really wasn't pregnant
I know
Actually Lady Mei Zhuang didn't know either
that she wasn't pregnant
When courtier was taking care of Lady
it was confirmed she hasn't had her period
but those dizziness, vomiting symptoms
are side effects of medicine, not pregnancy
But before Courtier checked Lady Mei Zhuang's pulse
I was ordered
to report that she is pregnant regardless of what her pulse was
Ordered to? By whose order?
That
She is gonna kill you and you are still covering up for her?
Hua Fei. It's Hua Fei.
If you dare to utter a single false word
Courtier doesn't dare! Courtier doesn't dare!
Courtier knows that my sin deserves a death sentence
That day, Hua Fei Niang Niang gave courtier some silver
and told Courtier to immediately leave Yuanmingyuan to avoid trouble
and comforted me by saying
there would be people inside the city to take care of me
but how did I know that would I be chased after once I entered the city?
so Courtier was forced to be like a stray dog
Little Yunzi, take him out and watch him carefully
don't allow any accidents to happen
Yes
Get up. Go
Emperor cease your anger
Would there be any falseness to Liu Ben's testimony?
There are actually several suspicious points to Shen Daying's matter that day
it's just that there are no evidence
Now that you think about it more intricately
If Shen Daying really got her period a few days before
then why must those blood-stained clothes be thrown away
when the Emperor is there?
And Shen Dayingn previous mentioned
that Imperial Doctor Jiang once gave her a medicine for helping her to become pregnant
It just happened that when she wanted it, it was gone
If that medicine never existed
Shen Daying mentioning it out of nowhere is extremely foolish
Emperor probably doesn't believe me
but Courtier Concubine has seen that medicine before
at the moment when I saw it, I didn't think anything of it
Hua Fei. Very good
That medicine that can prove Shen Daying's innocence
was probably stolen
And that palace maid called Fu Lin
was probably the culprit
I was too angry at the moment and ordered her to be killed
If I had investigated more closely that day
it would be different today
Emperor can't be blamed for this
Fu Lin even dared to wrong Shen Daying
she wouldn't have changed her words
But now what does Emperor plan to do?
I've wronged Mei Er. Release her
and recover her position
I fear that she won't be out soon
Did she?
No, she didn't commit suicide
but she was extremely depressed and unfortunately have contracted the plague
I've only ordered her to be grounded
she shouldn't have been so depressed
Although Emperor's grounding Mei Jie Jie
wasn't a very severe punishment
People in the palace
all do their tasks according to the Emperor's mood
thus all the servants despised her
I shall immediately order the imperial doctor
to treat Lady Hui for her illness
I want her to live on well
Please excuse Courtier Concubine's disrepectful crime
Courtier Concubines saw that Shen Daying was very sick
so I've already privately asked an imperial doctor to diagnose and heal her
Really?
Emperor please forgive this sin
If it weren't for you risking your life for this action
I fear I would really have wronged Lady Hui
This has nothing to do with Emperor
It was the crafty work of an evil person who blurred Emperor's vision.
Hua Fei has fooled me to this extent. I cannot accept it.
Su Peisheng!
Servant is here.
Go pass this edict to the Imperial Medicin House: Grant death to Jiang Cheng, Jiang Sheng
Consort Hua  Remove her titles and return her to the rank of Noble Lady.
Wait. Remove her titles and return her to the rank of Imperial Concubine.
Emperor. To remove her ranks is a great dishonor.
It is much harsher than moving her down a rank.
Emperor is this angry because...
First go to Xian Fu Palace.
What is important now is to heal her illness.
Yes. It's just, the removal of ranks for Lady Hua...
It is already very late at night.
If we pass another edict through to the department of internal affairs,
I'm afraid it will startle all the other consorts.
Then pass the edict tomorrow.
Servant will obey.
Servant will go righ away to Xian Fu Palace to pass the edict.
Huan Huan, the business with Liu Ben
you didn't purposely plan it, right?
What?
Nothing
Emperor thinks that Courtier Concubine instructed Liu Ben
to slander Hua Fei?
Is Courtier Concubine this kind of person in Emperor's eyes?
Courtier Concubine doesn't dare to, nor will be lowered to this extent.
If Courtier Concubine really wanted to manipulate Liu Ben
to frame Hua Fei and save Lady Hui
it would have been done a long time ago
I wouldn't have waited until today
when Lady Hui's life is in danger
If Emperor really doesn't believe Courtier Concubine
I'm sure Su Gong Gong hasn't gone far yet
Emperor can take back the edict
I was too suspicious. If I didn't believe you
I wouldn't have punished Hua Fei
If Emperor really believes Courtier Concubine
you wouldn't have questioned me earlier
Huan Huan
Courtier Concubine spoke wrongly
It's good that you know. You may rise.
Thanks Emperor
Hua Fei has served me for a long time. She was considerate and caring.
Though she's somewhat arrogant usually
but the thing today, I was really disappointed
Courtier Concubine understands
Congratulations to Palace of Salty Blessings and Lady Hui
Emperor already ordered to remove Lady Hui from her grounding
All rewards will just be like before
Thanks to the Emperor's great kindness
Congratulations
Thanks Su Gong Gong
The great injustice has finally been brought to justice. This is a great happy event
Yeah
But...Lady Hui wouldn't be able to hear this herself
Has she still not woken?
Milord Wen, Lady's fever has gone
but she has vomited the medicine
how much?
she would throw up one spoonful out of the three she drank
I did prescribe according to the symptoms
and boiled the medicine according to the formula
maybe the nature of the medicine was too strong
maybe it'll work if I change it up
Milord Wen, has Lady gotten any better?
She has gotten a little better
but her sickness was discovered late
and she was too sick so she hasn't woken yet
please let me think of more ways
Milord has a righteous heart
I heart that Milord has already been here for a whole day and night
If I can't cure Lady
I would feel guilty in my heart
Milord Wen's hard work
servant will surely report to Emperor so that he can reward you
Lady, now that the plague is so severe
why do we still have to go visit Lady Mei Zhuang?
Emperor has ordered to recover Lady Hui's position
so Lady Hui must've been very ill
but don't worry, there are guards outside
we won't be able to go in anyways
we'll just greet her from the outside
Yes
Ten thousand peace to An Changzai
Hi Xia Gong Gong, I've come to see Lady Hui
Imperial Doctor's busy inside
it won't be convenient for Lady to go in
besides, it's not good to go near the plague
Lady should stay far away
Gong Gong, please convey to Lady Hui
that I've come and seen Lady Hui
Servant will surely tell them
Oh and how did Emperor suddenly thought of recovering Lady Hui's position?
Didn't Lady Wan tell Lady?
she's caught the Liu Ben who framed Lady Hui
Really?
It's fine if Lady doesn't believe servant
You are one of the imperial servants
how can I not believe you?
it's just that this message came too suddenly
it certainly is happiness out of the blue
It's good that Lady believes servant
Now that Liu Ben is caught, someone will have to suffer great misfortune
Who is it?
I can't tell you
If I tell you, there would be a big fuss
Thank you for watching! Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki