Episode 56
Consort Xi returns!
Sincerely Emperor, I got returned.
Bless my Emperor and Empress healthy
and nourish from perpetual farewell(Enzer) entitled by the Heaven. .
Have you enjoyed safe journey in your long trip?
Fine
When heard from Emperor's message that you are arriving,
we were both really pleased to see the back of you.
Many thanks to Empress' concern！
Since Feudatory Guo has been promoted to the position of Ambassador,
you are to be engaged in the management of my harem.
Since all harem are present here,
Feudatory Guo,please establish the decree to the public for me.
Yes,Majesty！
On the Royal Decree of the Emperor,
Eulogize thee Daicing, thanks god for good fortune,
thy only lady with tolerance,charisma and the character of goodness,
Niuhulu Zhen Xuan,
born in aristocratic family and behave modest and courteous,
specially endorsed with Galeries’ kindly permission,
to bestowed as Consort Xi.
End of edict.
Consort Xi is here.
The mission is accomplished successfully by your humble servant(Poor Feudatory Guo,no excuse for couples to date),my Emperor.
How brave my mighty right-hand, you are suffering a lot.
I should thank you,specially！
If you would like,
you can make reparation to me with your priceless antiques as reward,
Just a bit of cake!
in case that I can't tolerant the itch for misery unrequited love(Sigh,Feudatory Gao,you've fallen in forbidden love!)
For the sake of Daicing's fortune and prosperity,
shortly after giving birth to my Prince Hong Li,
Consort Xi devote herself in
volunteering in blessing.
I'm very grateful for her charity work.
So I brought her back in this moment.
I heard Consort Xi is the previous Concubines Wan.Left Caption:Changzai KangRight Caption:Imperial Concubine Zhen
Does it matter?
She is whatever the Emperor entitled.
I thought I have no chance to see you later.
Unexpectedly,we encounter right now!
Long time no see, you behave and posses as usual.(No advancement means you are a loser!)
Consort Xi, you look a bit pale today,maybe you should have a rest!
Have you tired yourself on the way here?
Pregnant lady shouldn't stand outside for too long
You should go in and rest
Concubine Pin is delightful when hearing from you!
In order to welcome Meimei,
Emperor specially renovated Yongshou Palace for you.
Emperor is calculating and make full devotion in the renovation affairs,
besides he decorated with enormous jewelry
from the treasure house.
He didn't allow us to take a peek
until you come back.
Why don't Jiejie invite us over?
Your chance will come in future,
why in a hurry?
After Consort Xi settle down,it is never too late to visit.
Let me accompany you!(Too amenity!)
I know your favorite flower is water lily.
So I asked the servants to place a few dozen vats of water lily here,
especially for your affectionate care.
Humble consort is in tremendous pleasure especially for your shelter and special care.
When I asked them to renovate this place,
I told them to paint the walls red.
Very few get this privilege, but you're exception.
During these years, no matter who is favored,
Emperor has never bestowed this honour.
I'm overwhelmed by Your Majesty's love
Come and take a look at your bedroom.
Bless my emperor！
Su Peisheng.
Yes?
You've done a good job.
You are to be promoted as eunuchs of Imperial Household.
Yes,Emperor.
Emperor,Yongshou Palace is far more luxury.
I can not match up with it.
Please allow me to live somewhere else.
XuanXuan, you've suffered a lot outside
This is the least
that I can do
You are serious.
The journey is not as long as it seems,
as if the distance between you and I.(Just close as Durex?)
You don't have to feel uneasy.
Everything was prepared in my order.(A forcible meme？)
Empress even make some recommendations on her own.
There won't be gossips.
This incense smells very sweet.
Right, that's the smell of pear.
It's invented during the Southern Tang Dynasty by Empress Zhou Er.
After its abdication,
the recipe for this scent is lost.
How did you get this?
Ling Rong is a master of making scents.
It's made by herself.
She put much effort and
used hundreds of ingredients for this.
Others may not be as patient as her.
Whenever I can't sleep,
I felt better after I smell this.
Divine scent.
I come up with the pear trees at Suiyu Palace.
Exactly,since those good pear trees are to be memorized,
but they can't be replanted,yet,(Even Emperor have satisfactions!)
that's why I used this scent in replacement.
Su Peisheng- What can I do for you,Emperor?
Arrange a few capable servants to serve at Yongshou Palace.
Don't worry, Emperor.
I've made the necessary arrangements.
Greetings to Emperor and Consort Xi.
Raise up!- Yes!
Emperor,when Concubine Hui knew of Consort Xi has returned,
She's afraid new servants may not be experienced.
So she asked Eunuch Yunzi to come back and serve.
No one is as provident as Consort Xi,
plus Concubine Hui.
I'm going to Shoukang Palace now.
See you tonight.
Escort
Greetings to Consort Xi Niangniang.
Raise up.
Yes?
How's Concubine Hui?
She's pretty fine.
The only thing is that Emperor hasn't visited her for a long while
Hui Pin and the servants
have been looking forward to your return
There are not many old staff now
So the Imperial Household sent a group of new servants
to come and serve Niangniang
Are there any gossips about my return?
Whatever they say
Niangniang please don't take it to heart
But...
I heard the officials are objecting violently
about the renovation of Yongshou Palace
Even 10th Prince
They've been sending letters to Emperor saying...
that I returned as an abandoned consort
is unheard of
Yet my return is widely publicized
So they think I'll bring trouble to the palace, am I right?
They didn't put it so rudely
Niangniang is the mother of Hongli, and prayed for our country
Who dares to mention your abandonment?
The officials are like that
let them be. It's okay
Niangniang doesn't have to listen to them
You should put your mind on Jingren Palace
Even though Yongshou Palace needs renovation,
it doesn't have to be so grandiose
Haven't you heard just now
that Empress also made many adjustments?
How would she have such kindness?
She's just pleasing Emperor
and acting virtuous
So that people outside would think that
I'm a vixen who's spellbinding Emperor
Thus worsening my reputation
Focus on the future instead
Jinxi
Go get Physician Wen
Niangniang, rest assured
There's no abortive drug
like musk in this
Instead, the sweet smell of pear
is very good in calming the nerves
I just wanted to make sure
Yes of course
I'll just add
that when you use this incense
you must not place ylang-ylang in the room
Ylang-ylang is not poisonous
and has calming properties
Are they toxic combinations?
No
It's just that they'll increase sexual vitality
Love potion is not allowed in the palace
Who dares to use it?
Moreover, ylang-ylang is rare
Niangniang, Hongli wishes to see you
You may leave first
I'll take my leave
Please let him in- Yes
Greetings to Mother
Hurry rise
Let me take a look at you
You've grown taller
I've not seen you in a long while
I miss you very much
Hui Pin Niangniang told me
if you are around
I won't be a wild motherless child
With you, I won't lonely
I know
that you love me the most in the palace
Although you understand that,
but I've to tell you a few things
You've many mothers within the palace
There're Empress and Emperor
But you've to remember
no matter who your biological mother is
no matter how much you miss her
I'm your biological mother in front of everyone
You don't have to feel bad
You are the son of Aisin Gioro clan
and Niuhulu clan
My honour and disgrace is one with yours
Yes understood
My return has created gossips
Act like you didn't hear them
Just remember
you are the son of Emperor
A respectable prince
Just like the other princes
Yes
I won't forget
Good
Greetings to Empress
Wish you to good health and longevity
Rise and sit
Thank you Niangniang
Jianqiu serve the tea
It's not a big occasion today
Xi Fei's come so early
I should have come yesterday when I just arrived
So I'm here to ask for forgiveness
You're pregnant
and just came back from Ganlu Temple
Nothing wrong in resting
We'll see each other in future anyway
No hurry
Empress is caring. But I don't dare to be unrespectful
I won't forget your kindness
so I prayed everyday at Ganlu Temple
I asked for a bead bracelet to be blessed by Buddha
and hope that there'll be a day I can give this to Niangniang
May Niangniang be blessed
That's sincere
Gifts are not that important
More importantly is Meimei's wisdom
to predict our meeting in the palace again
Niangniang here are some flowers for your hairdo
You still remember the rule of serving me
by making my hairdo
It's my job
I won't forget the regulations
Time flies
You haven't change a bit
and have become prettier
Even time has doted on you
unlike me. I've become old
You're the mother of the world
Elegant like this peony
What made Niangniang say such emotional words?
So what if I'm a peony?
Any flower will wilt one day
just the matter of sooner or later
Niangniang the other consorts have arrived
They're all waiting outside
Xi Fei Let's go together
Since Xi Fei is back
Jing Fei, you should bring Princess Longyue
to visit Xi Fei often
Xi Fei is Longyue's biological mother after all
After Xi Fei has given birth
Princess Longyue should return to Yongshou Palace
No matter how close you are with Longyue,
it'll never be comparable to her biological mother
Yes
Sit
Oh yes, where is Ning Guiren?
Why isn't she here today?
Reporting to Niangniang, she said she's unwell this morning
So she can't come
Since she's unwell
then ask the Royal Physicians to take good care of her
Xi Fei, you're pregnant
You must take good care of your body
Rest more and avoid moving around
Don't have to bother with too much of the rules
Thank you Niangniang
Xi Fei has Hongli and Longyue
Such bliss
Not everyone has it
Ok, that's all for today
You may all leave
Request to leave
Niangniang if you like these flowers
how about bringing some back and making them into a scented pouch?
I can't keep them forever anyway
even if I make them into scented pouches
They'll wilt anyway
Let it be
Greetings to Xi Fei
I've never seen this Meimei before
I am Ye Guiren
I've been sick this two days
so we haven't met
How did you know I'm Xi Fei?
Your return was famous
Who doesn't know?
I heard you're feeling sick
So why are you not resting in the Palace?
When the sun is harsher you'll feel more upset
Thank you for your concern
Why did you pluck so many petals?
Physician said
these silktree albizzia flowers are needed in my medicine
So I'm here to get some
It'll be a waste
if they just wilt and die
I am not ungrateful.
I'm not feeling too well.
I'm unable to talk to you anymore.
I'll make a move first.
How can she be so rude?
She's just taking advantage of the fact that the Emperor likes her.
No wonder the others say that she is recalcitrant.
Niangniang.
I asked the kitchen to make a bowl
of soup to calm your nerves.
Please try it.
This soup's not too bad.
It's to help with the pregnancy and for my nerves.
Compared to other
bitter medicines this is much better.
Mistress, Concubine Hui is here!
Invite her in quickly!
I heard everything at the door!
Now that you're pregnant your appetite is sure to change.
I was just thinking of you, and here you are!
And green tea.
I remember that
when you are pregnant you don't like greasy food.
Try it, quickly!
It's been so many years.
Sister's
I thought of it often outside.
If you like it,
I'll just make it for you everyday, and have it delivered!
Huan Er, I really never thought...
that we would be able to see each other again...
and talk.
Since I'm back, you should be happy.
Of course I'm happy that you're back.
Maybe I shouldn't have told you about Uncle.
If you didn't tell me,
was I to sit back and watch my father die at Ningguta?
I understand.
How can people like us think of living for ourselves?
Family and clan.
None of them can remain unaffected by our actions.
Regardless of the reason,
it's good that we sisters can be together.
It's fortunate that Father has been brought back to the capital to be treated.
I can rest assured a little more too.
You have to be careful!
I know.
But back to the topic at hand,
it's better to have our own people in Qintianjian
deputy Ji Wensheng of Qintianjian
works diligently
I think he's a usable talent.
that head sits there but has nothing to say
he should've taken time off long ago
that's not difficult
everyone eats, and gets sick
Liang Duorei, the head of Interior Office
has sent some fashionable cloths
let him in
Okay.
Gonggong, please
greetings to Xi Fei Niangniang and Hui Pin Niangniang
rise
Huangshang said that Xi Fei Niangniang picks first
from these newly tributes of Shu and Su silks
comes over, Xiaoyunzi
takes that greenish one to Ning Guiren
Bengong thinks she likes green
that color suits her well
Nucai withdrew
have you seen Ning Guiren?
yes, she's not like anyone
Xiaozhu forgot what she looked like before?
why sent her such good silk?
I thought only
what cloth would suit what person
this color suits her
that's why I had Xiaoyunzi sent it to her
you just saw her once
how could you see her as a foe?
Nubi don't like her unruliness
what she thought she is
why did you talk so much
it's only some silk
go to tell Ning Guiren, Xiaoyunzi
doesn't have to come to express her gratitude since it's so hot
Yes
I have to tell you
don't treat her too well
Dowager is the first that doesn't like her
she's proud and aloof
no one gets along with her in the entire Harem
but Huangshang likes her
certain things one has to do
Mother, where are we going?
Longyue, E Niang takes you to greet Xi Niangniang
is she the one that wore very pretty cloth?
Longyue is really smart, it is her
is she also Longyue's mother?
why didn't Longyue see her before?
Longyue, Xi Niangniang was not in the harem before
Longyue,
you should play with Xiangniang more
Xi Niangniang really likes you
Xi Niangniang is pretty, Longyue likes her, too
but I still like E Niang the best
Sister's embroidering is getting better
my child would insist Sister be the auntie
why don't you do a few more Dutou?
haven't I done enough for Longyue?
almost all her Dutou were made by Jing Fei and myself
if you give birth all your life
didn't I have to make cloth for you all my life?
you're so good at calculating this
Niangniang, Jing Fei with Princess Longyue are here
have them in, quickly
it's really cool here
Yongshou Palace repaired in three months by someone sent by Huangshang
is really good
hurry Longyue, say
greetings to Xi Fei Niangniang
I couldn't say thanks yesterday because of so many people
see Sister today
grateful to Sister for so many years
of taking care of Longyue as you own
both of us are Fei
how could you bow to me like this?
if there were no Longyue with me these year
full of laughter and happiness
I couldn't imagine how my life would be
saw Cao Guiren and Qi Fei had child before
even Duan Fei later
had Princess Wenyi with her
I envied them so much
E Niang, wipe, Longyue'll be good
silly child, what E Niang or not
this Xi Fei Niangniang is your real E Niangniang
hurry, let E Niang hold you
good child, let your e niang kiss you
could e niang hold you?
let e niang hold
E Niang doesn't want me
Longyue, be good
how could e niang not want Longyue?
It's alright
Yuer is a good girl.
Come to Hui Niangniang's
Come.
Yuer is a good girl. Let me tell you
It's not that Consort Fei doesn't want you.
There is just another person to care for Longyue.
Is that alright?
Look at how much Xi Niangniang cares for you.
E Niang also cares for Longyue.
Longyue, give E Niang a kiss okay?
You are not my E Niang.
Sister, Yue'r is still young.
You just returned to the palace
so she doesn't recognize you yet.
Niangniang, Empress Dowager is about to wake from her afternoon nap.
It's waiting outside YongShou palace.
You returned just yesterday.
Why don't you come with me to greet Empress Dowager?
Okay.
Yes, if you two sisters go
then you can watch over each other.
I will take my leave first.
E Niang don't leave me.
Yue'r is a good girl.
From now on
you need to live at YongShou palace.
You need to accompany your real mother.
I don't want to.
Since Xi Niangniang came
E Niang doesn't want me anymore
Why did Xi Niangniang come back?
Long Yue, how can you say such things?
Sister,
I have never taught Long Yue to say such words.
It's because the Emperor never let me talk about you in front of her.
I am just a consort.
The Emperor's decision to not tell her is right.
Longyue still doesn't understand.
Sister, don't be too heartbroken.
Although the Emperor had intentions to hide this fact
deep down he still cares for you.
Longyue, look at you.
You have angered your real mother.
Quickly apologize and say you were wrong.
Hurry.
Xi Niangniang don't be mad anymore.
Yue'r is admitting her wrongs.
Xi Niangniang, don't be mad anymore.
Don't cry
It's my fault.
Suddenly asking her to call me E Niang.
I couldn't resist. Since she was three months old
we had never met again.
In the child's heart
she thinks of Jiejie as her mother.
To hear Longyue say E Niang
I don't know how to thank Jiejie.
Meimei, saying that makes us seem like strangers.
Don't cry.
Right now I am pregnant
and can't take care of Longyue.
So before I give birth
I need to ask Jiejie to take care of Longyue.
I don't know if Jiejie is willing to do this.
Since meimei places so much trust in me
there's no reason for me not to.
Even if it was for a lifetime I would be willing.
Meimei needs to rest well.
Huan'er is right.
Right now you're pregnant.
The doctors are saying that it is unstable.
You can't bump or jostle it.
Longyue is still young.
It would bad if you were bumped into.
Yes.
Since it is like this
I will take Longyue to Xianfu palace.
It's getting late.
You two
should hurry and give your greetings to Empress Dowager.
We will leave first.
Let's go.
Why is Empress Dowager taking medicine first?
I should be feeding it to you.
You came just in time.
Beside your Aunt Su,
you serve me the most comfortably.
I give my greetings.
Wishing Empress Dowager good heath and good fortune for thousands of years.
You've returned.
Are you living well in Yongshou palace?
Yongshou palace is very luxurious.
I feel uneasy.
Although it's luxurious, the Emperor is affectionate.
It doesn't matter.
This medicine makes my tongue taste bitter.
Go dump it out.
I've always said the longer you live, the younger you become.
Yet you don't believe me.
You say that I'm coaxing you.
Now, you don't want to drink the medicine because it's bitter.
Throwing a child's tantrum.
Isn't that becoming younger as you live?
I've always seen you
as such a stable person.
Now, you've learned to flatter.
The medicine is too bitter.
It was just to give Empress Dowager a laugh.
Here.
A pregnant lady is still kneeling.
Come help me rinse my mouth.
Yes.
Your ability to serve others has improved.
No wonder you've been at Ganlu Temple for so long
Causing the Emperor to think about you all the time.
The Empress Dowager has spoken very seriously. I am frightened.
Frightened?
And you are still frightened?
The Emperor came to Ganlu Temple because it had our memories.
I was very thankful.
Then I became pregnant.
The Emperor was thinking about the child's royal bloodline.
He didn't have the heart to leave the child.
So I came back.
In that case,
your meeting with the Emperor was a coincidence?
It wasn't a plot to gain the Emperor's favor again?
I don't dare lie to Empress Dowager.
Our meeting was not necessarily a coincidence.
Because at that time I just gave birth
and my health was not in the best condition.
When the Emperor didn't see me at Ganlu Temple
he thought I was still sick.
So he came to Ling Yunfeng to visit.
If this is the truth, then I have mistaken you.
It was because I wasn't able to explain this clearly to Empress Dowager.
It is my fault.
That day when you left the palace
you left your daughter.
Now, you've rekindled your feelings with the Emperor,
and have a child too.
Empress Dowager
I am speaking to her, why are you interrupting?
The Emperor is this country's ruler.
Not just mine.
On the political matters, although I am sad for my father
I would not hate the Emperor.
The day I left the palace
was because the Emperor treated me with no regards to our feelings.
But the Emperor came to see me.
I knew then that the Emperor wasn't heartless.
Today I was able to return.
I just want to peacefully serve the Emperor.
To repent for my wrongs.
You may rise.
Thank you.
I've always said that you are thoughtful.
How can you watch consort Xi kneel?
You didn't remind me to let her rise.
The illness is causing me to become muddled.
Did your brain become muddled too?
Empress Dowager, Consort Xi kneeling
is the same as your grandson kneeling.
The family is kneeling to give your their greetings.
Do I need to stop them?
Award her with a seat.
I gave birth to the Emperor.
I am afraid that he will have another Hu Mei by his side.
Now, you have a consort's title.
These clothes are too simple.
I have been meditating for a while, and I don't like luxuriant clothes.
For you to have such mature thoughts
it shows that my care for you all these years hasn't been wasted.
While I was at Ganlu Temple
thankfully I had your prayers.
I won't forget that so easily
Since you've returned
just pretend that this never happened.
I will tell the others about this too.
You need to remember it yourself.
With the three words Ganlu Temple
your future will be rough.
It's been four months right?
Yes.
The Emperor is aging.
But the people around him aren't striving to live quietly.
Now that you've returned
you should persuade the Emperor to take care
perhaps he will listen to your words.
I will adhere to your lecture.
I will not forget my duties as a consort.
You are smart and thoughtful.
You understand the meanings of my words the first time I say it.
Since we've gotten onto the topic of a consort's duties,
you must respect the Empress.
The Empress treats me very well.
I am very thankful to her.
That's good.
You are Consort Xi are like sisters
so now that she has her second child,
why don't you try harder?
I have always had my eye on you.
But you aren't willing to put effort onto the Emperor.
The Emperor doesn't even have someone who can give him advice.
How can I not worry?
Yes. I understand.
You can't just understand, you must take action.
You two,
if you can stay by the Emperor's side and serve him well
then I will be able to relax.
Longyue distanced herself from me.
It's heartbreaking.
Don't blame Consort Jing or Longyue.
You can only blame the fact that the Emperor didn't tell Longyue
that you are her real birth mother.
Two years ago a serving girl accidentally revealed it,
saying that Longyue's mother was at Ganlu Temple.
The Emperor was so mad that he killed her.
Longyue doesn't want to leave Consort Jing.
Through these years
Consort Jing has really cared for Longyue.
Just now I saw how deep their mother-daughter relationship is.
Even if I force Longyue back to my side
we will only grow more apart.
I am also worried that it would ruin the me and Consort Jing's long friendship.
As long as you understand.
The child is still young.
If you are nice to her, she will be nice to you.
No matter what, she is still your biological child.
Lower the sedan!
Hurry, lower it.
We are guilty.
Huan'er, are you alright?
You clumsy thing.
Niangniang is on the sedan.
Are you so careless when you perform other tasks?
Be careful that I will tell the Imperial Household department
to cut off your heads.
Niangniang have mercy.
How can you just suddenly trip?
Can't you even walk?
The stone path is originally easy to walk on.
But today, I don't know
how but there were some loose rocks.
So I slipped.
Niangniang.
Are you trying to trick me?
Is this the quickest path to return to Yongshou Palace?
Why would you go this way?
How would we have the guts to trick you?
Although this isn't the shortest path,
it's the coolest path to take in the summer.
Thankfully Niangniang is alright.
If there was some accident,
then even if we servants had a hundred heads
it wouldn't be enough to cut off.
Where is this place?
If you continue straight, it would be Imperial Concubine Qi's Chuxiu Palace.
Normally, unless it was specified
we go back using the original route that we came on.
Today is especially hot.
It's understandable that they would choose this path.
It looks like someone is intentionally doing this.
I've only been back for two days.
And someone couldn't wait any longer.