Episode 38
Greetings, Empress.
May you enjoy great fortune.
Rise.
Thank you, Empress.
It's been a long time since I've met all of you here.
If only everyone is the palace were as harmonious as all of you.
Jiejie and I have always gotten along quite well.
The temperatures are getting high lately, his majesty suggest to go to Yuan Ming garden.
We will be leaving in a few days time.Do prepare in advance
for things and people that you want to bring along.
Yes.
Your highness
ever since the empress has fallen ill, she has never left the palace to escape from the summer heat.
I would wish to stay to accompany the empress.
To contribute some filial piety.
It is naturally good that you have this intention.
Thank you your highness.
Everything has already been arranged.
His majesty is still at Kyushu,
The empress is at plum flower
Consort is still at Bluish Wood Library.
Isn't Lady An staying at House of Flourish?
Why are we going this way?
Lady An is staying in the House of the Free Moon now.
According to His Majesty,
You and Lady An are very close.
Therefore, it is good for you to be near each other.
His Majesty is nearby as well.
I have something to do.
You can leave first
Yes.
Are you feeling sad for Lady Hui?
She was amazing last year,
now that Ling Rong has moved into the House of Free moon,
things have changed.
I'm afraid that I'll feel sad when I go there.
Its good that you care about her.
But you have to know that,
there are a lot of women in this palace.
Today you may be favored, but tomorrow, she could be favored.
It isn't set in stone
Although you care about Lady Hui,
but you don't have to be sad about it.
Jin-Xi,
I have always cared about the little things in life.
You are sentimental sometimes.
But, only gentle people would think too much.
Cruel people will never do so.
Your soft heart is your flaw.
You've always think too much.
Consort Wan!
Get down 4th prince! Be careful.
Come down quickly
Greetings empress, Consort Wan.
Why did you climb so high?
Aren't you afraid of falling down?
No one else cares about me other than grandmother Mo.
Silly child
I heard that father is here. I wanted to greet him, but he doesn't wish to see me.
So I climbed all the way up there to see if I could spot his majesty.
I will bring you to him if you want to see him.
But your father is discussing things with some officers,
he's going to be busy.
How about you go home first. When his majesty is free, I'll call you.
Thank you, Empress!
I just want to see father.
Go along now
Oh empress, this is for you.
Your majesty.,
Nian Genyao used the credits,
that he doesn't deserve when the government needs power from the military.
He went into collusion.
And tried to gain extra advantages for his subordinate.
Nian Genyao's servant,Wei Zhi-Yao has always been arrogant.
He actually made the officers
kneel down
when he entered the capital.
Yet he just passed them by.
Your majesty,
Nian Gengyao has been rude to us.
He used some excuses to hold the children.
of many officers in his camps.
After Wang Yun-Ji retired,
Nian Gengyao ordered him to send one to him to train him.
But he actually held him as hostage,
and forced the officers to obey him.
Fine.
This is a big matter.
We will stop here first.
Ask Zhang Ting-Yu and Long Kodo to see me tomorrow.
Leave first.
Thank you, your majesty.
Empress,
Where is his majesty?
He can't come and have dinner with you today.
Please enjoy your meal.
And his majesty can't
come and keep you company as he is busy with state affairs these days.
I will take my leave first.
Stand up.
I have asked everyone besides his majesty,
so Zhen Yuan Dao reported about my brother and his subordinates.
His majesty has sent the ministry of justice to probe into those things.
They said that
my brother tried to bribe by using his position.
And depended on his subordinate to get extra money.
His majesty hates greedy people.
How can he be so careless?
And pissed his majesty off.
Its Zhen Yuan-Dao's fault.
Zhen Yuan-Dao is going against me for his daughter's sake.
I wonder if his majesty will lie the blame on my brother.
Its the thing of the servants.
It should not involve General Nian.
Some fools reported on General Nian in the past.
They were excused by his majesty in the end.
Its because his majesty has always protected my brother.
Now he has sent people to investigate,
if my brother knew about the things that Wei Zhi-Hao was doing.
It means that he has suspected my brother.
Empress, it is common for his majesty to follow the rules.
My brother's subordinate
still tried to hide it for Wei Zhi-Yao.
Now his thinks that my brother's subordinate are protecting each other.
That's why he sent men to question my brother.
No wonder,
his majesty has not been visiting me.
I think that he is partly blaming me too.
Don't be sad,
it is hard for you to meet his majesty now.
The more you should not speak of General Nian now.
What should I do now?
I can't say anything.
Empress, I think that you
have to pacify his majesty.
Then, I will get Lady Cao to speak up for me.
No. She isn't the one whom his majesty likes the most.
Neither is she someone that his majesty dotes,
it is inconvenient for her to do so.
I will have to arrange for someone
to stay by his majesty.
so that that person can speak on my behalf.
Your majesty, Wei Zhi-Yao is a small case.
I was told that Nian Gengyao has sent his family to do business everywhere to earn money.
Nian Gengyao's sons have
monoplolised the salt business.
Earning more than One hundred and seventy thousand dollars in the past 2 years.
These are only the tip of the ice berg.
According to the law of the Qing dynasty, the officers in our dynasty
have to use letters of contract to show that they are fair.
But Nian Gengyao used the decree
to contract with those officers.
He took himself as your majesty,
Nian Gengyao wrote
A poem for your majesty.
A few days ago,
Nian Gengyao used your name
to write a poem.
And spread it to the public.
As an officer,
it is easy perform merits,
but it is hard to be successful.
If it is easy to suceed,
it will be hard to keep the merits.
If it easy to keep the merits,
it wil be hard to suceed in the end.
If you depend on your merits to create trouble,
you will be in trouble in the end.
This is common for everyone.
Spread this.
Don't let him over estimate himself.
Your majesty, he is pushing his luck
and being rebelious.
Nian Gengyao
did many things for the country.
I don't want to make a clean break with him yet.
Your majesty, its tea time.
Serve it then.
Your majesty, this is latest Long Jin tea.
Please try it.  I did not ask for your opinion, shut up.
Please pardon me.
Song-Zhi,
its you?
Imperial Consort Hua ordered me to serve you tea.
You look good in this attire.
I will be taking my leave first.
Good bye your majesty.
Rise.
Did you say that it was Imperial Consort Hua who sent you here?
Greetings Consort Hua.
Greetings.
Rise.
Thank you, your majesty.
Please enjoy the tea.
Consort,
it is late now.
I think Miss Song-Zhi won't be
coming today.
Please take your leave first.
Thank you, eunuch Su.
You have really good taste.
That helped Miss Song-Zhi to see his majesty.
Aren't you sleeping?
I promoted them Consort
Cao and Consort Li were close to me.
But I don't really
want to send women to his majesty.
You were forced to do so.
I badly wish for Song Zhi's return
to tell me that his majesty doesn't fancy her
and wants her to leave.
But it brings no advantages
to our plan.
Leave.
You are a good servant.
I dare not forget my identity.
Speaking of which, I must not let you suffer.
Since you are with Imperial Consort Hua, I won't treat you badly.
You may start
from a higher rank.
Thank you, your majesty.
Go and give Imperical Consort Hua a kowtow.  She is your master after all.
You should be grateful that she promoted you.
Yes.
Consort, the water is warm.
I have put the roses in too, let me wash your face first.
She's back.
Did his majesty give you any position?
He gave me
a higher position because of how much he cares about you.
Its rare that his majesty is so nice.
He must have liked you very much.
Having these merit
is all thanks to you.
His majesty treated me nicely because I was your servant.
Fine.
You're already someone with position.
Stop mocking yourself.
Where did his majesty assign your new living quarters?
He asked me to stay with you
since I am your servant.
Although his majesty treated me well,
but its all because of your promotion.
No matter what my position is,
I am always your servant.
Rise.
Since you are grateful,
I will treat you as if you are my sister.
As Zhou Ning-Hai to clean the room,
and send 2 more people to serve you.
Thank you.
Go and have a rest.
Let the others serve me.
I am used to serving you,
please let me serve you.
That's rare of you,
Su Pei-Sheng,
Your majesty?
I am going to see the Empress.
Yes.
Then are you going back to Kyushu or to Imperial Consort Hua's place?
To Consort Hua's place.
Onward to the house to cool winds.
Do you think that I am temperamental?
Your majesty, you are ruler.
You can go anywhere you wish to go.
It is normal.
I haven't been visiting Imperial Consort Hua for quite a while.
She has become considerate.
I will wait and see.
You've not been coming here for a long time.
I was busy,
you have to understand that.
Take your seat.
I am happy to be able to serve you and his majesty.
We're sisters,
I feel bad to see you suffer.
Just let her be.
I remeber that you like gold,
my brother sent it here.
It is so rare that he is not extravagant.
He has always said
that we can't waste money.
His position is high
and your majesty has high regards for his ability.
Therefore, there are bound to be some people who are jealous of that.
Consort Hua,
I know what to do.
you've been with me for so long, you should know what can't be mentioned.
Yes.
Since you've finished your meal,
why don't we let Song-Zhi take a nap with you?
Yes, I am sleepy.
I will go to her room.
Yes.
Why did she
recommend her servant?
She is afraid of being dis commended again,
actually she started searching for a successor
ever since she lost Consort Li.
It just that she doesn't want to use girls from rich families.
As it might hard for her to control her in the future.
Thus, she chose Song-Zhi.
She's smart.
Do you think that Song-Zhi will succeed?
Do you want to hear the truth?
Imperial Consort Hua has overdone it.
Why?
Song-Zhi is smart and pretty,
but she is too obedient.
Therefore, she won't succeed.
Imperial Consort Huan wants to use Song-Zhi to fight with you and Lady An.
It is not a good idea at all.
I never knew that Song-Zhi can go against us.
Imperial Consort Hua has run out of ways.
In the past,
she will never allow any of her pretty servants
to get near his majesty.
But now..
She knows that.
Time has changed,
Yes your father
leads the other to lodge a report against Nian Gengyao.
She is doomed.
Consort, his majesty has honored one of the
servants of Imperial Consort Hua.
She is suppose to start from the lowest position.
Why did I not hear any news of this?
About them,
I don't think it follows the rules.
The rules are set by his majesty,
This palace hasn't had a new consort for a long time.
Just let them be.
How did you comb?
Comb my hair properly.
The weather is so hot, thank goodness your highness is bringing us to a show.
Its the order from his majesty.
It is so how now, it won't be any better in the afternoon.
Young master hates the hot weather, I'll give you a change of clothes when we get back.
Greetings, Imperial Consort Hua.
Rise.
Did you know that
what contributed to what I have today?
You are a blessed person,
your future is unpredictable.
Congratulations
to you.
Save it,
I wouldn't dare be disrespectful to Consort Wan.
The more you respect me,
the more I hate you.
Aren't you humorous.
Do you want me to be rude to you?
I dare not be rude to you.
Even if so, you have already done it.
I won't forget the past.
You are right.
I am willing to learn a lesson from you anytime.
You might want to listen,
but yet, I don't want to see your face at all.
Don't be angry,
its not worth it for you to feel angry because of me.
Everybody is different,
it is impossible for a honorable person to be angry because of a lowly individual.
It will only bring advantages to those lowly people.
You...
Isn't this Song-Zhi?
You are right,
everyone is different.
Its too bad
for you to be lowly ranked.
I will definitely speak up for you
to his majesty for a higher position.
It will bring out your identity.
His majesty
invited us to go for a show.
He even ordered them to perform your favorite songs.
Why should we speak with
such people under such a hot day.
Liu-Zhu, lets go.
I was worried that you weren't back from the hot weather outside.
I was about to send someone to look for you.
I was just walking around in the garden.
Nothing will happen.
It angers me so much.
We actually met Imperial Consort Hua and the newly favored Song-Zhi.
Young master suffered because of them.
Why?
His majesty likes young master now. Don't they know how to be careful?
Imperial Consort Hua used to be like this.
But Song-Zhi, who is a servant actually dare to be mean to master.
She is with Imperial Consort Hua,
its only natural that she helps her.
Young master was being too kind. We can let Imperial Consort Hua go,
but Song-Zhi was being too arrogant.
If I were young master, I would have given her a slap to the face
and report it to his majesty.
She is so mean.
She's my first subordinate.
You are being too anxious.
Nothing can be done like that.
I told you not to talk back to Imperial Consort Hua.
Don't even talk back to the people around her.
Just let them be, we still have a long way to go.
But Song-Zhi was so mean to you, are you just going to let it slip?
Huan-Bi, what do you think?
We should bear with it first.
We must do this.
Moreover, it is not worth it to take action on Song-Zhi.
Bearing with Song-Zhi doesn't mean that I am okay with such behavior from others.
Song-Zhi did so because she has Imperial Consort Hua backing her.
Do you think she has the ability for it? She is only a small servant.
Do you mean...
We should
aim the master first,
Yes.
I have read these documents.
They are all reporting about Nian Gengyao.
I have replied to them too.
Yes.
Please punish him.
Nian Gengyao is arrogrant.
Therefore, its natural that his subordinates are unhappy with him.
As the emperor,
I have to listen to the
the words of my officers.
Zhen Yuan-Dao,
Yes.
You have to
get everyone who has power in the government to speak up.
Yes your majesty.
2 days ago,
I asked Nian Gengyao regarding an important matter.
Of course,
I want to listen to your opinions.
Yes.
My 8th and 9th brother
have been imprisoned in the Clan Court for quite some time.
I hear that not only have they not reflected on their wrong doings,
instead, they accused me and my father.
What do you think I should do?
They went into collision secretly,
they deserve the punishment for not reflecting on their wrong doings.
What does uncle think of this?
Although they are guilty,
but they are still our family.
How about sending some elders from our family to teach them.
Zhen Yuan-Dao,
I think that we can't be easy on them simply because they are our family.
Perhaps, they are not reflecting on their wrong doings because of their relationship with us.
You are right.
I will think about it.
Your majesty has asked about the actions to be taken on his brothers.
What are your opinons?
The general has been complaining recently,
and yet his majesty...
But his majesty rewarded those who made the complain.
I think General is unhappy about it,
but he can't offend his majesty now.
Therefore he can't,
simply give an answer to his majesty.
Yes.
If his majesty shows no mercy to his brothers,
he will do the same to brother too,
When I am maligned in the future.
You are imagining things.
His majesty would not do such a thing to general.
Many people are complaining about my brother,
even his followers want to rebel against him.
What does his majesty want posing such a question to my brother?
What does he mean?
Perhaps...
Perhaps his majesty just wanted opinions.
No,
his majesty is not like this.
He has always been biased to brother.
But now he is starting to desolate him.
The Nian family has always been loyal to the royal family.
Yes.
His majesty must have been suborned by rumors.
He is concerned.
If you think that it might affect you, you can get
general to behave in front of his majesty, and try to move his majesty.
His majesty must be reminded
of the contributions that General has contributed to the country.
But my brother tried to fight for the crown with his majesty.
His majesty hates them the most.
Is it ok for me to answer to him like this?
Of course we can't let General to advice his majesty to release them,
but he may mention their brotherly love.
And show his loyalty.
Well, there's no harm in doing so.
It is only a moderate way.
His majesty is a soft-hearted person.
He must treat everyone the same way.
You sure are relaxed.
Greetings your majesty.
I have nothing to do.
Have you finished meeting with the officers?
Were you here just now?
Was it regarding General Nian?
Its regarding you.
Of course, I knew that you've done your best to tolerate.
You won't believe me, right?
Yes.
Imperial Consort Hua told me that you were disrespectful to her even though she bought Song-Zhi to argue with you.
She is stubborn.
Then what is your plan?
I don't want this to happen too.
I don't want you to be bothered by these things.
I just want to tell you that I can no longer tolerate Nian Gengyao anymore.
You are the ruler, there is nothing you can't do.
Since the blade has been in your heart for so long,
its time to remove it.
The reason why I tolerated him till now is just so that it will be easier for me to remove it.
Would you do so if it was you?
I understand.
Good,
its still early, I'll be going back first.
You may rest.
Goodbye, your majesty.
I will be organizing a feast at Kyushu inn tomorrow,
be there early.
Yes.
Consort,
his majesty too Song-Zhi's card again.
Take your leave first.
Yes.
Did you hear that?
His majesty went to see Song-Zhi again.
He has been so lately.
She is his majesty's new love.
Who does she think she is?
She was still a low servant yesterday.
But now, she has climbed onto his majesty's bed.
I don't want her to dirty the beds of Kyushu.
Sister Wan is straight forward.
But you can't speak like that to outsiders.
This is a fact. I am not afraid of other people spreading it.
I must make her desolated.
Your majesty, I hear that you been disliking General Nian these days.
And always scolding him.
Who told about it?
I dare not utter nonsense,
I heard this from Imperial Consort Hua.
What did they say?
Did they say that I wronged him?
No.
They said that General Nian did not behave properly and angered you.
I am angry is because I have high regard for his abilities.
I wanted him to settle everything for me,
and not let other people get a hold of him.
So you did not desolate him.
I love you and Imperial Consort Hua,
Nian Gengyao has contributed well to the society.
Moreover, I am his brother-in-law.
Imperial Consort Hua has been
serving me for many years and nurturing you.
I know what to do.
Your majesty.
My brother has followed my instructions and sent the document to his majesty.
His majesty said nothing.
But he has stopped accusing brother.
That's great, I can stop worrying too.
You know nothing.
I know how his majesty accused brother everyday.
It is really terrifying.
Luckily Song-Zhi knew that his majesty thinks
from his tone of voice,
that he thinks brother has done well for the society.
Yes.
I am assured too.
His majesty was just acting
in order to satisfy those despicable men.
How would he truly accuse the general?
Your idea really did worked.
As long as his majesty cares more about you, I am happy.
Good.
I will be good to you too
as long as his majesty treats me and my brother well.
I will let his majesty
honor you as consort soon.
Empress, Consort Song-Zhi is back.
She wants to give her greetings to you.
Ask her to go and rest.
Yes.
Wait a minute,
don't forget to bring some ginseng soup for her.
Yes.
Song-Zhi slept with his majesty again.
Your lesson is really good. She is new favor now.
It is her fate.
I trained you too.
But you don't seem to be getting the same treatment.
But recently,
I've heard some rumors
that Consort Wan isn't happy about Song-Zhi.
I've heard these from his majesty too.
No wonder his majesty
didn't visit her recently.
Why would his majesty
listen to Consort Wan's words of jealousy?
I will let her get what she wants.