~ Episode 15 ~
Auntie
What's the matter? So rash
Nothing
I didn't listen to Princess of Glory regarding An Bihuai
so she threw tantrums for a couple days.
I should do something to appease her
I treat you differently from others
You know that
I dare not think that
When I think of Yushi and Pin of Beauty,
I'm still a bit frightened.
How could I not understand your thoughts?
Actually I want to promote you to Pin
but you have only been here a short while,
and I promoted you to Precious just after you served me.
I've already gone against tradition
You'll just have to bear it for a few days
When you become pregnant then it will be justifiable
I don't care about status
as long as you have me in your heart
How could my heart not have you in it?
I care about you very much.
In the palace there are so many people and none of them allow me any peace
Only at your place can I feel satisfied
I know
You went to see Mei older sister
Has her appetite improved?
It's still the same. She still likes to eat sour foods
It would be good when you give birth to a white and chubby prince
A prince is good, and a princess isn't?
As long as it is our kid, I will like it
Good evening your majesty, good evening Precious Smile
You may rise
Thank you your majesty
Lingrong, where are you going?
To see Mei older sister
What a coincidence, that is where his majesty and I are going
let's go together
yes
let's go
Hui Precious I see that your color is very good
I believe that this birth will be very safe and healthy
His majesty has arrived
May your majesty have peace
Today is such a coincidence you are all here
Hui Precious is pregnant
As the Center of Harem
It is my responsibility to care after the others as it is my duty
We follow the Empress
Get up, get up, come come come
How is it
How are you feeling?
I think that everything is very well. Thank you your majesty
Has your majesty had dinner yet?
A new chef has arrived in my palace
and made great dishes from Jian Nan
I just had dinner at Bi Tong study
maybe some other day
Precious Smile's palace should also have a good chef
only that could give his majesty the incentive to stay
Princess of Glory, the Longan soup in your palace
already is unforgettable to his majesty
Now your palace as aquired a good chef
wouldn't his majesty's soul keep thinking about Princess of Glory?
Over a month I haven't chatted with Precious Smile
Wan Precious' speaking is as good as ever
She's young, clever and likes to joke around
Must you argue with her?
Your Majesty, I like Precious Smile's wit
I was just joking with her
Your Majesty, General Yili gave us some honeydew melons as presents
Let's try them together
Alright
Your Majesty, it's time to flip a plaque
Not necessary, I'm going to the Empress's
If you have more honeydew melons at your place, I will eat them there
Yes
Precious Smile, keep Precious Virtue company
Who's creeping around there?
We see you! Quick, come out!
Don't take me!
I serve Precious Virtue!
This...
Isn't she fleaing from Precious Virtue's palace?
Why is she sneaking around here?
What do you have in your hands?
What is this?
What?
Want to steal and run away with young mistress's things?
What a disappointing servant! Quickly drag her out!
You're pregnant. No need to upset yourself.
Young mistress, save me!
How do you expect me to tolerate
you doing such a thing? Hurry, go!
Wait!
This...
This...What is this?!
Blood!
Why do these pants have blood on them?
Did someone commit murder?
This is strange
Why didn't she steal something more valuable?
Only filthy pants and skirts?
Do these belong to Precious Virtue?
Why are they stained with blood?
Could it be...that Precious Virtue has her period?
I didn't
Your Majesty, this girl is acting very strange
I think she should be taken to the Bureau of Cautious Punishment
for a thorough interrogation.
Such dirty hands
Quickly drag her out to be beaten!
Young mistress
Young mistress...servant was destroying evidence for you!
But instead you will heartlessly see me die!
Why should I stay loyal to you?
Your Majesty!
Under the circumstances, servant dares not hide anymore from Your Majesty
Young mistress is actually not pregnant at all!
I didn't steal these clothes either
Young mistress had her period several days ago
She stained her underpants and told me to dispose of them!
These clothes are irrefutable evidence!
Sister
Your Majesty...she...she is slandering me!
Precious Virtue has been startled. Quickly get the imperial doctor here.
Yes
Su Gong Gong
Please get Doctor Liu who has been caring for my pregnancy
But, I don't know if he's on call tonight
Replying to young mistress,
Imperial Doctor Liu is not on call tonight.
Not a big deal if he isn't
Get the head of the imperial hospital, Zhang Ni
Yes
Your Majesty...but my pregnancy has always been in the care of Doctor Liu
Doesn't matter!
They're all the same!
Imperial Doctor Zhang, what is the situation? Was the fetus startled?
Your Majesties, forgive me
Precious Shen...she has no signs of pregnancy
Nonsense! The child is perfectly fine, how could I not be pregnant?!
Sister, calm down
Maybe the doctor made a mistake in his diagnosis
I do not have divine power
If I may recommend
Please ask imperial Doctor Jiang to confirm
Get him!
Yes
Replying to Your Majesty, young mistress is not pregnant
I don't know which imperial doctor diagnosed young mistress as pregnant
You're wrong! Young mistress didn't have her period
She vomits and also craves sour foods. Aren't those signs of pregnancy?
But in my humble opinion,
young mistress should have had her period in the past couple days.
Her period is just irregular and came late
It should be the result of taking medicine
Several months ago, Precious Virtue asked me
for a prescription to delay her period.
She said her periods were irregular, causing difficulty conceiving
Although I was hesitant,
young mistress kept on saying it was for the sake of Your Majesty's posterity.
I had no choice but to give her the prescription
As for why young mistress vomits and like sour foods,
that I don't know.
Your Majesty, I did secretly ask imperial Doctor Jiang for a prescription,
but this prescription was to help with conceiving, not postpone my period!
I've been falsely accused!
Where's the prescription?
Everything will be clear from the paper
Caiyue
Get the prescription from the bottom of the makeup box
Your Majesty, I know that secret dealings violate palace rules
Please forgive me!
Yes, engaging in secret dealings
is a much smaller crime than faking pregnancy to gain favor.
Young mistress, it's not here!
Stop looking!
Su Pei Sheng
Servant here
Go find Liu Ben
If he dares delay, immediately tie him up!
Replying to Your Majesty,
when I went to ask for imperial doctor Jiang,
I also ordered someone to get imperial doctor Liu.
But doctor Liu has already vacated his residence
Great
Precious Shen, you're both from the same town right?
You recommended him to care for the pregnancy, right?
Your Majesty
Whoever speaks for Precious Shen will receive the same punishment
Your Majesty, Precious Smile and Precious Virtue have long been good friends
Who knows if today's incident...
Shut up!
Your Majesty, please calm down
You deceived me and the Empress Dowager
You still dare wear and show off this hairpin?
Your Majesty, your health is of utmost importance
I have always liked how steady you were
I never thought you would succumb this easily
to fake a pregnancy to gain favor
I am so disappointed
You majesty I am innocent
I really am innocent!
Your majesty, I grew up with older sister
The type of person older sister is I am more sure about than anything
Although she was wrong today
because of her loyalty to you
Please giver her a chance to redeem herself
Please think about it again
Please forgive Precious Shen your majesty
Precious Smile's words are logical
Precious Shen was just to eagar to have an heir
Please look to your past feelings your majesty
Precious Shen
Your words are not reliable
Your status will be lowered to Promise and your title will be taken away
you will be put in Xian Yue Ge
Without my permission, no one may visit
Please direct me your majesty. What of Liu Ben and Fu Ling
Chase Liu Ben... catch him alive
Fu Ling... Kill
Sister!
How could this happen?
How could this happen, Bao Jian?
I'm so scared... Sister's situation would cause harm to us, right?
It''s okay, it's okay
At least Precious Smile is still here
Go quick. This
This
Quick, go burn it
Young mistress embroidered this for days
are we really going to just burn it?
The Emperor is investigating the fake pregnancy case
If this was discovered
It would bring ruin us
Go! Quickly, quickly
It has been done. Money
You'll have your share
Five thousand taels in paper curency. It is enough for the rest of your life
Go ahead and count
Just these taels
Is only enough for me to use in half a year
What?! Liu Ben escaped?!
Please calm down your majesty. Servant has already sent people to chase him
After they catch up to him, kill him without question
Liu Ben knows too much about us
There's no way we can leave him alive
Yes
Your majesty
You may get up
Thank you your majesty
Are the members of Fu Ling's family all set to go?
In reply your majesty
Servant has already given enough money and sent it to Re He
That is good
I had agreed to Fu Ling's request
If this plan did not succeed, her entire family would die.
If it went well
even if she died
I would make sure that her family would be showered in riches
Your majesty is wise. For Fu Ling to die for you
Your majesty would ensure her family's well being
Fu Ling's death is worth it
You may leave
Yes
He's coming
Zhang Gong Gong
Auspicious greetings, Promise An
You are being welcome
Zhang Gong Gong, you promised us yesterday
that you would bring young mistress' four bags back to her home
We prepared them. Sorry to bother you
Miss, I'm really sorry
What I agreed yesterday
I can't carry out today
Gong Gong, a private word please
Is twenty taels of silver not enough?
If it is about that, I'll go back and get more
Young Mistress, in the course of one night
Many things have turned the world upside down
Precious Shen became Promise Shen
Your bag... Servant is honestly scared to deliver it
Hey! Zhang Gong Gong, Zhang Gong Gong
How can you go back on your word?
At least, our Precious Smile is still here
It's not that I am going back on my word
Anyone who gets involved with Promise Shen will become taboo
I don't want to get involved
Then again, Promise Shen has fallen
How can Precious Smile not be dragged down
The way I see it
it just like a rabbit's tail -- not long
Alright Gonggong, let's come to the point
How can these things be sent to my mother
You give me half of these
Be carefulQuickly
This, and that one. Quickly
These things are mine
Why are you taking them out
Promise An, our Niangniang said,
you came here with Promise Shen
According to your status, you shouldn't have lived in such a good room
Thanks to Niangniang is kind, you don't have to move out
but these furnishings
are of no use to you
and you are also not qualified to use them
Niangniang said, we should move out all of these
They are just needed
in these servants' rooms
We can just take yours
Let us go
Foul-mouth's Promise Shen
We didn't get any benefit whe Promise Shen was favoured
Now she has become a Promise, everyone tramples on her
but we have to accompany, what the hell
Enough, keep it yourself
Young mistress, why are you still here. Please go back
The northwestern war is intense
Except the imperial court, his majesty stays in the hall of policy all the time
reading the booklet
or meeting the ministers
has no time for you
Thank Su Gonggong. I'd like to wait some more
Servant know young mistress is worry about Promise Shen
but you can't disregard your own health.
Young mistress, take this
Thanks Su Gonggong
The weather is so hot
but it is cool inside
Precious Smile
why are you standing in the sun
Are you mildewed (having bad luck)
and have to bask to get it back ?
Wish Princess of Glory safe and lucky
Once the evildoers are eliminated
I will certainly be safe and lucky
Get up
Isn't his majesty busy in political issues
Yes
The northwestern war is not over yet
so his majesty is concerning about my brother
My brother's letter has just arrived
I have to tell everything to his majesty
Thanks Niangniang for telling me these
but whether his majesty has time now
Precious Cao and Wenyi are inside
Precious Smile
Are you going to plead for Shen Meizhuang
His majesty has been bothered for several days
right now Wenyi is accompanying
so he can be a little pleased
Once you are in
no matter whether you will mention Shen Meizhuang or not
you will remind his majesty of her false pregnancy
his majesty will be more angry
I believe Sister Mei can't do this
Whether his majesty trusts you or what he saw
His majesty didn't kill Shen Meizhuang,it's her luck
She dared to play with the dragon's offspring
then she will wait to die in the palaces
The sun is so bright
SongziYes
Back
Su gonggong, please inform my coming once more
your majesty, Precious Smile is still waiting outside
Your majesty, let Precious Smile in
the sun is so bright outside, Precious Smile is worred obout Promise Shen
I'm afraid she will get sunstroke
If she gets sick, Promise Shen wii be worried
and can't calm and repent
The song you just sang souds good, sing it once more to Wenyi
Yes
Shaking and shaking, little baby, sleep quickly
Young mistress, his majesty doesn't want to listen
or want to think about Promise Shen's situation
I think, you should just go back
Thanks Gonggong
Young mistress, how about we go beg Empress Dowager
Younger sister must think it through
If you're health were to deteriorate
in the future if you were to be vindicated
you wouldn't be able to be happy
Thank you sister, for being brave enough to come take care of me
We shared a palace. With this type of incident
It is also because I wasn't able to properly care for you
Now, only I can come here occasionally
Although Precious Smile is worried about you, with all those guards outside
It is difficult for her to enter
You must tell her that she must take care of herself
and not upset his majesty trying to help me
Young sister, even if I were to nag her thousands of times
It would not be as good as you keeping your own body healthy.
If something were to happen to you, Precious Smile would be hurt too
Then, I should eat a little
Young mistress should stop ripping the Lotus
There are only 2 parts left
If it's messed up it's a shame
Things have developed to this stage
How could I not be worried?
Pin of Respects is not a hard-hearted person
I think she will take care of it
Sister Mei was originally highly favored
but now she's suddenly lost favor for committing a crime.
Even if His Majesty doesn't treat her harshly,
what about others in the palace?
Who knows how the others have insulted Sister Mei
Sister Mei is also so strong-willed
- What if she takes it too hard...- Young mistress
Let me speak
Why don't you go beg Auntie Fang Ruo?
She used to be your instructor
Right now she serves up front
Secretly give this to her for me
Say that I beg her help to take good care of Meizhuang
Alright
On my table get a tube of makeup for Fang Rong
say that up front
Her eyebrow doesn't look good
Young mistress
Go
The food is cold
Let's have them bring more hot food
No need
The Internal Affairs Authority only allows the kitchen to bring meals once a day
This is really strict imprisonment
Even I can't bring anything in
Hey, wait
You just said this food
Was ordered by the Internal Affairs Authority?
Yes
We must be careful of others
Toxic
What's wrong?
No, it's nothing. Promise Shen just accidentally dropped the bowl. Go
Young mistress
Young mistress, there's news from the House of Respectful Affairs
Apparently last night, his majesty went to Princess Glory
The closer his majesty gets to her
The more he will dislike Mei sister
I'm afraid that his majesty is even suspicious of me these days
So that's why it's been so long since he's visited
Maybe... his majesty is really busy with court dealings
Also, his majesty is the one by your side at night
Normally he is very trusting with you
If his majesty honestly believed me
After he dealt with Mei sister
He would've rushed to see me
He wouldn't ignore me
His majesty is the one next to my pillow
But he is also at other people's pillows
There is no difference between me and the others
Sister
His majesty is afraid that I'll ruin the royal reputation
So, he this is how he wants to deal with me
No, that's not it sister
His majesty wouldn't be this cruel
He still cares about your family's influence and position
You are from my palace
If you died
it would be said that you committed suicide because of your guilt
and I would also get involved
The person who wants to harm us
there is only one in this palace
Sister is saying.. Princess Glory?
Her vicious ways, I know best
That year, she avoided me and hated me so much
Using various methods to torment me
SIster, you have to tell his majesty for me
But in front of his majesty, I...
am a person whose words are not worth listening to and have no influence
If they really wanted to harm you
They must have plans to make it seem like you killed yourself due to guilt
By reporting it, it is only going to alert the enemy
Then
Then my food...
Not only your food
From now on you have to contantly be vigilant
and make sure no one tampered with anything
I will tell the Empress
and ask her if your food can be made here
it will be less work for the palace as well
Thank you sister for saving my life
What happened today
I ask that sister will not tell Precious Smile
Just in case she won't be able to control herself
Protecting you
is the same as protecting myself
I know what I should do at Precious Smile's place
Your majesty, becareful it's hot
Your eyebrows are drawn as far mountains
Yes
Yes, maid had served the Empress and did it for her
so I know how to do it myself
Greetings Precious Smile
Report to young mistress; his majesty said he will come over tonight. Please prepare yourself
you've worked hard gong gong
Servant is leaving
Finally his majesty is coming
Young mistress, do you want to bring up Mei mistress' problem and persuade him?
At this time, I am more afraid to say anything
I can only wait until his anger subsides, and slowly bring him around
In this event, protecting yourself is the right thing
If I could help her, how could I not say anything?
A couple days ago I lost my temper
You saw how the people in the palace
were eager for me me to lose it again and go beg his majesty
and want his majesty to get rid of me too
How can I satisfy them?
If only there was evidence that Mei mistress was innocent,
I know that Mei mistress was framed
But we have no evidence
Even if I had plan it wouldn't work
That reminds me Liu Zhu
You go tell Xiao Yun Zi to go find Wen Shi chu
Tell him to bring my letter
go to Zhen Fu
and Mei sister's relatives' home
Tell them that they must find Liu Ben for me
I want to see his body or his corpse
I don't believe
That a big living person, can escape without a trace
Yes, maid will definitely do a good job
Huang Gui Quan has really become well off
He has the nerve to put these kinds of flowers in my palace
These lowly people only go where the wind is blowing
Seeing Mei mistress lose her status
and the majesty not coming here anymore... he dares to bring this junk
I'll take it out later
so young mistress won't be irritated
My place is so empty
you don't even have to mention older sister's place
Tomorrow before the sun rises, place the pomegranate flower
In the showiest place
So it will remind me not to forget today's resolution
If his majesty hasn't arrived at this time, he probably won't come
How about you rest first, young mistress
That's not necessary
Wishing his majesty much wealth and health
I am very annoyed
Have some soup your majesty
This soup has been treated with ice but it's not cold
It's night. Eating cold items will harm your body
Mistress had put in two pots of jasmine
That way your majesty wil feel soothed
You don't have anything else to say to me?
Now, the weather is really hot
Gold colored is too obvious
yet light colored can't be spotted
Dear 4th, help me think
Should I use the coral or the jet black?
This is your important matter?
Girls care about appearances a lot
Isn't it important?
It is indeed the most important
In my opinion,
use the coral.
Huan Huan is as pale as snow
If the brows are a little red, you will appear more lively and cute
Many thanks Dear 4th
You're not going to plea for Precious Shen?
As distance tests a horse's strength, so time reveals a person's heart
If there is an ending, there must be experience
Then why do you insist on seeing me?
Dear 4th hasn't seen me in several days
Can't I come see you first?
Everyone says that you are close to Precious Shen
You must have been implicated by her incident
Why don't you vindicate yourself?
Though lies, if repeated often enough, will be accepted as truth,
Dear 4th is a wise ruler who also understands my nature.
Of course you wouldn't believe those one-sided statements
If Dear 4th really doubted me,
I wouldn't be able
to have this chat with you right now.
Right?
Are you that confident
I don't have the slightest doubt towards you?
Dear 4th is my pillow mate
If I can't even believe my own pillow mate,
then who can I believe and rely on?
Dear 4th has already made up his mind about Sister Mei
There's not much I can say about the matter
Didn't you already make that clear?
After Princess of Glory's favor is restored,
I might have to suffer a little.
I won't put you in a difficult position
Lately Dear 4th has been busy with official affairs. Go to sleep.
Empress, I woke up early to hear
that Huang Guiquan got into trouble.
He was sent to serve in the Bureau of Cautious Punishment
Of course. He can't even take care of small things.
This morning, when His Majesty left Precious Smile's place,
he saw a row of withered flowers head-on.
He became angry and sent him away
And I was wondering what huge offense he had committed
Let him return in several days
These palace matters are never trivial
He may neglect flowers and plants today
Then in the future it may grow and
He will even begin to insult and sneer at his masters
I know that Huang Guiquan is your distant relative which is why I must make an example of him even more.
Sister you are kind-hearted. You don't think it's a big deal.
But in others' eyes,
Huang Guiquan abuses his power in your name.
In the end, not to mention your reputation,
is this worth upsetting His Majesty
and alienating him over?
I just think that Huang Guiquan is used to managing the Internal Affairs Authority
There is no one else to replace him in such short time
I just brought it up casually, no other intention
That's exactly why he must be removed cleanly
to avoid tarnishing Sister's reputation.
Of course, the Internal Affairs Authority must have someone in charge
I've already appointed the assistant head
Jiang Zhongmin as the head of the bureau.
Empress is resolute, as fast as the wind
I heard Empress say
that this morning, His Majesty saw
these withered flowers at Precious Smile's place?
I heard the House of Respectful Affairs say
that last night, he flipped Princess of Glory's plaque.
Why would he be at Precious Smile's so early in the morning?
The emperor has thoughts on his mind
That's right
If Princess of Glory had kept him there,
and he hadn't gone to Precious Smile's,
then Huang Guiquan wouldn't be so unlucky.
Thank you for watching!
Subtitles brought to you by The Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki