Episode 39
Look at the document sent by Nian Gengyao.
Nian Gengyao has requested His Majesty to consider his brotherhood.
It doesn't look the same on the outside.
You have to be able to know the hidden meaning behind it.
You are now testing me.
Nian Gengyao is actually trying to use the brotherhood as his reason
and trying to find a way out for himself.
He is smart enough.
If I can forgive the rebellion of Yun-Si and Yun-Tang,
then I can forgive the discretion of Nian Gengyao.
His words are just the same
as said by Long Kodo.
Nian Gengyao and Long Kodo
are my helpful officers.
Even they were fooled by Yun-Si,
and pleaded for him, I'm very disappointed
in the both of them.
Before the titles of Yun-Si and Yun-Tang were taken away,
they were very close to Lord Dun.
So he's the one that you should be mad at, Your Majesty.
Now even Nian Gengyao is the same,
and he has military power too.
I think he's being controlled by Lord Dun.
It will be a grave matter.
I guess your worries will become reality soon.
I've know the conspiracy between Nian Gengyao and Lord Dun since the beginning.
It was not something done in a day or two.
You thought that Nian Gengyao is just a greedy and cruel person
But he is no different from those other rebellious officers.
I think that it's better to cut off their contact from each other.
You must eliminate Lord Dun first, before getting rid of Nian Gengyao.
There will be a lot of trouble
coming from the inner palace.
I must settle the matters of the inner palace first,
before I can concentrate with state affairs
Brother Zhen.
I feel that there is something wrong with His Majesty's words.
You are being too humble, be honest with me
I have only been here to see His Majesty twice,
so I don't understand what His Majesty meant.
Imperial Concubine Wan is most favored by His Majesty,
and would like to send you a message.
Do tell.
His Majesty mentioned Nian Gengyao and Long Kodo together today.
Maybe Nian Gengyao is not the only one that His Majesty wants to eliminate.
His Majesty is wise in his own way.
It is not something that we can fully understand.
Those that have followed His Majesty for a long time,
will naturally know what His Majesty is actually talking about.
There is another thing I noticed,
His Majesty wants the issues of the inner palace to be resolved
before the state affairs.
This might be due to his
promises to balance out everything
In the inner palace,
His Majesty needs to be aware of the situation.
Since all my sisters are present today
I would like to toast Your Majesty and Empress,
May you both always stay healthy.
Your Majesty, I know that drinking is no good for your health,
so I've sincerely prepared a plate of fruits
for Your Majesty to taste.
Not bad.
Song-Zhi Meimei, are these fruits really sincerely chosen for His Majesty?
He did not praise you for that,
looks like you have to pay more attention to what His Majesty likes.
Yes, you are right.
I've only been here for a couple of months
please do guide me along if I make any mistakes.
Although I don't know what His Majesty likes but
I do put in my best effort for all matters related to His Majesty.
All I think about is for you, Your Majesty.
I hope Your Majesty knows how I feel.
Yes I do know.
With me here,
no one will dare speak of you badly.
Your Majesty likes Wan Meimei
it's rare that he will speak up for you.
Looks like Your Majesty really appreciates you, Song-zhi Meimei
You are right, Song-zhi Meimei,
we all have to learn little by little what His Majesty likes.
So you expect His Majesty to be satisfied with empty passion?
But you really have to buck up
it's already July,
His Majesty has to leave in August,
for the once in three years beauty pageant be during mid-autumn.
And when the new ladies arrive, that's when you will have your hands full.
I can't be as busy as you
Imperial Concubine Wan is older and is doted on by His Majesty
I think you can handle everything well while teaching everyone else.
At the same time,
you are not just hardworking but you're good at observing
that's why Imperial Consort Hua likes you
and sends you to His Majesty often. All these are what I'm not capable of.
Imperial Concubine Wan is going too far
Your Majesty, are you going to just let her be?
Empress, what is your opinion?
With so many women around, bickering is unavoidable
I think they've drunk too much and didn't mean what they said
I will talk to them about this later on.
Is this how Empress takes care of the inner palace for me?
No wonder there has been so many problems in the inner palace.
Don't be angry, it is all my fault.
Do you know what you have done wrong?
Aren't you useless if you
can't even handle this small fight. It just shows how incapable you are.
Yes I know I'm guilty, please don't be angry Your Majesty.
Imperial Concubine Wan!
Yes
Go
Your Majesty?
Your Majesty means...
His Majesty is fair and just, he has never been biased.
Imperial Concubine Wan did not choose her words wisely
she will be sent to Penglai Island to reflect on her mistakes tomorrow
and may not leave the island until further notice.
Your Majesty, Penglai Island is such a deserted place only reachable by boats, not to mention how far away it is
and there hasn't been anyone living there. Seeing how it's Jiejie's first mistake, please forgive her.
Your Majesty, I've been here for 3 years
I know I have said the wrong words but please reconsider your decision
and forgive me this once. I will never do it again.
Weren't you all proud and arrogant when you spoke to Song-zhi just now?
If you could do this in front of me, I can't imagine how you are like behind my back.
I didn't speak those words on purpose.
I have doted on Song-zhi during this time,
so you have been making things difficult for her
and talking about her behind her back.
How can I forgive you?
I did not.
Your Majesty knows
I've always been straightforward
but I really didn't mean it.
Your Majesty, seeing as how it's her first mistake
why don't you just forgive her?
Penglai Island is too deserted and far.
His Majesty has already made his stand
do you still dare to challenge him?
Consort Jing,
Consort Jing, would you like to accompany her as well?
Ah.
It's must be hard on Zhi.
I will console her myself.
Su Pei-sheng.
Yes.
Imperial Concubine Wan, please rise
I will get some people
to send you to Penglai Island.
Imperial Concubine Wan, do take care.
I will take my leave now.
Although I am inadept
but I will help you take good care of His Majesty.
Please take care.
Good evening, Empress.
Go ahead.
Thank you, Empress.
Why did you ask me here in such a hurry?
Is anything the matter?
I feel that what happened tonight
is strange and
I can't stop worrying about it.
Yes, I agree as well.
No matter how much His Majesty likes Song-zhi
he needn't to go to the extent of getting angry with Wan.
Imperial Concubine Wan's father is the biggest critic of Nian Gengyao.
Is His Majesty using Song-zhi to protect Lady Hua?
Has His Majesty changed his mind
is protecting Nian Gengyao the reason for this?
If this is really the case
doesn't it mean that Imperial Concubinet Wan can't be saved.
If Imperial Concubine Wan is not the favorite, Zhen Yuan-dao will have no support at all.
And nobody will be able to defeat Nian Gengyao.
I refuse to let this happen.
What are you planning to do?
Although Nian Gengyao has been criticized,
thus getting scolded by His Majesty
but he was never really punished before.
Lady Hua has power in the inner palace
after Imperial Concubine Wan leaves, you'll be her next target.
Why don't you accompany Imperial Concubine Wan, and observe from afar?
What do you think?
Er...
If Imperial Cocubine Wan doesn't even come back
won't have to stay there forever with her?
Don't worry,
by then even if you want to stay of your own accord
I will still make you leave.
For this matter
I keep feeling that
it would be better
if you accompanied Imperial Concubine Wan.
Yes,
I will go with her then.
Jiejie!
Are you here to send me off?
I have already informed His Majesty
that I will stay with you in Penglai Island.
What are you saying?
I will stay with you in Penglai Island.
His Majesty has already given his approval.
So I'm not here to send you off.
Don't speak nonsense
do you really think
we're going there to be goddesses?
If you leave with me
your future in the palace will be ruined.
Why would you want live such a hard life with me?
Jiejie, I know it very well
that since I received this title,
I have offended a lot of people.
Only you treated me differently.
Now that you're leaving
rather than stay in the palace and be sneered at
and ignored
why not follow you there?
We can take care
and look out for each other.
Congratulations
you have eliminated another enemy.
She's only leaving for Penglai Island
you never know if she will come back.
With Song-zhi Meimeihere,
what do you have to be afraid of?
At the right moment
you just to utter a few more words,
which would be more than enough.
These are all not important
what matters is that His Majesty scolded Imperial ConcubineWan
teaching Zhen Yuan-dao a lesson.
I feel more relaxed now.
Precious An
even left with her.
The Empress' authority has been weakened.
Girls like An Ling-rong have no strong family backing
even if she sings herself hoarse, she is just someone who can sing.
She's just lucky that His Majesty dotes on her
but her luck is not going to last forever.
I have to say
you're really planned it out well
this time.
Now that Zhi is His Majesty's favorite,
of my effort would have gone down the drain.
Zhi has truly gained His Majesty's favour
it'll be even better if you can get the title of Chang Zai.
Yes, if you get pregnant
your position will be same as mine then.
Honoured Lady Cao please don't speak so highly of me
no matter what titles I receive, I am still your slave
I will never dare forget that.
Glad you know that.
Let's go.
There's only one way to Penglai Island
once the boat leaves you're stranded here and won't be able to leave the island.
I'm grateful that His Majesty has assigned me to such a peaceful place.
Although it can't be compared to Shu Yuan but it's not too run down
I initially believed that Penglai Island has lost all its lustre
but it looks clean and nice.
Although His Majesty sides Lady Hua but he would never treat you badly.
This place has been tidied up so well, I know that you must have done a lot.
Thank you very much.  You've always
taken care and looked out for me
now that you're here, I just wanted to show my gratitude.
I hope I have the chance to serve you in future.
Look, you've always treated others well and others are now reciprocating.
Even I get to enjoy the benefits of this.
I can't stay for long
in future I will get someone to send supplies to the island.
It's getting back, do rest early.
Thank you Gonggong.
Don't be dejected, His Majesty is just momentarily fooled by Lady Hua.
He still loves you deeply.
Who knows, one day he'll get someone to escort you back.
Don't worry about me, I feel bad for implicating you.
Why did you only bring along Bao-juan? What about Ju-qing?
Bao-juan has served me for the longest time
I'm used to having her around. Ju-qing was given to me by you
I'm can't bear to bring her along. Let her guard the House of Free Moon for me.
But don't worry Jiejie, I know some sewing skills
we can do everything ourselves.
Sorry to trouble you.
Consorts, Jing is here.
Greetings Empress, Wan has already left for Penglai Island.
Stand.
We can't even send her off
only Honoured Lady An is loyal and went along with her.
That's good too, with Lady Hua getting powerful
they should go as far away as they can.
Out of sight, out of mind
it's harder for us here, always having to be wary of others.
How do you expect us to feel if you say that
this palace needs you.
What else can I do? With Lady Hua lording over me.
That might not be the case, although His Majesty favours Lady Hua and Zhi
but he hasn't made any decision on Nian Gengyao's issue.
Why do you have to be afraid of you, you're the leader of the inner palace and we all obey you
she can't do anything on her own.
Yes I know and lucky I still have you all.
Wan and Honoured Lady An have both left
if we don't stick together, I fear we'll
be the ones going to Penglai Island next.
We see you as our leader.
That's enough, please stand.
Thank you NiangNiang.
Zhou Ning-hai offers his greetings to the Empress.
Lady Hua will be dining with His Majesty, so
she won't be able to offer her greetings today.
She hopes you can forgive her.
She's not coming but how about Zhi?
Zhi will be joining them, so she won't be able to make it as well.
Empress, you won't get mad over such a small matter,
right?
If this is a small matter,
what is considered a big issue then? Forget it
Lady Xin, issues pertaining to His Majesty are big matters.
Zhou Ning-hai you may take your leave.
Thank you Empress, I will leave now.
It's almost winter time, His Majesty should be back soon right?
Yes I heard it's the beginning of next month.
Then Consort Jing will be back soon too.
Consort Jing will be back soon, but not Concubine Wan.
What? I didn't dare inform you
that Imperial Concubine Wan incurred the wrath of His Majesty and was banished to Penglai Island.
Penglai Island is worse than the cold palace (where disfavored queen or concubine was placed)
it's like being in jail.  Yes
His Majesty will be back soon
yet no one is cleaning the House of Broken Jade
I don't think she can come back this time.
Consort Wan is alone without anything
how pitiful.
We don't even know what's happening now.
Why don't we get someone to send some things over?
She was so favoured before, what does she lack?
Don't waste your effort.
Are you thinking of His Majesty?
No I'm thinking of myself.
Maybe His Majesty has already forgotten about us.
How would we even know that?
Don't be sad.
I cooked you fish taufu.
Please come in.
You go ahead. I will be there in a minute.
Quick.
Eunuch Su is here to see you.
It's almost winter now.
You didn't bring enough clothes.
Lady Hui asked to bring a few clothes from the palace.
She still remembers me.
Lady Hui is actually very concerned about you.
These are for the Honoured Lady An.
but she prepared two sets. How can she forget you?
Your Majesty asked about you.
I'm fine thank you.
Yes.
What about Your Majesty?
He's fine as well.
Everything's fine?
Everything's fine. Don't worry.
Great then.
I came here this time is to inform you that
Your Majesty is returning.
We don't know what the condition is.
Please take good care of Your Majesty.
Yes.
Yes I have to go tomorrow.
I have a smart student. He will
send your things to you.
If anything happens in Capital,
please send someone to inform me.
Your Majesty is worried that you might be the first to get hurt.
So he sends you away for good.
Yes, I will pray for his safety as well.
I can't stay very long.
I have to go now.
Yes
You've returned.
Your Majesty, I got this
mail from middle.
This mail is from the messenger of Lord Dun.
He's trying to persuade Nian
Gengyao to help him and
let Yun-Si be the emperor.
Mother to Yun-Si as Empress.
I can't let them succeed,
else it will be a disaster for us.
Come
Your Majesty
Order your assassins to
guard Lord Dun for me.
I will send a troop of army
to capture everyone.
Thank you for your help.
I just tried my best to help.
You are the only one who can be around Lord Dun
without raising suspicion.
Help me guard his house tonight.
Report immediately if anything happens.
Yes.
Su Pei Sheng.
Tell Empress
that she is not feeling well tonight,
so she needs Lord Dun's wife and son
to serve by her side.
Yes.
Empress had already reminded me regarding that matter.
Your Majesty had already returned for almost a month.
It's almost winter time now.
What happened?
My hand is getting tired from holding the book.
No wonder, you are reading the
You must be afraid.
Yes, I am afraid.
The fight between the brothers,
there will always be a losing side.
This is a matter of life and death.
Those are the men's pride.
As for us, Your Majesty is the one who
gives up pride and honor.
We might not be able to share his glory,
but when he is humiliated, we will definitely be humiliated too.
You just can't let go of him, don't you?
It is not that I can't let go,
but after all these years, other than life and wealth,
there must be something that you can't let go.
He is the only man
in my whole life.
Yes.
Recently, you always seem worried,
is there anything bothering you?
After this light, no matter
what you worries are, they will be settled.
Look, this lady has been sleeping
I just made some food, please eat it while it's still hot.
It's been a long time since I last had taro.
I always had it at home.
Smells nice.
Eat it.
Your Majesty.
How was it?
Everything is under control.
We have captured Lord Dun.
When my father was still alive,
Yun Si, Yun Tang and Yun Er tried to
seize the throne.
They have gone too far.
So their title had been taken away.
However, because of Imperial Consort Xi,
they got their title back.
In order to calm him,
I gave him the Duke title.
But he is too greedy.
Yes.
Thank you for your help.
I never wanted to let you see this,
but thank you for your help.
There are still a lot of rebels,
but I hope that Yun will be the last
I hope that the others will just obey.
I can't say for others,
but I am just an ordinary person.
I just wanted to keep my position,
I do not wish to be involved in such dangerous matters in the future.
Since you have already said that,
how can I say no to you?
Thank you.
Honoured Lady An has not woke up yet?
Yes, she stayed up late sewing last night.
Look.
What are you doing?
Your Majesty told me that nothing is guaranteed,
so I have to protect myself.
I've promised Your Majesty that
if anything happens, I will not live alone.
Consort.
If Your Majesty failed,
I can't protect myself either.
Rather than being tortured, I rather die.
Is Your Majesty safe?
Yes, he is safe and healthy.
Consort
Consort, please do not cry. This is
Your Majesty order me to send you and
During these few months,
you've lost some weight.
I've been worried about you
Me too.
So I rushed here immediately once I know you are back.
when she knew that
you will be sent to Penglai Island.
It is really hard to find such a great friend.
Yes, she is
but I do not dare to tell her the truth.
It's for her own good.
Your Majesty, are you alright?
You have been asking this question ever since you returned.
Really? I did not realise that.
Everything is over now.
Yun Si will be renamed as Akina
Akina Saisihei?
It means pig and dog in our language.
They tried to rebel, giving them such names
is an insult to the animals.
Your Majesty captured Lord Dun.
This is all heaven's will for everything to go well.
I would like to tell you another thing.
Before he tried to rebel, he once requested
army from Nian Gengyao, but this letter
had been intercepted by Guo Jun Wang.
I don't think he really wants to rebel.
He just can't give up his wealth. If he really does that,
he would get less than what he owns now.
Nian Gengyao is unsatisfied with me...
but he will still consider about Lady Hua.
I am just curious,
why did Lord Dun seek Nian Gengyao instead of others?
Let me think about that.
I don't care about what other thinks,
all I know is that you have suffered
To be honest, I am not willing to send you to Penglai Island.
I am worried that you will be hurt if you remained here.
Without you here,
Nian Gengyao and Lady Hua will be less cautious.
Yes, I understand. This is nothing
compared to Your Majesty.
You are the one who understands me best.
Greeting, Empress.
Come back in the morning if you are just here to greet me.
You must be exhausted from
Thank you, Empress.If I don't visit you, I won't be able to sleep well tonight.
Please rise.
Did you complain anything
to Wan on the way back?
No, I would not dare to speak much.
Good to hear that. She will not easily tell you what Your Majesty told her.
and she will be praised for keeping secrets.
It will be better for you
Your Majesty had a great impression of you
for accompanying her.
If not for your advise,
I would not have
Wan is too smart,
making you seem foolish.
Although I don't understand, but I will listen to you.
Your Majesty is not sharing his worries with me now.
So I will have to find my own way,
else Wan might be the second Lady Hua.
I guess she won't be that serious.
She does not have the ability to do that either.
She have the ability to get Your Majesty love her.
It is always good to be more wary.
Nian Gengyao is also affected
by the capture of Lord Dun.
You can worry less about Lady Hua now.
Good morning Empress.
Please rise.
Thank you.I am feeling unwell,
I would like to excuse myself.
It's okay. Since there's nothing much, everyone may leave.Wan, please stay.
Goodbye.
Please have a seat.
Thank you.
You've have a hard time.
This is nothing compared to Empress.
It is our responsibility to take care of Your Majesty.
the people around here will be involved as well.
After that, not many will be left here.
Are you going to select more ladies for Your Majesty?
Your Majesty does not want that.
What we meant is that, many people have contributed
to put down Lord Dun. If there are any suitable
ladies within these people,
You have the same thinking as Your Majesty and I.
Then I shall choose a good day
Empress is the leader of the Inner Palace, it's up to your decision.
But you are also from a family that contributed as well.
I da