Episode 32
Empress, no need to waste time to look.
This month, other than going to Palace of Great Benevolence, for two three days, the other days were all at Lady An
come from a smaII famiIy
enter into here soonentitIe become honoured
she is no match
Lady An
oId foIk said crow choose taII branch
even Lady An's position is Iowhe is the daughter of officer
the pass Consort Liang is a servant
she is aIso entitIe to be consort
this you don't know
this smaII househoId got their benefit
aIways do the humbIe thing
we can't Iearn
what you taIking about, so excited
said aIthough these few days are hotgot wind when night aIso quite cooI
the hot about to endgot wind naturaIIy feeI comfortabIe
but when wind pass through my eyesgot few sentences enter into my heart
my heart feeI so cooI
king Ioss two chiIdren and feeI sad
every sisters serve the king with me
got any method make king happy
I had prepared the party
ceIebration with wine you aIso go before
king is aIso sad
you aIso don't have any soIution
now finaIIy got peopIecan reIieve the sadness of king
you shouId be happybut not saying the bad thing
aIthough her position is not gIory enoughbut now king Iove her
equaI to I Iove her
usuaIIy you aII Iike to jeaIousI don't care muchbut don't know
now she is Ioved by king
if you want to battIe with hermean battIe with king and me
understand
we don't dare
Sit down.
Yes.
Lady An's temper is humbIe
most suitabIe at this momentto pacify king
normaIIy her gentIeis a good medicine to cure the pain of man
if your heart reaIIy feeI painthan just treat it asking is appIy medicine
I serve for king so many yearsnaturaIIy know which kind of person serve king is better
We don't dare to have objection
I aIso don't have soIution
if you aII know to doaII peopIe can get the Iove of kingthen I no need spend so much effort
now Lady Chun don't have aIreadyConsort Nian aIso Iose the Iove of king
Lady Fuca and Consort Wan's bodyis bad
the concubine become zerothen if want anotherseIection of concubine
then add new peopIeyou must refuse
you are right
We won't make An Mei Mei's life hard,
as long as An Mei Mei serves the emperor well and makes him happy. Then it is all good.
Wan Pin,
Don't think too much about An Precious.
The emperor needs someone with him.
so difficuIt aIso you are cIose with her
so I can aIso Iook for herto reIieve the pain of king
Everything I do is for the sake of the emperor.
your word is too heavy
As long as it is for the emperor, I don't feel wronged.
I don't feeI griefI know you are understandingking is aIways Iike you
but I see you so miss the kidbody is aIso not good
the king can't Iack of peopIe to serve
you better recover your body firstthen serve the king Iater aIso no too Iate
I remember your word
the matter Nian make you suffer
empress dowager knowyou miscarriage feeI pity
hear that she is better now
you go to greet her
Yes
pIease stop a moment
did anything happen to Lady Fuca
she is better now
can see you are having goodreIationship with aII sisters
she just get Iove from kingyou are better now
Do I right?The sistersneed to heIp each other
I need to greet empress dowagerI go first
Consort Wan is reaIIy busy
don't see king than see empress dowager
reaIIy fiIiaI
I can't compare with her
sister with me never contact
now untiI this step
every word have to ridicuIe,no wiIIing to forgive
you and me are those who serve king
how I not forgive sister
I just feeIeveryone know ConsortWan and Lady An is friend
now use so much effortinvite empress to heIpher to get cIose to king
sister is reaIIy inteIIigent
that is right
sister work so hard to heIp Lady Anwhen she got chiIdthen is your chiId
you no need worrycannot protect your chiId
I thought you are same with meso you actuaIIy is a person whoeasiIy forget
you
master Fuca
is that just now usingthe Qin's waIking styIe
Iet Lady An sufferaIso know this is the Qin's waIking styIe
I aIways think you are ignorant
I hear you purposeIy Iearn it
for Iet the king to smiIeI heard this styIe
is Iike weak wiIIow accompany windis very beautifuI
so now I see itI beIievewhen king see your waIking styIehe wiII happy untiI forget the sad
never think that beside king for few daysknow appreciation
yes
Iast time king said some shows is no goodare very Iousy
one caII Handan Iearn to waIkanother caII simpIy imitate
now see thatyour show is best
when king see it he is very happy
How dare you mock me?
how I dare to satirize you
but empress said thatas Iong as king happyevery sisters can Iearn anything
you Iearn to waIkfor Iet the king to smiIe
if empress knowsure feeI very happy
you think empress reaIIy Iike you
onIy treat you as a medicine
you don't be so happy
even medicine if got use is aIso good
afraid the broken dog skin
go to where everybody aIso don't Iike
You suffer because of me
I'm Iate
It is not a big deal.
I shouIdn't bother her
in the pass you heIp me
now is exchange
do you bIame mewant to separate with me
you don't think too much
you bIame me before thething happen I didn't toId you
but the time is rush
and empress must Iet king happy
cannot toId to other
I'm humbIe, cannot disobey
moreover I think
if I get the Iove of kingI can heIp you aIso
then you no need so tired
Mu Rong
you is cover from coughiIIness you shouId teII me
Iet me worry
and shock
you understand invoIuntariIy
I'm weak
so everythingis a gambIe
Alright. Alright.
everyone has their invoIuntariIy
I know
Lady Fuca make me angryI Iet you cry
if you continue to cryI can onIy accompany you to cry
I greet empress dowager
hope you get thousands bIessing
you aII get down first
Yes.
Come.
sit with me
thank
Shi Lan this kid
I Iook she is nice
and inteIIigent kid
aIso beautifuI
sometime just arrogant
it can't be avoid
the chiId come from king
now is so vicious
I'm oId
no much energy
aII thinghave to handIe to empress
empress aIso no useso create a Iot of probIem
aII the things happen at paIace
empress aIso can't handIe too much
so pIease don't bIame empress
you this kidaIso care for other
you don't have anybIood coIour on your face
so thin and paIIid
must sad forthe kid that is Iose
you suffer so many thing since young
woman grow speed of womanis faster than fIower
cannot resist the oId
when oId can't beauty
hard to get the appearance before
These days,
you have only been mourning about your lost child.
Have you thought of the Emperor?
if you don't think of thinkthis time you just Iose a kid
next time is you
I know my fauIt
don't said know fauIt
Take care of yourself first, then take of the emperor.
then I wiII rest
Yes.
you go back rest firstIisten to my word
don't be sad again
thank
I Ieave first okayyes
masterwhy you write
empress dowager and empress teachwriting can meditation
the outside is in noisy disordernon stop singing
who can meditation
this worId got a Iot of thingscan be resisted
moreover the voice of Mu Rongcannot cover using onIy a door
your chiId is Ioss for how many dayshow many time she come here
when she sick she come Iesserwhen she get the Iovedof king she come Iesser
onIy care singingwho going to Iisten
she didn't get Iove for a Iong period
so hard get back the IovenaturaIIy have to care for king
come or not come don't depend on person
but his heart
Huan Bi, grind the ink
in the pass, king at that side of window
cut the Iamp core with you
you aIso know said in the pass
singing and dancingnaturaIIy is more fun than poem and book
even the best book aftermemorize wiII put it away
Iike this fanwhen hot then don't bear to hand off it
after autumn naturaIIy then don't touch
mastermaster why said fanHuan Bi and I got the same thought
master Mu Rong's voice recovery so fast
so coincidentdon't you feeI doubtfuI
so whatshe is fIourishing nowso you want her empty with me
the IoneIiness got me aIone is enough
stop
greet king
these period don't see you, where you go
Consort Jin with memanage the matter of prayingso no time visit king
aIthough Consort Jin busy,I manage see her few times
I remember the kid of Concubine Wan
so except the matter of prayingI aIso read verse and bIessing the kidhope him can reach heaven soon
hard job for you
how I hard work aIsouse my effort and energy
the bitterness of ConcubineWan reaIIy cannot said
I spoke wrongIy, pIease punish me
go to see herkingyou stiII need go to greet empress dowager
I cannot put her down
go
king had come
greet kingwhere is Concubine Wan
she sIeep insidedo she fine now
I'm stupid
you go inside then you know
you reaIIy can't put down the chiIdstiII bIame me
I stiII have thing to dosince she sIeep aIready
no need teII her I came before
you just gain Lady Anwhy stiII feeI sad
just now I saw Concubine Wan
she aIso can't forget it
I can't see her sadand no wiIIing see her sad
when she sad son wiII angry
angry himseIfaIso angry he make son angry
this is her wrongas a Concubineit is not important for herseIf
but serve the king
maybe you aIways dote herspoiIt her
aIways think she is understanding
since Iike thismaybe temporary don't see her
if she is inteIIigentsIowIy she wiII understood
I aIso got this pIanwait untiI she understand then go to see
then is goodIet Lady An serve wiseIyyou can go back rest
then I move firsttomorrow greet you again
king move now
the empress dowager IikeConcubine Wan so muchwhy don't heIp advise the king
and don't Iet king see her
I know my son best
he too care her
so when she sad he wiII angry
so the source is he angry himseIf
if Iet them meet againafraid don't know anything wiII happencannot turn back
then Iet down her
so you feeI sorry to her aIso
king can has someone to Iovebut cannot Iove one onIy
this wiII make big troubIe
now Consort Nian don'tget the Iove of kingif Concubine Wan become great aIonethe back paIace wiII not baIance
moreover her temper is not tender enoughit is better to train her
you reaIIy think far enough
what think far enoughcompare to onIyI just stay Ionger than them in the paIace
empress dowagerOfficer Long Ke Duo come
ask how are you
you teII him that I'm fine
he is officer, no suitabIe come insideno need greet
Yes
empress dowager reaIIy don't want meet
these two yearsthe reIationship with king become smoother
if king know he comeaIthough not said from mouth
but wiII angry inside his heart
Such oId age personwhy stiII so suffer to meet again
in the pass the coIour ofchrysanthemum are yeIIow and white
this year are red, pink and purpIe
so excitedIike in the summer
how the chrysanthemumin paIace got reputation
it can't compare with thechrysanthemum pIanted by Tao Yuan Ming
IoneIyaIthough goodbut peopIe don't knowadd some deIicateness of paIace
the more coIouring is better
so you want to warm me
I just simpIy said
what pIace is here
here is the pIace of Consort DuanaIthough I have interaction with her
but never visit her at her house
here is so remoteshe aIways sick
so Iive at here to recover
this few daysI heard her sickness is more serious
when I pregnant
she do two pairs of shoes for my chiId
now she is sickI can't just pass her door
you go to knock door
greet Niang Niangyou are the inner servant of Consort Duan
why you open the door
where is your Niang Niang
you come here is goodcome inside
where is the othersince Niang Niang sick few years agoempress dowager want herto meditation to recover
so don't Iet her sIeep with other Niang Niangthen where the serving one
aIso move aIready
Niang Niang ask them to go out
now she Iike thishow did doctor said
Niang Niang said just eat the medicine IeftpaIace happen many thing
no need interrupt doctor
she is too careIess
she shouId caII for doctor
cannot Iike this
Ji-Xiangyou fast caII Doctor Wen come here
yes, I go nowJin-Xinow Niang Niang Iike this
shouId have a person take care heryou go to Iook a steady personto serveweII
you Iie downwhy you come here
I coincident pass hereheard you are not fineso visit you
an inveterate diseaseeach time during the change of season
it wiII happen
nothing
you own your body
you have to take care
Iong time no seewhy you become so thin
do you fine
aIthough no much peopIe serve youbut you are inteIIigent
no need go out aIso know what happen
I just know the surface
chiId is their Iife of mumeven they haven't comeout from your stomach
you aIso very care him
you suddenIy Iose sonafraid you sad untiI die
Niang Niang said suddenIy Iose sonbut I ate the wrong medicine
I think even keep hurtthe body aIso don't know
not sure aIsoafraid more sad
the punishment of king to Nian Shi-Lan
she want foIIow the pass kingpunish Fujin
I thought king wiII Iether die because of you
I think
Nian Shi-Lan is not so stupidwait untiI she has the power in backpaIace then Iet something happen to you
according her tempershe just want to press you down
if she know you miscarriageshe is more afraid than other
this is stupid
stupid is more goodhave the intention aIso forget itI just hate
I can't revenge for my kid
I sick untiI this stepI aIso don't rush, why you so rush
I aIso don't rush, why you so rush
doing sinfuI things can't Iive
we just wait
greet Concubine Wan
Ji-Xiang, you go inside to seedid the medicine is weII prepare
I have some word ask Mr Wenyes
if Consort Duan is given to youcan you cure her
even the great doctor comeshe can't pregnant
I just can try my bestIet she can Iive weII in future
no wonder she Iove chiId so much
since the pass had aIready happenI just hope her can heaIthy
don't suffer from iIIness
I'II try my best
I have something ask you
you can ask
that day I miscarriageI thought I want go to toiIetso kneeI for haIf hour then miscarriage
it heaviIy use musk
sure bad to your body
but before thiseveryday I at PaIace of Shi-LanonIy 6-8 hours
Are this medicine is so strong
now think carefuIIyfew days before I go to her tempIeaIready have something symptoms
how to said
I use siIver vesseI to eatwouIdn't go wrong for food
then why got this bad feeIing
you think too muchmaybe I think about something
the year I avoid the kingyou give me the medicinewouId they harm to my body
make me feeI weakeasy to skidding
when I give you the medicineI'm very cautious for the ingredientmoreover after you eat aIso no feeI unweIIso skidding
but because each physique of us is different, is hard to said moreover the year you get the poison
from Yu, maybe the poison is not yet release.
Maybe this is my fault.Am I right
master, the thing aIready pass so IongNian or Huanyi perfume
you just remember is their fauIt
don't bIame yourseIf
master, why you come hereyou can ask servant to find
bIame me for the deIaymake you wait so Iong
what happenthe wind make my eyes can't open
afraid you get cooII serve you go back to rest
king very Iong time didn'tgo to see sister ZhenwouId you Iike to go tonight
is not I don't want
she don't have chiId I aIso sad
but her temper is too stubborn
if she got haIf tenderas you is good enough
If she got anything make you dissatisfyhope you remember she Iose her chiId
actuaIIy she is very toiIsome aIso
she is toiIsome, I aIso toiIsomewhy she don't think about me
you and her is Iike sisters
you understand her temper
she come from good famiIy,skiII is very good aIso
I reaIIy admire herhope you can Iike her
as the pass
now she don't understandso keep feeI sad
cannot serve you
I think no need to see her firstavoid you fight over each other
it is worsebetter Iet me advise her first
then meet again
this is better
I just give some opinionhope you don't mind
you so understand me and Concubine Wan
how I feeI no good
thank your praiseI just Iike youcan aIways happy
actuaIIy I have no skiIIcannot compare with sistercan every moment heIpking reIieve some burden
why so Iook down yourseIfyou and Concubine Wan Iike mooneach have own good
then you Iike her moreor Iike me more
this momentof course is you
you are tired for the country
I had pick some IoquatIet peopIe stew with crystaI sugarIater when you drink can prevent cough
moreover the taste is no bitter
suffer you do this aIone
master, is the time to drink medicine
master stiII no drink
don't know the day she see whatafter come back become Iike this
sick untiI this stepfor haIf monthking didn't come to visit
she aIso don't drink medicine
I said with the eunuch for few timeseven empress dowager know she is sick now
but the king aIso no come
Iook Iike he wouIdn't come
in the pass the PaIace of SupportingEarth and House of Broken Jadeis the most excited pIace at paIace
now is so cooI now
reaIIy Iose many
master
why you sit at outside
don't afraid the cooIwhy you comeLady An hear that master is sickso order some peach from imperiaI kitchenask me sen
thank you master
your master is so busy, can't come herethen I back first
when master is sick she don't comewhoIe daywith master Iike sisters
forget it, she don't knowwhy angry with her
this thing I see it I feeI angrygive toXiao Yun-ZiaIso good
now master is sickexcept doctor Wenwho come here to visit master
these medicine is hard to getI go to heat it
tomorrow I want to see king secretIywhen king come
see who wiII buIIy us
kingwhat happen
the peopIe of House of Broken Jade comesaid Concubine Wan is sick
hope you can see herI know
you repIy when I free I wiII goyes
actuaIIy king know sheis sick Iong time agonaturaIIy, I know you are busy
I'm busy
but I aIso don't wish to see her
I'm stupid
I had ask doctor Wen
she get sick because she is too sad
so is the probIem of kid
when see her each of us get sad
better no see
when she is fine, then naturaIIy is fine
then Iater I teII the Iady
when you are free you wiII go
greet Lady An
stand up
why see you from the directionof HaII of MentaI CuItivation
did you see kingmy master is sick
I go to report to king
then did she go to see sister
no yetbecause she is busy aIso
no free time
did sister bIame me I didn't Iook her
I have to serve kingafraid after gosister is going to sad again
so don't dare to goHuan-Bidid sister is better now
because of your bIessingsure wiII get weII
then I'm rest assure
Huan-Bi want to nextnext time when you saw kingcan you remind him
my masteris sick now
then I think the iIIness of my masterwiII get weII sooner
this is naturaIIywhen I see king I wiII mention
but afraid king is busy
but you rest assureI wiII advise king
thank yougo
just now she is rude to you
you stiII want to pIead for Concubine Wan
Huan-Bi is her inner servantHuan-Bi is rude mean she is rude
butwhen the time to adviseI stiII wiII advise
Su Pei-Sheng
kingI go
king, Lady An had come
weII, Iet her see me at House of West Warm