You are well versed in literature and poetry.
Zhen Yuandao taught you well.
But it remains to be seen whether you are deserving of your name.
Let me see your face.
Your family name is Zhen. It's taboo to share the Emperor's name.
(Yong Zheng's given name was Yin Zhen)
Empress Dowager your highness,
When my father was an official in the time of Emperor Kang Xi,
His Majesty Kang Xi remarked that Zhen is a good name
because it suggested loyalty and devotion; and as such, an encouragement for my father to be loyal and devoted.
I can understand Emperor Kangxi's intentions.
Mother, I have remembered something
The Qiao sisters of Jiang Nan (historically the area south of the Yangtze River)
and Zhen Mi, the beauty of Hebei
(All 3 women are found in the Tale of Three Kingdoms)
The Zhen family has always had beautiful daughters.
Zhen Mi was one of the three most beautiful women in the last era of the Han Dynasty.
Come forward.
She has a certain sense of dignity.
（He quotes the poem Zhen Huan's name comes from, meaning roughly:)
A shapely beauty, however elegant and graceful
Will lose her smoothness and the fragrant bloom of youth.
(A caution against over valuing external beauty)
But The forbidden city has a nurturing aura
You will not lose your youth and beauty before your time.
Who is the girl next to her?
Sister of Sun Zhuhe of Suzhou's Weaving Factory, Sun Miaoqing. Sixteen
Sun Miaoqing failed to observe the proper Imperial Court etiquette.
Take her away. She is never to be allowed to enter the Imperial auditions again.
Yes
Zhen Huan is kept. Bestow a sachet
- Your Majesty, grant me mercy.
Your majesty
Those who wished to stay have been sent away.
Those who have no wish to stay can never leave again.
Do you know how many people dream of a life in the Palace?
Come now, don't sigh.
Besides, we will be going together.
We can look out for each other
By this time the eunuchs will have arrived to deliver His Majesty's Imperial decree.
Uncle Zhen will surely be pleased.
Mei Jiejie.
It really wasn't my intention to be chosen.
I know you had no intention of being chosen,
but Heaven did.
He couldn't bear to let such a glittering jewel be buried in a life of anonymity.
But his majesty
Sun Miaoqing is only easily scared, hardly a serious flaw.
The Son of Heaven deserves the highest reverence. She lost her composure too easily.
Please wait, my ladies.
I have orders to see you both safely out of the Palace young misses.
My sincere congratulations for your successes in the audition.
Take care of yourself, Jiejie.
You as well, Meimei.
Huan Huan, a twist of a beauty's waist.
Your majesty. The Empress wishes to see you.
- Let her in
- Yes, sir.
I am here to congratulate Your Majesty on your acquisition of more, worthy beauties.
What have you heard?
Word is all over the Palace.
Your Majesty was very happy with the results of today's audition.
There were one or two of acceptable quality among the drones of unmemorable faces.
Acceptable!
I heard that Shen Zishan's daughter has an air reminiscent of Jin Ping (Pin Princess of Dignity).
And that the Zhen girl is a carbon copy of...
No more than a slight resemblance around the eyes and brow bone.
Even a small resemblance is remarkable.
I shouldn't say this, but...
Has Your Majesty thought of a rank for Zhen?
Gui Ren (Precious) will do. (6th rank of Princess consorts)
Precious?
Ok. Guiren it is.
Aside from Fucha of the Manchu Banner being Guiren,
and Borjite from the Mongolian Banner also being Guiren.
Of the girls from the Han Banner
there are also two Guiren.
Who's the other one?
Shen Guiren. Shen Zishan's daughter.
Shen Zishan's official post is after all ranked higher than that of Zhen Yuandao.
Although your majesty thinks highly of the Han Banner.
the long tradition of miscegenation between the Manchu and the Mongols must be respected.
If the Han Banner has two Guiren...
Would it not be too conspicuous?
Then make Zhen a Chang Zai (Lingering). (7th rank, though here he calls it 6th.)
She is from the Han Banner after all,
it won't do to rank her too high.
We trust Your Majesty's judgment.
Though she is only a Changzai
I nevertheless want to give her a title.
Then I will instruct Internal Affairs Authority to come up with some choices.
No need. I already have one in mind.
Come here.
Smile (Wan) ?
I remember a poem from the Tang Dynasty;
There was the line:
"A willow branch abundant with luxurious verdure"
Snakes down, dotted with a crush of nameless blossoms."
(She knowingly quotes a different "Wan" than the one he wrote)
There are few things more pleasing to the eye than Zhen's smiling visage.
Liuzhu, are we close to home?
Yes. Look miss, what a lively scene
Here she comes.
I can see her.
Congratulations. Congratulations
Father
Your servant Zhen Yuandao, with family in tow, respectfully greets the honorable Young Mistress.
Greetings, Young Mistress.
What is the meaning of this? Stand, stand!
Don't, Young Mistress, it would be improper to dismiss official etiquette.
Miss, you are an official Young Mistress now.
The Master is supposed to salute you according to etiquette.
Exactly so.
Liuzhu, Huanbi. Hurry and help Father and Mother up.
We are grateful for your kindness, Young Mistress.
It's windy outside. Let's go inside and talk.
This way please, Young Mistress
Watch your steps
I am an unfilial daughter.
I cannot keep you company in your old age.
Rise, rise!
Moreover I've subjected you to this new set of etiquette that needs to be complied with.
My heart cannot help but be uneasy.
Please allow me to finish
Although I now belong to the Imperial Family
But I will not disregard filial piety.
I ask you Father and Mother, to allow me to conduct myself
towards you as I have always done, before I depart home
If you will not grant me this request,
I would that I stay kneeling until you do.
I understand.
I have not raised you in vain.
Rise now, do rise.
Niangniang, You are awake?
Niangniang will rise.
I answer you respectfully Niangniang,
His Majesty stayed at Xin Changzai's place last night.
His Majesty doesn't visit the Harem for over 10 days
then he goes to that bitch when he does come.
It's been more than a month since she miscarried.
hasn't she had enough of the pitiful act?!
She's definitely playing her slutty tricks again.
Imbecile! How dare you be so careless?!
Niangniang, please forgive me!
What kind of servant are you?!
You were deliberately trying to harm Niangniang, weren't you?!
I know you did it on purpose!
Such a ruckus and so early in the morning too!
Why is she still here?!
Niang Niang, please spare me.
- Away with you.
Niang Niang!
Niang Niang! Niang Niang!
Spare me!
Niangniang, it looks as if Hua Fei will not be coming today.
Why don't we just end it early?
I am the Empress. She is but a mere consort.
She is obligated by protocol to come pay her respects to me.
We will wait, however long it takes.
Tea.
Yes, Niangniang.
Huichun, bring the tea.
Hua Fei is last again.
She is the Great General Nian's younger sister
Great General Nian has seen such favor from the Emperor
And His majesty dotes on Hua Fei like no one else.
(Cap: Xin Changzai)
Hmph. So what if she gets the most attention.
(Cap： Qi Fei)
The one and only Empress is up there.
Speaking of which,
(Cap: Cao Guiren)
It's been a long time since we last saw Duan Fei.
Aiyo! Duan Fei, that sickly creature!
Nine out of ten days, she can’t even get out of bed!
Caption left: Jìng Pín, Caption right: Lì Pín
Hua Fei arrives.
Greetings Hua Fei Niang Niang.
Please rise.
Looks like Xin Changzai has made a full recovery
You are quite early aren't you.
Thank you kindly for your concern, Niangniang.
I am not quite used to being up and about so early just yet
but I simply could not be late for paying my respects to the Empress.
It must be hard for you.
You need to take extra care of yourself after a miscarriage.
Your own health is tantamount in ensuring more heirs for His Majesty.
Thank you, Empress.
I answer you respectfully Empress Niang Niang,
Though Xin Changzai has yet to recover fully,
she is much better than before.
I also think she looks much more energetic.
Qi Fei Jiejie looks a bit more plump,
His Majesty will surely be pleased.
Thank you for your gracious words, Meimei
Oh, I almost forgot
It must have some time since His Majesty last visited Qi Fei Jiejie.
I have such a bad memory, please don't mind me Jiejie.
No harm.
Enough of that. We are all sisters here
no need to keep each other standing.
Take your seats.
Thank you, Empress.
- Greetings, Empress.
- Do sit down, have a cup of tea.
Yes.
Huichun. Bring Hua Fei Niangniang's tea.
This is last year's Longjing Tea?
Niangniang hasn't finished it?
Old tea
No matter how carefully stored, will still smell moldy.
I gave my unfinished tea to Songzhi and the servants.
I have some of this year's tributary Yu Qian Longjing
(leaves harvested before the rainy season in late April)
Songzhi can bring some later for Niangniang to have a taste.
Thank you for your concern
His majesty also gave me some of that.
But I figured that the third prince would enjoy it,
so I gave it to Qi Fei (birth mother of the third prince).
But of course.
It must be a rarity for Qi Fei Jiejie to receive tea of such quality.
The next time the third prince wants anything,
don't hesitate to ask me.
The third prince is most filial.
He would never disturb His Majesty over a triviality.
The credit goes to Qi Fei for raising a disciplined son.
the third prince is indeed filial
He must be very fond of study,
knowing how much His Majesty values knowledge.
And if His Majesty is happy,
neither Longjing tea,
nor even leaves of gold, will pose any difficulty.
the fourth and fifth princes are still young.
third prince is the oldest, and thus most exemplified prince
so his character will naturally be commendable.
His Majesty's ascension to the throne was such a rushed affair.
The Palace still lacks many things.
How deplorable that the Empress has to live in this Palace of Benelovent Hope.
I was thinking that we should pick a nice day and really decorate this palace.
It should make Niangniang's home more comfortable.
How very considerate of you Meimei
His Majesty has not been in power very long yet
We must be frugal if we can.
This matter can wait.
The Empress is indeed benevolent.
In comparison, my Palace of Wings is much too lavish.
I feel uneasy every time I visit you Your Highness.
The Palace of Wings used to be the residence of the previous Emperor's Yi Fei,
It is naturally grand.
Indeed. Yi Fei mothered many children,
Emperor Kangxi was very fond of her.
It's getting late, I will take my leave of you.
Your Highness, I will take my leave as well.
We take our leave of you.
What conceit. But it only took a few words from Niangniang to shut her up.
I only spoke the truth.
Our palace may not be the most opulent,
But it is a place of felicity.
(Cap： Jian Qiu)
His Majesty gifted this Palace of Benelovent Hope to Niangniang
because of your virtue and compassion.
That is a truelly harmonious union.
Don't be angry Niangniang,
the Empress is only jealous of the attention His Majesty gives to our palace.
Indeed, the former Yi Fei was greatly favoured and bore many children.
But her son was charged with treason, which implicated her.
She was cursing me with a similar fate.
There's no need to take her words seriously Niangniang,
Just look at how frail the Empress appears
she wouldn't dare to compete with you even at full health
His Majesty will surely antagonize her if she dares to antagonize you.
Aren't you wise.
Not at all. All I know is that His Majesty cherishes Niangniang like no one else.
Exactly. The Palace of Benelovent Hope is the Empress' residence.
The Palace of Wings is Niang Niang's residence.
Of all the palaces, only our palace (Yi Kun Palace) and The Palace of Peace (Kun Ning Palace)
where the Imperial Wedding took place, share the character Kun.
This shows how much His Majesty values Niangniang.
Exactly. Courtesy is all that exists between the Emperor and Empress.
But His Majesty's regard for you is undisputed.
We are here.
Are you a sister of Sister Zhen?
No way. Huanbi and I are the same, we are the personal maids of our young miss.
Even a servant is dressed in such finery.
The Zhen Manor must be very splendid.
Miss Zhen is waiting for you inside Young Mistress.
Mrs Zhen is waiting as well.
Please go in.
Jie Jie.
We are sisters. Such formality is unnecessary.
Auntie and I are connectionless here in the Capital
I'm very fortunate to have met you.
Now that you are here, you are no longer alone.
Do have a seat, Young Mistress An.
This is ?
This is Auntie Xiao.
She accompanied to the Capital to assist me with things.
Have a seat. Auntie
Thank you.
It's only because of your kindness that I have a safe place to stay Jiejie,
Nothing will ever repay the enormity of my debt to you.
I will feel at loss if you don't stop being so polite.
What are friends for?
I hope the journey was not disagreeable?
Don't get me started! The innkeeper almost wouldn't let Young Mistress An go,
thinking that he could profit from her.
But I scared him off in the end!
It was all thanks to Liuzhu's quick thinking.
Otherwise,
we would not have been allowed to leave, even if we paid him extra.
It's all thanks to Jiejie's good instruction that Liuzhu is so useful.
If you don't mind me asking,
which is the month of your birth?
I am seventeen this year. Born on April 17.
I'm sixteen this year. Born on Feb. 9.
You are really younger than me.
I need to call you Meimei from now on.
Yes. I will do everything Jiejie says.
Huan er,
Father. Why are you still up?
-Have a seat.
- Yes.
I have observed these few days, you have done well taking care of Young Mistress An.
Dad knows that you have grown up.
There is something that maybe I'm not supposed to say.
But at this point I feel like I have no other choice.
You must remember.
If you are not perfectly confident about keeping his majesty's regard.
You would do much better to keep a low profile and remain as anonymous as possible.
I'm not counting on you to rise to prominence and monopolize His Majesty's affections,
I would rather that the pearl of my eye
enjoy a peaceful, long life devoid of cares.
I don't seek His Majesty's affection
only that I can be safe in the Palace
and protect the lives of our family, as well as my own.
Good. I am glad to hear this.
Then, according to the rules,
You can bring a personal maid with you into the Palace.
This servant must be trustworthy
as well as smart and competent
Have you decided who to bring?
I have made up my mind
Liuzhu is smart. Huanbi is cautious
I want to bring them with me.
Good. The three of you grew up together
I can set my mind to rest with them accompanying you.
Especially Huanbi...she...
She is after all your younger sister.
What?
I have never told your mother about this
Many years ago. I...
I met a Han girl.
Then... we had Huanbi
No wonder when you brought Huanbi home
You said only that she would be my maid
Her mother was not only a Han girl
but she was also the daughter of an indicted official.
If the truth ever gets out
Not only will it affect you negatively
but Huanbi's life could be in danger as well.
I betrayed your mother's trust
And made Huanbi live an unfair life
You had your reasons, Father.
I will keep Huanbi's secret in mind.
If the opportunity ever rises
I will do my utmost to find a good husband for her
I appreciate it. The rest is up to fate.
All these years, Huanbi and I have been like real sisters.
I won't mistreat her.
Good.
Our miss is a young mistress now.
Yep, she sure is!
I hear she can bring maids with her to the Palace
as company.
Mhm, what about it?
Would you go?
Going where?
The palace!
I will go wherever our miss goes.
I grew up with her
I will never leave her.
And will you go?
I don't know.
Miss treats you so well!
I didn't say that she doesn't treat me well.
I'm only thinking
If we all leave with Miss so suddenly,
Who will serve the Master...and Madame?
You are right.
Master was the one who brought us here.
But, our job is to serve Miss
As if Master and Madame will ever need us to worry about them
By the mandate of Heaven, the Emperor decrees:
Daughter of Zhen Yuandao,
Coordinator of the Supreme Court, Zhen Huan
is hereby granted the sixth rank, Changzai, titled Wan
She is to enter the Imperial Court on the 15th day of the 9th month (Lunar Calender).
Qin Ci.
We thank Your Majesty's benevolent grace.
By the mandate of Heaven, the Emperor decrees:
Daughter of An Bihuai,
Magistrate of Songyang town, An Lingrong
is granted the 7th rank Daying (Promise).
to enter the Imperial Court on the 15th day of the 9th month.
Qin Ci.
My thanks for Your Majesty's benevolent grace.
Everyone, please rise.
Master Zhen
(lit. Person of great status/prestige/rank)
This is Fang Ruo GuGu, who teaches Imperial etiquette in the Palace
Greetings, Gugu
What a clever Young Mistress,
She is a credit to you, Master Zhen.
Thank you for your praise, Gonggong (Royal Eunuch)
Don't mention it.
Earlier, I brought another Gugu to Xia Changzai's home
Their manner was quite lofty.
(Cap: Fang Ruo)
Your servant, Fangruo,
pays respect to Wan Changzai and An Daying.
May good fortune be with you, Young Mistresses
Gugu is no ordinary person
（older Imperial servants are respected because)
Formal salutations will be unnecessary while you instruct us.
(of their long service and connection at Court)
I am hardly deserving of being bowed to by you.
You are very courteous Young Mistress.
Gonggong. Thank you for your hard work.
The heat has remained lingering these past few days.
You have been inconvenienced on our behalf.
You are too kind Madame Zhen.
Fangruo Gugu has served in the Imperial Court for a very long time
She taught Imperial etiquette to Young Mistresses even in Emperor KangXi's time.
The two Young Mistresses can't do wrong by attending carefully to Gugu's instruction.
We thank you for your elaboration Gonggong.
Since Young mistresses Zhen and An live together
it would be inconvenient to send a separate Gugu
We will trouble Fangruo Gugu to instruct them both.
The Young Mistresses can also help each other.
It is no more than what I should do.
Gonggong, please have some tea in the
reception hall (room usually reserved for receiving guests).
I can't, I still need to see to the next Young Mistress.
Ah, then this way please Gonggong.
Young mistresses.
There were eight girls chosen this time.
They will enter the Palace on two different days.
First are the Manchu and Mongolian girls. Then the Han girls.
Young mistresses An and Zhen,
And Shen Guiren of the family of Jizhou province's Coordinator.
Will enter on the same day, with the second group.
Jizhou Province Coordinator
Mei Jiejie is a Guiren!
we need to congratulate Mei Jiejie.
Yes, the three of us will have more time to spend outside,
and we are friends so we can watch out for each other
Oh? There's truly a girl capable of such arrogance?
Xia Dongchun is indeed arrogant, thinking she comes from a good family.
and is now a Changzai.
I heard that she had the audacity to Gugu went there yesterday.
I suppose she must be quite pretty?
She hasn't even stepped foot in the Harem and she's already bullying people.
This I have to see.
Oh, I heard that on the day of the audition some girl stopped her.
Who was it?
It was Zhen Huan, the daughter of Zhen Yuandao,
Coordinator of the Supreme court.
His majesty seemed to like her quite well; she was chosen as well.
She was granted the rank Changzai.
The harem will be quite lively from now on.
Tell Xia's Gugu
she need not be overly attentive with her lessons,
since the girl is so unappreciative.
That goes without saying, Niangniang.
Everyone cries about being poor.
Taxes are owed every single year.
There is not one province that doesn't owe the central government at least several hundred thousand.
The country is poor.
The people are poor.
So where did all the money go?
Please calm down. Your majesty
Your majesty, I figured,
money, being such a useful thing,
goes where it ought to go.
Have you heard, Your Majesty
right now a thousand year old piece of land can have eight hundred owners.
(...infer what you will)
Please flip a nameboard over Your Majesty.
Who said you could open your mouth, I never even told you to come in.
But Your majesty, the hour has already arrived.
Then Xin Changzai will do.
I must report, Your Majesty,
Young Mistress Changzai's green board has been put up.
Her name board will likely be unavailable for a month or two.
Why is that?
Hua Fei Niangniang said
Young Mistress Changzai hasn't fully recovered from her miscarriage
So she might be unable to attend to Your Majesty.
Hua Fei can be so willful.
Fine. Tell Xin Changzai to take good care of herself,
I will go visit Hua Fei instead.
Yes
His Majesty arrives.
Greetings Your majesty.
Where is your Niangniang? Why isn't she here to greet me?
Replying to your question,
Niangniang felt unwell today
so she went to sleep early.
Already?
I will go back then, since she is already asleep.
It's about time that I visit Qi Fei and the third prince
Don't bother coming again if you leave.
Childish. You are more willful than ever.
It's been awhile since your last visit,
perhaps you've already forgotten the name Shilan. (Hua Fei's name)
Nonsense
You are the only person who would ever dare to be this rude in front of me.
You smell very good.
It's the special Huan Yi incense (Joy &amp; Pleasant) that Your Majesty has gifted only to me,
I use it everyday
Exactly. This is the scent that I love
no one else has it.
We common people all have our own Master and Mistress at home,
It's the same inside the Forbidden City.
But there are only three true masters.
The Empress Dowager, the Emperor, and the Empress.
The other consorts can only be called "Young Mistress"
This is the inviolable rule that sets the "Di" (true wife and her issue)
apart from the "Shu" (consorts and their issue)
For example, even though Hua Fei Niangniang is the Emperor's uncontested favorite
she is still only just the Young Mistress Hua.
If we were being polite, we would call her Hua Fei Niangniang.
Niang Niang?
Yes.
But the title Niangniang
is not for just anyone either.
She would need to be in charge of her own Palace
(where other, usually lesser concubines also reside)
And her rank has to be "Pin" (ranked fifth, above Guiren) and above
Only when she is mistress of her own palace can she reside in its main residence,
and manage its daily affairs.
There is but one mistress in every palace,
but there can be an unlimited number of
Guiren (6th), Changzai (7th) and Daying (8th) in any given palace.
Then I have the lowest rank.
Actually no, Daying is not the lowest rank.
The lowest is Guan Nuzi (Serving Women).
I have only heard of the pea sized government official (lit. sesame) ranked 9th,
who knew that the same existed for a Young Mistress in the Harem?
What is a "Servant Lady"?
A Servant Lady is not so different from the serving maids
the only difference being that they can attend His Majesty at night.
If His Majesty likes her, she could be promoted to the rank of Daying.
Custom has it that serving women can only be promoted one rank at a time.
You can't skip a level.
Niangniang, your humble servant greets you respectfully.
Rise
Thank you, Niangniang
Niangniang, The Empress has drawn up the plans for
the new Young Mistresses' residences.
She wanted me to read it to you
If you find anything inappropriate, it can be modified.
All right. Read it.
From the Manchu White Banner, Fucha Guiren will live in the Palace of Lasting Fortune (Yan Xi Gong)
From Mongolian Minor Red Banner, Boerjijite Guiren will reside in the Palace of Essence (Zhong Cui Gong).
From Han Minor Yellow Banner, Shen Guiren will be in the Palace of Whole Blessings (Xian Fu Gong).
From Han Blue Banner, Wan Changzai is in the Palace of Imperial Heritage (Cheng Qian Gong).
What did you say? Wan Changzai?
Yes. Eldest daughter of Zhen Yuandao, Coordinator of Supreme Court
Of all the newly chosen Young Mistresses,
only she received a title.
Though her rank is not high.
The eloquent one?
Yes. You are correct.
Is this Palace of Imperial Heritage appointed to her by His Majesty?
His Majesty had nothing to do with drawing up the residences.
Everything has been to the directions of the Empress.
The Palace of Imperial Heritage is extremely well situated.
Not only is it large and grand, but it's also close to His Majesty's study.
The Empress really knows how to make His Majesty happy.
She would give him anything for just one word of praise.
She is herself getting along in years,
so she's preparing replacements who will be loyal to her.
The Palace of Imperial Heritage...does she mean for her
to be the sole inheritor of the Imperial attachment?
Let's talk about His Majesty now.
His majesty was the fourth son of the Former Emperor,
Formerly the Prince (Duke) of Yong (Harmonious).
He was married in his Princely Mansion.
The bride was the current Empress Dowager's niece, by a cousin.
(ie., her first cousin once removed; his second cousin)
Of the family Wulanala.
The Duchess was compassionate, wise, and elegant. People adored her.
She and His Majesty were deeply in love.
Unfortunately, three years after their ceremony the Duchess died in childbirth.
The infant prince died as well.
His Majesty is still saddened by the event, even now.
He bestowed upon her posthumously the title Chun Yuan Empress （Empress of Purity).
It shows how constant our Majesty's affection is.
Then the current Empress?
I heard that the Empress is issued from a concubine (shu)?
The blessed are not bound by the distinction of "Di" and "Shu."
Her highness the Empress has a virtuous nature, she is the mother of the nation.
I spoke out of turn.
Empress Niangniang is the Empress Chunyuan's s younger sister.
The Empress Dowager appointed her to the then Prince Yong as a duchess-consort.
(one rank beneath the Duchess)
After the death of Empress Chunyuan,
the duchess-consort inherited the Duchess's rank.
His Majesty treats her with courtesy and respect.
Are there any other palaces available?
There is...
the Palace of Jade Fragments (Sui Yu Xuan), where Fang (Fragrance) Guiren used to reside,
is tidy and somewhat refined, but it's a little out of the way,
a bit far and not too big either.
Not too big? It's tiny!
And there is also a stage there formerly used for opera performances.
It only became a residence for the less popular concubines because the Former Emperor thought it too far as a theater.
The location is also said to be unlucky.
Unlucky?
Just because Fang Guiren was banished to the
Leng Gong after her miscarriage...
(Leng Gong, lit. Cold Palace; place that concubines who fall out of favor are banished to,
most remain there til death.)
What's the big deal?
If she moves in,
she might even conceive a child like Fang Guiren had done.
Wouldn't that please the Empress even more?
Yes.
Who else lives in the Palace of Jade Fragments?
No one.
Clean it up a little,
Get it ready for Wan Changzai's arrival.
What of that Xia girl?
The one that His Majesty pointed to on a passing whim,
the one whose name he called "interesting."
Yes, the Empress had to ask His Majesty to make her a Changzai as well,
because of her father's official rank.
So you think the Empress is inclined to show her favor?
I can't be sure.
Watch her for me.
In case she intends to swear her allegiance to the Empress.
Put her in with Fucha Guiren.
We'll see how her insolence likes that.
But I heard,
His majesty now showers his attention on Hua Fei Niangniang.
Yes, it is so.
Hua Fei Niangniang is the Great General Nian's younger sister.
Her position was already uncontested even while His Majesty was still the Prince of Yong.
But if Hua Fei is indeed so adored by His Majesty,
why hasn't she been granted the title Gui Fei (Noble Consort, 3rd rank)
or Huang Gui Fei (Imperial Noble Consort, 2nd rank) yet?
That brings me to my next point.
The reason is because Hua Fei Niangniang has never borne any children.
So Hua Fei Niangniang was promoted to the rank of Fei (4th rank) without any children?
That's how highly His Majesty regards her.
Of course, His Majesty's affection is not the most important thing,
but conceiving a heir is.
Even a princess is better than no children at all.
Otherwise, you will have absolutely nothing to rely on.
But of course Hua Fei Niangniang still has her youth and health,
plus His Majesty's affection,
so naturally she will have eventual offspring.
I heard that Hua Fei Niangniang's beauty is beyond compare?
She is indeed a celebrated beauty within the Han Banner.
Well, not just in the Han Banners,
but in all of the Eight Banners, the Manchu and the Monglian together,
there is not one who can hold a candle to her.
That is why she is foremost in His Majesty's affections, and his Harem?
Li Bai (poet) once said
How long can you like someone if you only like her appearance?
Niangniang, Hua Fei changed Wan Changzai's residence
to the Palace of Jade Fragments (Sui Yu Xuan).
Poor girl.
That place is quite remote,
not to mention extremely plain.
It used to be no more than an opera stage.
Oh, Fang Guiren used to live there!
Hua Fei can be so insolent, making such a change,
without even one word in advance to Your Highness.
You speak of it as if it's something new.
That insolence is exactly what His Majesty likes about her.
Another Grey hair.
Whose nameboard did His Majesty flip tonight?
His Majesty is busy with state affairs today.
He has decided to rest at the Hall of a Resting Soul.
He is likely still awake.
I guess it's just as well.
His Majesty has a fondness for Wan Changzai.
Since the place is so undecorated and obscure,
send some osmanthus trees
(homonymous with "noble")
to ornament it a little.
Rest assured, Niangniang. I will take care of everything.
People always say that once you pass the Palace gates,
you are forever separated from the life outside.
I'd never expected for it to happen to our family.
Promise you'll take excellent care of yourself.
And be extra cautious with your interactions inside the Harem.
Don't start conflicts and don't involve yourself in disputes
Especially involving the Emperor's favorite, Hua Fei Niangniang.
If, one day, you have the fortune of becoming someone His Majesty esteems highly, then good,
But it's more important to stay alive.
Do you understand?
I will be careful,
so that you will have no reason to be concerned for me.
After I am gone, I'll need you to take care of father and mother, for me as well as yourself,
do you understand?
Yurao understands.
Young Mistress, time is running out.
I have to leave now,
Please take care! Father, Mother!
Thank you for watching!
Please join us!
Presented by Zhen Huan Team