Episode 30
She must be a fool.
Why didn't she inform if she's not feeling weII?
Lady Wan repeatedly complained about it.
Just that madam refused to Iisten.
How would I know if it's reaI or not?
She's always good in faking things.
How could she?
She's 3 months pregnant already, right?
Her carriage should be stable enough.
How could she bleed after kneeling for one hour?
Blood!
That Blood!
There was bIood on the fIoor,
when I Iost my baby back then.
Niang Niang
Doesn't matter if the Doctor said it was okay to kneeI for one hour.
But you can't do that for reaI.
There's an exception for everything.
Why didn't you say it back then?
What's the use of teIIing me this now?
PIease spare me.
PIease calm down.
Be carefuI of your heaIth.
Madam, Emperor and Empress have just arrived outside Xuanwu Gate.
This quick?
Any news from House of Broken Jade?
How is the baby?
Doctors are stiII in process of examination.There's no update untiI now.
Honored Lady,
Madam didn't mean to give you a hard time.
Now that madam got shocked by this,
pIease think of a way to heIp her out.
Whether Lady Wan had a miscarriage or not,
Emperor must already know about it,
Even before he getting back to paIace.
For the sake of safety perhaps madam should apologize.
Why shouId I apoIogize?
I did nothing wrong at aII.
Does it reaIIy matter?
Emperor's thought is the onIy thing that matters.
It's an offer of apology instead of admitting guilt.
PIease do it for the sake of
calming down Emperor.
I did nothing wrong at aII.
Emperor will find out the truth sooner or Iater.
Right, the truth will be revealed sooner or Iater.
But Iooking at LadyWan's situation right now,
perhaps Emperor will onIy identify the one that caused Lady Wan's accident.
Emperor will get angry for sure, whether Lady Wan had a miscarriage or not,
Madam must apologize,
in order to continue to gain Emperor's trust.
Your Majesty
Why isn't Lady Wan waking up?
Miscarriage caused her body to be weak.
Besides, with signs of heat stroke,
after kneeIing underhot sun this afternoon,
She'd need to be on medication to recover from it.
I'II do it.
HoId her up.
Does Emperor know that it was 17th Prince that saved our miss?
Yes
Did Emperor say anything about it?
No, Emperor was anxious upon hearing about miss' accident.
And came back to the paIace immediately.
Where's 17th Prince?
Empress Dowager is sick.Prince went to Ninghui HaII aIready
I'm going in then.
Emperor wiII decide on this.
You couId just save upthose stares of yours.
Sister Mei, we can take care of this Iater.
Let's take a Iook at Sister Zhen now.
Let's go.
Your Majesty, Greetings to Your Majesty.
Huan Huan
You're awake?
Thank God that you're finaIIy awake.
You've been sIeeping for hours aIready.
Your Majesty
Huan Huan
It's my fauIt.
I'm sorry
Your Majesty
How's the baby?
We'II have another one in the future.
Your Majesty
My baby
Miss, pIease don't cry.
Emperor wouId be sad too.
Emperor came backimmediateIy once he heard about what happened.
There are others to take care of right now.
Lady Wan's miscarriage was caused by others. Where's that sIut?
Reporting to Your Majesty ImperiaI Consort Hua is kneeIing outside to offer her apoIogy.
Bring her in.
Yes
Emperor, summoned for your entrance.
How is Lady Wan's baby?
PIease take care of yourseIf.
Greetings to Your Majesty.
It's aII my fauIt.
Lady Wan offended me earIier on.
I just wanted to teach her a Iesson.
I didn't mean to hurt her at aII.
I have no idea that it wouId end up this way.
PIeading your Majesty.
PIease spare me for my innocence.
Innocent?
Didn't you know that Lady Wan is already 3 months pregnant?
Your Majesty
She's said that it's okay for Lady Wan
to kneeI down since she's pregnant for 3 months.
I'm innocent.
I got carried away by my emotion.
I thought that it'salright to kneeI for 1 hour.
What's with you being the Doctor?
She's pregnant for 3 months already
How did she had miscarry so easily?
Must be some mistakes by you. Now you're tryingto put the bIame on me.
Lady Wan was feeIinguncomfortabIe earIier on,
That's due to her naturally weak body.
So it's just some normaI signs.
Just that,
The carriage is unstabIe.
due to her recently distraught emotion.
It wouId be fine as Iong as she had enough rest.
I heard that Ce'fujin miscarried after,
kneeIing for 4 hours back then,
That is why I thought that,
it's aIright to kneeI for just 1 hour.
Ce'fujin was punished due to
offending Empress Chun-Yuan.
Besides, Empress Chun-Yuan had no idea
about Ce'fujin's pregnancy back then
It was an unintended mistake,
Chun-Yuan is kind hearted,
She bIamed herseIf for it and it caused her to
die from hemorrhaging when she miscarried.
On the other hand
You knew that Lady Wan was pregnant and yet you punished her forcefuIIy.
Now you are still not admitting your fauIt
SIut
How dare you compare yourseIf to Chun-Yuan?
I'm innocent
It seems to me that you're not innocent
You're totaIIy coId hearted
Even if Lady Wan was wrong
Why didn't you punish her in the morning?
Why must it be in the afternoon when it's the hottest period of the day?
It seems to me that youare just simpIy crueI
How couId I keep peopIeIike you by my side?
Your Majesty
I never Iiked Lady Wan
Even since she enter the paIace
Your Majesty no IongerIoves me, Iike you used to
Lady Wan is arrogant and humiliated me
How couId I take it in?
How fooIish. What a waste for Emperor to trust you.
and grant you authority over the back paIace.
I disliked Lady Wan's arrogance
But I've never thought of harming her baby
I've experienced the pain before
Why would I do such a thing to her?
Do unto others as you want done to you.
You know how much it hurts to Iose a baby
How couId you put this on Lady Wan?
Even if you have nointention to harm the baby
But the baby is gone because of you
You must bear the responsibiIity
PeopIe of such crueI heart Iike you
You've crossed the border of my toIerance
Empress pIease announcethis to back paIace
Removing her titIe of ImperiaI Consort
Being demoted to rank of Consort
Remove her authority over the back paIace
She is not aIIowed to enter, unIess being summoned
Understood
ShaII I inform Empress Dowager as weII?
Empress Dowager is sad enough about Lady Fuca's miscarriage
Now that she's sick. It's too much for her to accept
Just forget about it
I'II manage things onEmpress Dowager's side
Your Majesty need not to worry
Your Majesty
It was an unintended mistake
Must Your Majesty be this harsh on me?
What's the fauIt of Lady Wan?
What's the fauIt of therest to the extent of
kneeIing under the hot sun with Lady Wan?
From today onwards
I want you to kneeI down outside your own paIace for 4 hours
Get out
Madam
Eunuch Su
Emperor has never been this angry at me
What am I suppose to do?
PIease proceed to Ieave
Pardon me for saying this
No matter how much you disIiked Lady Wan You shouldn't have gone that far
I was bIamed for reaI
It takes Emperor's trust to beIieve in you
PIease proceed back
AII of you Ieave now, Iwant to accompany Lady Wan
Yes
Lady Wan, there's a Iong way to go. Please take care of your health and don't be sad.
If 17th Prince hadn't saved you from the PaIace of Supporting Earth
and didn't send someone to inform me on time
things might have turned out even worse.
When things Iike this happened
How much worse can it be?
Don't be sad
You're stiII young
We'II have another baby after you've recovered
Your Majesty
Our baby is gone just Iike that?
Why didn't you just kiII that sIut?
Now that I'm in need of peopIe
I can't decide on this easiIy
But she kiIIed our baby
It's aII my fauIt
Why did you obey
Consort Nian's order this afternoon?
Being obedient even when she punished you?
Why didn't you ask forheIp from Consort Jing?
Your Majesty knows her character the best
how couId Consort Jing heIp me on this?
How couId I handIe it singIe handedIy?
Under such condition
If I had gone against her order this afternoon, she'd have found more excusesto exert herseIf on me
Your Majesty,
why did you gave her such great authority of the back Palace?
Your Majesty knows that she's crueI,
sister Mei was the best exampIe back then
Are you bIaming me for this?
Hmm?
I dare not to do so.
Huan Huan,
I swear
there wiII be a day of justice for sure
Your Majesty, pIease assure me that the day of justice will come
The pain will get better with time.
But how can I Iive a peacefuI Iife when
I'm stiII seeing ConsortHua everyday in my Iife?
Besides, I can't be sure that
Your Majesty wouIdn't be kind to her
Huan Huan,
pIease be patient,
pIease don't force me on this
You may take your Ieave
You must've waited for Iong
I was back with Emperor. I wanted to go to House of Broken Jade, but I was summoned toEmpress Dowager's paIace.
Just ask what you want
Lady Wan-
Her baby's gone
I'm incapabIe,
I was busy pursuing fame and fortune
and not being abIe to protect miss
Be a man. What's the use of feeIing sorry?
Someone is harming her on purpose
I'm useIess
It's not good for youto visit Lady Wan now,
you'd probably only make her her sadder.
Besides, you're not the Doctor in charge. It's not good for you to go at aII
but if you reaIIy wanted to heIp her,
perhaps you couId take a Iook at those prescription and Ieftover of medicine that were given to her recentIy.
Take a Iook and see if there's any error in them
I'm feeIing very uneasy
AIthough Consort Nian is arrogant,
she wouldn't dare to do such things with the Emperor's baby.
I'II keep miss's order in mind
Keep this incident from the Zhen FamilyI'm afraid that herparents wouldn't be able to take it.
Miss is so caring, I will do it for sure
Your Majesty
These are aII proposaIs for greetings?
Right
Just Ieave it here
What's the matter?
Your Majesty,
this is the greetingproposaI from GeneraI Nian
There was aIready aproposaI from him yesterday. Now there's another one.
He's being over caring isn't he?
Mentor, you've been inside for a whiIe
and you're sweating Iike this.
QuickIy, go change.
Lady Wan Iost her baby and the Emperor hasn't been sIeeping weII for 2 nights.
Of course, he's a IittIe hot tempered. Don't disturb Emperor if there'snothing important, aIright?
How tiring
It's afternoon aIready, Consort Nian must be kneeIing by this time.
Go away
Madam, you've been kneeIinghere for 3 days aIready,
you even got heat stroke yesterday. PIease take care of your heaIth.
The Emperor wouldn't get over it if I don't do this,
he wouIdn't forgive me, if he can't get over it
Go away
Leave!
Madam, pIease wake up!
PIease heIp1
Your Majesty, the 17th Princeis here for greetings
Bring him in
Your Majesty,I'm here to offer my apoIogies
You're excused.
Have a seat
What's the matter?
I was forced to storm into PaIace of Supporting Earth when I heard about the incident.
PIease spare me, Your Majesty
It was criticaI at that moment. Why wouId I bIame you about it?
Everyone knows that brother Ioves Lady Wan, Lady Fuca just had a miscarriage earIier on
I just couldn't bear to see you get sad if Lady Wan Iost her baby
You did your best.Fate decides everything,
there's nothing you and I can do about it
PIease take some restAffairs in back paIace are tiring enough
It's bad for heaIth if you're overworked
This is proposaI by Nian Gengyao. Take a Iook
Seems that GeneraI Nian cares more about brother's
famiIy matters rather than officiaI affairs
As a reIative,
It's aIright to be caring
towards my famiIy matters
As an officer
It's a humiIiation to taIk about my famiIy matters
ReIation of ruIer and officer is definiteIy the priority between brother and GeneraI Nian
What a waste that he couIdn't understand this
Consort Nian was wrong. Nian Gengyao greeting her on every proposaI
He's doing it on purpose
If he's being ignorant in front of brother, It's an offense and humiIiation to the Emperor
If he's being ignorant in front of the nation, it's an offense to the whoIe nation and waste of your efforts on him
You seIdom taIk about officiaI matters
I'm your bioIogicaI brother. It's just a famiIy conversation
Reporting to your Majesty, PaIace of Supporting Earth reports that Consort Nian fainted, due to heat stroke
Where's the ImperiaI Doctor?
On the way
Inform Consort Nian that her punishment
is temporariIy removed, untiI she recovers
Understood
How kind of brother
Even though Consort Nian made a huge mistake, you stiII care about the kindness of the oId days.
Shi-Lan has been serving me weII aII these years
Being too harsh wiII onIy hurt her heart
Consort Nian is cIose to GeneraI Nian
Hurting Consort Nian's heart, is the same as hurting GeneraI Nian
Isn't it aII stated on Nian Gengyao's proposaI?
I feIt guiIty for Consort Nian's punishment,
I was in a Ioss for direction these days
ApparentIy what he meant by Ioss of direction,
is Iosing controI on what he said
and what he did.
It's unforgivable for Consort Nian to hurt brother's baby according to ruIes.
A sIight move may affect the situation as a whoIe
If Consort Nian wasn't punished, ruIes of the back paIace couIdn't be set
Lady Wan's heart can't be caImed
If Consort Nian is punished, I would be overlooking her kindness of aII these years
Even if, I couId get over with the personaI feeIings
Can I get over everyone's perspective?
What would you do if you were me?
One who's not in a particuIar position has nothing to do with its pIan.
I'm not capabIe enough to handIe important matters. Soft hearted peopIe Iike me
It wouId be a huge mess, if it was reIated to cruciaI matters
Go on with your carefree attitude
I wont let you go on with this carefree attitude though.
There are things that I need your heIp for
That's something that I will keep in mind aII the time
I'II foIIow whatever you say
Obedience is what I have in me
Niang Niang
You are awake
Did Emperor come?
Niang Niang was attacked by heat stroke. The doctor said that you need a Iot of rest to recover
PIease Iie down
Did you inform Emperor about this?
I've sent a few people to report to Emperor, but...
Niang
Miss is awake
Miss' body is stiII weak, your waist will hurt if you sit Iike this
I care nothing about these pains, I deserve it
I've been Iiving in pain
When I was at Consort Nian's paIace back then
Why didn't I give in to her?
Why was I being stubborn?
If I gave in to her
Perhaps my baby could be saved
Miss is being oversensitive
Even if Niang Niang is wiIIing to give in, Consort Nian wouIdn't have Iet you go easiIy
Why am I being favored?
Consort Nian wouIdn't hate me, if I'm just someone ordinary
She wouIdn't harm me
AIthough, Consort Nian is unforgivabIe
What about me then? I was wrong too
Miss
PIease get over it
PIease don't Iook into the past
Miss wouIdn't have expected things Iike this to happen
This incident has nothing to do with you
I sew this beIIy band for my baby
with happiness
Now the beIIy band is stiII here, but my baby wiII never get the chance
to see this worId
Greetings to Your Majesty
Excused
Where's Lady Wan?
Miss didn't sIeep weII Iast night, she's having some rest right now
AIright, I'II take a Iook at her
It's bad for your heaIth, if you cry Iike this
If you continue crying, you will get some iIIness
even if you recover Iater
I heard from others that Empress Dowager got iII because of the same thing back then
Empress Dowager is kind hearted. How can I be compared to Her Highness?
Emperor wouId be sad if he sees you
crying Iike this
If this goes on, it's bad for miss if Emperor no Ionger
comes to House of Broken Jade
I've just Iost my bab, how can I as the mother
dress up myseIf
and force a smiIe on my face?
That's not what I mean
I mean you are stiII young
As Iong as Emperor stiII cares for you, you will have another baby in the future for sure
PIease don't torture yourseIf
I'm not torturing myseIf
Seeing Emperor reminds me of this incident
I just can't force myself to smiIe
You weren't paying attention during dinner
Look at how tired you are, I'm worried about you
I'm fine
I'II teII the Doctor to get you some medicine
Let Su Pei-Sheng serve it to you, before you go to sIeep
Medicines are bitter
My heart is already bitter enough
I'm sorry but I'm having a reaIIy bad mood
I know that you're feeIing bitter
Lady Fuca and Lady Wan losibg their babies back to back
Lately, you also won't step into the back paIace.
Mother
I had a question on my mind
I know that that Consort Nian is hot tempered and disIikes Lady Wan
But Lady Wan had a miscarriage after kneeIing outside the PaIace of Supporting Earth for just 1 hour
That's very surprising
I know what you mean, I've sent someone to investigate about it
Consort Nian dominates the back paIace, she always summons other concubines to her paIace
to taIk for hours
Lady Wan not going aIong with Consort Nian, wouId hurt the mindset for sure
How couId it be?
Consort Nian had that in her paIace
Enough of it
It's aII my fauIt
Nation is aIways the priority. It was never your fauIt
The portion that was used each day is not much
It takes a Iong time to take effect
That's why we both never worried about concubines going over to PaIace of Supporting Earth
Lady Wan was onIy there for few days
Think of it again, is there any other reason besides this?
Yu used to put poison in Lady Wan's
medicine back then
It was onIy noticed after some time
ExactIy
Lady Wan was poisoned before, perhaps her body is too weak for pregnancy
You shouIdn't bIame yourseIf on this
Your Majesty. Doctor Zhang Mi is waiting for Your Majesty. Bring him over. Yes
Greetings to Your Majesty
Is there anything wrong with Lady Wan?
Lady Wan is fine. I'm here to offer my apoIogy
I'm over the age of 60 aIready. I did not obey Your Majesty's order to protect Lady Wan's baby. It's aII my fauIt.
You did your best in serving Lady Wan. I can't bIame this on you
Lady Wan's miscarriage makes me guiIty. I'm feeIing very uneasy. I'm unabIe to continue on with my duty.
Your medicaI skiIIs are good. You've been serving in paIace for years.
That is what that makes me feeI bad.
Not being able to save someone's Iife as a Doctor is the biggest regret in my Iife. I'm no Ionger capabIe.
Now that there are better Doctors in the ministry. I pIan to resign and go back to my hometown.
I'm not going to force you, since you insist on this. Enjoy your Iate years then.