Episode 64
Niang niang, we've cut off Jing Bai's tongue.
Reward it to the person of Gua Er household.
Here
One more tongue
That'll teach her how to use her tongue.
Your heart is very poisoned
I have to thank An Pin for this idea.
Wen Shichu!
Even though you didn't have an affair,
can you say that you've never had secret feelings for her?
Do you have the guts to swear upon your family, your parents?
That to the Emperor's women that you've never had any romantic feelings for?
Mistress,
You're delirious.
Delirious?
Do you think the Emperor and I don't have eyes?
Official Wen.
I've heard that you still aren't married.
Whether I am married or not,
This doesn't concern you.
Emperor Emperor
My feelings to you are true.
Emperor
I've served you for many years
Why can you only think about the slut who offends you?
Emperor
Emperor Emperor
Take her away
Emperor Emperor!
Wen Shi Chu, as long as you are with her
You will be the death of her.
I will open my eyes and wait until that day
Emperor
Sir, you should know
You, your feelings
will cause people to die.
Emperor, Niangniang,
I will prove myself.
Take this dirty thing away.
It's been a chaotic day.
I'm tired
The queen is tired too.
Your health has always had problems
In the future if there's any problem in the palace
let Xi Guifei handle it.
Emperor
with help from Duan Fei and Jing Fei
You can recover your health in peace
With the two of you handling things
I am really relieved.
Thank you Emperor
Your Majesty,
Dr. Wen...Dr Wen,
Say it clearly
Dr Wen castrated himself
His life is in danger.
Mistress! Mistress!
Doctor! Doctor!
Quickly, hang in there!
Quickly take this medicine!
Mistress, push hard!
Mistress
Mistress, quickly!
Mistress, push hard!
Mistress, Mistress!
Quickly! With force!
Harder!
Mistress, push hard!
Hang in there!
Quickly go and take the medication that stops the bleeding.
His life will be saved after he takes the medication that stops the bleeding,
Go quickly!
Mistress, push hard!
Hard! Yes, yes, yes!
Almost there!
Just a little more!
Mistress, hang in there!
Push hard, mistress!
Push hard!
Why is she bleeding so much?
Bring hot water!
Quickly! Quickly!
Mistress
The water is here!
Move over.
Hang in there, mistress!
What do we do?
You knew Mei Zhuang was pregnant.
She can't handle shock right now.
Yet your servant ran to Sui Yu Xian to tell her.
Lingrong.
What motives do you have?
Jie Jie I don't know about this issue
Jiejie don't blame me.
I really don't know about this issue
Jie Jie you have to believe me
Bao juan didn't mean for this to happen!
If I knew it would be like this
I would rather suffer in Mei jiejie's place
Jiejie,
We entered the palace together, I
I don't care if you planned this
All I care about is that they save her.
If there's the slightest problem
I won't ever let you go.
I deserved to be slapped.
I was unable to control my servants
and that led to today's disaster.
Bao Juan, come here!
Greetings, Niang niang.
You still dare to greet me like this?
Niang niang, I know I'm guilty.
You've put Hui Pin in shock!
You want me to feel bad, don't you?
Mistress, take care of your body.
Niang niang, forgive me.
I've been friends with Mei Jiejie this many years
And you had to startle Mei Jiejie's pregnancy.
If anything happens to Jiejie
I will go with her.
What's the point of living?
Who told you to speak out of turn?
-You stupid servant! This is for speaking out of turn!  -I won't do it again. Niangniang, I know I was wrong.
If the servant doesn't know things, An Pin don't break the rules.
Greetings Emperor.
If the servant disobeys the rules
Go to a quiet place and just beat her to death
Su Bi Sheng.
Come.
Emperor, spare me!
I know I was wrong
I won't dare to do it again
Emperor, spare me! I won't dare to do it again!
I won't dare to do it again!
Emperor, spare me!
Us your strength mistress!
Mistress!
Push!
You're almost there mistress!
Your Majesty,
We have stopped Dr Wen's bleeding
There is no danger to his life
However...
Speak.
He's the same as the eunuchs now.
He can't have children anymore.
I understand.
How come there is no news about Imperial Concubine Hui?
Don't be anxious, Emperor
Your Majesty,
Hui Pin was shocked.
and her pregnancy became unstable.
The situation is very bad.
My healing skills are shallow
and before, it was Dr. Wen who took care of her.
I don't know anything about how her situation was before.
I really cannot do much right now.
What about the child?
Niangniang has lost a lot of blood
so she doesn't have the strength to push.
The baby's head won't come out
I've already given Niang Niang guchong soup to drink
and has not seen a good turn
I really don't know
Niangniang's health.
I am afraid to use a medicine to stop the bleeding.
If Dr. Wen were here,
Dr. Wen is already stable
But in his current condition
I'm afraid he can't deliver Hui Pin's baby
It's ok if Dr Wen can't walk
He can be carried on a stretcher
Although Dr. Wen cannot help with the delivery
he knows of her situation.
He can help me prepare the medicine.
Dr. Wen suffered for a crime he was not guilty of.
If it causes something to happen to Mei jiejie or the baby
that would be terrible.
Hurry and carry Wen Shichu over here.
Yes.
Teacher, teacher.
Gu Lin, Gu Lin
Hui Pin has always been gentle and kind.
She
is suffering difficulties because of circulation problems.
Hurry
Hurry and use wild ginseng to keep her conscious.
Then have her drink the Shengju soup.
I understand. Hurry and prepare it!
Bring the medicine!
Teacher.
This is to speed up the labor process.
What did you say we should add?
Add seven salted plums.  Salted plums.
Burn them to ashes.  Burn them to ashes.
Then add one ounce of aged cassia flower.  Then add aged cassia flower.
Half an ounce of herbs.  Herbs.
At the end,
Red agate.  Ok.
Give the special beverage to Niang Niang as well. Hurry.
Got it! Go prepare it!
Emperor, Hui Pin has taken Dr. Wen's medicine
She is bleeding a bit less
Now she can use her strength.
Emperor please don't worry. Jiejie will be fine.
Go tell Imperial Concubine Hui
that with my edict
Hui Pin is promoted to Hui Fei
and relax while she delivers the baby.
Yes.
I owe MeiEr too much.
Wait for her to give birth
and then I'll make it up to her
Congratulations Emperor! Hui Pin gave birth to a princess!
Good, this is wonderful!
How is Hui Fei?
She's very tired, she can't even speak.
I'll go see her.
She just gave birth and is extremely tired.
Let's let mistress rest for a while.
Your Majesty must be exhausted, hurry and get some rest.
Come back and visit her when she's feeling better
I'll stay here and look after her
No need to worry
Alright.
But you should rest also.
Don't tire yourself out.
I'll escort you out.
Farewell, Emperor.
Great!
Now Niangniang can relax.
Have some tea.
Bad news!
Mistress has died from vaginal bleeding!
How is it?
Hurry and grab the coagulant.
No need.
Who says no need? Who said that?
Bring the best medicine!
If you don't save her, I'll kill you and have you buried with her.
Yes.
Huan Er
Jiejie
Don't cry.
I want to talk to you
Tell them all to go outside.
Go outside.
Wen Shichu, you stay.
My child
still this small
This soft.
yes
but she'll grow up quickly
Look how fast Hong Ye and Ling Xi grew.
Jiejie, the Emperor hopes that you're well
He already promoted you to Hui Fei
Are you happy as Noble Consort Xi?
You are the Xi Guifei that he will always love
but you don't like your title.
What do I care about being a Consort?
I know you don't care about being promoted
But your child depends on your title.
You have to prepare for the baby's future
She won't care about these things
Shichu, have you held the baby?
Hold her
I...
I don't dare
Do you still blame me?
I'm also at fault for that night
Don't blame yourself.
Today you castrated yourself
isn't that because your guilty conscience was too strong?
I know
I know you hate me
You hate that day
with the wine the Empress Dowager rewarded me and the Emperor
I coaxed you into drinking it.
And made it your life-long regret.
Jiejie, you're confused
I'm about to die
what do I have to fear?
Being confused gave me happiness.
I have no regrets.
Huan Er,
All these years I've only had you and Shichu
who have been kind to me
but it's you in his heart
so he has been good to me
because of you
Jiejie
Shichu
I want to ask you one thing
These years
have you ever truly liked me?
Even a little?
Never mind.
I rather you don't say it
than to
have you pity me because I'm about to die
and lie to me.
That day's wine wasn't enough for me to have feelings for you.
So
I'm good to you
I wasn't good to you just because of Zhen Huan
Really?
Hearing you say this
I
I'm so happy
To know you in this lifetime
I'm not regretful
Shichu
Hold our child
Ok?
Yes
Huan Er
The baby doesn't have a name yet
Jing He
Call her Jing He, ok?
Gentle and easy-going, a quiet and peaceful life.
Isn't that what we've always wanted?
Don't cry...Don't cry
Although I am now a cripple
But we,
we can be together forever
No one will ever do what they did to Noble Consort Xi
to us anymore.
Shichu,
Raise our child well
don't let people bully her
Huan Er
Help Shichu take care of the baby
Also the Empress and Ling Rong
you have to
be careful of them
I'm so tired
It's so nice.
I
I have never been like this
being embraced by you.
Go serve jiejie
What's up?
Don't speak
Ok
I'm done fixing it
Even though it's not good
it's still much better than before
It's very nice. It's like a lively centipede.
No other girl has sewn clothes for me before.
just my mother
My mother is Xi Tai Pin.
She used to embroider.
She takes good care of you
She must care for you a lot.
Princess drink your medicine.
Here.
The Princess won't take her medicine
How will she get better?
Even the tone of her cries are low.
The princess is too young, she won't be able to drink the medicine.
Even if she drinks it she will spit it out.
Then have the nurse drink it and liquefy it.
Feed it to the princess.
This idea will work.
Niangniang, Consort Hui passed away
no matter how much Niangniang is grieving, you must watch your own body.
These past two days I keep dreaming.
I dream about the times before I entered the palace
when I was with Mei jiejie
I always think she's still here
Niangniang is thinking too much.
You've lost weight.
It's good that the Emperor cared for Consort Hui
All the funeral customs will be of the Noble Consort status
and he let you care for princess Jing He.
How is your teacher?
He is a cripple now
and his mental strength has collapsed.
All he does is drink.
He never knew his feelings until she left.
What's the point in it?
Take care of him for me
Yes Niangniang.
With Wen Shichu's situation
A doctor that I can rely on
there's only you.
Thank you for trust.
I will do my best.
Having such thoughts is good.
I won't mistreat you.
In a couple days invite Wen Shichu
to take Jing He princess's pulse.
You know the importance.
I understand.
Niangniang, if you don't have anything else
I will leave.
Go.
Thank you.
Greetings
Please rise
Niangniang, the Emperor has a gift
is the second miss here?
She went to Empress Dowager's palace.
Then please accept it in place of second miss.
The gift from the Emperor is the palace's newly created
bingdi begonia hairpiece
to commend Second Lady for bravely barging into the Empress's palace
to save the Noble Consort's courage.
Thank the Emperor for me
I'll depart then
Has Bao Que's funeral been settled?
Yes.
Except, mistress, at this time
why are you only worrying about Bao Que?
Then what should I worry about?
The Emperor hasn't been here
to visit us in several days
You're not making a plan or worrying
What is there to worry about?
It's not just here that he's not going to
He's feeling down because of Hui Fei
But don't worry
He'll be better in a few days
Don't I know the Emperor?
Mistress, forgive my blunt words
but even if Consort Hui didn't die
she wouldn't be in our way.
It doesn't mater if Consort Hui died.
Except, her relationship with Zhen Huan is so strong
that with her death
Zhen Huan will become extremely depressed.
Only seeing Zhen Huan grieving
will make me comfortable.
Consort Hui jiejie,
I drink this cup to you.
When you arrive in front of the god of the underworld,
Zhen Huan caused your death
I don't remember rewarding you
Cui Bai's painting.
My younger sister's graffiti work
has fooled the Emperor as well?
The girl who stormed into the Empress's palace?
I rewarded her with jewelry and she hasn't thanked me yet.
Today she's at your palace, she can't delay it anymore.
Greetings, Emperor.
Do you not like the hairpiece I gave you?
You're not wearing it
She usually doesn't like these accessories
so she doesn't wear it.
You didn't thank the Emperor for his gift yet.
I not only dislike golden accessories,
but also those begonia flowers on the hairpiece are my sister's favorite.
Jiejie loves it, so I won't take any part of it.
Ok then
You like to paint,
would you like to paint with the artists from the palace?
I can arrange that for you.
The painters of the palace mostly like rich, gaudy colors.
You've seen my copy of Cui Bai's painting,
so you must know that the palace painters and I won't be compatible.
You paint geese very well.
I like birds of loyalty.
When you have time, go to Ru Yi Guan
and get Cui Bai's real sketch.
This painting is well-liked by both Yunli and Yunxi,
He's asked for it many times
and now I give it to you.
Thank you your Majesty.
This painting is a good omen.
I also hope that when my sister gets married
that she won't be too far from me.
Like the painting's
goose and flowers.
If sisters separate then it's boring.
What a coincidence.
What coincidence? I think that it's more like "the road between enemies is narrow".
If we aren't enemies we wouldn't meet.
My brother has given the painting to you?
It was to make Jiejie happy.
I asked my brother for this so many times
and he didn't want to give it.
It seems like he has Noble Consort in his heart.
What? You like this painting too?
Aside from everything,
The pair of geese is the best.
The vast, mile-long layers of cloud.
A thousand mountains and twilight clouds, to whom does the shadow go?
You also like the words?
Yuan Haowen's good poetry is only this one.
Geese are birds of loyalty.
So I like it.
Right, thank you for helping jiejie that other night.
No need, it's something I should do.
But this thanks is very late.
If you really want to thank me
then let me admire this painting.
Okay.
Cui Bai's style
has changed Northern Song dynasty's superficial extravagant art style.
He pursued realism
and was able to convey all the expressions.
So it's not like you don't learn art.
I don't learn art?
How about we have an art competition?
Alright. What do we draw?
Draw, a spring scene.
Okay.
We'll go to Ru Ye Guan to paint.
Yes.
I heard that the Emperor is ignoring Imperial Concubine An and the others.
But the Empress is getting it easy.
The Emperor let her off so easily.
He really doesn't distinguish good from bad.
The Emperor is not being unfair here.
He is remembering his past relationship with Empress Chunyuan.
Besides, the Empress Dowager is protecting her.
He can't do as he pleases.
Wen Shichu greets Noble Consort Xi.
I can smell the alcohol from a mile away.
Aren't you afraid of intoxicating Jinghe?
The one with a dead heart,
how can he care about his hygiene and appearance?
You carry her.
The child has become a bit heavier.
The princess is healthy
all thanks to Niang Niang's careful nurture.
No matter how much I care for her,
I am still not her birth parents.
This child always cries loudly when nearing dusk.
Perhaps she misses Mei Jiejie.
That day when Mei Zhuang entered the casket,
I put the jade pot that has been passed down to me
into her casket.
Maybe I should've given it to her earlier.
I was too foolish.
And I made her regretful for so many years.
This lifetime
it was always me who was sorry towards her.
Though Jiejie has gone, Jinghe is still here.
You must at least take the child into account.
Will you be drunken all day?
I will never forget in my lifetime
that feeling of her passing away in my arms.
Huan Meimei,
guarding you has already become a habit to me.
Habits are hard to change.
But toward Meizhuang,
her every loneliness and perseverance in this palace,
I can empathize.
She guarded me, just as for so many years
I guarded you in the same way.
I've already petitioned the Emperor
to guard her palace for three years as my punishment for not fulfilling my duty.
I understand Shichu Gege,
but the dead ones have already gone,
the live ones must continue living and take responsibility for everything.
You must live well
so that Jiejie can rest in peace.
Ever since Consort Hui died,
the Emperor has only gone to Yanxi Palace once.
And he only sat for a bit before leaving.
I already know all this.
Go touch Jingren Palace's walls and floor tiles,
they're cold like ice house.
After the Dragon Boat festival, the Emperor hasn't come here once.
You must be proactive in gaining your favors.
Is it so hard
that I have to drag the Emperor to your palace?
Niang Niang don't worry.
As long as I live,
I will not let Noble Consort Xi live so easily.
Enough.
I promoted you because I had hope in you.
Don't let me down.
Niang Niang's expectations are my expectations.
The Emperor arrives.
Greetings to the Emperor.
Rise.
You usually can't tolerate heat.
I should be taking you to Yuanmingyuan to escape the heat.
Until one manages the household, one wouldn't know the hardships of rationing resources.
The Empress Dowager's body is not well enough for her to go on long trips.
If I take all my kids with me,
it wouldn't be easy either.
Nurses and nannies are so numerous.
Yuanmingyuan would have to be refurnished again.
That would cost oceans' worth of silvers.
How frugal of you.
I looked over the account book for this month's spending
and it was less by seven thousand than last month.
It's the fruit of your frugality.
Emperor shouldn't be happy so soon.
In the future,
when the Emperor takes in a few more consorts,
even ten thousand silvers wouldn't be enough to cover the cost.
I smell jealousy and sourness in your words.
If you want to save some money on that matter,
I will tell you a marvelous trick.
I will only marry some of your palace maids as Promises.
Their monthly allowances
will be deducted from yours.
You can marry whoever you like.
A few Promises is nothing uncommon.
If you really have a couple you like,
you might as well ordain them as Precious.
If you are really this generous,
then I shall marry Huanbi today!
What do you think?
She's my only dowry servant left.
Will you take her too?
Because she's one of your close people,
I will not treat her lightly.
Just like that year when I married you, how about I ordain her as a Lingering?
I'll ordain her as Lingering Xi (meaning happiness)