Episode 45
Apricot
Although the flower is beautiful, the fruit it produces is extremely sour.
Almond is even more bitter.
What is the point in working for others,
If you have a good start but ended with failure?
It would have been better to be the evergreen pine
It doesn't matter whether it flowers or bear fruits
young miss we should get going then, the kitchen has prepared the south north stewed partridge
It will be most nutritious if you eat now
Let's go , I am feeling hungry too
Reporting to emperor
I believe the investigation into Qian Ming Shi case is sufficient by now
it would be better not to go too far into it
If the epistolary incident spreads to everyone's ears
officials will be mired in panic.
Who would then dare speak their minds?
If pandering proliferates
then justice and rectitude will be stymied.
Are you implying that I obstruct freedom of speech?
No, I would not dare.
I am only an official
if I cannot uphold my given duties
I would be letting you down.
Your majesty,
Zhen Yuandao is being obdurate and blasphemous
he should be severely punished.
Your Majesty,
Zhen Yuandao's treasonous intentions are apparent
but on account of Imperial Concubine Wan's pregnancy,
your majesty should
postpone Zhen Yuandao's penalty.
As Imperial Concubine Wan's father, Zhen Yuandao
should not be protected by her daughter's saintly halo
He has offended you with his choleric temper and unfettered arrogance
If you come down on him mercifully for Imperial Concubine Wan's sake,
what about the discipline of the courts?
All cases of treason should be punished equally
Zhen Yuandao shall be stripped of his post and incarcerated.
And his family shall be confined to their dwelling
Thank you, your majesty.
Jinxi, today is the Double Ninth Festival (festival for the elderly)
we have to pay our respects to the Empress Dowager
Have you prepared the chrysanthemum cakes and wine?
Yes, I even decorated the box
with three colours
Fang Ruo came to pick it up this morning.
That sounds perfect.
Greetings, Imperial Concubine Wan. What are you doing here, Aunty?
The Empress Dowager was thrilled to receive your gift
and is concerned about your pregnancy, so she sent me over.
I'm ever so grateful.
It must be a hard time for you,
let us know if you have any difficulties.
Everything's fine,
but today is the Double Ninth Festival
I miss my family.
According to the harem regulations, you may invite
your family over when you are 8 months pregnant.
That should be any time soon.
I will remind the Internal Affairs Department to invite your family in.
Although I am found guilty towards His Majesty, it seems my family doesn't being involved of it. I am relieved now.
I still have errands to run for Empress Dowager. It's not convenient for me to stay too long.
I shall take my leave first.
Thank you, Gugu. It's just that I won't be able to send you off.
Take care, Niangniang.
Imperial Concubine Wan didn't suspect anything, did she?
It's a grace from Empress Dowager, I don't think she would suspect anything.
Thank goodness it had finally passed.
How could it be so unlucky? Early this morning
I came to give the Emperor
I never thought that helping the Empress deliever this errand
Early in the morning i knew something was wrong, and i'm so distraught
How would I dare to meet Niangniang?
So I had no choice but to trouble you, Gugu.
You may hide it from her for the time being. But you can't hide it forever!
Niangniang is in the advanced stages of her pregnancy.She mustn't find out about this...
Otherwise, what's going to happen if it affects the fetus?
Yes. Those are my thoughts too.It's a good thing that the penalty for the Zhen Residence isnt' settled yet.
Perhaps, for Niangniang's sake, His Majesty...
will be willing to show some mercy.
That's not something we should concern ourselves with.
Let's return.
It's always been Fangruo who comes. Why was it Sun Gugu today?
Perhaps it's because the present young miss sent over was favoured by The Empress,thus sent Sun Gugu here as dignity.
Don't you feel that Sun Gugu's mannerisms were a little weird?
Young mistress please don't think so much.It's time for you to have medicine. I'll go take the medicine over.
This soup has been stewed for 6 hours.
It melts instantly once enters the mouth. Do you like it, Mother?
It's very good. Tastes sweet and soft.
It's good as long as you like it, Mother.
People say,eat desserts will make one feel happy.
However after I ate this dessert,
it still seems tasteless to me.
I heard there was official pleading for ZhengYuan Dao
He made the emperor very angry, had be put into the prison
It is like that
The polity is so turbulent that the harem is not calm
I am incompetent
It's not that you're incompetent, it's that you're
much more bright and competent than Chun Yuan
I don't want to invade your affairs that how to be a wife and how to be a queen in these years
but only one rule that the Imperial Heirs are the most important
Women in the palace are like the endlessly blooming flowers.
Even if you remove one, another will replace her.
The queen should be in charge of blossom rather than always mows them what cause the tragedy, and especially
No matter what, you must not hurt the Imperial Heirs.
After my first son was gone, I've been hoping that there will be someone to pass down the Emperor's throne
Even though there are three princes at the moment...
Three?
How many sons did the previous Emperor have?
It's nothing compared to the previous Emperor
It's your responsibility for Emperor's lack of sons...
Go reflect under the Door of Zhong Si
Think about my concerns.
Yes.
Peace upon you, Empress.
Niangniang, the winds are strong. Why don't you return to your palace first?
An, do you know the mean of the door of Zhongsi
I don't. Please enlighten me, Niangniang.
Zhongsi. Should your descendants names act as Zhongsi (crickets).
The meaning is expect lots of children from the Emperor
The Emperor throne shall be for ever extended
I really hope to have a prince of my own.
My prince could already laugh and speak, yet a wind illness
made him die in my arms
Now, seeing others becoming pregnant one after another within the palace
these children were born one by one
how could I afford this emotionally
Niangniang, children that you do not like...
should not exist in this world.
Not for any other reason, other than the fact that you are the Mother of this nation.
Similarly, women that you do not like...
should not continue to exist and cause you annoyance.
That's why I like you.
Niangniang.
Wuan ping has only 8 more months before she gives birth.
The birth of a baby is a blessed event
I've fulfilled my responsibility
Poor Wuan Ping, she's already so far into her pregnancy.
If she were to find out that something happened to her family,
who knows how she will be hurt?
You'd better get the Medical Department to take good care of her.
No matter what, you mustn't let the cat out of the bag.
I will remember that.
Niangniang, let me accompany you back first.
That's not necessary.
His Majesty should have just awoken from his afternoon nap.
You should return to attend to him.
Thank you for your understanding, Niangniang.
Go.
I've been pregnant for 8 months now.
Why hasn't the Internal Affairs Department arranged for Mother to enter the palace yet?
In the morning, when Aunt Fang wu came she was also stuttering
Last time when Su Pei came to pass on a message, she said the weather is chilly today
and to not go out for a stroll. They were thinking for your health
I also resisted my predecessors. Please ask your mother to come to the Palace. This is internal affairs' matter
These few days, I've been feeling very uneasy.
You're baby is almost due. It would make sense for them to be more cautious.
Thats true, the baby is almost here.
By that time, it will be cold
I want to sew a couple blankets for him.
Okay, I'll help you too. You don't need to do any of the needlework.
Let me do it.
I will pull the cotton then.
I give you, Wuan Ping niang niang my greetings.
Your childs birth is approaching. The Imperial household ordered the delivery of these ‘easy birth stones'
I bless you a successful delivery and wellness for you both.
What's your name? Why have I never seen you before?
Im new, originally Huang da ge was supposed to come.
He suddenly had a stomach ache, so i came instead.
This money is an award from our lady, treat yourself to some tea.
Thank you Niang Niang.
This is not much.
The day my family arrives at the palace,
I will greatly award you.
Thank you niang niang.
But I have not heard lately, that anyone was entering the palace.
May I ask, what kind of job they do? (social status)
My family is not a very renowned one.
At such an old age, sent to jail
How did this happen?
Niangniang, there's a lot you're unaware of. Even with that contribution, they commited a grave crime.
For example, that Nian family.
He was reported by someone.
Who reported it?Out with it quickly!
-It was Lord E'min.-Lies!
Hasn't Lord E'min always been on good terms with Lord Zhen? Why would he report Lord Zhen?
How would I understand what's going on in Court?
But everyone knows about this!I wouldn't dare to lie about it!
I have other errands to run.
I'll take my leave first.
Young Mistress, what should we do?
Alright.
Young Mistress!Her fetus has been affected! Call Physician Wen!
Greetings, Young Mistress.
Have you completed the task I assigned to you?
Exactly as per your instructions, I just heard them summon for the Physician.
Very well.
How fortunate she's going to be now will depend on her own fate.
Carry out another task for me.
At your service.
Help me look for something, and deliver it straight to the prison.
Gonggong, it's unclean inside. Come out quickly.
Do I need you to instruct me?
Yes yes yes. Please go ahead, Gonggong.
Someone come quickly! There's a mice! A mice!
Lord Wen, there's nothing serious with our Young Mistress, is there?
Not anything serious.
But, there are something things that I would like to ask Niangniang.
I have something to ask you too.
Alright.
Niang Niang, you shouldn't stress yourself, it'll hard your fetus.
Yesterday, someone told me what happened to my family.
You are able to exit the palace everyday.
You must be clear about the situation.
Niangniang, you're aware of everything?Who was so daring to tell you about it?
So you did know about it.
Even if I didn't ask...
there would be someone who would think of ways to let me find out.
Firstly, the Emperor ordered it. Secondly, I had to ensure your health.
Now that I know about it...
how long were you intending to keep me in the dark?
Madam and Second Miss have been locked up at home.
Their predicament is exactly the same as yours.
Exactly the same?
I have the amnesty because I'm pregnant
My parents have the same treatment ？
He commiserate the usurper？ Why do you say this？
niangniang，do you remember the case of Qian Mingshi
This is a set-up，isn't it？
So, the Emperor believed it?
not just me
The Zhens have been framed
Young Mistress, something's not right.
Xiaoguizi said he arrived shortly Imperial Household
He did not know that the family name of Young Mistress is Zhen How could he knew the affaire of our family
You too believe that he's new?
As the emperor attach importance to Suiyu Xuan
Someone purposely sent him to tell me the news.
If I had been a little more softhearted,
I'm afraid I would have lost this child.
They're so evil.
I would like to beg an audience with His Majesty.
Except, this isnt something that can be easily changed.
His Majesty might not able to come
Can you bring the item and letter in this box to His Majesty?
Dear Huan Huan,my dear wife,
Wanwan, if you were around...
you would probably understand the dilemmas that I'm experiencing.
I know in this world...
only you truly understands me.
No one else but you
Doctor Wen told me to bring this to you from Shattered Jade Palace(the palace that Huan Huan lives in).
My little owner don't hesitate.
My family's life and death depends if His Majesty will meet me.
Master. Soo goong goong
His Majesty tells you to go to Meditate Heart palace(the palace where His Majesty lives).
Wait outside. i would be coming.
I would wait outside.
since you are sick, you don't to have to bow
After you got pregnant, you start to have a lot of dreams.
are you still sleep peacefully?
Now you know i am not seeping well huh?
Fong Goog Goog said
then you believe i am not sleep well
then why don't you ask the royal doctor...
to prescribe me some sleeping medicine
What do you want to say?
I want to say that,
you can't just hear one side of the story and judge
Then are you sleeping well these days?
Initially, my sleep my indeed fitful.
Recently, it's improved.
Fangruo Gugu had no intention of lying to Your Majesty.
You came all this way and you didn't even ask if i am feeling well.
is this all what you want to dicuss with me?
you even know?
What happen if i say i don't have the intention to, would you believe it?
having intention to or not, wrong is wrong
can i ask how deep is Queen's punishment?
Can you retrial my father's case so innocent people won't be killed?
You said it just now too.
You said that people can't only hear one side of the story.
I wouldn't fully believe E-min's words either.
I've taken all that into account.
In all these, I haven't maligned your family at all.
I don't know the full story either...
But my father's loyalty to you...
have you disregarded that completely, Your Majesty?
I've already passed the edict...
This is also my consideration for his many years of hard work.
The hardships at Ningguta are second to none.
My parents are so advanced in age...
how would they endure such hardships?
Your Majesty!
Do you know what you are saying?
Are you saying that everything I've ever received...
was all because of Empress Chunyuan?
Just because of Wanwan.
Then what am I?
Just what am I?
You know it now.
Actually, the fact that you resemble Wanwan to some extent is your fortune too.
Really?
Is it really my blessing or my curse?
It's not justy Your Majesty who has made a mistake.I made an even bigger mistake!
All these years of love and moments...
I've really given them in vain!
Your Majesty.
What is it?
Say it quickly!
Someone from the dungeon came to report that...
Lord Zhen has contracted the plague.
His life now hangs in the balance.
Niangniang!
Niangniang, you're pregnant. You have to take care!
Your Majesty, I know you have made your decision,
but my father did nothing wrong.
Please save my father's life.
Don't let my father die wrongfully!
I will take responsibility for all the crimes.
I understand.
Let's go, Niangniang.
Niang Niang
What's happened?
Niangniang.
Come.
the giell is ready
Niangniang, take care!
Niang Niang
Be careful.
Hurry up
stop master master
master master
huan pin has a lot of blood i think she will give birth
after leaving meditate heart palace( the palace where His Majesty leaves), she shacked the fetus peace.
Ciyiair ciyair please prepare me a ride to shattered jade palace(the palace where haun pin leaves)
Hurry and prepare I need to go to Sui Yu Xuan.
No.
delivering a baby is big news, i must accompany her. You can't go.
you need to let His Majesty see how huan pin risks her life to to born his child
then the king won't forget about Wuan pin and she will get a chance to receive the Emperor's love.
What use, is this kind of love?!
You can choose to not want it, but she can't.
then if Wuan pin can't keep her life, the child can't survive either.
then i should go invite His Majesty
the king should go by himself or else...
right now there is one more important business that needs to be taken care is huan pin's father's life.
even if huan pin born the child, huan pin will a still be a guilty men's child.
then how can she ever will be able to raise her head up
okay
Then I'll make the arrangements for Physician Wen to save Lord Wen first.
Niangniang, use more strength!I can see half a head!
More strength, Niangniang!
please use your strength half the head already came out
Niang Niang, push harder.
His Majesty don't worry.
Did someone visit her father in jail yet?
That's good then.
He's here.  Congratulations Your Majesty, its a princess.
Congratulations, Your Majesty.
A princess is good too!
I'll go take a look at Concubine Wan.
Your Majesty, look at yourself!It's not even the first princess!
It's just a princess! How am I that happy?
Your Majesty, you can't even hide your smile!It's all over your face!
Reporting to Empress.
Concubine Wan has given birth to a princess.
A princess?That's good.
I wonder if the Emperor will have a change of heart because of the princess?
Wan Pin wouldn't let it.
She's really pretty.
Niangniang,
congratulations,you've given born to a princess. She is doing well and is so beautiful!
Young Mistress, you gave me a shock.You were unconscious for quite some time.
I'll pour a cup of tea for you right away.
Niangniang. Come, carry her over.
Let Niangniang take a look at the princess.
This is the princess' wet nurse.
The princess was born premature.
The Imperial Physician has visited. He said she need lots of care.
Young Mistress, His Majesty is here.
His Majesty has arrived!
Peace upon Your Majesty.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
-All of you, get up.-Thank you, Your Majesty.
Imperial Concubine Wan, have you still not come to terms with it?
Your Majesty, what do you want me to come to terms with?
You've already given birth to a princess for me.
Are you still going to do things out of anger?
I've decided that regardless of what happens to the Zhen family, it will not implicate you.
As long as you are willing,
I can confer the title of Consort on you tomorrow.
I've fallen from favor. I dare not take up a Consort's position.
Huanhuan, if you're willing, you're still my favored concubine.
I will still treat you the same way as I did in the past.
In the past...
Does Your Majesty think that we can still return to the past?
Indeed, I've given in to you too much.
This obstinacy of yours does not fit in the palace.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Go to the shrine and meditate. You don't need to live here anymore.
That's right. I don't need to live here.
If the Princess were to have a mother like me,
and such a family clan that is in such dire straits,
she will be implicated and suffer a hard life.
I would like to leave.
As for the child's name, please permit me to choose it.
Your Majesty, please permit it.
Very well.
She'll be called...Wanwan.
Wanwan?
How could I be so disrespectful to allow the little princess to share the name of the previous Empress?
What I'm unable to accomplish, let the princess do it.
I'll pray for her at the temple
for the rest of my life
It's fine if you don't want to go to the temple
Baohua Hall in the palace...
No, this unfortunate aura of mine...
has disturbed the peace in the palace.
It's good if you leave sooner too. The palace won't keep you.
-Niangniang.-Young Mistress.
I have one more favor to beg of you.
Say it.
After I leave the palace,
I hope to have Consort Jin bring the princess up.
If that can be so, I will harbor no regrets.
Consort Duan has already taken Wenyi under her wing. Consort Jin can have this responsibility.
The moonlight is dim. Let the princess's name be Longyue.
Princesses are only titled at the Full Month.
Longyue received this honor the moment she was born.
I thank Your Majesty for this favor shown.
Do you have anything else to say to me?
Strings break, Mirror imperfect
Dews sob, stops when it's time.
Recite when old, Sad farewell
Please eat well, no need to miss me.
Time keeps moving on,
it's time for an everlasting parting with you
Fine. Fine.
Since that is the case, I have nothing to say either.
Your intention to leave is firm.
As for Longyue, Consort Jin and I will take good care of her.
Niangniang.
Young Mistress.
Meimei, why did you do that?