The weather is hot recentIy
Your nanny said that
You study untiI midnight of everyday
AIthough it is good to be hardworkingYou have to take care of your heaIth
You asked peopIe tosend soup to me everyday
I didn't feeI tired
The soup
Is to remind you to have a rest
But not to study after drinking it
I have misunderstood you
Greeting, consort Xi 4th prince
It's Iate now Consort Ning
Why are you here aIone?
His Majesty wanted me to come
But 3rd prince is inside now
Eunuch Su said that
His Majesty is pissed off
He asked me not to enter first
You can memorize
The poem of the previous emperor
But
You can't answer
Why the previous emperor
Can easiIy ruIe the country
Didn't your teacher
TeII you about the
PoIicies of the previous emperor
He did
Mother toId me to read it too
Your teacher and mother are hardworking
But you are Iazy
You went to schooI since 5 years oId
It's been many years
Yet you didn't Iearn many things
I remember you can
Memorize the poIicies in two years ago
Now you actuaIIy forgot them aII
LukiIy your teacher is patient
If I were him
I wouId have died
PIease don't be angry
I don't want to be angry too
But I can't do it because of you
You are my eIdest son
I don't hope you to do something big
I onIy want you
To be the roIe modeI of your brothers
So that I don't have to worry about them
But you did
So many useIess things
His Majesty is so angry
He is the ruIer
It is sure that he isnot as amiabIe as you are
You stiII don't have a son
When you have
a son in the future
More strict than His Majesty
Oh 4th prince
I heard that you are hardworking
Do you know the thingsthat His Majesty mentioned
How can I hoId a candIe to 3rd brother
I studied Iater than he did
Consort Ning means I am stupidby saying that I am hardworking
Because I need more times
Or The teacher wiII scoId me
Memorize this articIe within three days
Or you don't have to
come and see me anymore
Greeting, consort XiGreeting, consort Ning
Faster go in
His Majesty is pissed off
He might be harsh
Take it easy
They are father and son, anyway
Everything wiII be fine after a few days
Yes Thank you
You stiII have to go back Hurry up
Mother is waiting for me in the paIace
It's so Iate now
What time are you goingto the schooI on tomorrow
Tomorrow's dawn
Then you'II sIeep at here tonight
My mother said stupid birds fIy first
I am not as smart as other peopIe are
Therefore I have to work harder
By studying everyday
The empress wants you to be successfuI
But you have tot takecare of your body too
I heard that your father
Is Iooking for a wife for you
It's better to form a famiIy now
Yes It's Iate now
I wiII Ieave first
Mother 3rd brother
is so hardworking
I must work harder
Then onIy father wiII Iike me
Just now you toId consort Ning
That you don't know theanswer of the questions
But I heard you
Memorizing them on few days ago
You Iike to keep a Iow profiIe
So do I
You are smart
Of course
I am same with you
Mother 3rd brother
is the eIdest son
WiII he be the emperor
I have no idea
But 6th brother is your bioIogicaI son
Father Iikes him too
So he wiII be happy as Iong as he be the emperor
Your 6th brother is stiII young
I don't Iike him
to be the emperor too
OnIy usefuI peopIe
Can be the ruIer of our dynasty
Do you get me
Yes
Hong-Shi Do you have your beIoved
You wiII decide for me
Just go and pick one
TeII your father whenyou have your beIoved
You have grown up I can onIy arrange
But not decide for you
Greeting,
consort Xi
Greeting, empress
Stand up
Thank you
Nice to meet youWe wiII keep meeting in the future
3rd prince is taIIer now
The weather is coId Therefore I invited you and consort Jing here To pick some Outstanding Iadies
You have a good taste
I think everyone of them is good
Take your timeYou wiII find one in the end
She asked us to come here
So that we can support her
Next time if 3rd princefaIIs for anyone of them
She doesn't want peopIe tothink that she decides everythingIt Iooks as if we Iike the girI too
Who do you Iike
The niece of empressThe girI in green-coIoredshirt Qing-Ying
Qing-Ying Come over hereGreeting, 3rd prince
Yes
Greeting, 3rd prince
She is the youngest daughter of your uncIeYou shouId caII her as your cousin
Cousin
I am Qing-Ying
You are as pretty asYou are as pretty as
Thank you for your compIiment
Meng-Yue Come over here
Longyue, come here.
Meng-Yue The crapemyrtIefIowers have bIoomed
Let's go and take a Iook
SureThe crapemyrtIe fIowers inmy house are the prettiest
Take your time to see
I wiII Ieave first
I heard that you Iike to eat pIum
Thus I speciaIIy brought it here
Do you mean this
ActuaIIy I don't reaIIy Iike it
It's just my mother said thatPIum can reIieve thirst
So she made them intofoods and want me to eat
She is doing that for your own good
You shouId foIIow her order
It seems Iike you don't reaIIy Iike kids
Kids are naughty
We don't have to botherourseIf arguing with them
And entertain them
I speciaIIy made this cIoths In order to meet you
But it is broken
AIright Meng-Yue Come
You Iike the pIum I'II give it to you
You Iove me the mostEat it
Meng-Yue Let's go
The kids feeI weird
With our existence
It's windyConsort Xi I am going back to get a change
Mother is goneConsort Xi, pIease goand Iook for her with me
Go with her
Then I wiII Ieave first
She is here
Why didn't you teII us
LuckiIy she didn't bIame on us
She wiII not do soNow her mind is occupiedBy the reputation of her famiIy
She won't think about usYou must be boredTherefore you simpIy foundan excuse and Ieft there
Look at those girIs They are outstandingBut 3rd prince doesn't seemto be interested in them
YesMeng-Yue 3rd prince Iooks unhappy
Go and get him hereAsk him to come and have a waIk
Hurry up
Don't you Iike those pretty sisters
I don't Iike arrogant
And hypocriticaI women
So do IWhat kind of girI do you Iike
Tender and quiet
Are you saying that I am taIkative
You are the most cute
Why is the coIor of the fIowerDifferent from the coIorwhen I saw it in the morning
The fIower
Is red in coIor in morningAnd pink in coIor in evening
It is Iike the face of a beautyThey have a Iot of emotion
This Iady is beauty
Do you agree with me
Both of you are pretty
I don't deserve you to caII me as a sister
Princess I am Lady Ying
Lady Ying Why didn't I see you before
This is
This is my 3rd brother
Greeting, 3rd prince
3rd brother, lady Ying is our mother too. You don't come often here, that's why you don't know her
Greeting lady Ying
Greeting 3rd brother, greeting lady Ying too. Greeting you two
Lady Yin is appreciating the flowers alone
It looks like you're not very happy
I'm just missing my family
Even we met, we'll separate.
My birth mother has died.
Even if I want to see her, I can't.
Prince don't need to be sad.
Though your birth mother isn't here,
but no matter wherever or whenever, her heart will always remember you.
Before, whatever she did
was also for the good of you.
Thanks for Ying Niang Niang's enlightenment.
Why don't you have anyone serving you?
What does it matter to have a servant around?
If the one with you doesn't understand you,
it's a waste.
But sometimes I also feel, the more people present, the lonelier I feel.
You are right about this idea.
It's getting late. I shall bid goodbye now.
So having many people with you still makes you feel lonely.
Only having someone who understands you by your side
is real happiness.
Third brother, what are you mumbling about?
Nothing. Let's go.
In the palace, the imperial noble consort plays pipa the best.
Noble Consort Xi plays the qin the best.
As for zithers, you are number one.
I'm merely an amateur.
How can I be compared to the other Niang Niangs?
You have a quiet personality
and do not like to fight for favor. This naturally has its benefits.
Your Majesty,
Third Prince is here.  Let him in.
Then I shall leave first.
No need.
You are also his senior.
Greetings to imperial father.
Why are you here at this hour?
Have you completed the lessons for today?  Yes, and I have read through all the teacher's lectures for today.
That's good.
I will test you on your lessons another day.
Imperial father,
I came today with a request about my schooling.
Say it.
Both imperial father and mother feel that I am grown up and should start a family.
But I feel that right now is a good time for studying
I don't want to involve myself in any relationships
so I don't want to marry and start a family yet.
Our original intention
was to have another person take care of you.
But I have many servants to take care of me, which is enough.
If I have a wife, I will most likely be distracted.
I know that I am not especially gifted
and can't share your burden
so I want to study well and let your mind rest in peace.
If that's what you think, then I feel at ease.
This was your imperial mother's wish anyways. I'm not worried.
Imperial father,
in the future I also want to
marry a virtuous and quiet wife.
Yes.
Peace between the husband and wife is the most important.
You may leave now.
Ying Niang Niang's playing of the zither is like mountains breaking down delicately and hibiscus crying tears of dew.
I am in awe.
Thanks for Third Prince's compliment.
You really have a good ear. This song "High Mountains Flowing Streams" is her best.
You can leave
Yes
Gugu can just send me here.
Gege (daughters of nobles), please wait a moment.
What matter does Gugu have?
Though Gege can't become a wife for now,
Niang Niang's words do have reason.
How about we ignore titles and have you serve Third Prince as an escort concubine first? You can always be promoted later.
Even if aunt (Empress) was unlucky back then,
she was at least a secondary wife.
But now I can only be an escort concubine without titles.
Auntie really does care for me.
Gege shouldn't just look at the short term effects.
You should bear the humiliation for now.
Bear the humiliation?
Isn't my humiliation now not big enough?
Third Prince doesn't like me and even the Emperor agreed not to have me as his wife.
Now I'm the laughingstock of the entire palace.
Then what am I?
And now you want me to so shamelessly attach to him.
Please forward this to auntie: thank you for your great love.
Gege leave carefully.
Niang Niang,
she's been sent out?
Yes.
Gege wasn't very happy.
Did you say that it was my idea?
Gege has a high temperament and does not want to comply.
She's too young Have no patient.
What's the matter with being an escort concubine or a wife?
When Third Prince inherits the throne,
I will become the Empress Dowager.
I'll be the one to decide whom the emperor chooses as his empress.
The empress's seat must be someone from the Wulanala clan.
Niang Niang is right.
Gege is still young and can't think this far.
It's a pity that she can't. Wulanala clan still has plenty of good girls.
When the new crop grows up,
she won't even be considered anymore.
That's Gege not realizing her fortune.
She even talked about how you were a secondary wife back then and started complaining.
Fine then.
If she likes complaining about how I was a secondary wife back then,
and if she refuses to be the escort concubine,
then I shall promote her for once. I'll have her realize that being the secondary wife
of some other princes is worse than being the escort concubine of Third Prince.
Your meaning is?
Fourth Prince is already sixteen.
I will ask the Emperor for mercy
and have Qingying
become the secondary wife of Fourth Prince.
Wouldn't this be too good for Fourth Prince?
Too good? We are giving the Fourth Prince someone the Third Prince doesn't like.
Besides, Noble Consort Xi and I have bad blood. With this new daughter-in-law, I wonder who is blocking who?
Niang Niang is indeed right. But I have one matter to ask,
court officials are electing candidates for the crown prince. Why did Niang Niang let them mention Sixth Prince?
The Emperor is suspicious and is most afriad of the court collaborating with the harem to manipulate politics.
We must constantly give Emperor a reminder.
These few years,
I keep feeling that my body is not what it used to be.
Empress is saying
to have a marriage arranged for Hongshi.
The court also keeps mentioning the election of a crown prince.
You don't know how annoyed I am by this.
Do all these ministers feel that I am getting too old
so they're rushing to elect a crown prince?
You are still rich in your years and strong in body. No need to appoint a crown prince yet.
Third Prince, no matter how good, still needs experience.
The court ministers are just
worried that you are overworked
and want someone to share your burdens.
Even if I was to choose a crown prince,
I would have to wait for our Sixth Prince.
Some ministers
are patient when they shouldn't be or impatient when they don't need to be.
Now that I think about it,
Fourth Prince is already sixteen.
When you mention Third Prince's marriage,
I think of Fourth Prince.
Emperor,
you must not pick favorites.
Your words are
the same as Empress's.
Empress said that she has a niece named Qingying
whom she wants to marry to Hongli.
Empress is picking favorites!
Why does our Fourth Prince need to be stuck with someone Third Prince doesn't like?
You already said yourself that you've chosen Chahaer Administrator's daughter, Fucha.
You must not go back on your words.
I know that you also like Fucha,
Fucha is younger than Hongli by a year but is reliable.
But the Empress says that Qingying only wants to be a secondary wife.
Since Empress is this humble,
I also don't have much to say.
Wulanala clan is a noble clan.
I just fear that Empress's niece won't feel right with us.
If the Empress is willing,
I should at least save her face this once.
That's fine.
After all, our Fourth Prince is the one getting the bargain.
Today's weather is good.
Walking out here is good. If we stay inside all day,
we would grow moldy.
It's already September.
Did you ask people in your palace to pick some switchgrass?
Why so?
Switchgrass and stay are homophones. It's also September (homophones with longevity), so it means to have the Emperor stay long.
I don't believe this.  You are in favor right now so of course you don't believe these.
Isn't that the Prince?
Prince Guojun?
It's been a while since I've since Prince.
Since you married and started a family,
you can't be as free as before.
Now that you have one wife on each side, trapping you. Even if you have wings, it would be hard for you to escape.
Noble Consort Jing is still this humorous.
Long time no see, how is Noble Consort Xi?
Thanks for the Prince's concern. My body is well.
So why is Prince here in the palace today?
I've come to greet the Emperor after a long time of absence.
It's windy so Prince should wear this cape.
No.
We are married, why do you have to act so formal?
This must be Wife Xian.
I am Prince Guojun's Secondary Wife Meng Jingxian.
I hereby greet Noble Consort Xi,
wishing you longevity, happiness, fortune, and peace.
Please
hurry and get up.
You were sick on the day of your wedding so this is our first meeting.
We are all family
so no need for formalities.
I should've come greet Noble Consort Xi sooner, but my body was always unwell.
So today I came with Prince
to greet the Emperor and ask forgiveness of all the Niang Niangs.
The Emperor and I both were worried for your health.
Why wasn't Yuyin here today also?
She really has no rules.
Since Wife Xian is serving the Prince along with Yuyin,
please teacher her well for me when you have freetime.
Today the farm is reporting the harvest for this quarter and Yuyin is tending to that so she couldn't come.
Yuyin Meimei is good at tending to domestic affairs.
Unlike me,
with my ill body
I can only trouble others.
You are overthinking it.
I heard that you are well-versed in poetry, how can that be a burden?
Jingxian,
don't overthink it.
Yuyin Meimei is Niang Niang's godsister.
If Niang Niang doesn't mind my abstruseness,
you can also treat me like your sister.
I am not worthy of your compliments.
It's getting late.
Let's not have the Emperor wait.
Prince Guojun's treatment towards Wife Xian is indeed intimate and no less than your treatment towards her godsister.
It seems like the two wives by your side are sharing your love equally.
Prince Guojun, you are quite passionate.
Farewell.
As soon as you came, Niang Niang arrived.
It's so rare for Meimei to visit here.
Do you usually have this many people serving you?
If there's nothing to tend to, have them leave for now.
The imperial garden is windy. I was afraid that your wind would get cold.
Drink some warm tea.
You saw?
Wife Xian's infatuation I have long heard of.
It's better to see something for yourself.
Where was Meimei hiding and watching this drama unfold?
Being a human is hard.
You have to act wherever you are.
And this palace is filled with good dramas in every corner.
So you think that Wife Xian was merely acting?
Some things you think it's false,
but they were actually genuine.
Niang Niang only saw it once and you are already upset.
I wonder how Wife Xian's infatuation
looks to Wife Yu, who has to endure it daily.
Yuyin isn't that type of person.
Don't underestimate a woman's jealousy.
Since their marriage,
the Prince has only brought Wife Yu with him to the palace.
But now, with Wife Xian's conditions bettering,
I'm only afraid that in the midst of Wife Yu's busy domestic management, she would have to taste loneliness.
No way.
After all they are equal in position.
It's exactly because they're equal in position and power
that if the Prince treats one a bit nicer,
the other, if she has a narrow heart,
then there would be quarrels.
The reason the Prince married Yuyin,
I think Niang Niang knows more than I do.
That image, how did it fall out so easily?
The Prince isn't that type of uncautious person
The wood has already become the boat.
Ning Pin should understand that the thing grasped in hand is the most reliable.
But you and I have lost an opportunity like Yuyin's long ago.
Though she was selfish, she had no harm intended.
If not self-centered, the heavens would bring curse.
Just hope that Wife Yu won't kill off her conscience.
I'll go back and rest. There are plenty of good acts later on in this palace.
I can't miss them.
I'll bid goodbye now.
Does Niang Niang know why all the consorts in the palace like desserts?
Perhaps their hearts are bitter so they can only compensate with desserts.
Then Niang Niang should eat some more.
In reality Ning Pin's words don't need to be taken seriously.
That's true.
After a few days Yuyin will come to the palace to greet.
You should prepare some of her favorite food.
Alright.
Precious,
Third Prince.
You should call me Ying Niang Niang.
It's only you and I here.
Greetings to Ying Niang Niang.
You can leave now.
What does Third Prince want to say?
I converted that song you played on the zither into a singing song.
Did you hear it?
Third Prince don't say this.
If the Emperor knows that you are not doing proper things, he would rebuke you again.
I knew that only you understand and care for me in this palace.
Third Prince, what are you doing? I'm your stepmother!
I know that you treat me well! I don't care about titles and positions!
Please leave Third Prince!
Am I really not on the level of my father?
My heart has you! Imperial father is already old!
What happened today? Precious Ying was so anxious
and Third Prince acts like he lost his soul
and saw a ghost or something.
Both are at the peak of youth,
perhaps...
No wonder, the last few days when the opera was arranging the music,
I heard someone singing Precious Ying's "High Mountains Flowing Streams".
It seemed that Third Prince found someone who arranged it according to Precious Ying's zither music.
You are saying,
Right now Third Prince is the Empress's adopted son
and the Empress is his rightful mother.
This is an important matter.
Have someone follow them.
Yes.
You've already stayed here for a few days.
If you don't go back,
the Prince will worry.
The Prince Lord treats Meng Jingxian more closely than he treats me.
The people in the household has also taken sides.
It's meaningless to go back.
Niang Niang,
Prince Guojun household's Wife Xian has come.
She said that she has come to greet you.
Speaking of the devil,
so it seems that gossiping is not good.
Elder sister, I don't want to see her. I've already seen enough of her infatuation with the Prince.
I wanted to come here and avoid her for a while, but I can't even do that!
As long as your eyes don't see her, it's fine. Go hide over there.
I'll take care of her.
Niang Niang  Let her in.
Greetings to Noble Consort Xi
You may rise.
Sit.
Why do you have free time to
come here and visit?
I just went to greet the Emperor
so I came to see you also.
Right,
I heard that Yuyin Meimei is also living her for a few days.
But I don't see her.
How unfortunate,
she went to Noble Consort Jing
and said that she was going to make clothes for Princess Longyue.
Yuyin Meimei really likes children.
Drink some tea.
Niang Niang's tea is so aromatic,
but I shouldn't drink tea right now.
Or else I would want to taste some of this tea.
Why? Is your body not well?
The imperial doctor said that I am already pregnant one month.
I'm not stable yet so I can't drink tea for now.
This servant girl is so clumsy.
She can't even put a hanger back properly and startled you.
What's wrong with you? Why can't you even put back a hanger properly?
Don't cry, the two Niang Niang are still outside. You will disturb them.
Then this really is good news.
This servant girl doesn't know anything because of my lack of discpline. Please forgive us.
New palace maids are always a bit clumsy.
It's fortunate that our household has Yuyin. If it were me, how could I manage all the servant?
No matter how able Yuyin is, she still isn't on par with your achievement of bearing a child.
Ever since I married into the Prince's household,
I've always heard how the Prince loved Yuyin Meimei for many years
before marrying her.
Yuyin has great feelings for the Prince, and so do you.
The Prince only has sympathy for me.
Only I know myself how this child came about.
Because only with a child would I be able to retain his heart.
But these days I find that Yuyin is also trying as hard as I am.
If the Prince really was, as rumored,
to be this in love with Yuyin Meimei, why would she need to try this hard?
Since you are already married into his household,
I'll tell you something that I have realized over my years of experience in the palace.
Suspicion creates hidden demons.
Some things, the more you think about it, the easier conflicts will arise out of it.
Those who don't worry are the smart ones.
Hopefully.
But I really can't understand the reason behind all this.
I already said, Wife Xian is worrying too much because of your pregnancy.
Since I am one besides the Prince in bed,
there are many things that the one in bed knows
but outsiders can't see.
Between couples, this is normal.
I shall bid goodbye now.
Meng Jingxian is too smart.
Her suspicion will sooner ruin the Prince.
She loves the Prince deeply and will place his benefits first.
But now that she has his child,
what place do I have in this house?
Meng Jingxian's child is the Prince's child both by name and by blood.
You are his mother in name.
Naturally, there is a place for you.
You are Niuhulu clan's second miss,
Prince Guojun's secondary wife. You must be virtuous.
Since I love the Prince, I will naturally not mistreat his child.
Elder sister,
my heart is bitter though.
Things of the past are all not important. What's important is now.
The Emperor likes Meng Jingxian and this is the first child born of Prince Guojun's household.
You must take care of her well and have no accidents.
I desire to know the reigning. My long life would never decline.
I desire to know the reigning.
My long life would never decline.
Third Prince, I've heard you reciting this poem for many days now.
Little Lezi,
am I not good?
Good, how are you not good? You are the heaven's proud son.  What good is being the heaven's child?
The one who really cares for me is only her.
Who?
I have stomach-ful of words I want to tell her, but I don't know how.
If you can't say it, then write it.
You are indeed smart.
What did Imperial Mother summon you to say?
Imperial mother said that I am of age
and that imperial father will arrange a marriage for me.
Fucha is a good child. My mind is at ease.
I believe mother's taste.
But I am still young, I just want a wife. But imperial mother still wants me to have Wulanala as my secondary wife.
Does Mother know, that Wulanala-
I know it all.
If the Empress wants you to marry, then marry her.
Don't become her enemy over small things like these.
But giving someone Third Prince doesn't want to me,
You are welcoming the one Third Prince doesn't want. This shows your tolerance.
His caprice has fulfilled you.
She's just a secondary wife. You just have to feed her at home,
no one's forcing you to treat her with mutual feelings.
Yes.
If you really don't like Qingying,
I've already found someone. Gao, who's taking care of you, is caring and virtuous.
I also know that you like her.
After a few years, I will ask your imperial father to have her marry you as your secondary wife as well.
Yes. Mother is planning for me
so I know to look at everything long-term. I will not disappoint you.
That's good then.
Greetings to Niang Niang.
Please rise Su Gong Gong.
Emperor is asking Niang Niang to go to Palace of Resting Soul.
I will go immediately.
Greetings to the Emperor and the Empress.
What happened?