Episode 47
Your Highness, please pay your tributes.
Royal Concubine Jing and Royal Concubine Qi, please pay your tributes.
Lady An and Lady Qi, please pay your tributes
Lady Hui and Lady Xin, please pay your tributes.
How audacious! Who is it hiding here so suspiciously?
This lowly wife greets you Your Highness Empress and Young Mistresses.
Amitabah, and here I was being worried who it was.
It was only Lady Wan.
Oh wait, you're no longer Lady Wan. How does one address you now?
This lowly is known as Mo Chou of the Gan Luo Temple.
Mo Chou (one who has no worries) is true.
But how come you address yourself as lowly wife ("I" used by ladies) and not this lowly one ("I" used by nuns)
So you rather yourself to be a lowly wife
than being in your place and offering your prays to buddha.
Also Mo Chou is someone in training as her hair isn't shaved yet so she's not truly a nun yet.
Well thank you for the concern, you are treating Mo Chou so good.
My sister was so careless, and she stepped on Mo Chou's hand, are you okay?
No problem no problem
Mo Chou does heavy works all the time, stepped on hand is a piece of cake to her.
heavy works?
Yes
She was not born from the rich after all, and she has to cut firewood, wash and starch, grazing and so on.
Has no different to the other girls in the temple.
Mo Chow used to belong to palace, being like it, it's so grievance.
It should, entering to temple means to get everything behind.
Buddhism said everyone is equal
Lady Mo Chou should do the same
Your are right
Queen Godness
Mo Chou is taken out for practice by Emperor after all
and she is the princes bio-mother as well
You know she is weak by just looking at her.
But in the temple
Even ask her to do all kinds of heavy works, it is too harsh on her.
the queen has already said
You need to leave everything behind, princess is princess, Mo chow is Mo chow
Emperor has said princess has Lady Jing as her mother.
You had better not go against the Emperor's will.
The floor is so cold, just get up already.
Lady Hui, Come here. That position belongs to Mo Chow.
Go quickly. It's not a problem.
Everyone has their own position, is like human being and ghost.
You two can not standing together right there.
Queen Goddess Although Mo Chow left palace
She doesn't deserve all these.
Buddhist takes calm as an important thing
Lady Hui, you are so impatient today
You can't go and visit Buddhist
Kneel here and think it through yourself
This way please
Be careful
Queen goddess should be tired today, please have a good rest.
You are usually smart, don't you see goddess today
is very happy?
I am not happy, I am please
I am please Mo Chow is no longer a threat to us
I would not believe it unit I saw it
This is way better than letting her die
It is said that living is worse than die
I told the owner in temple before I left today, told her not to take care of Mo Chow, regardless of her live or die.
Now that Mo Chow is not a threat, but
The king hasn't let her go completely.
You two need to work harder
go get his heart
Yes Queen Goddess
Empress, are you feeling better?
This little old sickness, I've got use to it
You are caught so serious, I will go get you sth
Why is you smelling so heavy on herbs today?
I am almost dizzy (by smelling it)
I've kneelled for a long time so..
Kneeling is kneeling
Queen Goddess is using you as an example for others.
It was my wrong doing, I deserve it
But Mo Chow is having a hard time now, I am just worry about her.
If you want to say something say it yourself
I hope you think of Mo Chow as princess's bio-mother
help her through this hardship
Why are you treating her so well?
Yes We are living so close
I heard of that as well
It's not sth that matters
I am just feel bad about the princess, she was born without her bio-mother by her side.
Princess is even more poor than Mo chow
Everything should have a space
Ok. I will send people to see
I will not let Mo chow die
Thank you so much, I can not wish more
Think of yourself more instead of others
everyone is fighting for the King's love, how long hasn't you seen the King?
When King is happy, he will think of me
I have another request
There is place left empty, can I have it?
You are planing to have it for her?
Ever since she is left, every one is saying there is bad luck over there.
I am living with Lady Jing now
Although it is convenient to take care of little princess
I think it is too narrow
I think it is better now to move the princess than she gets older
Please let me move over there
You need to think it well
If The king is still hating her
Once you get into that place, it has no difference as marginized.
When the King solve his problem it will become good
No one can tell
If you like it you can do it
Thank you
Jin
Long time no see, you become more pretty now
You are becoming better at talking, dislike!
You said you will be coming 5 days prior to the kid's birthday but didn't tell me the exact time
So I decided to come earlier, didn't expect you to be here already
I wanted to come here earlier
If we happened to meet,
then it will be a surprise
If we didn't schedule a time but still run into each other
It must be fate!
To tell the truth, I don't believed in fate in relationships
They use the word "fate" as an excuse to get close to each other
But they also use "no fate" as an excuse to distant away from each other
I always find your words fascinating...
It always gives me surprises
Thanks for your compliment
Maybe one day when I see an end to a relationship
I will also use "no fate" as an excuse to end the relationship
If you were to be at a good time like before, these words wouldn't mean much
But do you still not believe in fate even when you are Buddhist now?
Even though I believed in Buddhism, I still have my own faith
After the Emperor passed away, it has been a while since the last time I saw someone from the Palace
We have have special fate with each other, You Majesty
No only did we run into each other today,
I also have a jin (instrument) that used to belong to you
Really?
It is in fact in the temple right now
I remembered when I left the Palace,
I left both instruments behind
Since the Emperor passed away,
It would be meaningless for me to keep the instrument
I never thought it would be passed on to you
Since I haven't seen the instruments for years,
If you will, can I take a look at it?
i would,
but few days ago I broke the strings...
If you don't mind,
Can I take a look at it? I might be able to fix it
Sure
If it really can't be fixed, I would regret not being able to hear the jin's sound again
Then next time when you come,
Please bring the jin with you
I really enjoy talking to you
Thanks for your invitation!
Go ahead