~ Episode 14 ~
What's wrong with you?
On such a good day, why are you ruining the mood?
I'm not very sad over anything.
But I saw Precious Smile dance Wild Goose Fly
it recalled my sadness, so I lost my deportment
You were not in the mansion when Empress of Origin dance the Wild Goose Fly
Where did your sadness come from
I read some poetry during my spare time
and read the Poem of Eastern Building that was written by Princess of Plum
it touched my heart
Wild Goose Fly originate from Princess of Plum, she danced it when she's favoured
while Poem of Eastern Building wrote when she was restricted in Palace of Shang Yang
Today the Wild Goose Fly, reminded me of the poem
I feel so sorry for Princess of Plum
You never put your heart into books
why did you read them then?
I was silly
I heard that reading could cultivate myself.
I know I have no talent
if I don't educate myself
I will have no face to serve your majesty
You just said the poem touched your heart
Come and tell us.
Your love was deeply attached to meWe talked hert to heart sentimentally
You promised me your love will last as long as the world exists
but the beatiful and angry one
robbed my favour and restrained me in the cold palace
The favour won't come again, even unclear in the dream
Everytime I read this
I know Princess of Plum's lovesickness deeply
My King, this matter concerning lady Hua Fei
is the private matter of your family.
I dare not intervene.
It's just that Lady Hua Fei served the King for many years.
And she hasn't made any major mistakes.
So if she ever serve you wrong
Please be kind as she has been with you for a long time and
Forgive the lady.
Hua Fei
I have really wronged you.
The place you live is too far away.
When I have free time, I will come visit you often.
Thank you my King.
This sister would like to ask you something.
That piece of paper
was kept hidden in your sister's sleeve the entire time right?
That is why the dance,
was set by my sister.
My older sister has a good heart.
Little sister, what are you talking about?
I don't understand what you mean.
My sister is very clever.
So of course you would know that without the Wild Goose Fly dance the poem will never be read
Princess Plum's love poem didn't win the king's heart back
Lady Hua Fei has touched the heart of the King.
So if Princess Plum is still alife
She would definately understand my dear old sister's well-intentioned act
Little sister, whatever you say
I your sister, isn't a good arguer
However, if my daring little sister is ever free, you should really take care of Precise's fetus
That is what the King really cares about.
Of course.
I spend so much time and thought into bring her down
And now I have to watch her coming back up so easily
How am I suppose to deal with it willingly
Actually, deep down in you heart, my sister, you know that
Concubine coming back up is well-expected
It's only a matter of time of when she will regain her power
No...I was just scared that our life won't be as easy and comfortable as this again
But as long as we have this one in my sister's tummy, we don't have to be afraid of anything.
So you shouldn't be angry
You should take good care of your baby instead
It's only one month old.
We don't even know if it's a girl or a boy.
Whether it's a girl or a boy, both are good.
It'd still be our lovely baby.
Baby, convince your mother to not be angry anymore.
You, always like to joke around.
You know... After what happened today, The queen is the one who is suppose to be getting all the headaches
And she isn't even in any hurry, so why should we?
You're right.
But when I saw you dance, I was so worried.
I know that you can dance.
When actually, whether you danced or not was still wrong.
What happened today is only due to my luck
But Precious Cao is vicious inside
Even if she hates you, it can't compare to how much the King loves you.
But you, always make the King so stressed.
If you showed off your dance skill earlier, they wouldn't set such a trap
Thanks to they don't know what I can and cannot do.
otherwise, they would know how to put me into the trap
Precious Smile
His majesty got some good poems
Please go to the Hall of Politics to appreciate
Then you better go quickly, don't let the King wait.
Then I'll go.
Su Gonggong
Greetings Lady Wan.
Some of the court men are still in there.
you will have to wait a while, young mistress
Yes.
Your majesty, now the imperial court is useing military forces to defend the Northwest
Princess of Glory's elder brother is in charged
Please think twise
Now the soldiers are needed, for the nation's sakeyour majesty should forgive Princess of Glory
to comfort the soldiers
I know. You may all leave.
Greetings Young Mistress
Young Mistress, this way please.
Your Majesty, Lady Wan is here
Greetings your majesty
Peace and prosperity to you
My head hurts really bad. Come here and help me massage it.
Yes.
Your Majesty is troubled
How do you know?
Although the hall is filled with Muo Li flowers,
i can still smelled the menthol oil
You always use menthol oil when you're troubled
You always know what I am thinking
Guess what I am troubled by
your majesty must be worrying about government and court issues.
correct
the royal harem is also part of my troubles
the empress has worked hard to manage and fix the big and small issues in the royal harem.
someone should help her out
what do you think?
Concubine Hua has always been helping the royal harem
she may be able to help the empress
Besides, that case was Pin of Beauty's fault
Princess of Glory may not involved
Pus, what the empress dowager does not really like
concubine hua is that she is so tactical and cruel sometimes
The punishment to her is enough now
This case
may be unfair to you
but don't worry, I will be on your side
Nothing is unfair to me
as long as it is for your majesty
It was strange
even the Prince Dun has come to plead for you
he's usually arrogant, has no respect to his majesty
he has the right to be arrogant
his birth mother, Precious Princess of Wenxi, is Empress Xiao Zhaoren's sister
and the Empress Dowage at presant was once the Empress Xiao Zhaoren's school maid
when the nine princes faught for the throne
The 8th, 9th and 14th prince who got along well with 1oth prince were all demoted
only himself is still a prince
How could he bear seeing his majesty got on the throne
So why does he help you
He is not helping me
he is following the current situation and do my brother a favor
General Nian?
Prince Dun 's status is hight
When the late emperor's alive, he has worked together with my brother and 14th
dealed with the Qinghai's case together
we can say they're friends
It doesn't matter. Whoever helps my lady is still good in the end.
As long as you can receive the love of the King.
Is everything ready?
Yes, everything is prepared.
The King loves it when the lady wears red.
Then quickly help your lady dress. Yes.
Don't make the King wait.
Niang Niang worked hard all day
It would be beneficial to rest now.
During these past few days, I've laughed so much, my mouth has become tired.
In these times, my lady must smile even when you don't wish to.
It must be tiring for my lady.
It's because the Queen must never show her tired state.
Then, I'd be seen as insufficient by others
Those who eye my position
If they don't try to strip me of my health and title, it'd be strange.
My lady's words are correct.
The way Princess of Glory looked so content today
I couldn't stand it.
What happens to her depends on the emperor
It's just that when I set my eyes on that child, Wen Yi.
I think of my Hong Hui at his first birthday.
If 1st prince were still alive...
If Hong Hui were still alive,
He'd probably be taller than the Third Brother.
He'd look more handsome.
And he'd definitely be smarter than the Third Brother by far.
That's right.
When he was two, he could already recognize characters.
The Third Brother can't compare at all.
Niangniang are still young
You can definitely have another prince
I'm already in my forties.
I'm beyond child-bearing age
As well, after sister's death,
His Majesty never treated me again the way he did before.
The state of my body, I know it myself. It can't happen again.
Although the King does not speak of it.
But in his heart, he still listens to my lady very well.
A woman can't even receive her husband's love.
If she only attains respect, what use is that?
You've spent all this time with me
How does His Majesty treat me
compared to how he treated Jiejie in the past?
Niang Niang, actually before Empress of Origin entered the estate,
He treated you very well.
No matter how well he treats me, it can never compare to how much better he treats sister.
Empress Dowager too
After all, I'm a illegitimate
unlike sister is legitimate
If Hong Hui were still alive,
he would be the eldest son of his majesty,and legitimate
How honourable he would be
When Hong Hui died,
The weather was just like this.
My head hurts so much.
My lady.
Has young mistress eaten well for the last couple days? Do you still feel like throwing up?
That's what's weird.
During these few days, I haven't wanted to vomit at all.
As well, my stomach aches for no reason.
You have had the medicine
so you are fine
As for the stomach pains and chills,
It's only been a month since you've been pregnant.
It's very normal. Do not worry.
If you say so, then I feel much at rest.
I thought that it's a time when I should be vomiting.
Young mistress's health is sturdy, how could you get morning sickness?
I think that my lady
will give birth to a very healthy son.
Then I'll believe you
Cai Yue. Yes.
Give the hawthorn cake from father to Doctor Liu.
Thank you very much.
I can tell right away that this hawthorn cake is from Qishun Store
Didn't Qishun stop making cakes two years ago?
Doctor Liu came to the travelling palace at the beginning of the year
How could you not know?
Uhhh...when I think of home, I always remember snacks from Qishun
so I always think the store's still there.
I misspoke, I hope young mistress forgives me
Seems like you miss home
If you like, I will have Caiyue wrap up more of them for you to bring back
I thank young mistress
- Fuling- Yes
- Escort Doctor Liu out- Yes
Doctor Liu, this way please
Humble servant thanks young mistress
Take a break, young mistress. Be careful not to strain your eyes.
It's almost done. Let me finish first.
Why the rush?
Precious Hui has only been pregnant for a month
It will be 8 more months before the baby can wear the undergarment you embroidered
I must finish embroidering this first
If Sister Mei sees it
and likes it, I will make some more.
Don't you know, children grow very quickly
They grow up in an instant
How could it work if I don't make more?
Look at you...as if you've had children before
When I was at home,
I often saw mother sewing this and that for the first wife's children.
So I know a little bit
Servant misspoke, and brought up sad memories for young mistress
Young mistress please punish me
Quickly get up
Why would I punish you?
I just don't know how mother is doing right now
Madam must feel proud that you've entered the palace
I am only a Promise without favor
His Majesty probably doesn't even remember who I am
No need for this dragon to fly
as long as it stays
Young mistress, bad news
What happened?
Mr. An is in trouble!
Young mistress!
Jiejie!
Jiejie help!
Lingrong, what happened?
Get up, speak calmly
Jiejie, my father has been imprisoned
How could that have happened?
I received news from home that Jiang Wen Qing
has been under orders to go to the Northwest
My father was also sent along with the troops
Who knew, they met enemy soldiers along the way
who robbed them of the army provisions.
Jiang Wenqing also escaped
with a good amount of silver.
His Majesty was furious and ordered Jiang Wenqing to be immediately captured
and imprisoned along with father.
Right now, it's uncertain whether he's alive or dead
I'm afraid that in a moment of anger,
His Majesty will take father's life.
Are you sure
that your father was really involved in this?
He couldn't be. Father is always overcautious
and only seeks self-preservation.
He would never ever be involved with Jiang Wenqing's affairs
Things have not been settled yet. Don't cry so much right now.
It's more important for us to think of a solution
Yes
I know that military intelligence is a serious matter
I'm afraid that things look grim for father
This has happened to your family
Of course we will plea with the Emperor for you
But on affairs of state...
it might not be our place to intervene.
True
No need to disturb the Emperor
Mei Jiejie can solve this matter
Me?
Because this happened in the jurisdiction of Ji Zhou
Mei Jiejie's father is one of the examiners in the case
Mei Jiejie, I'm begging you, please save my father
Let me think of a way
Let me think
I'm begging sister to write a letter to save my father
Alright, don't worry
But I must first see the Emperor to test his intentions
Thanks Jiejie! Lingrong is eternally grateful.
Lingrong, stop crying
Precious Hui
You are with child. How could you come out here?
Watch out for the sun
Is His Majesty inside?
He is
but Mr. Zhang Tingyu and Mr. Longkeduo are also inside.
Young mistress, you must wait a bit
What? Even Longkeduo is here?
Something happened to the military provisions that were en route to the northwest
It's a matter of military intelligence. His Majesty is absolutely furious right now.
Is Promise An's father involved in this?
That I don't know
I just know that His Majesty ordered
that Jiang Wenqing be immediately executed.
Then...what about the other people?
I don't know
What?
Did Precious come to plea for Promise An's father?
Yes, Promise An is devastated
I can't just sit by and watch
No no no
In my opinion, Precious best not get involved in this
Gong Gong, please elaborate
His Majesty hates when the inner palace meddles in political matters
In particular, this is a huge matter of military intelligence
dealing with Nian Gengyao's military situation in the northwest.
If you open your mouth,
aren't you making enemies with Princess of Glory?
But this isn't an issue of making enemies
If I can save someone's life,
I can't just stand by and watch.
You can only watch
Just think, whether the Emperor finds out or not,
if you write home, Mr. Shen will be more lenient in his sentencing.
But if someone gets a hold of this and blows it out of proportion,
the Emperor will be furious!
Then what about your father's future prospects?
But...if Promise An's father is really innocent...
If he's really innocent, he will be vindicated
Didn't you see the big temper His Majesty threw over this just now?
If you go you'll be in trouble
Besides, you are now pregnant with His Majesty's child
You will soon assist in managing the six palaces
You can't afford to tread through these troubled waters
Besides, once you open your mouth, and Princess of Glory finds out,
Promise An's father will definitely die.
Then...
Gong Gong, please don't tell His Majesty I came
Yes
It's hot outside. Young mistress, hurry and go back.
Don't be sad
We will think of other ways
What else is there?
If Mei Jiejie can't save him,
then others are in even less of a position to help.
Mei Jiejie has good reason
If she does this, Princess of Glory will want your father dead even more
Then what should I do?
Today His Majesty already ordered to have Jiang Wenqing executed
Tomorrow it will probably be my father
Let's go beg the Empress
Empress?
Respects to young mistresses
Please notify the Empress that we wish to see her
Your timing is unfortunate
Niang Niang went out
I remember that Niang Niang usually rises from her nap at this time
Niang Niang went to see the Emperor
Young mistresses rushed here on such a hot summer day
It must be for the same thing
The Empress hears news so quickly
She knew Jiejie and I would come beg her
so she went to see His Majesty first?
I don't know when she will be back
Why don't you wait for her in the side hall?
The tea has already been prepared
Thanks for your troubles, Auntie Jian Qiu
Please
The empress went to Qingzhen
Why would she go there in the middle of the day?
I heard that Empress went to plea for Promise An's father, An Bihuai
You mean to say, An Bihaui's failure to deliver the military provisions?
Niang Niang's older brother General Nian is hard at work leading the war campaign
Meanwhile they can't even handle such a trivial task behind the front line
No wonder His Majesty is upset
But...Empress just paid him a visit
Perhaps Niang Niang should also make a trip?
Promise An is very close with Precious Smile and Precious Virtue?
Like sisters
There're no sisters in the harem
just the weak depends on the strong
silly follows the smart
Sisters today, enemies tomorrow
Smile on the face, knife in the back
Niang Niang is exactly right
Do you think it's better to govern the inner palace amicably
or with an iron fist?
I'm stupid...I really don't know these things.
Where there are many women, there will be many disputes
schemes, tears, acting, troubles
Peaceful waters on the surface
hide a turbulent undercurrent.
If I were in charge,
I would govern with an iron fist and iron heart!
who dare regardless of the rules under strict laws
Niang Niang is right
Empress returns
Respects to Empress
Everyone rise
Yes
Sit
Thanks Empress
I've already tried my hardest to plea for Promise An's father, but there's nothing I can do
His Majesty only said this an official matter, and nothing else
Since Niang Niang puts it that way, then there's nothing to be done
Under the current circumstances, it will depend on (1) your father's luck,
and (2) if there's still any room for discussion with His Majesty.
Lingrong thanks Empress for your care and concern
I will always remember your favor
Get up
Yes
Everyone has setbacks at some point in life
As the head of the inner palace
and as your sister in serving His Majesty,
I should help you whenever I can.
Whether this matter works out favorably or not,
we are endlessly grateful
for Empress's words.
Since I've entered the inner palace,
I've seen so many arbitrary things that Princess of Glory has done
but Empress is so kind,
I...
Precious Smile, you've always been understanding
You should console Promise An on this matter, understand?
Niangniang's concern, I also appreciate
How can I repay Empress's kindness?
Conflicts are frequent in the inner palace
My body is weak, so I'm really tired of dealing with it
Precious Smile are considerate, if you know what I want
you must be able to share my burden
It's so hot today, the ashes in the censer burn up again
What should I do?
We concubines in the Inner Palace
all depend Empress' kindness
It's my pleasure
to share your burden
as the saying goes, wise man work with his mind
I'm lowly, I can just repay Empress with my physical power
Good, you haven't disappointed my hopes
The moon is bright, while the stars are sparsea magpie fly to the south
it circled the tree for many times, and finally find a branch to rest (depend on)
Actually, in this inner palace, there has always been only one tree
but many flowers are misleading
As long as you can distinguish which is a tree, which is a flower
Many thanks for Empress's advice. I will remember closely.
The Empress pleaing for An Bihuai before His Majesty...
Princess of Glory already knows about it.
At this moment, no one cares about the Empress more than Princess of Glory
Take a guess, what is Princess of Glory doing right now?
She must be doing the exact opposite of what Empress is doing,
asking His Majesty to punish An Bihuai harshly.
Then I should thank her
What does young mistress mean by that?
Thank her for putting in so much effort
That way, it spares me much worry
When did you come? I didn't realize you were here.
Dear 4th was sleeping, I couldn't bear to disturb you
busy in public affairs
I read reports for a whole day
Those old men have nothing better to do than bother me with reports. Really annoying.
As imperial officials, it's their duty
Dear 4th need not berate them
Besides, beauties come at times
So Romatic, where is your toil from
It must be the woman's sleeve smells sweet,so poetic
It smells so good.
You are gliber, I connived you too much
Princess of Glory understands you better than I do
I only know how to make you upset
How do you know that Lady Hua Fei came?
The smell on the fan called Tian Gong Qiao
This kind of rouge smells overwhelmingly sweet, and is hard to make
Not many people in the palace use it.
Empress doesn't like fragrances
I'm sure that when Princess of Glory comes to see Your Majesty,
she dresses up with the utmost attention and detail,
even scenting her fan with rouge fragrance.
You have a keen sense of observation
Dear 4th, am I right?
I can't hide anything from you
Right after the Empress left, Princess of Glory came.
Both came for the same person.
For Promise An's father,
An Bihuai?
Exactly.
Then what about you? What did you come here for?
Let Huan Huan venture a guess
The Empress is kind and generous
She must be pleaing for Promise An's father
Princess of Glory is outspoken and tenacious
She must want Dear 4th to strictly enforce the law
and not give into personal feelings.
Then what about you?
The inner palace must not interfere in politics, Huan Huan knows deeply in my heart
It's just that it's strange.
The Empress and Princess of Glory
both met with you regarding An Bihuai.
Is it really because they have opposing views...
Or is this matter
itself deserves careful reconsideration?
What reconsideration?
When I was young, I read many history books
I know that when wise Emperors punished the officials
they usually punished the head official and forgave the retinues, both strict and kind
made others revere and appreciate
your majesty always admire the wise emperors of Tang ang Song dynasty
your majesty are also a wise and kind emperor
I am ignorant
but I think there are wars outside and imprisonment inside
distinguish them clearly so that the nation will be peaceful
I always thought you only read history books intensely
I didn't think you were also fluent in national policy
none of your words interfered policy but each of them pointed it out through history
there is someone like you
as if I find out a treasure
I will have someone reexamine An Bihuai's case. I won't let anyone suffer false accusations.
As a woman
I was too bold in front of your majesty
I beg Your Majesty to not take offense
The inner palace does not interfere in politics
When we are together alone,
I am your husband.
A wife speaking her mind freely before her husband, about history and politics,
what's wrong with that?
I don't dare.
Precious Smile Zhen Shi dares not, but Zhen Huan may as well
Yes, I dare not break the rules in front of your majesty
but I will tell everything to my dear 4th
Servant congratulates young mistress
Auntie is too polite. What is it?
This morning, His Majesty ordered Ji Zhou official Shen Zishan
to reexamine Sir An's case.
Sir An has hope
Really?
Of course.
She went to the King herself to plead.
Of course, the King will not embarrass her and give her face.
Thank you so much to the Queen.
Don't, young mistress. Wait until Sir An is completely out of the woods.
Please go yourself and thank my lady.
I think Precious Smile also went to plea with His Majesty yesterday
Precious Smile and Precious Virtue
are really close sisters with you.
Sister Zhen indeed treats me sincerely
But Sister Mei...
Precious Shen has already written to Sir Shen
asking him to look after this matter.
Who wouldn't do a favor if it goes with the current?
Actually, with Empress pleaing for leniency,
His Majesty would definitely forgive Sir An.
But if Precious Shen was willing to write Sir Shen earlier,
you wouldn't have to be so worried.
I still have other matters to attend to. I'll leave first.
Auntie go well
Bao Juan!
Quickly find me some valuable things
Throughout this whole ordeal,
the family must have spent
a good deal of money to save father.
If I don't help them financially,
mother must be having a hard time at home.
Mother's eyes are not good, and she's constantly bullied by the other wives
If Concubine Xiao didn't protect her,
Then I wouldn't know what I'd do.
Fortunately, Precious Smile has given you quite a few gifts
Young mistress can pick some good ones to send back home
So what if they're expensive goods.
I finally know that
No one's words can have as much use as the Queen's.
But of course. Other than the Empress Dowager,
the Empress is the most powerful woman in the palace.
Through this experience,
I know that nothing and no one can be relied on.
Mei Jiejie normally calls me sister,
but when I need her help, she avoids me.
I believe that
Precious Smile is sincere towards young mistress.
Who treats me well, I know well inside my heart.
I believe that it's better to rely on oneself than on others.
If young mistress wants to make master and madam proud,
it's better to win favor yourself, and hold your head high.
That's more satisfying
But I don't have that ability.
And I don't have that chance.
But my lady, you have intentions. With intentions comes good opportunities.
Young mistress fear the heat, but why don't you fan young mistress inside?
The King is inside. I don't dare stay there.
These noisy cicadas are keeping young mistress from sleeping well
I came out here to chase them away!
What's the use in only getting rid of these? There are plenty more outside in the garden.
It will only be quiet if they're all gone
Eh, you're not staying with me?
Young mistress asked me to pick some lilies. She wants to see them after her nap.
I'm going to put them in a vase
I'm so sorry. I did not know the King was here.
It really was unintentional
Young mistress, Huanbi didn't do it on purpose
You're that Huanbi who likes to wear green?
Yes I am. The King has good memory.
Put your things down. You may go.
Yes.
Why would you put the flower in the bowl?
I reply to the King, my thoughts are that if the flowers are floating instead of stuck in the vase
they would look better.
You are pretty, and also meticulous
Thank you my King.
Of course, it's someone you've picked out.
Thank you for watching!
Subtitles brought to you by The Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki