Episode 48
Did Ah-Jing piss you off
He used to be straightforward, so I won't be mad at him
I am so happy for you
I knew that you wouId say so
Protector Pei's famiIy is renowned
AIthough he has no reaI power
But he educated his famiIy weII
His daughter must be outstanding
Moreover, the Empress Dowager Iiks her
Jing-Xian
Her name teIIs us that she is a tender girI
CongratuIations
Are you sincerely congratulating me?
Of course
I'II do it
No matter what
I just want you to know that
I don't Iike Meng Jing-Xian at aII
No matter how good she is
I don't Iike her
The Empress Dowager Iikes her
You are at the age to get married too
The Empress Dowager doesn't know about it
But you do
Even if you don't Iike her
The empress dowager wiII choose another girI for you
Are you going to reject everyone of them?
The person that you Iike
Might not Iike you back
I am not His Majesty
My marriage doesn't reIate to the country
The empress dowager won'tcompeI me to get married
I don't care if
The one I Iike Iikes me too
My beIief is that
Sincerity matters Sincerity matters
Perhaps it reaIIy matters, but I wiII not be moved again
It is not convenient formen to come to GanIu TempIe
I don't want to create rumors too
It wouId be better for us to meet Iess
If you think that I offended you
It's better from now not to see you
You are not
It's another thing
You are from the royaI family
You shouId not come here so frequentIy
You are not fit in this place
Don't you want to see me?
We shouIdn't be seeing each other
PIease respect my decision
Since you say so
WeII
You have been
Coughing and
Not sIeeping weII since winter came
What shouId we do?
How?
I went to doctor Wen
The peopIe said
The sickness of empressdowager has reIapsed
Doctor Wen is taking care of her now
He is not aIIowed to Ieave the paIace
Oh
The empress dowager'sheaIth is more important
It is normaI for doctorWen to take care of her
Fang-Ruo can come to protect us
OnIy when the empress dowager is heaIthy
The medicines don't have effects
LuckiIy Ah-Jing sent us
Some nutritive bird nest
Finish them first
I wiII eat after I finish writing
I am not so weak
It is not severe
It is
You keep coughing
Yet Jing-Bai keeps asking you to wash the cIothes
I think you are exhausted
PIease don't taIk so much
There are many
Rumors about your sickness
Some peopIe even say that youare infected by tubercuIosis
Who is the one
I think Mistress is tortured by them
GanIu TempIe shouIdn't havea carrier of tubercuIosis
Yes
No one wouId be dare to stay here
We can't Iet
The reputation of our tempIe be ruined by her
Did any doctor say that
She is infected by tubercuIosis?
Aren't you afraid of being punished by God? By spreading the rumors
You!
Even if it is not tubercuIosis
It has not much differencefrom tubercuIosis
Yes
We can't toIerate
her anymore
Yes, we can't toIerate anymore
She is disgusting
It's my fauIt
I am unheaIthy, that Ibring troubIe to you
You shouId have Ieft
right
You shouIdn't be staying here
Yes Yes
Look! She is a thief!
The evidence is here
What
You must have evidence
Since when did I steal your things?
OnIy me and the abbess eatbird nest in GanIu TempIe
Where did your bird nest come from?
Yes, where did it come from
The imperiaI doctor hasn't been
Visiting you for some days. Don't you say that he gave it to you
The aunty from the paIace hasn't been coming for a few months too
You must have stoIen it from me and the abbess
The bird nest wouIdn'tappear automaticaIIy
Yes, just where did you get it from?
She goes to the room of master every time aftercoIIecting the firewood
She must have stoIen it from there
Yes, she must be the one
Since you eat bird nest everday
You shouId have started Iooking for it
When it was gone
Why are you seeking it now, and maIigning me as a thief
I don't want to speak nonsense with you
TeII me
Where did it come from?
If you can't give me ananswer
It means you stoIe it
Yes
Can't other peopIe have bird nest too?
Other peopIe
Other peopIe might have their famiIy to send them something
But Mo-Chou was chased away from the paIace
How couId she havesuch expensive bird nest
You can't deny it
I wiII go and find the abbess
What's going on Why are you aII being so noisy
Mo-Chou is a thiefShe stoIe our bird nest
Now she is infected by tubercuIosis
She shouIdn't stay at here
Yes
Enough
I saw how you AII tortured her
Did she offend you
She didn't
She came from the paIace
You know weII about the attitudeof the peopIe from the paIace
If we toIerate with her
Sooner or Iater
She wiII bring troubIes to us
Yes
Enough for you
Mo-Chou is pity
If you sympathize her
We wiII be pity
Yes
Why is your sickness so severe
That
What's going on with the tubercuIosis
No doctor says that this is tubercuIosis
I am just having a severe cough
Did you take the medicine
She did.
It is just the effects haven't shown
Mo-Chou has been coughing
Since two months ago
But it wasn't this severe
She wouId have recovered If this is not tubercuIosis
Yes
She is so thin. Her face turns red once she coughs
This must be tubercuIosis. We must not stay with her anymore
Yes. You are right
Mo-Chou
Now you are unheaIthy
And they don't want toget aIong weII with you
Why don't you move out first
Abbess
You know that
We don't have famiIy now
Where can we move to
As a abbess, you can't heIp us
Instead, you can onIy Iisten
To them
Shut up
You can't accuse the abbess
Carry on
What's wrong with you
Abbess Can you Iisten to me
We don't know If she is infected by tubercuIosis
But she is so weak now The sickness is so severe
Yet the weather is coId
Where can we move to
Abbess PIease
Let us stay for few days more
How can such patient
Stay together with us
Yes
We are not
Going to sIeep weII when she coughs
Yes She is a thief
If we toIerate with her She wiII steaI more things
We are moving out If Mo-Chou stays in GanIu TempIe
Yes We are moving out
Since they don't Iike us
I won't stay at here
But
I am not a thief
I didn't steaI this bird nest
Since they don't want me to be here
I wiII move
I
Go and cIean your things
Abbess Miss
Since she a thief We have to check Those things that she is bringing away
You!
It wiII be hard to check
If you bring anything out
Jing-Bai Stop saying
We wiII Ieave here
I'II heIp you to cIean your things And send you Iater
Mo-Chou
There are somerooms in Ling-Yun mountain
You wiII stay at there first
Take care
Thank you
Keep putting on act
Come and taIk to meif you have any opinion
Miss Miss
She is having a fever
What shouId we do now
The snow is heavy
It is too Iate for us togo to Ling-Yun mountain
We can't go back to GanIu TempIe
This pIace is so remote We can't find any doctor too
What shouId we do What pIace is here
Huan-Bi
There is a house in front
Go and get heIp from the peopIe at there
Hurry up
Miss
What shouId we do
Why hasn't Huan-Bi back yet
WiII that person come
I don't know
If we reaIIy have no choice And miss can't get heIp
We wiII stiII be with you
Lord
Why is her fever so severe
She is weak
Yet she was exposed in wind
I think she has caught coId
The route to escape here wiIIbe bIocked once it is winter Go back with me Before it is too Iate
Thank you
We need to cIean the room
In Ling-Yun moutain I wiII do it
Send her back When she is better
Thank you
You saved her
You don't know
You are a man
Man aIways hurts woman
I won't hurt her if I can save her
I wiII do my best
Trust me
I'II trust you once
Come
Did you find doctor Wen
I did
I said that you are not feeIing. We need doctor Wen's heIp
But the road is sIippery. It is not easy for him to come
He stiII has to come, anyway
I don't have much medicines here
She is not getting better
She won't recover if this carries on
I have used coId water towash her face for many times
But she is not getting better. What shouId I do
Hurry up
Huan-Bi
Go and have a rest first
I wiII take care of her
No one can take care of her
If you faII sick too
Ah-Jing
Bring Huan-Bito go have rest
Yes
Huan Bi Miss, let's go
Wang Ye, I live her with you
take care
You may leave
Yes
Lord Are you crazy
I must Iet her to recover
Even if I have to be crazy
Go and watch Don't utter nonsense
FinaIIy you are here
Greeting, Lord
Let me take a Iook
The road is sIippery PIeasepardon me for coming Iate
I have brought Some medicines to cure fever
PIease cook it
Yes Be quick
Yes
Is she better
LuckiIy it is not severe
It wouId be a probIem If it is as severe as you toId me
AIright
I wiII get a change first
I wiII come back in a whiIe
Lord Go and get a change Your Iips are turning purpIe
Don't mention it with anybody
Lord Is doctor Wen here
He is in there
Lord What's going on with you
Nothing I feII in the snow
Faster get in
Lord Why are you here
I am here Don't worry
I need your consuItation after this
I have been
Coughing recentIy
You have to have some rest Or
It wiII bring negativeimpacts to your body
Isn't everybody busy
I feeI bad if I am theonIy one who is free
Therefore I speciaIIy come and take a Iook
If I don't feeI weII,at Ieast you are here
Huan-Bi You haven't been sIeeping
Go and have rest
Yes Master Wen
So do you
No one can take care of miss If you faII sick too
Then
I wiII stay at here tonight
Doctor Wen and Huan-BiwiII sIeep at my house
We can take care of each other
Thank you
Miss
Do You feeI better
Where is here
You feII sick sevreIy
We brought you here
I am so happy
Doctor Wen is at there I'II ask him here to take a Iook at you
Master Wen Miss has woke up
She is better now
Then we
WiII go back now
You have to have more rest
I seIdom have visitors
It is the best pIace
ActuaIIy here is not reaIIy good
Can you find
Another pIace which is better than here
Moreover, you can't
Move here and there now
Where is Jin-Xi
I came here with you
Jin-Xi went toLing-Yun mountain
So we can take care of each other
Cai-LanCai-Ping
It is hard for
Huan-Bi aIone to take care of you
Cai-Lan anCai-Ping have been
Cooking the medicines for you
Now I wiII Iet them to come in And take care of you
The Iord doesn't seem to be feeIing weII
Look
He is exhausted
In addition, he caught coId
And is having a fever
He wiII be fine
After sweating
And eating the medicine
Thank you
Ah-Jing
Come and carry the Iord
It seems Iike
It seems Iike I must sIeep
Have a good rest
I'II bring him out
I am fine
Go and take a Iook at him
You care about him
He used to be kind
And he is the host now
He saved me
I am just doing what I shouId do
You wiII go
And have rest too
AIright
Take care
I go
and take a Iook at Lord
He used to be a heaIthy person
Catching coId isn't a big probIem to him
Having rest wiII do
Thank you
I have sent some peopIe to cIean the room. You may go and rest
Yes
Ah-Jing
Why are you here
Is the Iord fine
Yes
Ah-Jing
I have some questions
Do you mean
Cai-Lanan Cai-Ping
Didn't serve you weII?
They don't seem
To be normaI servants
How am I dare to order them
What
Aren't they the Servants
who sIeep with the Iord
You are so humorous
I am the onIy servantwho is cIose with the Iord
They are just normaI servant
The servants here Have no famiIy
They serve at hereafter being saved by Iord
Don't imagine things
You don't know But your misswiII definiteIy know that
Our Lord doesn't have concubines
Even if he does, he wiII onIy have a wife
Ah-Jing Is your Iord fine
Not reaIIy
He is not having appetite recentIy
And he is thinner
Why is him getting sick
You aII may Ieave first
I need to taIk to Ah-Jing
Yes
Our Lord is a fooI
He faIIs for someone who he shouIdn't faII for
He does what he shouIdn't do
You didn't recover
No matter how many toweI we put on you
Our Iord Iied in the Snow and
Hugged you after
His body is coId
After repeating this for many times
FinaIIy you have recovered
No one can stand With the coIdness
But
Rest assured that
He is not dare to be rude to you
You were not undressed on that day
It was not the first time our Iord does stupid thing
Since the time he saved you
I knew that
He was into you
Why are you saying
this to me
I don't know Why did our Lord do such things
But I know that He reaIIy racked his brain
I see
Now he has faIIen sick
WiII you visit him
I am his guest
Of course I wiII
Even if you didn't mention it
You might not know aboutit if I don't mention it
We have many siIIy peopIe here
Some peopIe are happy for nothing. Some peopIe didn't say anything because of siIIiness
Our Iord wiII definiteIy teII you about it
In the end, I have to mention it with you
Then
Go with me to visit your Iord
Did the consort visit him
She can't Ieave that pIace forever
We are hiding this from her
Fine
Don't let his wife worry
You are here
Are you feeIing better
I am standing in front of you know
What do you think about it
How Iong have you been here
About two hours
I didn't wake you up asyou were sIeeping soundIy
Do you want to drink some water Yun-Li
What did you caII me as
Zhen-Huan
Am I dreaming
Drink some water first
Lord His Majesty and consort Jing is here
Why is His Majesty here
I
You wiII meet them if you go out
I have a paper screen there
Go an hide yourseIf behind of it
His Majesty is here
I have no one to chat with me
When you are not in the paIace
Greeting, Your Majesty
Don't stand on theceremony since you feII sick
Greeting, Iord
Why are you And consort Jing
Here today
The snow has meIted
It is boring to stay in the paIace
I passed by here
When I was having a waIk
I heard that you feII sick
So it is reaI
Yes I heard that you have faIIen sick
I speciaIIy come to visit you
Meng-Yue is here too
AIright 17th uncIe got sick
Don't fooI around with him
This girI is so smart
She knows that you are sick
So she doesn't Iet you to hug her
She is as smart as her mother is
17th brother
I am so bored
That I don't have
Someone to taIk to
When you are
not in the paIace
If she is stiII here
I heard you singing
Together with the your
wife when I was young
After that,
onIy Zhen-Huan
can have nice chat with me
It is too pity that she is too stubborn
Zhen-HuanZhen-Huan
Do you know who is she
I heard that your pIace
is a good pIace
It is true
Do come here aIways if you Iike it
It is hard to Ieave the paIace
Many officers are Iooking at me
AIthough it is good here
But it doesn't have a femaIe master
You no Ionger are young
It is the time for you to get married
We wiII decide it Iater
I wiII definiteIy make her the owner of this pIace
If I Iike her
I wiII Iove her forever
It is good that you know
I wiII pick and reserve a good girI
From the renowned famiIy if you want
You must be kidding me
It's Iate now
I have to go back
Take care
Yes
No need
Take care of yourseIf
Goodbye
He has Ieft
AIthough brother doesn't want to admit it
But you are Meng-Yue's mother
No one can change this fact
It is good that Meng-Yue
doesn't know about it
It is a shame for her to have a mother Iike me
Nonsense
That is her biggest proud to have
A mother Iike you
Lord
Zhen-Huan
Why are youcaIIing me Iike this
I misbehaved just now
PIease forgive me
Just caII me Iike how you caIIed me
Is it because of my brother
His Majesty's coming
wakes me up
I was muddIeheaded
That I offended you
His Majesty has never been here
I don't know why he was here
Perhaps he happened to pass by here
But everything
Is unpredictabIe
But you didn't say so just now
We have been disturbing you for many days
The snow has meIted
We wiII Ieave on tomorrow
Go to the room on Ling-Yun mountain
Thank you
for taking care of us
Take your medicine
Miss is getting better now
How about the Iord
He wiII be fine soon
Autumn is coming soon
Everything wiII be fine
Today is the 3rd day of March
Let's go and visit the consort
She must be happy
We haven't been seeing her We shouId go now
Today's weather is good
You rareIy wiII tocome out and have a waIk
I haven't been visiting you for some times
It's my fauIt
Greeting, consort
I wouId Iike to
Listen to some music
I have fixed the broken zzither
You may try on it
I happen to bring aIong my fIute
I can pIay the music together with her
I heard that your skiII is good
Can we pIay the music together
The previous owner of the zither is here
How am I dare to exaggerate about my skiII
I never pIayed music together with you
I am afraid
if I can't foIIow your speed
I never touch this zither
Since the previous emperor died
PIease fuIfiII My wish
I reaIIy
hope to Iisten to
The music pIayed by
This zither and fIute again, When I am stiII aIive
Since you are saying so
I wiII just do it
What shouId I pIay
EndIess Iove
Both of you know each other weII
We are thinking of the same song
Because of the name of the zither
AIthough I am not educated
But I know this poem
We wiII pIay this
EndIess Iove
It hurts
The sunset is coming
She stiII can't faII asIeep
She is thinking of
Her beIoved
HopefuIIy her beIoved who
went to the battIefieId
Can know that she misses him badIy
She reaIIy misses him so much
She used to be optimistic
But she keeps crying now
He can stand in front of the mirror
and Iook at her when he is back
I haven't been
Listening to the music pIayed by
The zither and fIute
It reaIIy has the
FeeIing between me andthe previous emperor
You are right
Our zither and FIute not onIy Need good skiIIs
The pIayers
have to know
each other weIl
Then onIy they
can bring the atmosphere out
If not
there wiII be boring feeIing
It is just
A coincidence
We don't reaIIy know weII about each other
It wouId be funny
To say that we Iove each other
I was too excited
PIease forgive me
There was onIy music in the past
Now your voice Has made it perfect
The music
onIy can make us feeI the atmosphere
Singing the Iyrics
WiII be more meaningfuI
To consort
being honest
WouId be better than trying to hide your feeIing
We can
be bosom friends