Subbed by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team@Viki
Episode 40
Look.
These are Yun-Li's indictments that were drafted
by the imperial ministers.
There are a total of eight accusations.
Contempt towards the king, desertion of the late emperor,
Cronyism, disordered affairs of state,
impeding anothers voice, beating up the minister,
ill-intentioned, abuse of martial arts.
All the indictments lead to the death penalty.
All of it is the truth. He isn't innocent.
Does Your Majesty really want to sentence him to death?
Now matter how, I have to forgive his sins.
I can forgive him because of
him killing his own brothers.
He is not worth it.
On account that Dun Qinwang has merits on the battlefield, and contributed for so many years,
and him being my brother,
killing him will upset the soul of the previous Emperor.
I cannot bear to kill him so I need to  spare him the death penalty.
His title is to be removed...
and he will be demoted to a commoner.
He is to spend the rest of his days under arrest in Zhong Ren Fu.
No visitors will be allowed.
Then what about his wife, daughter, and son?
They will be demoted to commoners too.
But I have allowed them
to stay in Lord Dun's old residence.
Empres Dowager agreed with me.
Since Yun-Li has been punished,
his followers must be dealed with next.
This is the most important now.
One of my ministers said,
in order to avoid another upheaval
we must annihilate Du Family
as a warning to others.
What do you think Your Majesty?
It is somehow reasonable.
Your Majesty, the greeting memorial from the Northwest has arrived.
Please look over it, Your Majesty.
Nian Genghyao's is acting fast.
Lord Dun's case has just happened,
I don't know what could Nian Gengyao's memorial contain...
... I am afraid his intention is to test Your Majesty.
It's a congratulatory letter
about the sky phenomenon.
I'm too lazy to read. You read, I'll listen.
Your Majesty, I don't dare to read.
Why? Let me see.
Your Majesty, you shouldn't look over the words of regicide.
Bring it over.
The four words "Chao Gan Xi Ti",
originally praise me for working hard on government affairs.
Except in illegible handwriting in Nian Gengyao's letter
He has written the four words as "Xi Yang Chao Gan"
It means the end of a Dynasty.
This might have been because of  General Nian's inadvertent mistake.
Nian Gengyao is not a careless person.
He doesnt wish to praise me with the words
"Chao Gan Xi Ti"
That being the case,
with Nian Gengyao's merit at Qinghai,
I am still considering whether I want to approve.
For the most recent cases,
I have reprimanded Nian Gengyao
for his unsuitable speech.
But he did not mend his ways,
but he counted on his merits
and even used disrepesctful words.
This mistake is definitely deliberate.
Don't get angry, Your Majesty.
Why don't we make note of those disrepectful words,
and send them back to General Nian
and let him explain to your majesty.
This is obviously in black and white. What else should he explain?
Your Majesty, just let him explain..
We should give him the chance to explain
before we judge him.
Su Pei-Sheng
Your Majesty.
Send it back to the Northwest as it was to Nian Gengyao's hands..
Don't make any mistakes.
Yes.
Deliver an imperial order- dismiss Nian Genyao's relative-
Hu Qi-Heng, the grand coordinator in Gansu province.
Transfer the Temporary Sichuan Prefect, Na Tai back to Beijing.
Your servant will handle this immediately.
Zhou Ning-Hai, make your words clear.
Imperial Consort.
General Nian has sent a congratulatory letter to the Emperor about the astrology matter.
But maybe because General Nian is busy, he wrote the wrong words.
What are the words?
Great General wrote the "Chao Gan Xi Ti" as "Xi Yang Chao Gan"
Thats not too bad..
It is just a bit different..
But the Emperor is very angry.
How about the memorial?
The Emperor didnt approve it. He sent it back.
Imperial Consort.
These days are really not as good as the past..
Last time it was brothers retainers..
...now it is Lord Dun's case..
Although it is not directly related to my brother,
it all depends on the Emperors approval.
It seems like it is not approved.
I am afraid it is not good news.
Imperial Consort, you have to find a way to help Great General.
What else can I do?
We can only let brother give out his loyalty
and try to seek forgiveness from the Emperor.
Go and see
if the Emperor has time to meet me.
Yes.
Your servant will go immediately.
Report to Your Majesty.
Nian Gengyao relied on power and influence for domineering
recruited the people of the same view to take bribes,
abused military exploit, misappropriated public funds,
killed and persecuted the innocent civilians,
plotted rebellion matters is too numerous to record.
Your Majesty,
Nian Gengyao deceived monarch, disloyal and illegal.
Anybody has the right to put him to death.
Your Majesty, Nian Gengyao has failed to live up.
His loyalty to country, he should receive death penalty.
But he has a high official position and military power.
He is far away at Northwest and has many partisans.
We cannot be hasty.
I am afraid we might force him to rebel with his military power.
Why don't we blame strictly and punish slowly?
Nian Gengyao didn't abide to the behavior of the minister.
He broke the law openly without fear.
If I don't punish him strictly,
how can I appease the people and regenerate the imperial regime?
How can I appease the people and revive the imperial regime?
Nian Gengyao's followers
are still together.
If they follow the old ways
and fail to live up to the loyalty of the country for self-benefits,
outwardly denoucing
but secretly encouraging,
they should be punished strictly
for the crimes agains the country.
Your Majesty is brilliant.
Greetings Your Majesty.
Get up.
Thank you Your Majesty.
This is Nian Gengyao's explanatory memorial.
You may read it.
Nian Gengyao recites his loyalty to the Emperor
over all those years.
Only, this is my presumption,
Nian Gengyao carefully calculated his merits.
He lists his merits to the Emperor only to gloat.
He is using his merits to intimidate the Emperor.
It is obvious.
In order to clear his name,
he even took the risk to indicate that his merit is greater than the Emperor.
I also think so.
He means
I can't bring peace and stability
to the country without him.
Nian Gengyao has gotten arrogant.
Your Majesty repeatedly tolerated him  but he only got more arrogant.
When punished minister, Yun-Li wanted to rebel
he contacted Nian Gengyao by sending letters.
Your Majesty just got one of the letters,
there must have been more previously.
Nian Gengyao withheld the information
and attracted Yun-Li to become his friend in order to cooperate with him.
Without Nian Gengyao's mistake,
I would've never believed that.
Nian Gengyao makes my blood freeze.
I have tolerated it for too long.
Now I no longer have to.
My order.
Dismiss Nian Gengyao's post as Sichuan's and Shaanxi's Governor
and demote him as Hangzhou's general.
Yue Zhong-Qi will concurrently be responsible for his post.
Zhang Ting-Yu,
draft an imperial decree according to my words.
Yes.
I heard that brother's explanatory memorial has been sent.
I don't know how it is.
His Majesty was always generous with Great General and Imperial Consort.
No matter how angry His Majesty is, it will be fine after His Majesty reprimand or punish him.
Don't be worry, Imperial Concubine.
These events happen constantly.
Although His Majesty dotes on you
and also treat me as usual,
his heart is still unstable.
After the replacement, Imperial Consort is uneasy everyday.
If it goes on like this, it will affect
Imperial Consort's health.
Imperial Consort, bad news..
Great General's post as Sichuan's and Shaanxi's Governor will be dismissed.
Imperial Consort.
Greetings Your Majesty.
Your Majesty seems to be in a good mood today.
Yes.
Lately I was too busy with political affairs
and had no mood to listen to your singing.
I, too, haven't seen Your Majesty for a long time now.
Haven't seen for a long time?
Do you have no energy to play Yueqin?
Yes.
Because I haven't seen Your Majesty for awhile now, my skills are rusty.
What happened to your hand?
Its nothing.
It is almost healed.
You are not allowed to hide something from me.
Sister Wan and I are as close as sisters,
A while go, Sister miscarriied.
Although she recovered, she is still weak.
I heard that taking human blood as medicine is the best for physical health.
So I cut my wrist
for my Sister.
It is an unreliable rumor. You're silly.
But Sister's body improved a lot,
didn't it?
That day, I sent Imperial Concubine Wan to Penglai Island.
You came to me and beg to follow.
At that time I knew that there is a strong bond between you two.
If you didn't follow her,
then she must've had it tough in those days.
I should share weal and woe with my sister.
In the future, I also hope to always accompany Your Majesty
and my sister around.
Stop the sedan chair.
Stop quickly.
My lady.
I wish Imperial Consort Hua auspicious. I wish Imperial Consort Zhi auspicious.
Is His Majesty here?
Lady An is accompanying him.
Move aside.
His Majesty gave orders that Imperial Concubine doesn't need to come greet or request to meet.
Why does His Majesty refuse to meet me?
It is His Majesty's orders. I don't dare to speculate.
Imperial Concubine. Imperial Concubine, think twice...
Imperial Consort. Imperial Consort
Imperial Consort...
Your Majesty.
My brother did not intend to confront Your Majesty's dignity.
The four words "Xi Yang Chao Gan" is an unintentional mistake.
I hope Your Majesty look at my brother's credit,
and forgive him, Your Majesty.
Imperial Consort..
the more you do things like this,
the more embarassing it will be for you.
I must kneel
until His Majesty is willing to meet with me.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty. Imperial Consort is begging outside.
Would you like to see her?
I knew she would come.
I don't want to see her so I summoned you.
But Imperial Consort Hua is begging miserably outside.
It has disturbed Your Majesty.
Su Pei-Sheng.
Your Majesty.
Go tell Imperial Consort Hua that if she wants me to be angry, then just keep crying.
Yes.
Your Majesty.
Sister,
you're being at leisure.
You've came.
Are you still blaming me?
If I did, I woud've let you freeze at Penglai Island
Why did I send You autumn clothes then? I am regretting it.
It's too late for that.
I have already worn them.
It was all my fault that day.
I shouldn't have doubt you.
That day I told you I have reasons for concealing it
As it was connected to state affairs, I was unable to tell you.
This caused our misunderstanding.
I do not know why
I said to you those things then,
Sister's tongue is sharper than her heart.
I always knew that.
I heard that Nian Gunyao has lost the favor.
Imperial Consort Hua's position is precarious.
Lady Zhi also moved out.
It's not enough for her precarious position
I am like you, sister.
We are both waiting for this building to tumble down.
We are not from her circle,
therefore have no information about her
It's time for us to use few people.
Imperial Consort Hua's brother was punishedfor his disrespect towards the Emperor.
Although I am aware
that you don't like Consort Hua's temper
we are all however sisters in the palace.
We have to comfort her at this time.
Yes, Imperial Consort.
Anyway
Although Imperial Consort Hua is to be pitied,
it was her brother's, Nian Gengyao's fault.
He was always dominant and arrogant.
he even dared to disagree with the Emperor.
If he mended his wrongdoings earlier,
he wouldn't have come to the situation, where all ministers are blaming him.
Please forgive me, Imperial Consort. I am guilty.
What happened to you suddenly?
I am aware of a matter but has concealed it until now.
Now I don't dare to conceal it anymore.
What is it? Say it.
A few years ago when I was in the Summer Palace, Imperial Consort Hua incited someone to
put tapioca into Princess Wen-Yi's chesnut soup to poison her
put the blame on Imperial Concubine Wan.
She failed to put the blame on Imperial Concubine Wan
so she incited Xiao Tang from the Imperial kitchen to be the scapegoat.
Since you knew this,
why did you hide the truth until now?
Originally, I didn't know about that.
I was hoodwinked by Imperial Consort Hua too.
I believed that Imperial Concubine Wan did it.
Until one day, I saw Imperial Consort Hua
incited Xiao Tang to be the scapegoat did I know.
But Imperial Consort Hua discovered me,
she threatened me
that if I spread this matter,
then she will deprive the custody of princess.
Poor little Wen-Yi.
She has to sustain to such a sin at such a young age.
I understand Lady's Cao's feelings.
What mother is not afraid that her child
is deprived of them.
That day, her poisoning incident,
Everyone doubted it.
But His Majesty refused to track down
In order to take account of consorts' dignity.
If that is the truth,
Consort Hua is really evil!
Although she isn't Wen Yi's biological mother,
-how could she do that to a child?- But Niangniang,
Xiao Tang has already been beaten to death.
The dead can't bear witness now!
That day, Consort Hua instigated two courtiers to say that they saw...
Imperial Concubine Wan passing my residence.
Later on, Consort Duan bore witness to the fact that it was slander.
That was Imperial Consort Hua's real intention.
My poor Wen Yi. She is just an infant, but has to suffer so.
Imperial Concubine Wan,
this case is related to you.
What do you have to say?
That day
I
...really am innocent.
I know.Sit down.
Thank you Niang Niang.
Jiang Fu Hai
Your servant is here.
Ask Imperial Consort Hua to come here.
Yes.
Imperial Consort.
In regard of Great General,
there is a new decree.
What did Emperor say?
That... that...
Just say it.
There is nothing I can't stand.
Great General is to lose his title as a teacher,
and the title of the First Duke.
Also his two sons, Nian-Fu and Nian Xing, will loose their posts
It's brother's fault.
Why are Nian-Fu and Nian-Xin also involved?
Emperor must still be angry, otherwise he wouldn't refuse
to meet Imperial Consort.
Greetings, Imperial Consort.
What is it?
Empress wants to meet you.
Please go to the Palace of Great Benevolence.
Great. I also want to meet the Empress.
Let's go.
Please forgive me, my lady,
I have something I dare not disclosure.
Don't be afraid to speak.
Lady Chun
was murdered.
Didn't she drown?
As I know,
Lady Chun knew how to swim.
You speak
That day, Lady Chun picked up at kite by the lake.
I was playing with princess at rockery.
Who would've known
I will see Consort Hua ordering her eunuch, Zhong Ning-Hai
to press Lady Chun under water.
Lady Chun died after few moments of struggling.
Then Zhou Ning-Hai pushed Lady Chun into water
to make it look like she drowned.
What happened then?
I... I was to scared.
I wanted to leave as soon as possible.
But the princes started to cry.
The cry alarmed Consort Hua.
I was so scared I lost strength in hands and feet.
Imperial Consort Hua said
that if I tell others
she would kill me and the princess.
I was really scared.
Imperial Consort Hua dared to kill Lady Chun in the palace,
naturally she would also kill me and the princess
However, every night I see Lady Chun succumbing to her terrible fate.
I really can't stand it anymore.
Why did she kill Lady Chun?
I inquired some more after this incident.
Lady Chun was killed because she accidentally ran into Imperial Consort Hua
collecting bribes from the officials from outside, who were willing to get introduced
to General Nian as officers.
My lady, how can Consort Hua be that audacious?
No wonder she likes expensive things.
She spends the money like water.
I thought the money comes from  her mother's house or General Niang
I didn't expect her to actually collect bribes.
How much has she received?
I don't know it for sure...
but the total shouldn't be less than two hundred thousand.
His Majesty hates corrupt officials the most!
But the corruption has entered the palace!
Slut!
Consort Hua, what are you doing? I will not tolerate such wanton behavior in Palace of great Benevolence!
This is not the first time I act like this, although you barely tolerate it.
From now on it will only become worse.
Slut. Slut. How dare you betray me?!
Did you forget who gave you this position?
Weren't you willing to please me in any way?
I wasted all that effort on you!
Everybody heard what Consort Hua said herself!
Lady Cao was under her care previously,
thus there is no doubt in Lady Cao's words.
Jian Qiu, inform the Emperor I request Criminal Division
to investigate people from the Palace of Supporting Earth
Yes.
It's you.
Or the Empress.
Or maybe one of you here
who incited this slut to frame me!
No one wants to frame Imperial Consort.
What is done by night, appears at day.
You are all putting salt in my wounds.
You all want to go against me.
I don't think I will get anything from you in this condition.
Go back to your palace.
Don't act like a shrew.
No matter what, you are still emperor's concort.
If the Empress wants to ask anything,
just come to the Palace of Supporting Earth for answers.
I will be waiting for you.
I have tolerated her for so many years.
Finally, the happy day of her downfall came.
Interrogate all people from her palace.
Don't miss anyone.Especially Zhou Ning-Hai.
Ling Zhi, the sound you heard from outside
was it Zhou Ning-Hai suffering from torturing?
Imperial Consort, don't fret about it.
I's already two days and nights.
After Criminal Division' investigation, some serets will be revealed
They are able to get information even from the dead.
Imperial Consort, in case you...
I will not regret anything I have done.
I will not blame Zhou Ning-Hai if he betrays me to save himself
I will answer for all by myself.
I only hope that for the sake of our old relationship
Emperor will stop punishing my brother.
Has Huanyi perfume finished?
Hurry, refill it.
Yes.
Greetings, Imperial Consort.
Why did you come here again?
Empress knows you are concerned about your brother
So she asked me to inform you that...
My brother has been demoted.
The Emperor is still refusing to spare him?
As soon as the general returned to his provinces there were rumors saying
he accused Emperor of believing calumnies said by one of the ministries.
What was also said?
He even dared to utter that he wants to become the Emperor.
One should not believe in gossips.
My brother would never utter such rebelious words
I think all of you just want to put the blame on him.
Imperial Consort. It is people who gossip, but it is the person who does the deeds.
You can't blame others.
General arrived in Yizheng of Jiangsu and did nothing
than instigating others to give himthe position of Shaanxi Governor.
Emperor scolded him angrily for doing nothing and delaying.
Imperial Consort, there is a new decree from Emperor.
General is demoted to being a guard at Hangzhou gate.
Imperial Consort. This decree was just written out.
Emperor is really ruthless.
Emperor is really very ruthless.
Imperial Consort. Please wake up, Imperial Consort.
Your Majesty, this is Zhou Ning-Hai's confession.
This confession mentions the tapioca case mentioned by Lady Cao
Lady Chun's death, collecting bribes from officials,
inciting someone to put poisonin Consort Wan's medicine,
pushing Lady Hui into the water, framing Lady Hui for fake pregnacy
and giving the utensils previously usedby epidemic patient in the palace
to Lady Hui in order to infect her.
There are also events concerning other concubines.
Please have a look, Your Majesty.
That all was exposed by Zhou Ning-Hai?
Yes, Your Majesty. Zhou Ning-Hai fainted twice during interrogation.
He said he only knew of those and of nothing else.
There are more?
Imperial Consort Hua's sins are not enough?
Take it away.
Imperial Consort Hua's crimes are too many.
Your Majesty, how do You plan to dispose of Imperial Consort Hua?
Go and investigate all people that stayed in touch with Consort Hua.
All suspicious people are to be beaten to death.
Yes
Consort Hua has been doing bad deeds in the palace for many years.
Take away all her titles and demote her toDaying status (female attendand second rank)
You Majesty's generosity and tolerance towards the harem
In my opinion will help Lady Nian to turn over a new leaf
I thank Your Majesty in the name of Lady Nian.
But Lady Nian always askfor a meeting with you, Your Majesty
I think she would like to appeal
for Your Majesty benevolence towards her family.
I have nothing to say to her.
I remember the day when shefirst entered the palace.
She was bright and lively.
What made her turn out like that?
Lady Nian can only blame herself for her misfortune.
Which girls from contributor's families were picked  to enter the palace?
I have to refer my thanks to them.
I have chosen,
Censorate Censor, Guwalgiya E-Min's daughter,
as well as Guwalgiya Wen-Yuan and deputycommander of the Calvalry Camp, Li Bin's sister, Li Ying.
Please make a decision, Your Majesty.
- Li Bin serves under Han's flag?-Yes.
Guwalgiya E-Min serves under Manchu Army's yellow flag
The palace does not have many consorts
under Manchu Army's flag.
It's good to add one more.
Yes.
What status will Your Majesty grant her?
I have chosen words "Qi" and "Xiang".Both can be used as titles.
Just name her Lady Qi.
Palace entrance on 1st November.
Good.
How should we dispose of Lady Zhi, that was constantly with Lady Nian?
Just let her continue to be the maid, serving Lady Nian.
Lady Cao was also very close with Lady Niang.
Lady Cao
Since you knew what she did, why did you tell it only now?
Please forgive me, Your Majesty.I dared not to say anything.
She was too domineering.She hurt so many concubines.
Under her power, I could only remain silent.
to protect myself and the princess
Now that Wen-Yi grew up
I do not want her to share my fate of being compelled by other people
It doesn't matter what happens to me.But Weng-Yi is Your Majesty's daughter.
Only after Your Majesty struck them down,
I was able to tell everything to the Empress.
I shouldn't have been forced by lady Niang.
I am willing to receive any punishment.
But I beg Your Majesty not to blame for it our princess
Your Majesty, Lady Cao was forced.
Moreover, princess is still young.
Sister Cao suffered greatly  for the sake of the princess.
Your Majesty should reward her for that.
Lady Cao, exposing lady Niang's crimes,  rises your virtue.
Thus your title rises to Pin (imperial concubine),
titled Xiang.
Elevating ceremony on 1st November.
Thank You, Your Majesty.
How...?
Was she sentenced the death penalty?
Then relegation to Cold Palace?
Her titles have been revoked  and she was demoted to Dayin.
She is still allowed to stay in Palace of Supporting Earth.
What?
Only this?
Emperor has known all her crimes.
He does so due to the guilt he feels when recollecting their long relationship
What about Cao Qin Mo?
Seven truths, three lies.
She evaded all the bad things she has done.
She is just a helpless mother, used by the bad consort.
She gained sympathy and forgiveness.
Cao Qin Mo is much more smarter than Consort Hua.
Imperial Consort Hua, without Cao Qin Mo,
is like an eagle with broken wings.
Reckles, with no sense of direction,
only knowing how to snatch.
Unable to protest when being blamed.
Is your Majesty still worried  about Nian Gengyao's case?
I have deprived him of all his titles,
and made him guard of the gate.
If he would took the punishment humbly, I wouldn't have to kill him.
But Nian Gengyao dares to wear a golden jacket
gifted by me while on the guarding post!
He is so blatant and caused the rumor.
Letting everyone think I am an uncaring monarch.
Maybe Nian Gengyao is using this jacket to remind Your Majesty about his merits?
It is only that he thinks only of himself,forgetting Your Majesty's dignity.
It should remind me of his merits?
The ministers decided that he committed crime of regicide 5 times,
crime of deceit nine times,
crime of transgression 16,crime of insolence 13. In total 92 crimes
All his crimes should bring him death penalty.
Your Majesty, Lady Nian request meeting with Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
I refuse to see her.
But, Your Majesty, Lady Nian kowtowed 3 times already begging for an audience.
This time even her head is bruised.
Go and tell her, that it is useless even if she kowtows 300 times!
Your Majesty. Your Majesty!
Your Majesty. Your Majesty.
It doesn't matter if Your Majesty punishes me
but please spare my brother's life.
Think of it like keeping a horse or a dog
to keep you company, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, I beg you, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty. Your Majesty.
Find someone to cure her wounds.  Let her go back to her palace.
Yes.
I beg you, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
Because of the contribution in Qinghai, I am unable to give the severest punishment.
I am granting Nian Gengyao death by suicide,  Nian Fu - death by decapitation.
His sons above 15 are to be exiled.
Things are almost done.
I plan to promote your father as Chancery board of civil,
also for the position of  Left Censor in Censorate.
Thank you, Your majesty, for Your generosity,
but I am afraid my old father will be unable to undertake such difficult tasks.
Although your father is old,  but having him with me brings me comfort.
Just like you do.
Therefore the post is a reward for him,
but also for you.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Greetings, Madame.
Get up, girls.
Lady is so kind.
Young Master is waiting eagerly. Please go in quickly.
Its is so warm, like in springtime.
Young Master hates the cold, so the Emperor  ordered to bring in bronze heaters.
- Nice smell. What flower is it?- Its Camellia Pearl. We receive all of them, except the ones for the empress.
- Mother.- Greetings, Consort Wan.
If Consort will does not allow me this courtesy, others will think we are lacking in etiquette knowledge.
Get up, Mother. Sit, quickly.
Why mother didn't bring Yao - Yu this time?
Your father just got promoted,  so Yao-Yu is getting busy.
This morning she went to see the snow with girls from Officer Zhou's family and Cavalry Camp's family.
Mother, I think that
girls should not get involved in official matters.
Father was favored by the former dynasty.  We should remember that big tree attracts the wind.
Lately Nian Family disappeared
and our Zhen Family is still in emperor's high regard.
Father has to be careful in his behaviour and speech.
Family Nian's fate is a good lesson for us.
Your father often says  we need to be very careful
In fact, you know your father well.
In his leisurely time just like to buy antiques.
I think that there's nothing to worry about.
Then that's good.
Since Mother came today, I will  request something of You.
Imperial Consort may freely ask.
Huan-Bi reached the marriageable age.
Please ask father to choose a well-behaved and good-looking person from the courtyard if possible.
I would like to accept Huan-Bi as my sister,  and marry her off gloriously.
It is only natural that Imperial Consort  worries about Huan Bi
Thank You, Madame.
Mother, please take care  of this matter also for Liu-Zhi.
Huan Bi and Liu Zhu
both grew up with you.
It will be best to have double good news.