Episode 67
You betrayed me...
Royal mother,
Royal mother!
You promised.
That after the draft
what are you crying for? royal mother is still here
royal mother is certain to have something to say to Huangshang
we sisters are better waiting outside
where is the 14th Prince?
how come I haven't seen him?
Royal Mother, you are confused
I won't be here very long
can't you let Mother see the 14th Prince?
Royal mother, your son
grew up under the Xiaoyi Ren Empress
not like the 14th Prince brought up by you
your son didn't spend a lot of time with you
let me with you at this time
you can't let the 14th prince go, can you?
Mother knows your temperament
thus I hadn't mentioned it
also wouldn't dare to say it
but now, see it as Mother begging you
Let your little brother go.
the things in the court
Royal Mother don't need to worry
Emperor.
you imprisoned the members of the Royal families
cruel to your brothers
You can't even let go of your brother
you'll become not having anyone close to you
or separate from your own family member
It's not what your son wants to do,
they are the ones who forced me.
Aijia started as a low ranked Xiunu
and became Feipin one step after another
For myself,
for the emperor's position,
I had to go through great pains.
do I have to watch you two to hurt each other
in my older age?
Blood siblings hurting each other?
royal mother
you don't need to care about these trivial things
late Emperor is watching in heaven
you can't even let go of your blood younger brother
how did you get the crown at the time?
late Emperor is watching
how did I get the crown
royal mother got involved in everything
the thing between Royal Mother and Longkeduo
I forbear from speaking
and cared sincerely for Cunyuan and treat Yihiu well
I am filial to extreme
certain things
royal mother really shouldn't say
your son are grateful to Royal Mother
to deal with Longkeduo for me
so that your son didn't have to carry the Burdon of bad reputation
Royal mother.
Hurry and sleep to grow up well.
to grow up to stretch a bow
such song to amuse a child
you never
never sang to me
can you sing once for me?
Royal mother.
kneel
kowtou
mourning
how did come back from Shouhuang Palace?
I heard Royal Father is sad
Erzi is worried
come over
though your father is sad
that is not the most urgent
then Erzi won't worry
what I worry about is you
it is hot now
your father insists to hold the vigil
and tainted several times
you are the most reasonable prince in the eyes of Emperor
if not step in to keep the vigil in the front of Dowager for Huangshang now
how much gossips that would cause?
your son are foolish
Erzi thought only to visit Royal Father
you show your filial obedience right now
it's more urgent than whatever ginseng soup
these are the ideas of little girls
don't care too much of little things
Mother will go to Shouhuang Palace to watch over for you
you come over after putting down the ginseng soup
Royal Father
Son's greeting
everything is well in Shouhuang pa;ace
please take it at ease, and care about your health
Huangshang arrived
all rise
today is Yuanxiao Festival
Zhen came over after seeing the ministers and others
it is slippery in a snow day
the people serving Huangshang should be extremely careful
zhen saw there is no excessive decorations for the festival in the Harem
on my way here
very good. have seat
Dowager passed away not long ago
Chenqie thought it's better to have everything simple
counted it as filial
Empress is right
Xi Guifei
do Hongyan and Lingxi sleep well?
does Jinghe cry still?
everything is well at Princes' place
wet nurses take care of them in tetail
Huangshang want to see these three children everyday
and still worry
really show the feeling of kind father
not only Huangshang
Chenqie as mother
even see these children everyday
always have something to worry
yes, Xi Guifei worry like this
you look thin and palilid
that is a mother
has to think about everything carefully
Empress is the mother of the world
is the mother of all people
the things you have to worry
are certainly much more than that of Chenqie
Empress hasn't been a mother of her own child for long time
certainly don't remember how exhausting and tiring
to take care of young children
why suddenly did you pay respect?
congratulations to Huangshang
An Pin of Yanxi Palace
is pregnant for three months
really true?
doctor has checked
absolutely true
sit, sit,
Empress hid it completely
only revealed only after An Pin's condition is stable
have really expended much care and thought on this
An Pin is weak originally
her period was irregular
she didn't know until after three months
her father is still in prison
she didn't dare to let everyone know
Bengong also took preventive measure
in case some Feipin had a wrong idea
taking the path of Qi Fei some years ago
what Empress said is correct
Chenqie help to manage the Harem with the order from Emperor
I'll try my best to assist Empress
safe keep An Pin's royal baby
it couldn't better that
Xi Guifei can see the big picture
An Pin's health is fragile
and worries a lot because of her father
to safe keep the baby, to comfort An Pin
Chenqie ask to promote An Pin to position of Fei
there should be four at the position of Fei
yet
Chenqie thinks about the royal baby
if not promote her, gossips in the harem
would say that was caused by her father
that would further sadden An Pin
how could she safe keep the baby?
it's okay if Empress have made up mind
the title of An Pin was named based on her surname
she is pregnant, and has higher identity
should have the Interior Office figure out some titles to pick
that will make it more formal
let the Interior Office to do it. Xi Guifei have cared it
many positions of Fei are hanging
it is good that four corners of Fei positions are complete
Niangniang is not feeling well?
How could An Lingrong be pregnant?
didn't she use the muscle resting pills?
how could she be pregnant?
though the drug damage the body
it may not cause infertility
now Empress is spirited
Empress mentioned again
An Lingrong's father and safe keep the baby today
to protect royal decedent
I'm afraid the corruption of An Bihuai would be forgiven in no time
in case An Lingrong gives birth of a royal prince
there would be two princes in the hand of Empress
no matter who becomes the heir
our situation then
how come you came? have a seat
it's true that a person's spirit is up if he has a happy occasion
Huangshang looks well
that shows how happy Huangshang is
about Sister An's pregnancy
Ronger looked weak all the time
didn't expect her baby looks stable
that shows how close Huangshang feels about Sister An's child
who would be filial and good in future
it's good you came
Zhen was bored by reading myself
Chenqie thought
Huangshang is happy the thing of Sister An
probably ate too much at lunch
and felt a bit indigested at this time
so Chenqie brought with me a dessert
let Huangshang enjoy, is it good?
our hearts are connected
lotus leaf soup
pick fresh lotus leaves before sunrise
the water in the soup were dew collected from lotus leaves
in the last year
lotus osmanthus cake, sweet-scented
try it, Huangshang
in the past the lotus osmanthus cake in Meizhuang's palace
was the best
Huangshang think about the Sister
happy to taste
and cherish the memory of the Sister
what 's the matter?
reply to Huangshang
the Interior Office set the title for An Pin
please review it, Huangshang
you take a look for Zhen
the meanings of these words are all good
this word, Su,
Su means strong, virtue, restrain
Su also means appearance obedient, heart respectful
yet this word, Wen
suits Sister An's personality
Ronger is quiet and modest, a person of propriety
this Wen does suit her better
Wen could mean gentle, quiet, and polite
yet most time
describes someone that learned and talented
if choose this word
I'm afraid Sister An would be suspicious
then only the word, Li, lest
Li,
beautiful appearance,
means couple, pair
could also mean a beautiful couple love each other
it's exellent
what, Huangshang? is this word not good?
An Pin is Zhen's concubine
how could be called husband and wife?
if Zhen used this word to award her
gossips would start among ministers and officers
saying Zhen favors concubines too much
pass my order down
tell the Interior Office that none of the words are good
select others
why need to bother the Interior Office?
Huangshang point a word to be the title of the Sister
what could be better than that?
Zhen can't think of one in short time
what about you think one for Zhen?
how could Chenqie decide such a thing?
let's do this, you wirte, Zhen have a look
Zhen help you change if it doesn't suit
look, Huangshang, is it good?
Li
good at singing and dancing
temper is as obedient and gentle as Huangli bird
and Huangli is also a love bird
Nucai heard that Huangli has more decedants
like An Pin is pregnant
that means more children, more happiness
it sounds really good
go to send the royal order
have Empress choose a lucky date
master, what's happened today?
so happy?
An Pin niangniang got a good title
why not happy?
go to tell the Bird Office, prepare for 50 Huangli
we go to congratulate An Pin niangniang
what are you thinking? so focused
big happy occasion for Sister An today
brought me back to the day we entered the harem
Chenqie and Sister An, as well as Sister Mei
we came on the same day
have been like sisters
Zhen didn't treat her well when Meizhuang was here
thought about it, Zhen feel troubled
Chenqie position as Guifei now
Sister An is Li Fei now
though Sister Mei awarded Hui Fei
her posthumous title has not decided
Chenqie beg for the favor of Huangshang
award Sister Mei a posthumous glory
dead is died
living person couldn't do more for them
do what you suggest to express our rememberance
Empress is ill; you go take care this
then Chenqie dare to beg one more favor
Qi Fei was killed herself for fearing the crime she commited
she couldn't be awarded any title follow the tradition
but the Third Son is growing up
have to care his face
since award all passed away Pins and Feis posthumous titles
do it all together
Nian Gengyao and Longkeduo had been punished by law
Zhen don't want to have a reputation of abusing the harem
award Hua Guifei as Royal Guifei
as Zhen's rememberance
talk about award posthumously
virtuous Pin Fei
Chenqie position at high rank, often feel uneasy
in the harem
think about it, haven't awarded many titles at once for a long time
since Empress didn't mention it, Zhen didn't think about it
Chenqie think the same way
the ones passed away could put aside for a while
the sisters together in the harem
should get some promotions
harmony in the harem
would be helpful for Huangshang in the court
Chenqie ask only one thing from Huangshang
no matter how Huangshang award others
please put Duan Fei sister at the top
above all the concubines
or else, Qhenqie won't feel at peace
Duan Fei entered the harem the longest
she deserves the position of Huang Guifei
only that Zhen really want you to have the position
Huangshang have Chenqie in heart and Chenqie know
and don't want to make fuss about it
thus, Zhen will award Duan Fei as Huang Guifei
Zhen treated Jing Fei wrongfully at the early time
she's been calm and gentle
award her as Guifei, the same as you
besides, Xin Guiren has served Zhen for many years
award as Xin Fei
Huangshang cover everything carefully
Chenqie would never think through that clearly
it was not that you couldn't think through
you just waited for Zhen to speak
you begged so much for everyone else
and expressed the gratitude for everyone
why don't ask something for yourself?
Chenqie have the favor of Huangshang
that is the biggest award from Huangshang
I have no other desires
what Xi Guifei means
let us discuss with the Ceremonial Office
to arrange the ceremony of awarding the concubines
working these days
you have to put into 120% effort
this is the happiest occasion in the harem
and can't have anything gone wrong
have you seen the list of the awardees?
from now on
you are to be aware that
who is in charge of the harem
let me tell you
the errand in Yongshou Palace
is the most urgent thing
thank the General Manager for reminding of us
furthermore,
about awarding the title of An Pin
who handled it?
it was Nucai
you wanted to fawn on
have to know who you want to fawn on
and should you fawn on or not
someone come
drag out and spank 40 strokes
and throw into the Bureau of Shenxing and serve there
Nucai is wronged, is wronged
this An Pin, who awarded Li Fei
looked like favorred
but if you curry favor from her
you offended someone without even knowing it
that deserve to be beaten to death
Xiaozhu can't be unhappy
look the baby in your womb
though awarded Fei
what word picked
how could they be beaten for picking a few words
how could they be sent to the Bureau of Shenxing?
maybe they didn't do other things right?
what else they could do?
it was all because of me
they were beaten for picking a few nice words
nobody is allowed to be nice in the harem?
who dares?
Xiaozhu is carrying Huangshang's baby
isn't the Interior Office sending good food here?
they won't dare if it is not the best
how could I not know
that is just for my womb
if there is no this child
no such nonsense, Xiaozhu
what's the noise outside that makes me headache?
throw out, throw all them out
that are sent by Su Gonggong
to congratulate Xiaozhu's promotion
what Su Gonggong meant
maybe what Huangshang meant
Xiaozhu, you can't let Huangshang thought
that you didn't like the title Huangshang gave
throw out, throw them all out
have you heard what I said
throw out, Xiaozhu
I don't want to hear
where did these Huangli come
where else?
more or less from Li Fei's palace
Bengong have favored her
to let her know
even she was promoted to Fei, she didn't deserve it
she didn't deserve
dared to say the words picked by the Interior Office better
word, Li, is used by Empress
showing husband and wife love each other
Li Fei dared to say that without much of education
big award in the harem, Zhen Huai took a big advantage
let her be pleased for a few days
Niangniang is intelligent
does doctor send the drug stabilizing fetus on time?
the best, according to the instruction of Niangniang
the doctor reported yesterday
to stabilize Li Fei's condition
they started burning Ai herb
burning Ai in four months?
it's hard for her health
she has been obedient these years
taking the medicine, and didn't get pregnant
now listened to Niangniang
used the drug of fertility
and let Emperor's seed stays in her for a few months
it has been her luck
tell the doctor that no matter what he does
he has to make Li Fei's baby
look fine
burning Ai stops now today
the stabilizing fetus drug
must take on time each day
to sure everything is fine
besides
Niangniang must stay happy and relax
to ensure safe for the baby
weichen will come to burn Ai for Niangniang
Weichen withdraw
Baojuan
throw out these Ai herb quickly
not let anyone smell the burning Ai
yes
niangniang
the news that Huangshang is going to award the concubines
spread everywhere
Empress mentioned Li Fei
Niangniang asked immediately to promote everyone
now everyone
is waiting to thank Niangniang
I don't want to have Empress alone to be a nice person
Empress wanted to promote An Lingrong
why didn't I push the boats down stream
anything good shares by all
save what I want, and
cut off what I consider unnecessary
in fact, pruning flowers and managing the Harem
are same
I understand the reasoning
Empress understands it better
this flower looks very good after pruning by us
flower is like a person
can branch out anywhere anytime
pay attention
Niangniang is right
bird nest soup is ready, niangniang
it used to be bloody swallow
why did it change to white swallow?
the Interior Office said that Empress had an order
Li Fei is pregnant
bloody swallow is saved for Yanxi Palace
white swallows are used in all other palaces
Empress really cares about Li Fei
she shouldn't be this obvious if she really wants to award her
just orders the Interior Office send it to her everyday
giving all to her
would cause discontent in the Harem
that's why Empress is devastating
on one hand
let Li Fei not too pleased so that
to forget how Empress treated her
secondly, Li Fei had many enemies in the Harem
the more favor she gets
the more jealousy and hatred she gets
to protect herself and the fetus in her womb
she has to grab tightly the big tree of Empress
though it looks that
there is a deep grudge between two of them
Emperor's edict
promote Duan Fei to Huang Guifei
Jing Fei to Jing Guifei
managing the Harem with Xi Guifei
An Pin to Li Fei
Xin Guiren to Xin Pin
Ning Guiren to Ning Pin
Ying Changzai to Guiren
the end
gratitude to Huangshang
the sound of singing and dancing arises outside
is the ceremony of awarding concubines over?
it is good that Xiaozhu didn't go
you with baby can't go where there are a lot of people
I didn't deserve it
Xiaozhu don't think this way
Empress niangniang cares about Xiaozhu
it's getting hot, and it's not good to go where there are more people
cares?
even Shen Meizhuang who was dead is promoted
did Huangshang try to slap my face?
don't say that, Xiaozhu
that's taboo for a royal baby
why is it a taboo?
dead doesn't count
I'm only afraid there is something in Huangshang's heart
Xiaozhu, don't hold a grudge
Hua Guifei was caused so much pain to Huangshang
didn't she award posthumously Huang Guifei?
Huangshang is probably afraid of others' disputes
just something superfacial
Xiaozhu is at ease
Huangshang has forgiven Master An
and awarded him 100 tael gold to retire back to his hometown
that shows how much Huangshang cares about Xiaozhu
after this thing is over
all my suffering to carry this child is worthy
Bengong is later. here is bustling with noise
Sister came
lying down quickly
you are pregnant
should rest well
Baojuan, take out the Yuqian Longjing Tea I've kept
Xi Guifei must like it, too
I remember that Sister used to use
a soft pillow with embroidered golden leaves
how come you use this now?
Sister don't know
Sister Li Fei is pregnant
though the soft pillow with golden leaves
was embroidered with golden thread, it is still rough unavoidably
to have Sister Li Fei sleep more steady
Huangshang sent this soft pillow with Su embroilder
the filling of the pillow is made of millet jade
supposedly best for preserving mentality
I had been used a pillow of Lianyun Silk
a few days ago, Huangshang just awarded me a pillow with negative flowers embroidered with golden thread
I love it so much
is it me that have rough skin
that couldn't tell the roughness of golden thread
how fragrant the tea is!
what I have is not as half as good compared to yours
Sister is joking
how can my things
compare to that of Sister?
it is good if Sister doesn't dislike it
sister is pregnant now
how come you still use the incense that smells so strongly?
it has to be careful
especially musk
Sister always like to mix fragrance, don't make mistakes
Sister worry too much
that fragrance was mixed with juices of fresh flowers
how could an expensive fragrance like musk be necessary?
Sister still argues
this lace used to call Moon Shadow Lace
a precious tribute from foreign country
a roll is worth 100 tael gold
hanging in a room
light is as soft as moonlight even under sunlight
just look at these, it would worth 10,000 tael of gold
say yourself
how can other palaces compare to yours?
it shows that Huangshang cares about you
isn't it?
Huangshang really cares Li Fei's fetus
if Sister like it, I will give it to Sister
please accept it
how can I take sister's thing?
back to why I came,
I'm here to congratulate Sister's pregnancy
and congratulate Sister's promotion to the position of Fei
Xiaoyunzi, come
this white jade fan is the best to get cool down
don't feel hot while holding in hand
this ruby is raw
you can have a skilled worker to carve and put on a crown
this ruby of pigeon blood is bright red like blood
and so pure that has no tiny bit of defect
it's so beautiful
how could I accept such precious thing from Sister?
Sister is the treasure of Huangshang's heart
how could it match Sister
if it is not a precious thing?
is the doctor that stabilizes Li Fei's fetus here?
report to Xi Guifei
it is Doctor Xu here
greeting to Xi Guifei
sister is pregnant
everything has to be extremely careful
it's exactly like what Empress niangniang said
what happened to me, miscarriage, can't happen here
including what I gave to Sister
things sent by everyone have to be checked
Sister said this that view me as an outsider
how could I take it?
if I had a tiny suspicion of Sister, I would...
what are you saying? not afraid of taboo?
I'm doing this
is for our sisterly feelings
in case someone tries something
there won't be an opportunity
this is Doctor Wei
it is more reliable to have two doctors checking on you
report to Niangniang, in these things
there is nothing that will harm fetus
I agree
as such, both I and Sister An feel at ease
Sister An tried hard and got pregnant finally
have to take good care
Doctor Wei is here today
why not have him to check your pulse again?
and one more layer of safety. --- thanks for care
I should've listened to Sister and checked one more time
but Doctor Xu was recommended by Empress niangniang
I'm like Sister, should have one more safety
but if Empress knew about this
she might think we didn't trust Doctor Xu's skill
doctor Xu, how is Li Fei niangniang's condition?
her condition is very good
just look at her face, you can tell
Li Fei likes incense; is it a problem?
no problem
Sister is good at making incense
what incense you use today?
it is called Ninglu
if Sister like
I can give Sister some?
Baojun, go to my fragrance box
and wrap some Ninglu for Xi Guifei
how could I bother Sister's maid?
Xiaoyunzi,
go with Baojuan for some incense
have you seen something strange?
not yet
but Weichen have suspicion
I am still not sure
I'll report back to Niangniang after I think through
Nucai went to get the Ninglu
saw several boxes put on top of the shelf
said that Li Fei put away herself and didn't like use anymore
Nucai saw that box with elegant painting
not like something she didn't want
I forced open the box and took a few pills when Baojuan didn't pay attention
it looks like fragrance or honey
what is this?
Bengong call you here is want to know
is Li Fei's pregnancy stable?
report to Niangniang
like Niangniang's guess
Li Fei's child probably won't be born
how could you know that Bengong's guess is that Li Fei's child won't be born?
it's a big crime to accuse Bengong
Weichen wouldn't dare
Doctor Xu who checked Li Fei
had reported that her condition is stable
if Niangniang believe it
naturally won't ask Weichen
rise to speak
since you know Bengong is suspicious
tell the truth
Weichen saw the diagnosis when no one was aware
it said that the condition is stable
and the prescription is common fetus protection drug
yet in the herbs
it added Aiye, Huangqin, zhumagen
and Baizhu, and so on
Bengong don't know others
but Aiye is to stop bleeding
if not necessary, it can't be used lightly
Niangniang is wise
though Li Fei lit incense
to cover the smell of smoky Ai
Weichen still detected it
and there was trace of smoking Ai
Li Fei is pregnant for four months and uses Aiye
that means she has bleeding
besides, Huangqin, Baizhu, and Zhumagen
are effective to stop bleeding and compensate Qi
that means that Li Fei has symptoms of lack of blood and Qi
sweat, and fetus moves
in addition, Weichen heard that
Li Fei is depressed in recent days
I'm afraid that the more time passes,
the more dangerous the fetus in the womb
and it won't last to full term
nothing could be perfect
doctors try their best
maybe can help Li Fei to give birth smoothly
Li Fei uses Ai, it means that she knew she couldn't keep the fetus
if the fetus can't be saved
who Niangniang think should be responsible?
if she can't keep herself, it's okay
otherwise whomever would be unfortunate
this thing, you know, I know
Bengong naturally don't have to take the responsibility
take a look: what is this?
Jinxi
forgive me, Niangniang, Weichen is careless
Weichen didn't know this incense drug is so strong
what is it?
man and woman intercourse, use it to attract
you mix a little with water
it is already so strong
Niangniang don't know
Lilangxiang and Shezhuangzi in this incense
are 100%
if burn this incense, it would be stronger
therefore, when used routinely
it is used only a tiny amount in
other fragrances and the effect will be shown immediately
and difficult to detecting
the Yilang flower has the effect of moving the feeling
what happens if use Elizhangzhong incense?
similar but not as strong as this fragrance
Yilang flower is still a plant
but the Yilan in this incense
is purified from a great quantity of the flowers
do Niangniang know that Yilan Flower are not seen frequently