Lady, you didn't eat at aII...
why don't you eat something?
Niang niang, Duke Dun's wife wishes to see you.
I only meet her once
I've only met her once.
Why she want to see
Why would she come to visit me?
A sick and discarded and unloved consort like me.
Ask her to go. I will.
Why have you come, Fujin? (note: Fujin = the title of the wife of the son or brother of an emperor)
I came into the palace today to pay my respects to the Dowager Empress.
then I went to visit the Empress.
Please take a seat.
I heard that you weren't feeling well, so I stopped by to visit.
Thank you Fujin.
I shouldn't be seeing anyone while sick.
I didn't expect you to come.
I'm sorry for my appearance.
Though it's only been a few months since I last saw youNiang Niang has become like this...
Thank you for your kindness and thoughts.
I am visiting today to bring a box of ginseng for Niang Niang.
I hope that you will accept it to nourish your body.
Thank you for your kind thoughts.
I know that the Duke my husband often has a bad temper.
If he's somehow offended Niangniang,
and Niangniang is unwilling to associate with us,
you may just throw out my gift. I won't be offended.
How can it be so?You must not worry about that.
I came without being called by the Emperor. I don't dare to stay long.
I'll come another day to see Niangniang.
I hope that the Consort recovers soon.
Jin-Xi, see the Fujin out.
I will.
Lady...
Lady, do you wantto throw away the Ginseng?
Though her husband doesn't get along with us,
but this ginseng is her gift.
Send it to the ImperiaI Doctor Wensee if the ImperiaI Doctors have use for it.
We will.
I've been sick for so long,
Who knew that she would be the one who is still willing to come see me?
The changes in people's attitudes from warm to cold has always been this way.
thanks goddess, ConsortHui and Consort Jing
still always think of Xiaozhu, right?
Let the servants do things like this sort of massaging.
This humble servant wants to do things like this.
If I can make Your Majesty more comfortable,
It makes me happy.
"If there's was no heIpfuI andcIever person in the country"
"if there's were no intruders andenemies among the country (people)"
this country wiII be destroyed quickly.
you can Iearn to survive suffering, whiIe being comfortable can cause your death.
Meng Fuzi's words are very wise.
A comfortabIe Iife can makepeopIe Iose their minds.
onIy hard work and and seIf-motivation can lead to success
think of dangerous during safety Iife, be prepared and predict the outcomes before facing the difficuIties.
All the greatest emperors in history have been so.
Don't you agree?
Of course.
Your Majesty spoke a lot
Take some water
perhaps have some water?
If the Consort Wan is here
If Consort Wan was hereshe could be able to talk with me about this.
Jie jie is educated and talented.
Speaking about history is her expertise.
I heard she became sick at the start of autumn.
Did you pay her a visit?How is she?
The sickness comes from the heart.
if Your Majesty pays her a visit, I think she wiII recover quickly.
It's not that I don't want to go visit her.
it's just that I am afraid that closeness will make affection more hesitant.
How is her wound? Has it gotten better?
It's much better and there is no scar.
That's good. There's nothing more important for a woman than her appearance.
Your masjesty
I have a request to ask of you.
What is it? Ask standing up.
I will.
After Jie Jie lost her child, she was so upset that she became sick.
If Your Majesty does not go to see her,
Why don't you allow her family to see her?
So that she can talk about her pain with someone, and find release.
Since she lost a child, it would be good for her to be comforted by her family.
But right now her heart is full of hatredof me and of Consort Nian.
If she speaks about it with her familyshe will only become more upsetand be unable to let it go.
And it will not be good for her illness.
Your Majesty thinks thoroughly,this humble servant cannot match you.
You and her are close like sisters.I'm sure you are thinking only of her welfare, and that's good.
Earlier Your Majesty said,
When people make mistakes, they  should be able to correct their mistakes,
that's something I understand.
Though I often am lacking in many things before Your Majesty,I have corrected my mistakes.
I only hope that Your Majesty will be moved by my efforts.
You know the meaning of those words,
but a clever woman Iike Imperial Concubine Wan can't?
It's all right if Jie Jie cannot understand it,as long as she remembers one thing:
That Your Majesty has the Mandate of Heaven,and Your Majesty is always right.
Don't bother going back to your palace tonight.Stay here and keep me company.
Did Your Majesty forget? You have plans with the 17th Prince
to admire the calligraphy of Dong Qi-Chang.  The 17th prince is already here.
He doesn't have anything better to do anyway.
Let him stay a few days at the House of Concentrating GIow.
I'll meet with him another day.
Your cIothes was made of siIk brocade.
Of course. Did Your Majesty forget?
You gave me some silk brocade last time,
so I asked the ImperiaIHousehoId to make me a set of new cIothes.
SiIk brocade, you Iook good in it
Whatever stock we have in Imperial Affairs, they're all yours.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Though Lady has been ill for some days now, no one has come to visit her.
ahh..
"You only find out people's true character after a long period of time."
Now we see how true that saying is.Some people were only close to us before,
just wish to take advantage of Lady's favor from His Majesty.
His Majesty seIdom comes to the palace now,
And when he is here
he always goes to see the Empress At the Hall of Complete Happiness.
Though the words "take advantage of" are ugly,
if you have nothing for people to take advantage of, that's when you're really in trouble.
Though that's a horrible thought,I think you're right.
in the paIaceonIy a vaIueabIe person can survive
So we've got to be people who have something that others want,
It's only when we allow others to take advantage of us, that we can take advantage of them.
It's useless to just say that.We have to think of a plan.
These days, Precious An gets to meet His Majesty nowadays often.
but we can't possibly rely on her to help.
Eunuch Su is a servant, he can't heIp
We have to find someone whose words have weight,
but who we can see to ask to talk some sense into Lady
Oh! I heard 17th Prince is in the paIace.
What's the use of that? He's not someone we can reach.
Jie Jie, you've been here for more than half the day.
Why do you persist in staring at me like that?
I was just thinking, "What would it look like if she really gave up on the Emperor?"
Do you really think I haven't already given up?
What do you think?
If you really do not care for him still, why would you still be stuck in illness?
Rather than be like this, even though His Majesty has not come to see you,
you can always go and find him and stop making your place as lonely as the Cold Palace.
if His Majesty wanted to come, he would come.
if not, what's the point of forcing him?
You are different from me.I was never close to His Majesty.
Since he put me under house arrest and never looked into the matter again,
I know that he is cold and unreliable.
Though now he acts as though I do not exist,I don't really mind at all.
But it's different for you.
Why, because I have more feelings for him than you do?
if you reaIIy didn't care for him, you would be as I am now.
You would not feel pain from his words.
In the end... you know that he does care about you.
Anyway, since Ling-Rong was so close to us before,
even though she is two-faced, do you really think
that I should vie for attention and pit myself against her?
Besides, His Majesty really loves her more than he loves me.
When you were in favor, you helped her gain favor.
But now that she has favor, has she ever helped you?
If she really meant to help you, then there would be no talk of vying for attention.
But if she won't help you, do you plan to be like this forever?
Besides, His Majesty merely likes whoever he likes at the moment,
and his favor changes all the time.
Isn't the whole point of vying for favorto just be loved a little more than another?
if you reaIIy give up on His Majesty,
you wouldn't be wasting your time being heartbroken here.
Jie Jie, I'm really stupid, aren't I?
I really wanted there to be a little bit of genuine and pure feelings
in a palace such as this.
I wished for the one thing I should never wish for.
Huan-Er
There are too many heartbroken people here already.
Don't add yourself to those ranks.
I understand.
Well, I must go pay my respects to the Dowager Empress.
I'll come to see you tomorrow.
Do you often go and visit the Dowager Empress?
Since my health recovered, my feelings for His Majestyhave changed greatly from what they were before.
Since Ling Rong is the favorite now, we see very little of His Majesty.
I must find someone to rely on too.
The Dowager Empress must Iike sister very much.
She has been quite ill.
Since I have nothing better to do, I ought to keep her company.
I'll be going now.
Thank you for your hard work, Aunt.Why don't you let me feed this to her/.
Whenever you're here, they get plenty of free time since
you do all the work for them.
Since I rarely get to come and visit you, please let me show my filial heart by serving you.
You? Rarely here? You are here every day!
If the Dowager Empress thinks I'm too stupid to be of use,I'll not dare to come anymore.
You have a warm and calm personality and you are thoughtful and careful.
I like it when you are here.
I'm happy that the Dowager Empress does not dislike me.
Here--careful, it's hot.
It's because I like you that I feel the need to remind you,
Since you have the time, try to spend more time with the Emperor.
Lady FuCa and Lady Wan both miscarried.
The Emperor is upset, and now especially needs someone at his side.
I have been thinking that only one who did the knot can undo it.
His Majesty is upset because Imperial Concubine Wan has lost her child.
if Imperial Concubine Wan can spend time with His Majesty,it would be the best.
If two people are frustrated with each other,
to force them to be together would make things even more awkward.
This can only be solved if one of them is able to get over it,
and make the first step towards reconciliation.
I understand.
Lady, the moon is quite lovely tonight.
Why don't we bring the Chang Xiang Si so you may play a song?
(Chang Xiang Si: "long love", the name of her guzheng)
It's true that there's something very poetic about playing a song to the mon.
But Chang Xiang Si will only hurt my heart, so I might as well not play it.
In the past, Lady's favorite was Li Bai's Chang Xiang Si.(note: the poem from which the name of the guzheng comes)
At this moment, even if I wanted to, I don't dare to play it by myself.
Though Lady is unwilling to play that song, who is that out thereplaying Chang Xiang Si?
This is the second half of the poem.
The long feelings in Chang'an,
The lady, lovely like a flower, is separated clouds away.
Above is the clear and blue sky, and below is the green sea foam of the ocean.
Sending the soul that distance brings pain.
Even in dreams the soul cannot make it to the mountain.
Huan-Bi, Iisten, the fIute is such a lovely sound.
What is Lady and Huan-Bi saying? I don't hear any flute.
You didn't hear that?
No, I don't.
Though the sound is soft, it is lovely.
Isn't it amazing that there's another person in the palacewho likes Chang Xiang Si the way that Lady does?
Chang Xiang Si is a song that is too sad.
But when this person plays,
There is a stronger feeling of longing, but less sadness.
It makes me feel as though the feeling of longing is also a beautiful thing.
I wonder which Lady in the palace can play the flute so beautifully?
You've been moved too by the flute, haven't you?
Why don't we take a walk, Lady?
The people of ancient times tread snow to find plum blossoms, following the scent of plum.
and now we are searching for a person, by the sound of their flute.
But with such a soft sound, I wonder if we'll find them at all?
I also wonder what the flute player looks like, but things like this are all up to fate.
It would be best if we could find them, but if we can't, that would be all right too.
You've gotten much thinner.
During this season, the wind blows from the west
So of course it is easy to become thinner.
I am very grateful for the help you gave me the other day.
Imperial Concubine Wan, please do not say such thingsto me as if we were strangers.
It's regretful that I was unable to save your child also.
Everyone thinks that the 17th prince broke into Yi Kun Palace and saved me because
I was a favorite with His Majesty.
And that to help me was just to do something for His Majesty.
But in any case, this kind of lending hand and justice, only seems to come from you.
Even though I have fallen far these days,
but I'm not someone who forgets what they owe.
In the future, if there's any help I can give to you, I will of course do my best to help.
I wanted Imperial Concubine Wan to be safe because--
I see you as an important friend.
I know that the 17th prince is only thinking of my wellbeing.
But if my lord associates with my close servant too often,
it would not be good for the reputation of my lord.
Thank you for your advice.
why is Lord here tonight?
His Majesty asked me to stay the night.
Just now I went and greet His Majesty,
and saw singer An Guirenwho seems like someone I've seen before.
She used to be An Changzai.
Is that so?
An Guiren's voice has improved greatly.
but her voice is lacking her own personality.
As Iong as His Majesty Iikes it, that's what matters, right?
Pure jade or goId are beauty made by nature.
but they must not lose their own qualities.
"The more you take, the more you lose,even if you are stubborn, don't lose yourself."
The Chang Xiang Si I played just now, I hope
it will take away a little of your sadness, Wan Ping.
It's just a song.
Songs reflect what is in the hearts of people.That's true, for you and for me too.
Since His Majesty asked my lord to stay, there must be things you have to do tomorrow.
I won't bother you any longer.
When did you start associating with the 17th prince?
It's not your mistress who's speaking to you now,but your older sister.
You can answer or not.
I didn't mean to lie to Jie Jie.
Did it begin on my birthday?
That was why you never let me near the lake that day, wasn't it?
He's the one who told you to do that, isn't he?
About what happened in the PaIace of Supporting Earth...
Are you the one who asked him for help?
That day Jing Xi Gugu was in the palace with you  and could not get away to find help.
The Empress Dowager was ill, and in the palacethere was no one who could help Jie Jie.
So I took a chance and asked the Duke.
How many times have you met since then?
just twice:once was during your miscarriageand another time is today.
Lord never spoke about other things.
He just asked me to take good care of you.
Why is Jie Jie suddenly asking me about it today?
Did the Duke tell you about it?
Today you only did the regular greeting bow.
If you weren't meeting privately day to day, you would be doing the more formal greeting.
I'm sorry--I wasn't careful enough.
Since I'm in a strange position right now,
If you meet with him too often, it's not good for us or for him.
Don't meet with him again in private.
Hello, Hui-Chun.
Congratulations, Mistress, for having had the favor of His Majesty last night.
I'm here to follow Empress's instructions.
As usual, please drink this.
These days, all the sewing work must be done by you two yourselves.
I've caused you two to be dragged down with me.
Not at all. To get close to those who are high upand step on those below is the usual thing here.
The Internal Affairs people are busy making silk blockade clothes for An Guiren these days.
Actually, I your humble servant enjoy making my own clothing.
There's true warmth and fit when I wear it.
In the end Ling-Rong is the one with good fortune now. She's become the favorite these days.
Hello, Jiejie.
Why are you all making your own winter clothes?
The Internal Affairs people are too busy to bother with us presently.
Since it's getting much colder now, we must make the clothing ourselves.
Come with me somewhere.
Let me finish organizing these silk threads first.
Come.
Where are we going?
Let's go.
Jiejie, that's the Cold Palace ahead.
Walk quickly.
just guess! Guess when His Majesty will finally come?
You cheat! I don't want to play with you
One day His Majesty wiII faII in love with me
His Majesty? Does he even remember you?
Give me that!
I won't!
Take a guess at who she is.
Are you OK?
Did Jiejie want me to come here
So I can see Li Ping?
Did you see the womannext to Li Ping?
She is someone who used to be a Guiren.
Who is she?
It's not important who she is.
What's important is that she too was once pregnant but fell and miscarried.
Because she was too sad, she gave up on His Majesty.
And then, she complained and accused Hua Fei of murdering her child.
That's why she's been sent here to the Cold Palace.
Are you afraid I'll follow in her footsteps?
Whether she really did accuse and insult Hua Fei, no one knows.
What matters is that His Majesty believed that she did.
The saying goes, "The more you see someone the more you are fond of them."
She wallowed in her own pain and refused to care for His Majesty.
So she never even had the chance to see him and defend herself.
But if she was set up, all she can do is be set up.
This is an example of what can happen to you.
if you keep going Iike this,
what they look like now is going to be what happens to you.
His Majesty gave you the best quality silk brocade.
When you wear it you will look moving and beautiful, gaining you even more favor from His Majesty.
I am but a lowly person, and do not deserve such good things.
All the treasure of this world should belong to you the Empress.
That is why I have brought these to offer them all to you.
When you are a favorite with His Majesty, even gold threaded clothing will be easy to get.
These brocades are nothing compared to the favor of His Majesty.
I am only where I am today with the help of you the Empress.
I shall never forget it.
You may stand.
You have a good heart.
The silk brocade His Majesty has given you now is several timeswhat he gave to Wan Ping in the days she had favor.
How does it feel to monopolize his favor?
In my heart I understand that without your guidance, I wouldn't have any of this.
I know your feeling of gratitude.
You wanted to replace Wan Ping, andI have made that dream come true.
Nian Fei is too arrogant, whiIe Wan Ping is too cIever.I do not like either of them.
Since you are a good child, I helped myself by helping you.
But there is one thing you must remember no matter what---
After I've served His Majesty intimately, I have followed your instructionsand drank the medication you gave me.
It's good that you are an obedient child.
It is not that I won't allow you to have a child,
but that you've only gained favor recently.
if you are pregnant others wiII get the advantage and have time to steal the favor from you.
You are still young, and there are many days to come yet.
Thank you for your guidance.
Hurry!
Oh, it's Wan Ping.
Why aren't you more careful while you walk?
Have you forgotten about the rules of the palace justbecause you haven't seen His Majesty in a while?
I'm sorry for running into you, Qi Fei Niangniang.
Oh, I wondered who you were.
Why, if it isn't the previous favorite of His Majesty, Wan Ping!
No wonder! Favorite consorts always walk all over everybody.
Please forgive me, Qi Fei Niangniang.
Oi, you say "Niangniang" so intimately!
Let's just go. Just looking at her makes me feel unfortunate.
Niangniang, of course she is unfortunate.
She caused you to not be able to be with your son.
I really didn't mean to run into you, Qi Fei Niangniang.Please forgive me.
Wan Ping Niangniang has always been known as the one who is strict about rules and about treating your betters well!
And now, you don't even do the proper greeting when you run into Qi Fei!
Please forgive me, Qi Fei Niangniang.
Fine. As long as you don't appear before me I'll consider myself lucky.
Get out of here, as far as you can.
Niangniang, she's the one who wronged you first.Don't let her go just like this!
Forget it. I don't have the time to waste sitting here arguing with her.
Just let her go.
You've forgotten, Niangniang. These days, Nian Fei is no longer the favorite.
Jing Fei is completely useless and Duan Fei is always ill.
Among the Fei rank, you are the most important now!
If you don't show people what you're made of now,
Who will even remember you in the future?
Just think about it, Niangniang. If she weren't such a slut,
Why would His Majesty lose interest in us?
Why would my child be dead when hers comes?
And the 3rd prince can't even come see you, his birth mother!
I didn't forget!
It's you. It was all you!
According to Fucha Guiren I caused your child to die.
but what of my child? Who killed it?
When I lost my child, yours suddenly appeared!
My saddest and most painful days were the daysyou were just flying to the sky with glory!
If it weren't you who killed my child, who did?!
That your child died is obviously karma.
If you are convinced of that,
then I have nothing further to say.
YOU have nothing to say?
If you hadn't ratted Niangniang out to the Empress, she would be able to see her son now!
It's all because of you, the bitch.
There is a cause to every effect.
Why Qi Fei Niangniang was punished, she knows very well herself.
I didn't want to keep at her about it, and so never informed His Majesty.
If it weren't for that, I think her punishment
would not stop at not being able to see the 3rd prince occasionally!
Good. Very good.
You even dare to talk back to me now?
Cui-Guo, sIap her until her mouth rots!
Please forgive me, Qi Fei Niangniang.
Don't worry, Cui-Guo. Hit her as hard as you can.Even His Majesty won't see her now.
It's just Qi Fei Niangniang's duty to punish those who do not behave.
Those who dare to falsely accuse their betters,already deserved to be slapped long ago!
Cui-Guo, if you don't sIap her,I'II send you to Sheng Xing Si for punishment.
Do it!
You've finally wised up to the fact that
there's no use in begging, so you might as well be quiet.
It looks like Nian Fei really gave you a good lesson!
You can stop now.
You have plenty of time to sit here and be slapped,But I have no time to waste on you.
You just kneel here at this door and think about what you've done.
Cui-Guo, stand here and watch her.Don't let her get up before two hours are up.
Since Wan Ping is no longer pregnant, it won't hurt her to kneel.
Only when her body feels pain, will she know our pain.
Qi Fei Niangniang, must you persecute me this way?
Don't you love to talk behind my back to the Empress?
It's been so long now and you have no proof.
Even if I put the poIIen of oIeander in your food, so what?
All the evidence is gone now.
If you dare bring it up again, I will punish you wellfor your sin of slandering!
Don't be angry, Wan Ping Niangniang.
Please bear this small amount of humiliation with a smile.
Do you honestly think you are the same Wan Ping as before?
Let's go. We've still got to go to InternalAffairs to pick out some things!
Wan Ping Niangniang, why don't you stand up?I won't tell anyone.
Cui-Guo, is that the PaIaceof Supporting Earth?
Yes.
Where is Nian Fei?
She's living well in the palace.
That's right.. she's still living well.
Greetings to the Empress. Greetings to Mistress An.
Niangniang, I have heard from Jiang Luhai that Qi Fei is
punishing Lady Wan in the corridor by slapping her face.
Has His Majesty heard?
His Majesty is still with the government.
There's no need to tell the government what's happening in the palace.
If His Majesty doesn't even care about it, why should I?
Empress Niangniang, Wan Ping is truly pitiful.
can you ask Qi Fei to stop?
If you pity her, who will pity you?
If I show compassion for her, so will His Majesty.
When that happens, you will lose all of your favor!
I understand.
Go quickly. Don't stare.
Niangniang, it's been 2 hours. Please get up.
I'm sorry you've suffered, Niangniang, our Niangniang is not usually like this.
Your kind heart will bring you good fortunes.
Please let this humble servant help you home.
Don't bother.
Lady, massage your face with egg;
it heIps with the sweIIing.
She's bullying you too much.
I will go tell the Empress.
I was kneeling there for hours. How could she not know?
If she was going to come she would have.
Why do you allow her to do this, mistress? You might as well break with her anyway.
Break with her?
Who do I think I am now? Can I afford to?
Fucha Guiren was right.
The pain on the body reflects the pain in the heart.
Liu-Zhu, ask Xiao Yun-Zito catch some butterfIies.
Mistress, it's not the season for butterflies.
That's right... butterflies are out of the season.
But I must have them. The most beautiful ones.
Yes, mistress.
Huan-bi, bring me my powdered make up.
Mistress, we've used it all.
Go get some from the Internal Affairs office then.
The Luizi eyebrow color is also used up?
We've used it up.
Never mind.
These days I shouldn't be using Luizi anyway.
Just bring the regular kind that you use.
I'll go get it now.
Xiao Yun-Zi, there's a butterfIy!
Where?
There!
it's a dead butterfIy.
What's the use even if it's living? It's gray and ugly. What good is it?
I can't even complete a task this simple. I'm so useless!
Where are we supposed to find butterflies in this season anyhow?
Actually I know a place.
Where?
There's a hot springs at PaIace of Forever PeacefuI.
it's warm there, and there are still many fIowers,
So there are sure to still be butterflies.
But we can't leave this palace for there.
And besides, during this season no one else is likely to go there.
You keep looking.
You too. I'II be back.
Miss Huan-Bi aIways comes in siIentIyas if she's trying to scare people on purpose.
My lord, if A Jing keeps saying that, I won't dare come again.
Leave us.
Has something happened at the House of Broken Jade?
Well well, don't speak at all please.
Last time you came and cried and asked for a favor,
to advise Wan Niangniang.
What is it now?
Nonsense.
Just tell me what's happening.
My lord, I don't know what happened to my mistress. She's asked us to get butterflies for her.
But where are we supposed to find butterflies this time of year?
I'm just worried that last time, your advice didn't work and she's too upset and not thinking straight.
Has she asked for anything other than butterflies?
Not much else.
If butterflies can help her feel better, then I'll try my best to get some for her.
But besides that, you must stay with her.
it's aImost winter.How can we catch butterfIies?
I heard there are hot springs in PaIace ofForever PeacefuI, so it's warm.Maybe you can find some there?
Then I'II go to the PaIace of Forever PeacefuI.it's not hard at all.