~ Episode 18 ~
Have some tea to freshen up
National affairs are worrying, as are family affairs
I'll have to trouble you
Is that General Nian's report?
He says fighting in the northwest is successful. Everything is going smoothly.
General Nian leads wars on the battlefield
His younger sister works hard in the inner palace
Early this morning, someone from the imperial kitchen came to report
Xiao Tang, who managed the dessert material, has admited his guilty
he said he was momentarily oversight
and messed up the powders
as a result, made princess sick
Right now, the imperial kitchen is waiting your oder
how to punish
They are resolutely
found the murderer all at once
The murderer has been found
but whether I should give this case an end
is up to your majesty
What do you think
Once the harem is chaos
your majesty can't concentrate on the policy
someone has so much power but also made many troubles
even use princess
to frame up your majesty's lover
In my opinion, such things shouldn't be tolerated
Once the harem is chaos, the politics will also be the same
if continue to investigate
I'm afraid it will hurt the soldiers' morale
end this
Then, your majesty should comfort Precious Smile nicely
I know
how about Xiao Tang
Kill him
My palms are sweaty
I'm afraid I'll dirty the color of the thread. I'm going to wash my hands.
Huanbi
Young mistress, do you need some tea or fruits?
Didn't you go to the imperial kitchen last time
to pick up some cassava powder for the pearl balls?
Go get some for as snacks
Why does young mistress suddenly want to eat that?
After what happened last time, I thought it was bad luck
so I threw them all out.
What a coincidence
I was just thinking of the taste
Lingrong, I have some new chestnut cakes from his majesty
Jiejie can decide
You go get them
Yes
What do you have there?
Lotus seeds I just peeled
Your majesty are reading booklets all day, will inevitably get inflamed
lotus seed can diminish inflammation
I've troubled you
Peeling these really hurts the nails
Your Majesty usually drinks lotus soup
These fresh lotus seeds,
I've already removed the cores
It has a different flavor
Indeed
But without the lotus heart,
the lotus seeds lose some flavor.
The lotus heart is the most bitter
Others cannot experience
so I removed them.
The cores have been removed
but your love to the child is great
I've heard rumors among the older eunuchs
that there was a Concubine Jing during the Wanli (Ming) Dynasty
who used her own children to fight for favor.
She wouldn't hesitate to let her infant child run a high fever
to attract the emperor's attention. What do you think?
If I were Emperor Wanli,
I would definitely kill Concubine Jing.
The hardship of 10 months pregnancy and childbirth
only a mother can understand.
For Concubine Jing to harm her child...
unless she's not the birth mother.
She must have secret sorrow
if not, then she wouldn't be qualified to be human
not mention her life
You are always docile and reserved, rarely this enraged
I misspoke
It's just that as a mother,
I was overly emotional.
The love of child
Not just mothers, but fathers too
You spent so much time peeling these
You're not only meticulous, but also patient
Princess of Glory has never raised her own
You can take your child back
Thanks Your Majesty
Quickly bring Princess Wenyi home
Yes
Your Majesty, Precious Cao seems really happy
But why is Your Majesty not very happy?
Did you see how Precious Cao
left to get Princess Wenyi?
So happy she almost flew
She ran straight to Princess of Glory's place
Servant misspoke, servant deserves to die
You spoke the truth
I saw it too
And because of this,
I feel discouragingly disappointed.
Your Majesty
Princess of Glory prepared your favorite snacks
She invites you over to taste them
Your Majesty, you haven't flipped today's plaque yet
These days you haven't gone to Precious Smile's
or visited Lingering An,
much less Princess of Glory.
You can leave now
Yes
Su Peisheng!
Servant here
I'm a bit hungry
Then I will have the imperial kitchen bring over some snacks
Doesn't Princess of Glory already have some ready?
Servant understands. Your Majesty, please.
Also tell Precious Smile
that I will go to her place tomorrow morning for breakfast.
Yes
Stop dawdling around. Young mistress is already up.
You go. I will be there right away.
Today His Majesty is having breakfast with young mistress
I'm going now, hurry up
Later, I still have to pay my respects to the Empress
This ornament is too showy
Young mistress is too cautious
His Majesty doesn't care for Lingering An
as much as he does you,
but doesn't she still dress ostentatiously all the time?
Full head of jade and pearl ornaments
As many jade and pearl ornaments as she wears,
Lingering An has never stepped beyond her bounds.
Don't say that again
If any troublemakers hear that,
they'll think I can't stand the sight of Lingrong doing well.
Yes
Lingering An is not that pretty
Her family background is also modest
Why does His Majesty like her so much?
Just because she can sing?
Favor is not based on appearance, or family background either
It only matters what the emperor likes
Otherwise it's futile
Why have you been so rash lately?
Discretion and propriety have always been your strengths
Don't lose it
Yesterday, His Majesty said
that he wants to have breakfast with young mistress.
Young mistress should dress up more vibrantly
You look quite colorful today
Young mistress forgot? Today's ghost festival day (7th full moon in lunar year)
too much ying on this day
servant make up myself colorful, to keep the ying and yang balance
Indeed, today's the ghost festival
Tonight, the palace is doing an offering ceremony to the spirits
and will burn paper-made boats and oblations
You go too, as a sign of filial respect
Many thanks young mistress
Liuzhu
Go check on the kitchen to see how the food is coming along
I told them
to make it more delicate and tasty.
Yes
Your Majesty has worked hard lately
I already had them prepare ginseng soup
Your Majesty can drink it after court
You have worked hard also, serving me
You can sleep a bit longer
Just have them deliver the ginseng soup to me
Then I will wait for Your Majesty for lunch?
Many official matters await me. I will come visit you tomorrow.
I thought
that because of Princess Wenyi,
you were upset at me.
That you would never come again
Silly words
Right
Yesterday your brother sent a report
and asked if you were well.
Brother still cares about me like he did when we were young
I also care about brother
I don't know if his old wounds are getting better
It's natural for siblings to be close
I already told him that you are well
and not to worry.
As for his wounds,
I know you're concerned about them.
I've already asked him for you, and granted him medicine
Many thanks for Your Majesty's care
Your Majesty, tonight is the ghost festival
There will be a ritual ceremony tonight
I already had them prepare some things to burn
to comfort the souls of soldiers who died in battle.
Let the priest find peace for their souls
You're rarely this considerate. I can feel relieved.
Emperor arrives
Respects to Your Majesty
Everyone rise
Thanks Your Majesty
I just finished court. I'm hungry.
I have some speciality dishes
I have already asked someone to send it to your personal kitchen
We will eat it together with porridge
This is soya milk made from soya beans grinded in the morning, try it Your Majesty
Your Majesty seems to be very happy
What is it that has made you happy?
Nian Geng Yao has defeated the enemy troops in the war in the Northwest, claiming victory
I feel very consoled
Your Majesty is intelligent and wise at strategy
I will use porridge instead of wine to congratulate you
Do you think you can avoid drinking as a result?
Your Majesty shouldn't be so insistent
I will have to go back to the capital at the end of the month
Everything is so troublesome and tedious
I'm afraid the Empress is unable to cope by herself
I wish to allow Princess of Glory to help her with a few matters
What do you think?
How does the Empress feel about it?
I haven't asked her yet, I'm asking for your opinion first
Your Majesty cares for Princess of Glory
Naturally there is nothing wrong with it
Princess of Glory may be impetuous when she handles matters sometimes
But Princess of Modesty suffers from weak health and Princess of Regularity is incompetent
Only Princess of Glory is able to offer some assistance
Your Majesty may have good intentions
I believe the Empress
will not have any disagreements with this
Only that General Nian has just reported victory from the frontline
Your Majesty immediately reinstated
Princess of Glory's power to head the Harem and handle its affairs
Understanding ones will praise Your Majesty for taking care of his subjects
Those unknowing ones
I'm afraid will neglect Your Majesty's brillance
Thinking that Your Majesty is over reliant on the Nian family
That Nian family is the only one that can win battles
So you cannot wait to hand power to Princess of Glory
to use her to pull strings
There are actually such unfound rumors in the Palace?
Just some ignorant people loving to gossip behind other people's backs
Your Majesty, please do not take it to heart
Only there's one thing
General Nian is so accomplished, he naturally thinks very highly of himself
If Your Majesty bestows power upon Princess of Glory at this moment
I'm afraid that General Nian will become arrogant
That will not be good
I am being muddle-headed for discussing political affairs
I seek Your Majesty's forgiveness
It's alright, I said before that you're allowed to discuss political affairs
I'm only afraid that besides you in this Palace
No one will dare to analyse and discuss like that with me
I'm saying these today
not because I'm jealous of Princess of Glory
but because I hope Your Majesty is able to weigh the goods and bads appropriately
Postpone the reinstatement of Princess of Glory's power to handle the Harem's affairs
Firstly it helps to quieten down the gossip
secondly not to damage Your Majesty's heavenly aura
thirdly she can be titled again during a major festival or celebration
Then it will be completed and rightfully deserved
It's the Ghost Festival today, not auspicious
Mid-Autumn Festival is just round the corner
Then it will be New Year's Eve
Not good for further title decoration
We have to wait til the Lantern Festival
It's not too late to talk about it then
It's good this way too, only that it will be hard on the Empress
Your Majesty does not need to worry
the Empress is familiar with affairs of the Harem
And there's Princess of Regularity and Pin of Respects to assist
There will not be any mishaps
Actually when Mei Jie Jie was a Precious
Your Majesty still liked her
Intended to let her learn the ropes of handling the Harem's affairs
In order to help the Empress with the miscallaneous affairs in the future
Only that it's shame now
Liu Ben is not caught yet
It's only right to let her meditate and cultivate morals for the time being
Yes, as long as we catch Liu Ben
Mei Jie Jie will be vindicated
Get up
I thank Your Majesty
Your Majesty's words
must have made you thirsty, do drink a bowl of soya milk
I'll do it, enjoy Your Majesty
You dress pretty handsomely today
Thank you Your Majesty
Your green dress is flirty and cute
Only using a pink rose as embellishment
and wearing pink shoes makes it tacky
I just obtained a new band of pink silk cloth
You may use it to make a dress
Change yourself out of this green dress
Thank you Master
Then I'll take my leave
You're quite generous and kind towards your servants
They are already having it tough being servants in the Palace
If I don't treat them well
They will be too pitiful
I agree
Once servants have dissatisfaction in their hearts
They will not do things instructed by the masters well
Reporting to Your Majesty
Military subjects are already waiting in the Imperial Study
Then I will go back first, I'll come and see you again tomorrow
Farewell to Your Majesty
Seeing this in the early morning
This beautiful scene mixed with tears
Respects to Duke Guo Jun
Get up. Which palace do you belong to?
I am Precious Smile's dowry maid
Thank you for your compliment just now
But I look extremely tacky with red and green
Who says you're tacky?
Someone said it
He doesn't think it looks good because he doesn't like red and green together
Actually, beauty is in the eye of the beholder
I think it looks pretty good
You need not make me happy on purpose
Why should I make you happy on purpose
To be truthful
If you do not believe me, look at the flowers during spring
Most of them are red with green leaves
Everyone thinks they're very beautiful
Your Highness does know how to tease someone indeed
A beautiful person will look good in anything
If you're well-versed in poetry and literature
Your disposition will be even more extraordinary
You will not suffer if you follow your Master
Young Mistress,Huan Bi ran out crying just now
She's not back yet
Just let her be
You may leave
No wonder you're angry
It's more difficult to guard against one of our own than an outsider
You noticed it too?
Pardon me for being nosey
Just now
This Huan Bi was too sharp-tongued
It's rare that you're so meticulous
I'm only afraid that the others are still kept in the dark
I have not mistreated her
Yet she couldn't hold back
Do you still want to give the band of silk cloth to Wan Bi?
Yes, give it to her
Take the pearl necklace on my dressing table and give it to her as well
It's obvious that Your Majesty didn't notice her
I want to see what havoc can she wreak
Yes
I guess that the trouble created by Can Qinmo of Qin Zheng Dian
is made possible by her leaking information
Maybe even the matter involving Princess Wen Yi this time
is related to her as well
That cassava powder
was brought back by her
Yeah, it's difficult to read one's heart
Only that we do not know who is behind her
Is it Princess of Glory? Or Precious Cao
I think Princess of Glory will not meet her directly
Most likely it's through Precious Cao
This lass
It's a wretched fate
But she's way too ambitious
She let down my intentions towards her for nothing
Do not let any news leak when you give the things to her
to prevent her from doing anything out of guilt or rashness
I understand
Bitch, dare to get in my way
Please do not be angry Your Highness
Since His Majesty has the intention of restoring
Your Highness's power of handling the Harem's affairs
it doesn't matter waiting longer
Princess Smile can stop once
don't tell me she can stop twice?
Wen Yi's affair last time
Not sure if His Majesty is suspicious of me or not
and hence listened to that bitch Zhen Huan fanning the flames
Please do not be paranoid Your Highness
General Nian has fought winning battles consecutively
His Majesty can't wait to be overjoyed
Why would he suspect Your Highness?
His Majesty has been visiting me often lately
Hopefully it isn't because of elder brother
Your Highness is getting more and more paranoid
It cannot be anymore normal for His Majesty to come here
This also proves that
His Majesty has not grown suspicious of Your Highness
because of the matter last time
Yes
His Majesty not allowing me to handle the Harem's affairs just yet this time, so what?
If His Majesty had allowed this time
It would have been mostly because of elder brother and not me
Not allowing me to shows that he treats me well
It's truly because of our relationship as husband and wife for many years
And not because of relatives
Exactly, so Your Highness
should just relax and not worry
Elder sister
It's rare that you come here
I heard that Princess Wen Yi followed you back
I miss Wen Yi very much
so I came here specially to take a look
I hope I'm not unwelcomed, am I?
You must be joking
I've been hoping day and night for you to visit me
I'm just afraid that
You're still angry with me over the stupid thing I did last time
I'm afraid that you're still affected over it
so I came here specially
We both serve His Majesty
we shouldn't draw the boundaries so clearly
Why should our relationship be spoilt
because of some small misunderstanding?
Exactly
Although I am older than you by a few years
I am a muddle-headed person
I believed those bastards' words last time
and caused you so much misery
I really deserve a beating
Don't mention the past
I know it's surprising for me to come over suddenly
Hope you're not offended
Nah
Liu Zhu
Yes
These are a few undergarments that I sewed myself
For the princess's use
My needlework isn't good, they're just some gifts of appreciation
Please do not despise them
And these makeup powder
They were handmade by Jin Xi in her spare time
It will make your face glow in pink and smooth
No harm trying it
You're too considerate
You're great with your hands
Look at this sewn flower, it looks
so real as if one can smell it's fragrance
These are nothing but normal things
I still have one thing to give to you
But it's not too convenient here
Can we talk in the inner chamber
Ok, follow me
You must accept this
What is this
This thing is just way too precious
I definitely cannot accept it
You better take it back
Originally I had something to ask of you
Now hearing you say this
It's making me unable to say my request
You may speak your mind if you have something to say
I definitely will not refuse if I can help in any way
Princess of Glory is elegant and classy
I respect her very much in my heart
But not sure what has happened, I have offended her
Only for her to misunderstand me
I am alone and lonely being in this Palace all by myself
And now Shen Da Ying is being grounded again
Now I'm even more lonely and alone
Hope you can take pity on me
You're being loved by His Majesty
and is as close as sisters with An Chang Zai
Why would you say something like that?
His Majesty only hasn't grown tired of me yet
thus coming over for two more days
Now there's An Meimei
Where will I stand in the future
Your words are making me sad
But aren't I in the same situation as well?
Although I have Wen Yi, but she's only a princess
Princess of Glory trusts you
I will have to depend on you to put in a few good words for me in front of her
If I can get Her Highness's attention for one day
I will be endlessly thankful
Her Highness will naturally learn of your good intentions one day
But...this item is simply too precious
It's better for you to take it back
I will try my best to put in a few good words in front of Her Highness
If this is really the case
I am willing to work faithfully for you and Her Highness
This small box of Mi He Xiang was bestowed by His Majesty
Heard it's a tribute from the exotic land
Just this small box is available
Hope you do not look down on it
It's the fragrance of Mi He Xiang
Just that this fragrance is light
One can't really detect it unless one smells hard
This fragrance indeed has an outstanding aroma
Only takes a little opening to obtain the aroma
Just after you left
The servants in Precious Cao's place threw away all the items that you had given
How would she accept my items sincerely
Was the fragrance thrown away as well?
What fragrance? No sight of it
Nothing, you may leave
Yes
Why are you so confident
that Precious Cao would accept the fragrance?
She has been under Princess of Glory for a long time
Not overstepping her boundaries in terms of food, clothing and makeup
Even her sleeping chamber is so simple
hence it's obvious she has never used
any expensive fragrance
what more Mi He Xiang?
Except for the Empress who doesn't love fragrances
Which woman will reject it?
Even if she is still very guarded against me
She still cannot bear to throw away the box of fragrance
One who is unable to give up fame and wealth
will forever be unable to make it successful
I've been following you for almost a year
You are slowly learning how to read people's intentions
You learn and grow through experience
Looking at how Mei Jie Jie has suffered so much
Can I be not afraid?
Actually, you only need to learn
how to read His Majesty's intentions which is enough
To rise in status in this Palace
one has to read His Majesty's intentions correctly
To live, you have to read
other women's intentions correctly
Are all the matters arranged as per instructed?
Yes as per instructed
Xiao Yun Zi and I have arranged them perfectly
No one else knows about it
Please rest assured
That's good to hear
Do not let down the efforts of my box of Mi He Xiang
It is one precious treasure indeed
Who is outside?
Master, the Internal Affairs Authority has sent over some jewellery
Do you want to take a look?
Understood
Pick two nice pieces of jewellery and send it to An Chang Zai
and tell Pin of Respects
that I will go over to her place to chat with her tomorrow night
It's not early anymore
Have your offerings been made?
I'm about to go out
Good, go early and return early
Help me make one offering as well
Make a little effort for me
Yes
Mother, I have already thought of all the ways
But I still cannot get what I wished for
I don't know what to do
Mother, you have been a servant all your life
And still had to be restricted by your Han identity
unable to obtain the status you deserved
Even I can only be a servant
Mother
Why, both Master and I being Father's daughters
Master can receive love from His Majesty and bring glory to the family
but I cannot?
Health and prosperity to Princess of Regularity
According to me
You better not waste a trip there
His Majesty has something on, he is not seeing anyone
His Majesty has been busy dealing with the war in the Northwest recently
He indeed is unwilling to see anyone, thanks for informing me
Eunuch Su
Master, His Majesty is waiting for you
Thank you
Master, Princess of Regularity's face has an awful expression on it
The way of dealing with relationships and people
Since its impossible to take everyone into consideration
one can only take care of himself
Health and prosperity to Your Majesty
With you taking care of things beside me
I will not feel frustrated however tough the state affairs are
Since Your Majesty allows me to enter in and out of the study freely
Naturally I cannot allow Your Majesty to dislike me
Huan Bi
I'm going to Xian Yue Court to see Mei Jie Jie
Why are you suddenly going there?
Didn't His Majesty say without an edict
anyone is not allowed to see Precious Shen?
I've been missing Mei Jie Jie
I need to ask her personally about some things
Huan Bi, you're my dowry maid
Not many people in the Palace have seen you
Hence I will claim to be you
and have Jin Xi bring me to Xian Yue Court to deliver some stuff
I've taken care of things over there already
I will wait into the night
and sneak in when the guards are changing shifts
It will be foolproof
But Master, if you get discovered
it will constitute as a major offence
Now you're receiving much love from His Majesty
There is no need for you to take this risk
I will lower my head and walk later
and will not be discovered by people
No matter I am being loved by His Majesty or not
I must make this trip
His Majesty will be sleeping alone tonight
There's no better opportunity than this
Young Mistress you must consider twice
I know
Huan Bi, wait in the sleeping chamber
Don't ever let anyone see you
Let's go
You're going out? Yes
Young Mistress please go in and change your clothes
Xiao Yun Zi is waiting inside
I hope I wasted my efforts today
You all better go, be careful
Yes
Master you're here
Is Pin of Respects here?
Yes
Xiao Yun Zi, wait here
Health and prosperity to Pin of Respects
You came in without a sound, you scared me
Seems like you're in a good mood
There's nothing to do, so I took a piece of cloth to make an undergarment
Come come come
Look at how well done is this undergarment
Ru Yi, pour tea
Yes
I'm not in a hurry, I'm here to chat with you
Once other people enter
they will spoil our moods to talk
Yes
Normally I also think they're too restrictive being by my side
Doesn't look like I restricted them
More like they're restricting me
You're always loving the peace and quietness
There are too many worries and frustrations in the Palace
If I do not let my heart quieten down
How am I supposed to pass the days?
Yes you're indeed right
Princess of Glory arrives
Princess of Glory
Why is she here?
She has her own reasons for coming here
Princess of Glory has gone to Xian Yue Court
claiming that Precious Smile's servant Jin Xi
brought someone to pass something in
to Precious Shen
Understood
Let's see what is going on first
Ok
Jin Xi only brought some daily products and food
and asked the servant to pass it to Shen Da Ying
Because there were many things
hence two servants from Palace of Shattered Jade were brought along
But there is no sight of Precious Smile
Master Fang Ruo is right
I simply obeyed the order of Precious Smile
to come here and pass some items
I did not defy His Majesty's order
to meet Precious Shen secretly
Really?
Didn't Jin Xi bring over two servants?
Why is there only you and this
who is that?
That is a maid of Palace of Shattered Jade, named Pei Er
Due to some matters in the Palace
I let her go back first
Really?
Then I need not
waste my time with you all here
I heard someone barged into Xian Yue Court
to visit a grounded concubine
It defies the Palace rules
So I came here specially to check it out
Precious Shen who is grounded, is kept under supervision according to His Majesty's order
Why would there be someone that is meeting up with her?
That may not be the truth
There are many people in this Palace who become arrogant because they're heavily backed
One cannot guarantee there will not be someone who is bold enough to do such things
Your Majesty, Pin of Respects's servant Ru Yi is here
Princess of Glory has kicked up a fuss outside Xian Yue Court
Seems like she's suspicious
of someone barging into Xian Yue Court without permission
to meet Precious Shen in secret
She wants to investigate this matter
Thee is seriously no single day of peace
Your Majesty is going to be busy again
Then I'll take my leave first
Being wifeless makes one carefree, I really envy you
I still thought
you were being frustrated over this set of dead chess game
I will solve this set tonight, you're not allowed to leave
It is unsure when will you return
Why don't you leave it til tomorrow before we play again
Then you'e not allowed to leave the Palace tonight
I will play with you again after I finish my court session
Su Pei Sheng
I am here
Get a room and tidy it up til it's clean
King Guo Jun isn't leaving the Palace tonight
Yes
Then Your Highness may sleep for a night in Peng Lai on River Heart Island
The place is far away from the concubines' living quarters
and it's quiet and classic
Ok
I will know immediately if there is or there isn't when I go in
Princess, there really isn't any other people inside
You really need not go in
I am following His Majesty's order
and really dare not let you in
I ask for your forgiveness
How dare you stop me
I do not dare to do so
Will you give way or not
Princess, Princess you must not go in, Princess
His Majesty arrives