Subtitles brought to you by The Legend of Zhen Huan Team
~ Episode 8 ~
"Precious Smile"
Has Precious Wan's stick been made?
Just finished.
We can add it tonight.
The Emperor hasn't given the order.
Keep it for now.
This Precious Wan is highly favoured.
Her stick will be flipped often in future.
Not wasting everynight's candlelight,
It's finally blossomed
The Emporer visits often.
He brings the Dragon aura, of course the flowers are blossoming.
Greetings to Precious Wan.
Mistress, you're lucky,
The Emperor grants you a bath in Soup Spring Palace.
And asked Jin Xi Gugu to serve.
Thank the majesty.
Jin Xi Gugu, please make everything ready
Sedan chair will be waiting outside afternoon.
Yes, I'll make everything ready for young mistress.
Then, Servant will go.
There is still a lot to prepare for.
Where is Soup Spring Palace?
Why use sedan chair?
Soup Spring Palace is a Royal pavilion of Chang Ping ( a place in Beijing )
His Majesty must think that the Royal Palace is too crowded
and thus wants to bring young mistress out
My young mistress is physically weak, and hot spring is best for her.
Your Majesty,
Has everything been prepared
When is the Emporer leaving?
At noon.
Su Pei Sheng just said
the Emporer has invited Precious Wan to the hot springs.
Jian Qiu. Tell the Emperor
I am feeling unwell today.
I cannot travel with His Majesty after all.
Yes.
Your Highness
Your Highness uses the Queen's spa
Precious Wan
will use the Concubines' spa.
She cannot disturb you.
The Emperor is in a good mood today.
I should let him be.
Your Highness is so virtuous.
If this were the Princess of Glory,
who knows what she'll do out of jealousy.
Is Your Majesty trying to be Emperor Han.
I dare not be Zhao He De.
Such impudence
You dare compare me with Emporer Han.
Your Majesty is sharp and wise.
Emperor Han is unable to compare.
Even though it is blatant flattery.
I like hearing it.
But you live in the Inner Palace
how would you know if I'm wise in Court.
Don't discuss matters of politics.
I don't know what happens in the Courts.
Except one thing.Your majesty
posess beauties more beautiful than Fei Yan, He De.
and more virtuous than Ban Jie Yu
Emperor Han is less fortunate than Your Majesty.
My Precious Wan posseses a ready tongue.
You are above Fei Yan's empty beauty.
I am indeed more fortunate than Emporer Han.
Scared?
I'm not scared.
No? You are not looking at me.
Girls are always scared during their first time.
I am not scared.
To Your Majesty I am just a normal girl.
But I see Your Majesty as my husband.
Tonight is my wedding night.
So I am nervous.
It's alright.
The servants by your side
shoud have already taught you.
I am fearful.
The servants taught me how to serve the Emperor.
But they never taught me
how to serve my husband.
I am too bold. Please forgive me.
Usually the girls are terrified when they serve.
They are too cautious; even the Queen is no exception.
No one has ever said anything like this to me.
Since you treat me as your husband
Don't be so so cautious in front of your husband.
Your Highness' back has been giving you pains.
You should rest after eating the medicine.
The Emperor is finally with her.
Being with her now means nothing.
Jumping to the rank of "Precious",
visiting her every other day,
even taking her to the hot springs.
He only took her.
He's treating her like Concubine Yang.
That Concubine Yang
met a untimely end.
The Emperor is temporarily smitten.
Yu was also high in his favour.
Now she doesn't exist to him.
Hopefully it is like that.
But who can guess His Majesty's heart.
What are you doing?
I've woken you up.
That candle is flickering.
The candle is giving light, I am happy.
Is there a story.
I've heard that one tradition of marriage
is to light a pair of candles on the wedding night
and keep it bright til morning.
That way the new couple will be together
forever.
But usually a Pheonix Candle is used.
This plain candle can be used in its place I guess.
I am over 40.
To ask you to grow old with me,
means I'll have to live to over 100.
The Emperor lives ten thousand years.
If you only live til 100 because of me,
you'd be getting the short stick.
You know how to comfort me.
Your Majety is making fun of me.
Since I believe in the candle tradition.
I think you are cute and naive.
In my life
I've only lit a Pheonix Candle once.
Not twice?
The Queen succeeded the First Wife position.
There was no need to re-enact a new wedding night.
Do you wish to grow old with me?
All girls under heaven
would want to grow old with their husband.
I am also this ordinary.
But I am scared.
Scared this is just wishful thinking.
You know that your ordinary wish
is hard to come by for me.
I value your wish;
I will not dissapoint you.
Don't cry.
Is there ink here
What do you need ink for.
I want to record it.
Your Majesty cannot go back on his word when it is in writing
So childish.
I am Son of Heaven, I do not go back on my word.
Don't worry.
Rest early Your Majesty.
You need to get up early tomorrow.
How can I rest with you here?
Respects to young mistress
Meimei
Respects to Precious Shen
Jiejie came this early?
I originally wanted to pay my respects to the Empress
but she wasn't feeling well, so there's no need.
So I came to see you
Look at you...your undereye circles have darkened
Didn't sleep well last night?
It's not that. Last night I was chatting with Pin of Respects.
It got late
Zhen jiejie has gone to the pavilion with his majesty.
She might have served his majesty last night.
Yes,
I wonder how's she doing.
To be sent back out of the Hall of Resting Soul...
I was probably the first.
Don't think about the past too much
It will be better next time
Next time?
How am I as fortunate as my two sisters?
When Zhen Jiejie returns, I will congratulate her
I pay my respects to the Empress
Jian Qiu, quickly help Precious Wan up
Yes, Niang Niang
Thanks Empress
Young mistress please get up
Please sit
You just recovered and returned to the palace
It's too hard for you to give a salute.
But the ancient rules dictate
that you have to came the day after serving his Majesty
so we have to follow it
I should have come early
and give the salute.
But I was in pavilion, so I come late.
It's my fault.
It's important to obey the rules
But it is more important
to search for a Win-Win Solution
You were in pavilion, accompany his Majesty,
I'll be happy if his Majesty is happy.
These salutes are just formalities
It's kind of you, my Empress
It's a fortune to the six palaces
that you're safe and sound.
No wonder his Majesty likes you
Your speech and actions are indeed endearing
Actually Meimei, with your beauty and talent,
you should have been favored long ago.
But until recently...
but not bad. Although through a lot
the moon finally come out from behind the clouds.
Meimei, in the future come and go often
and treat this place like your own home. No need to feel uneasy.
Yes
I really like the fruity fragrance in Niang Niang's palace
It smells especially comforting
Yes, I don't like to burn incense
I also find cosmetic fragrances too common,
so I ask them to put fresh fruits in the hall everyday.
Turned out to be good.
Niang Niang's unique way
I learned a lot.
Ever since Precious Smile has been sick,
Niang Niang wanted to visit you many times.
but young mistress were having seasonal epidemics
afraid of infection
didn't come.
But in Niang Niang's heart,
she often has concern for young mistress.
I'm appreciate Niang Niang's concern.
The choosing last year was
meant to pick conscientious girls to serve the Emperor
Now, you just need to keep healthy.
only in this way, can you please the empire and rise offsprings.
I'll keep Niang Niang's words in heart
I'm so agreeable with you,
that I can't help concerning about you.
It is too late now,
Jian Qiu, send Precious Wan out.
This is good
Young mistress
Xiao Yunzi?
At this time why are you not in the palace?
Why did you come here?
First servant wants to congratulate young mistress
You're little monky, come for sweet thing specifically.
We won't forget you
Gugu misunderstands me
I came here by imperial decree
Young mistress, for now please don't come back to the palace
Why?
Young mistress don't ask now
Please take a leisurely stroll through the royal garden
Very soon you will be able to return to the palace
Alright
Pin of Beauty Niang Niang, servant's stomach is not feeling well
Go
Although Kang Luhai now works for Jiejie,
he hasn't fixed his bad habit
of sneaking around at all.
Seeing as he once served Princess of Modesty,
I feel he is at least discreet.
Otherwise I wouldn't use him at all
Jiejie has such a good temperament
Abandoning a former master...
if it were me, I would absolutely not dare to do it.
This royal garden is so pretty
Yes
Yes, the flowers in this royal garden
are different from those anywhere else.
Servant greets Precious Smile. Fortune and respects to Precious.
It's Kang Luhai
Kang Luhai?
Young mistress still remembers servant?
Good morning Kang Gong Gong
You're not with Pin of Beauty?
Pin of Beauty and Precious Cao
went to pay their respects to the Empress.
Servant knew young mistress would pass through the royal garden on your way home
so I respectfully waited for you here.
Do you have some words from your Niang Niang?
No, it's not Niang Niang
It's just that servant has something selfish to request of young mistress
Speak
Servant heard that young mistress was promoted to Precious,
and wholeheartedly wanted to pay my respects and regards to young mistress.
But I couldn't, I had too many errands
His Majesty also ordered a decree
to not disturb young mistress's rest.
Servant longed for the stars and the moon,
so much that my neck is stretched out.
Until I pay my respects to young mistress, I won't have peace of mind
I like people who are direct
If you don't find servant too stupid,
with just one word from you,
I am willing to serve young mistress without any hesitation.
Your intentions are good
but does Pin of Beauty know?
This...
You are now her servant
If she knew of your thoughts,
I'm afraid she won't be too happy.
Besides, I am merely a Precious
How could I be at liberty
to ask Pin of Beauty for her servant?
Don't worry, you are in favour
Just one word from you,
who would dare go against you?
Just one word from you is enough
Great! So you pretended to have a stomachache
and snuck out here
just so you could meet up with your former master!
Respect to Pin of Beauty NiangNiang.
Respect to Precious Cao
You and I are the same
Meimei need not be so polite
You're also aware that you have the same status?
But she doesn't know her own status
Right, I heard that lately his Majesty
assigned quite a few servants to Precious Smile's palace.
Precious Smile doesn't already have enough servants
to order around?
To actually consider this useless servant of mine?
Not like that
Jiejie is so kind
to have received Kang Luhai
Since he is already Jiejie's servant,
how could I ask for him back on my own will?
Although I'm young and inexperienced,
I would absolutely not make such a mistake.
Precious Smile does know the rules
No wonder his Majesty favors you so much
I can only stay behind in the dust
His Majesty only pities me
because I was gravely ill recently.
In his heart,
of course he cares about Jieijie 100 times more than me.
Confused servant!
Upsetting Niang Niang first thing in the morning!
Slap yourself!
Servant deserves to die!
Jiejie
Why upset yourself over a servant?
What if you damage your health?
Servant deserves to die!
This servant is bent on climbing the higher trees,
too greedy.
we all say eunuchs are stupid ass without cock
they do not have one bit of dignity
These servants nowadays
disregard me more and more.
They chase after those who are powerful,
Why doesn't he think
of how he begged me back then
to dig him out of his live grave!
even learned to be a spy
Li jiejie, I know you're angry,
Not worth wasting
your words on a servant.
Disciplining a servant
I have ridiculed myself before Precious Smile
Since he's your servant,
Jiejie can punish him as you like.
to hit or kill, that is up to you
But there are many poeple in the garden
it may cause gossips
If you're so angry with him
you can take him back and then punish.
Alright,
I have to give the Empress my regards
Today, I show you some mercy.
Thanks! Li Pin Niangniang.
Thank you saved my life.
Thank you my young mistress.
You're clever,
If you didn't say in that way,
Li Pin Niangniang couldn't have forgive me
Li Pin may not forgive you
save your life on your own.
Li Pin and others dislike you
you, you,
Shame on him, flunkyism.
Even those maids around Li Pin
can dress Kang Lu Hai down.
He's having a hard time.
Servants should be loyal to thier boss.
Flip-floppers
will not be used by others.
Kang deserves it.
But Li Pin's words
were too tart and mean.
I was aggrieved for you when hearing that.
But I like her personality.
Congratulations, young mistress.
The room is made into Pepper room, It is a great honor.
Young mistress, look our palace,
so pretty.
Sweet! What's this smell?
It's wall! Young mistress, the wall gives out the smell!
It's his Majesty's command this morning.
We servants made it in a short time.
Hoping young mistress is pleased.
The pepper room is only used for newly-married.
Using pepper flower mixed with mud, stands for warm and many seeds (children).
Except for the Empress,
no other princess can have this rare honor.
Only Princess of Glory!
Congratulations young mistress!
Young mistress, please go inside
Young mistress, please look carefully at the bed
Is this a routine for those who are favored?
Thank you for your arrange, Seneschal.
Yes,but except the good intention underneath.
His Majesty actually took my words to heart like this
His Majesty heard this was a marriage custom among the among the people
and specially instructed us servants to do the same.
His Majesty also said if it wasn't for the hurry in the pavilions,
the present should have prepared already.
It's not the time matters, it's his Majesty's intention.
Alright alright, young mistress is tired from yesterday
Let's take our leave
Liuzhu, Huanbi
can stay behind to serve young mistress in her rest.
Yes
This is great, young mistress!
Now old master and madam can put their minds at ease!
Under the current circumstances,
his Majesty must really care about young mistress.
After suffering for more than half a year,
we can rest assured.
You are right
but the days ahead are still long.
The days ahead are long
but our young mistress's fortune is even longer.
Everyone else is carried out to serve his Majesty
but you are different.
His Majesty personally accompanies you there
Jiejie, you're laughing at me
I'm not laughing at you. I'm happy that he favors you.
But the other Pins might not be happy
There is open strife and secret struggles in the palace. One rises as another falls.
When has it ever stopped?
With Pin of Beauty's temper
she can't hide any of her thoughts.
She is more bark than bite,
I'm not afraid
You're right. Pin of Beauty is not a problem
but everyone knows that Princess of Glory stands behind her.
Now that you're honored with the pepper room,
you are following in her exact footsteps.
Jiejie, that his Majesty would treat me this way...
I didn't expect either.
These things came too quickly and too greatly
Greater than my wildest expectations
Jiejie, tell me. Is it real?
Of course it's real
Even I'm a bit envious
His Majesty's love is real
Pin of Beaulty's objections is real, too.
In the future, jealousy and hatred in the inner palace will also be real
Jiejie, tell me, what should I do?
Endure
Endure?
Princess of Glory dominates
Even the Empress can't touch her
much less those of our status.
You and I are newly favored.
When it come to the extraction and his Majesty's favor.
we are not equal in force.
Instead of acting up against greater forces, we should just wait calmly
So, you have to endure
You are right.
But, Jiejie, will you be angry?
We came into the palace together, I knew this would happen.
Although his Majesty hasn't asked me serve for several days.
I still have the chance to lift my head in front of others since you are favored.
We have been good friends for many years.
I envy you, but not angry.
Jiejie, will you be jealous?
A little
But there are many Princess who were favored in the palace
Princess of Glory, then you
and there will be others
If I am jealous of each one
I would rather die.
the moon is full
wonder if mom and dad are well at home
mistress is homesick?
being here by myself, how can I not?
mistress is not alone
Precious Wan, Precious Shen
and you are like sisters
mistress should visit more
right now Wan mistress is being favoured
You may meet his Majesty there.
Jiejie is favored now,
If I always visit her
I will annoy them
why would that be? mistress is thinking too much
Precious Wan always shares her good fortune with mistress
Like this morning;
she event sent two bolts of silk over
Jiejie was just being nice
No matter how strong the friendship is
you will break it if you are careless.
For example
Mei jiejie and Zhen jiejie are close friends.
but the day Zhen jiejie was favored
Mei jiejie couldn't go to sleep that night
Mistress, Shui Gong Gong of Rites has arrived
Greetings, Precious Wan
Why did gong gong come here himself?
His Majesty decreed
to have servant personally come here to tell mistress
that you will be spending the night with the Emperor
Thank you, Gong Gong
Your servant will take his leave
Mistress only came back the other day
But the Emperor wants to see you already
The Emperor really can't let you go
Don't talk rubbish
This way, please. His Majesty is still busy with court petitions
he will be here soon
Mistress please make yourself at home
Don't I need to go cleanse myself and change?
His Majesty wants you to wait here
Mistress should just wait
Thank you, Gu Gu
Your Majesty
Hungry? I have prepared some snacks for you
Why did the kitchen only prepare one bowl?
Your Majesty should eat first
I already ate in my study
Try it and see if it is to your liking
Thank you, Your Majesty
It's raw! (have the meaning of "birth")
You said it yourself
When my Precious Wan is angry, she is both cute and pitiful
Your Majesty is mocking me
All right
I did not intend to mock you
This bowl of wanton
was already eaten by you
I heard that commoner brides must eat wanton
But the palace has rules and I
can't do it exactly the same
But if it can be done, I will definitely do it for you
Your Majesty treats me so well
When I first saw you in the Royal Garden
you stood alone in the shadows of apricot flowers
That peaceful and distant expression
was as though the chaos of the back palace
had nothing to do with you
you stand aloof from the world
I am not as good as you just said
There are many others both beaultiful and talented in the palaces
I am no match for them
Why compare yourself with them?
Zhen Huan is Zhen Huan
You are the best in your way
She just became the Precious in a few days
and could publicly poach my servants
What will she be like in future?
It's because you don't discipline your servants well
but when can you change your short temper?
You should learn from Precious Cao
I can't let let any sand leave in my eyes
His Majesty favours her
so she will forget her place
As she forgets her place, His Majesty will stop liking her
Yu is an example
Precious Wan is timid;
she is afraid of you, and gives in to you
She didn't forget herself, but you lost your temper
Forgot your propriety
She is merely a new favourite
Newly favoured?
His Majesty gave her a pepper room
apparently following you
His Majesty often went to the palaces this month
nine out of ten were Precious Wan accompanying him
If you don't talk, then will you become a mute? (Stop talking)
Niangniang, have you seen good dogs
The dog that can bite don't bark
Earlier than yesterday
I was always wondering when the night would come.
I played chess with majesty this afternoon
and went back at dinner time
One-day's apart, feels like many years
one-meal's time
I felt like have spent a year
Precious Wan, served the night before last.
and then last night
This afternoon, she played chess with his Majesty
and now, she is still in Hall of a resting soul
Doxy
Always hanging around the emperor
Because his majesty likes it that way
Anyone else would be unable to even if she wanted to
As arrogant as Yushi was,
she's better than her.
Pavilion records
Slut!
You will die a horrible death!
Slut! Die a horrible death!
I pay my respects to the Empress
I came late. Niang Niang please forgive me.
Not late. You're young, it's understandable to oversleep.
Many thanks Niang Niang for empathizing
I...pay my respects to all the sisters
Rise
Thanks Empress
You've worked hard serving the Emperor the past couple days
It wasn't convenient for me to send things to you
The Lama Masters of Tibetan Buddhism contributed a few
consecrated blissful quilt with word "wan" to us.
I left one for you
If you use it to sleep in,
you may have a prince soon.
Many thanks Empress
But of course
If you have a prince soon,
you can catch up to Princess of Regularity.
Princess of Regularity has good fortune
Make sure not to have bad fortune
like 4th Prince's mother.
Not even a glance at 4th Prince...
Why are you bringing up 4th Prince again?
Are you at liberty to comment on the princes?
Fine if you choose to talk about this at the Palace of Benevolent Hope
But if His Majesty hears of this,
he will be angry.
Pin of Beauty, 4th prince's birth mother does not have good fortune
then why bother mentioning her?
Enough, you have all paid your respects. Everyone leave now.
I have to pay my respects to the Empress Dowager now
We respectfully send the Empress out
Why did you have to mention 4th Prince?
Upset now?
Being upset only hurts oneself
What are you afraid of?
Who is 4th Prince? Who is his birth mother?
Someone so kind like the Empress...
why did she get upset when he was mentioned?
I'm not sure either
I've only heard others vaguely mention it
4th Prince's birth mother was lowly and ugly
The Emperor dislikes her extremely
and as a result, also dislikes 4th Prince.
So they've been kept in Yuan Ming Garden Pavilion
and are not allowed to enter the palace.
If 4th Prince's birth mother is lowly and ugly,
why did His Majesty take interest in her?
Lower your voice
His Majesty was supposedly still a Duke at the time
It was a drunken mistake
For this incident, he was also harshly reprimanded by the late emperor.
At that time, nine princes strove for the throne,
No wonder His Majesty takes his anger out on 4th Prince
This is a hugely forbidden subject in the palace
Just pretend you don't know
Thanks Jiejie for warning me
Greetings Princess of Glory. Greetings Pin of Beauty.
Get up
Thanks Niang Niang
Precious Wan has always paid respects to the Empress
early in the morning.
Why were you late today? It's uncommon.
Sisters are diligent. I was lazy.
I dare not say you are lazy
You must be tired from serving His Majesty
unlike us, idle with so much free time.
Pin of Beaulty has served his majesty for a long time
must know a saying-- do not say things which are not conform to the rites
I am still young, I hope for more advice from Niang Niang
I haven't been in the palace for long. I have little experience.
If I have misspoken,
I hope that Niang Niang won't take offense.
Lately Precious Wan has been busy serving His Majesty
Precious Shen must be free
Do you have time
to copy the female Analects of Confucius for me?
It will also remind people in the harem to scrupulously abide by the model female,
to speak and act cautiously.
Niang Niang's orders, how could I not comply with?
But, when would Niang Niang like it by?
Not a hurry, take your time copying
When I want it, I will send someone to get it
Precious Shen seems thinner
Is it because His Majesty hasn't called for you lately?
Niang Niang jokes with me
But, it's because of the hot and muggy weather. I don't have an appetite.
I see
I thought it was Precious Wan's being favored
makes you sick
I dare not
Precious Wan is smart and pretty. Being chosen to attend to His Majesty
is common sense.
Never mind if you are anyone else
Precious Wan and Precious Shen are close sisters
how can you forget to share with your sister
when you are specially favored