His Majesty has arrived
Wishing your highness peace and fortune.
You may rise
Yes, your majesty
How is your mother?
In reply to your majesty
Mother went back
What?
Am I really that frightening?
I even scared away my mother in law?
Mother often says...
my father also reminded my mother
to avoid staying in the palace too long in fear of creating rumors.
Where are you coming from your majesty?
I just came from Chen Ju palace
Mei Jie Jie's Lotus Omanthus sweet cake tastes the best.
Did you try it?
The Lotus Omanthus cake was indeed sweet.
Yet the person wasn't sweet.
When I go
there were two out of three times that she doesn't get close with me.
Unless she's still angry at me for falsely accusing her.
Your Highness you mustn't blame her.
It is my fault.
I didn't mean to blame her so why are you admitting your guilt?
Why would Mei sister be mad at you for something that happened so long ago?
Forgive me if I say to much
Mei Jie Jie and I were childhood friends
and came in at the same time. We hope to stay by your side for a long time.
Mei Jie Jie has been thoughtful and thinks about your health.
If you spend too much energy on your concubines
it will eventually be harmful.
So she told me this in private.
She is worried
and also you are concerned with me a bit more than An sister.
Mei Jie Jie has decided to be like the historical Xian Concubine
and pray for your health rather than your physical self.
All in all Precious Hui seems to care a lot for me.
On this matter I am not as good as Mei Jie Jie
What?
I can't be like Xian Concubine
I, just want to be with you some more.
Although Xian Concubine is good
she also lost her appeal, not like you.
Niang Niang's long cherished dream is achieved. You don't have to worry anymore.
It doesn't disappoint my intentions.
I've created such good prospects for Wen Yi's future. I congratulate you.
Don't be in such a hurry to congratulate me, this is only the Imperial Concubine rank.
Consort, Noble Consort. I will climb up the ranks one step at a time.
The higher I climb the better Wen Yi's future will be.
In the future, she will be able to marry and gain a good husband.
Niang Niang you are over thinking it.
Actually if the princess gains the Emperor's love that's the most important.
You don't understand this
The Emperor is in his prime years.
Soon he will have more and more sons.
Princesses already aren't as valued.
If it was the Empress's daughter Gu Lun Princess then okay.
compared to a small Precious's daughter.
One small mistake
and I will have to take the path of Princess Chao
For the princess Niang Niang sure tries hard.
I only have Wen Yi this one daughter.
And she only has this one mother.
In this big palace
only the two of us have similarities.
Niang Niang please don't say that.
At least there is Imperial Concubine Wan.
We can't depend on Noble Consort Hua.
Imperial Concubine Wan even more so.
Coming and going when it is to their advantage.
If one day Imperial Concubine Wan prevents me from getting a "Consort" ranking
I won't have mercy.
I've heard that you ordered Nian Geng Yao to commit suicide.
Yes
Nian Geng Yao doesn't have the nerve to disobey.
Once Nian Geng Yao's matter has been resolvrd
you will have one less thing to worry about.
But Nian promised her...
How do you plan to deal with it?
Shi Lan and I
have been married for years and still have feelings.
There are many things I'm sorry for.
As long as she doesn't create problems
I will eventually give her the "Consort" title.
To let her live peacefully in the palace.
You used your emotions to make decisions.
But Precious Nian's attitude is as aggressive as fire.
This may be difficult.
Mother,
Right now it is a good time to grant Precious Cao as a "Consort"
I will tell her to bring Princess Wen Yi to greet you.
Sounds good.
I haven't seen Wen Yi for a long time.
You have done a good job of handling Precious Cao's issue.
It's not like I don't know that she betrayed her old master.
But that time
required her to do these things.
In exposing Promise Nian
only she can ensure everyone is convinced.
Your idea is very good.
But this kind of person
giving her a title is right,
but you shouldn't be intimate with her too much.
Who knows what she thinks about as she goes to sleep?
Both intelligent,
Imperial Concubine Wan is much better.
Being too smart isn't a good thing.
Nian Geng Yao's problem has been solved.
You don't need to speak to Imperial Concubine Wan about political matters anymore.
Although she listens appropriately,
listening to political matters too often will cause her to be too calculating.
If that happens it would be difficult to deal with.
I have my own judgements.
Although Nian Geng Yao has been disposed of
there are still people in the court who, like him, fight to be favored.
We have to clean them up one at a time.
Nian Geng Yao and Long Ke Duo
helped you become king and have accomplishments
Nian Geng Yao is bossy,
Long Ke Dong has aged.
You can allow him to go back home.
Mother has been thoughtful for Long Ke Dong.
Yet he might not be.
We'll talk about this in a few days.
Not to mention that I didn't bring up uncle Long Ke Dong.
How would mother first think of him?
It just came out of my mouth
It's getting late,
I will take my leave first.
Okay.
Be careful on your way out.
Yes.
His Majesty is leaving!
Zhu Xi,
Yes.
What do you think the Emperor's intentions are?
After Nian Geng Yao
does he plan to dispose of Long Ke Duo?
The Emperor isn't the type to be ungrateful.
Really?
But Nian Geng Yao's situation
is being discussed by many people
"The Emperor is harsh
and is ungrateful"
Nian Geng Yao has been unrighteous
But Official Long Ke Duo isn't.
But the things I have heard
Long Ke Duo sponsoring officials,
and creating factions
is not uncommon.
Empress Dowager,
Don't worry so much about the Imperial Court.
Healing yourself is the most important.
Cao jie jie,
Wan mei mei seems more energetic.
How can it not be? Cao jie jie is living well.
This morning Precious Qi entered the palace and lives in Chu Xiu Palace.
Now it will get interesting.
Chu Xiu Palace is wealthy and grand.
We can see how much the Emperor values Precious Qi.
Precious Qi's father Gua Er Jia E Ming
is the hero for managing Lord Dun and Nian Gen Yao.
The Emperor would naturally be more taken by her.
Yes.
Are you alright?
Get up.
What happened?
What's wrong?
Greetings to Consort Duan.
Greetings Niang Niang
No need.
What happened?
A bunch of worthless people,
How come you can't even properly watch over the princess?
Every day you know how to be lazy
Tomorrow when I return the Empress will beat the crap out of you.
Why don't you check to see that the princess is okay?
Thank you for helping, Consort Duan.
It's no problem.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
The princess just slipped
and I was able to catch her in time so it should be alright.
But you should call for a doctor to double check.
You are right,
Yin Xiu hurry and get a doctor.
Yes.
You may rise.
Little Wen Yi,
This child isn't afraid of strangers
and seems to be very close with you.
She's such a good kid.
Princess Wen Yi really likes Consort Duan
It's very nice.
Niang Niang why are you along?
Where is Ji Xiang?
I asked her to retrieve some water from bamboo leaves.
I was waiting for her here.
Careful you don't get your clothes dirty.
If you don't mind you can come to Sui Yu Xuan to get a change of clothes.
That will be good.
Huan Bi,
Escort her highness.
Yes.
Niang Niang can leave first, I will arrive shortly
It's a pity that my family is falling apart.
Although I have a Imperial Concubine title
It seems nearly impossible to ensure a good future for Wen Yi.
If I could be like Consort Duan and be a Consort
then that would be different.
I was just saying it,
please don't take it into heart.
Of course,
It's a good thing that you have these kind of feelings.
Even if you don't care about yourself you need to think about the princess.
I'm the princess's godmother,
I also hope that she will have a good future so I can benefit.
Then let's hope your words come true.
I can't compete against you for the Emperor's affection.
Your father just accomplished a major victory and has the Emperor's trust.
It seems that becoming a Consort is inevitable for you.
Wen Yi will have to depend on you.
Assist
Help
The Emperor selected these words for your title
and it has quite the deeper meaning.
But your words aren't very clear
so please explain it to me.
What is the reason for your "Precious" title?
It is because the Imperial Court subdued Nian Gen Yao's situation
and in the Harem
and Consort Hua needs someone in front of her to pull down.
You came at the perfect time.
So the reason why the Emperor gave you the "Precious Xiang" title is because of this.
Unfortunately Nian Shi Lan is still a "Promise"
Due to his affection,
the Emperor won't cause her too much grief.
Consort Duan is still in your palace changing clothes.
You should hurry up and go back.
I also need to go back with the princess.
After today's events you need to be careful.
Thank you.
Niang Niang
You've returned.
Please sit.
Jin Xi, take her highness's clothes and tell people to wash it.
Okay.
It's cold outside isn't it?
Sit please.
Niang Niang are your hands alright? Let me look at it.
It's fine, nothing is wrong.
Niang Niang hasn't ever liked Consort Hua
and Imperial Concubine Xiang was once her person.
How can you selflessly save her child?
The child isn't in the wrong.
You must really love that child.
I am destined to not have any kids.
So I can only show some love for other people's kids.
But that kid really is adorable.
She does have her mother's intelligence.
Hopefully,
she won't learn to be cunning like her mother.
People learn from what they see and hear.
Unfortunately it seems impossible.
If we can change her mother,
and teach her properly then it would be fine.
Greetings to the Empress and my fellow sisters.
You may rise.
Thank you your highness.
So it's true that you were born a beauty.
Come to the front so I can look at you.
Yes.
The person looks decent,
and the title is also nice.
There have been many happy events in the palace.
Precious Qi is very beautiful.
But her eyebrows
reveals a calculating personality.
The more people in the palace, the more calculating people will be.
The drama will also increase.
But in the palace there will only be more people and never fewer.
You guys guess,
will the Emperor visit her tonight?
What's so difficult to guess? Unless it's going to be you or me.
Oh you!
Her father is the hero for suppressing Nian Gen Yao.
Yes, I think that Precious Qi isn't an ordinary girl.
Of course.
The palace is going to get interesting.
Imperial Concubine Wan!
Wishing that Imperial Concubine and Precious Hui have good fortune.
Greetings Precious Qi.
Before I came in here, father had some instructions.
Your father and my father were at Du Cha together at one point.
So I especially came to greet you.
I have heard that your father
worked tirelessly to handle Nian Gen Yao and now the Emperor has rewarded him generously.
You are exaggerating.
I just came here so if there is something I do incorrectly,
please help me out.
We made it clear that we are old friends,
and yet you still speak so formally, aren't you making yourself a stranger?
If you don't mind,
Can I go to your place to sit?
Of course. I'm only worried that you won't come.
Emperor.
Someone from Jing Shi has come.
Emperor,
It's time to choose the person.
What is that sound outside?
Yes
I will go look
Precious Qi,
Sister, I came here to accompany you.
How come you didn't tell me you were moving here?
That way I can arrange things for you.
I just came here and feel very close to you.
And I saw that you are the only one living in Sui Yu Xuan
and thought it would be lonely.
So I specially asked the Emperor and Empress to live with you.
But Sui Yu Xuan is far away
how can it compare to Chu Xiu Palace?
Please don't be upset for making my own decision.
In this palace I have no one to rely on.
And the sisters in Chu Xiu Palace aren't easy to get along with.
I just hope for peace
so I came here to be by your side.
Although Sui Yu Xuan is a bit far, it is the most peaceful place.
As long as you like it it's fine.
but...
the west wing was once inhabited by Precious Chun.
Why don't you go to the East wing?
It's bigger too.
Thank you sister!
Miss, everything is ready.
You can leave.
It is quite smaller than Chu Xiu Palace
but it is indeed a nice place.
You may like it, but I think that it is small and far away.
Going to the Emperor's place would take a very long time.
It isn't nearly as convenient as Chu Xiu Palace.
Chu Xiu Palace is convenient,
But there's many people watching.
Although Sui Yu Xuan is far,
but as long as the Emperor thinks of me,
the distance doesn't matter.
I'm just worried that you will feel wronged.
Before you came in the master told us many times
that when you come here you must stand tall.
Standing out is of important matter.
But I can't become someone who will be calculated by others.
Everyone knows that the Emperor likes Imperial Concubine Wan.
Staying by her side
I won't be at an disadvantage.
Last night you served him
and came here early so it's fine.
Yet you personally help me get ready.
You have worked hard.
i was able to come to the palace because of your care.
Or even if I wanted to serve you I wouldn't be able to.
In the end your father is successful.
The Emperor knows of his accomplishments
or otherwise nothing I said would have worked.
Three years ago during the big serving girls selection
I was sick and missed it. It was a huge regret.
I thought I could depend on this year's selection
but who knew that he wouldn't choose?
Thankfully with your words you were able to grant my wish.
Helping you is helping the Manchurian people.
Take a look around
Beside me and Precious Fu Cha
everyone else is Han.
Before, Consort Hua was. Now Imperial Concubine Wan also is one.
The Han people get affection...
How do we make ourselves known?
My father also said this.
Both are heroes for subduing Nian Geng Yao
Yet why do some get to become officers of the Board of Civil Chancery
but my father is only a vice minister, ranking below others?
There are two kinds of people in this world.
One is first sweet then bitter, the other is first bitter than sweet.
It depends on which one you choose right now.
I choose to work first and then enjoy life.
That's good.
The others can climb their way up because they have a daughter who is being loved.
You can also do that
If you want to receive affection, the best way
is to watch others and see how they behave.
Thank you Empress
The Empress is so kind to you
and thinks of everything for you.
It's not for any reason
other than we are Man.
Of course she would treat me well.
Young miss is getting affection from the Emperor
Of course the Empress wants to keep you close.
Of the things the Empress awarded us select some of the better ones to give to Imperial Concubine Wan.
This will be a token of my gratitude for living with her.
Who is so insolent as to not bow to Precious Qi?
It's no other than concubine Hua.
But you are forgetful
You still think about your previous glorious days,
yet forgot that it collapsed and disappeared.
Collapsed and disappeared?
This phrase was well said.
You rely on your family's accomplishment to come into the palace.
What difference is there between you and the old me?
You think you are living in a wonderful dream.
I'm afraid you'll only end up just like me.
You are only a small "Promise"
yet you offend me.
Wait until I tell the Empress and Imperial Concubine Wan.
So what about the Empress?
So what about Imperial Concubine Wan?
Back then they both lost to me.
And you think you can do better? You are nothing but a maid next to them.
Even though right now they may be content,
do you think they will be like that forever?
Let's wait and see.
Miss, let's hurry up.
It's illegal to burn paper money in the palace.
If we get discovered we will be punished severely.
In Yi Kun Palace there are only the two of us left,
and I can't leave the Forbidden Palace.
If I don't burn some money for brother here,
where would I go?
And there's only you
you've been dragged down with me
but you're still willing to stay with me.
I have served you since I was very young.
Everything I do is necessary for you.
I better go outside and watch.
Today you offended Precious Qi, there might be trouble.
Why should I be afraid of her?
If she wants to come, fine.
If the Emperor wants to kill me, fine.
Right now, living
and dying means no difference to me.
Don't be too sad, miss.
We still have many days ahead of us.
But the Emperor,
he killed brother, Nian Fu and Nian Xing.
He's ended our relationship.
What else do I have to live for?
This life
will be spent waiting to die in here.
The Emperor is so unfeeling.
It is all because of Zhen Huan that wrench.
Even if I die,
I will never have mercy on her.
Where is Su Xi?
According to your wishes Su Xi went to work.
His majesty has arrived.
Greetings Emperor.
What's wrong?
You aren't happy?
Since I've come out of my mother's womb I've never suffered so much.
What exactly happened?
If you don't tell you how am I supposed to know your grievances?
Emperor, when I came here,
I don't know if there are different statuses.
Of course.
If someone of lower status offends the one above,
Shouldn't they be punished according to the rules?
You're right.
Look at you. You've said so much yet still haven't gotten to the point.
How am I supposed to bring justice for you?
I encountered Promise Nian
when,
she didn't respect me
and said that I came to the palace due to my family's accomplishments
and that I am living in a dream.
Then I will end up like her.
Promise Nian's personality isn't that great.
Just ignore her.
Look at you,
after crying your make up is smeared and your face is crooked.
It's not pretty anymore.
Emperor you are being biased.
You just said that the ranks need to behave appropriately
yet when you heard it was Promise Nian you don't care anymore.
She has the nerve to treat me like this
If she kills me one day,
that's not impossible.
Okay,
if you get killed I will be sad.
Go wash your face,
and let me handle this issue.
Really?
Then I can relax.
Su Pei Sheng
Yes?
Did what Precious Qi say really happen?
Emperor,
Precious Qi's words hold truth
but Promise Nian also had a reason
Today marks three weeks after her brother's death.
No wonder her mood isn't good.
I heard that last night Precious Qi was upset.
As a girl, losing her temper like this is normal.
Precious Qi isn't the type to make a fuss
so this time there must be a good reason.
Not really, it's just being mad at Promse Nian.
Promise Nian is really something
It's gotten to this point and she's still restless.
Promise Nian has made many errors
The Emperor has been gracious yet she still can't change.
It really is betraying his kindness.
Then what do you think we should do?
Nian Geng Yao has died.
Leaving Promise Nian's life is already showing mercy.
Yet she doesn't know how to be repentant.
Your majesty why don't you punish her harshly?
Kill her, so the Harem can have some peace.
Come,
You are very smart,
and ruthless as well.
You think that Imperial Concubine Xiang is ungrateful and disloyal,
because she wants to kill her old master.
Then I also believe
that this type of person
shouldn't be left by your side.
Actually I know
that Shi Lan's personality isn't evil.
Many things,
were the result of Imperial Concubine Xiang's schemes.
Thankfully Imperial Concubine doesn't have a prominent family.
And you don't show her a lot of love.
or else this type of sly and evil woman
would have been able to stay.
but Wen Yi is still small
and can't leave her mother.
There are plenty of women who don't have kids.
I think
that concubine Jing and concubine Duan are fine.
They both really like kids,
as much she does.
Miss wake up.
I just heated some medicine to calm the nerves.
You should drink it before you sleep to feel better.
In your reply,
What?
In these past few days I've been attentive
and noticed there are always people outside peeping at us.
You clearly saw it?
Yes.
There were two time that I was unsure of,
but I definitely saw it twice.
His disguise is as a road sweeper.
He hides by the corner of the wall.
Did you see who it was? Which palace her was from?
It's the servant from Promise Nian's place.
His name is Su Xi.
After the Emperor disposed of Zhou Ning Hai, it's been Su Xi who's been serving her.
I've seen him carrying flint around with the intent to use it.
Only the palace's rules are strict and he hasn't gotten it yet.
Do you want me to capture him and take him to the Emperor?
Just ignore him.
Make sure that you watch his every move.
Don't alert him to anything.
Yes.
I will take my leave.
Today's sunshine is really nice.
Go invite Mei jie jie to come play chess.
Yes.
But today the Empress invited Precious Qi and them to watch opera.
Do you want to go too?
I heard that Precious An is going too.
Today it's their turn to be the main character.
I won't go disturb them.
Go invite Mei jie jie.
okay.
Today I've called you to watch opera
because it is almost the new year.
I believe that everyone will miss their homes.
Secondly, here we don't have to talk so formally like in Jing Ren Palace.
Niang Niang is generous. We will keep that in our hearts.
Okay, get up so we can watch opera.
Thank you.
Thankfully Empress is here.
Otherwise when it's the new year
I would feel all empty inside.
Including being bullied and be looked down upon.
In my heart -
Living in the Palace is different from living at home.
No matter what you will feel upset.
But everone here ares sisters.
So we must treat each other well.
With your words I feel so much more warmth in mt heart.
Precious Qi speaks so eloquently.
You've said everything we wanted to.
It makes us seem inarticulate.
Now we don't know how to say anything.
Listening to your conversations makes me think you are talking to family members.
I feel very comfortable listening to it.
As long as you don't mind my rambling then it's all good.
At home I have two concubine sisters but we can't carry conversations.
But after seeing you I feel as though I have many things to say.
I have misspoken, please forgive me.
Empress, Precious Qi didn't do it on purpose.
No matter, let's watch the opera.
Thank you.
Please forgive us.
I've already said
that we are all sisters and don't need to hold grudges.
Get up.
Thank you for your generosity.
You may all leave.
Yes.
You are also tired, why don't you retire early?
Talking to Precious Qi is indeed tiring.
But you are different, you are smart.
Thank you for your compliments.
But I hope that you won't be mad at Precious Qi.
Precious Qi is foolish but is a beauty.
The palace needs this type of woman.
To serve the Emperor well one does not need intelligence, beauty is all that's necessary.
This type of person ensure that his love will be split and not compete for it.
So I like you.
You aren't the most beautiful but you are clever and loyal to me.
I am a boring person but being by you
I will definitely be loyal.
Being loyal isn't just something you say.
Time reveals a person's true character.
I understand
I'm petty and lowly.
I have no title and I'm only a "Precious"
I can't compete with Precious Qi
So what if your background is low?
I was also born from a concubine.
So I hate it the most when others say the words "of lowly birth"
But then again so what?
I still am the mother of the entire kingdom.
At least your father was the county magistrate of Song Yang.
If you think your background is really that bad, why don't you use your charm to turn things around
and rise?
I thank you for your advice
and will definitely keep your words in my heart.
Wrong, wrong!
I want to change my piece.
Don't be like that.
Fine fine.
It's inevitable that I'm going to lose anyways.
I don't want to play anymore.
What's with you.
You can't win so you don't play properly.
You're being so petty.
Here, let's play again.
I am really troubled
even if we play ten more times I will still lose.
I know why you are frustrated.
But the time isn't right.
You've been loved for so many years
but having results isn't something that can happen immediately.
You don't understand the hatred in my heart.
I can only hate even more.
The one I lost was my flesh and blood.
Where's Precious Qi? Has she returned?
You've forgotten
After she watched the opera she went to Consort Jing's palace to have dinner.
The snow outside has just melted.
I'm afraid she can't find her way
Go light some extra lights by her door.
Su Xi has arrived.
He sneaked into Precious Qi's sideroom.
After so many days
he finally has a chance to do his deed.
Whether or not he's able to all depends on you.
If I don't grant his wish
how will he tell his master?
What are you two talking about?
You wait outside first.
After the flames rise then catch him.
Yes.
Jie jie
Do you want to see how Nian Shi Lan digs her own grave?
Come with me.
Precious Qi's hall connects to mine.
If the fire on her side grows
I won't have a high chance of surviving.
This is oil used for brushing hair, what are you doing?
Don't say anything.
What are you doing, don't hide it from me.
Nian Shi Lan sent someone to burn me to death.
I am not harming anyone
but I can't let others kill me.
So
you want to help her.
I'll count it as "borrowing flowers to present to the gods"
Okay, if we are going to act then we need to do it thoroughly.
I don't want her to have a chance of living.