~ Episode 17 ~
Huanbi Jiejie, your outfit is beautiful
Back at the imperial kitchen,
even those eunuchs were staring at you.
My outfit is the same as young mistress Lingrong's
Young mistress loves Jiejie the most
She shares all her good things with Jiejie
Say, do I wear this outfit better
or does Lingrong wear it better?
Before, about the same
But Jiejie's earrings are sublime
Are they gifts from young mistress?
She's born from a poor family
The best cloths would be a waste on her
Let servant pick it for you. Young mistress watch your step.
Young mistress, look!
What's the big deal?
Young mistress, look. The outfit Huanbi is wearing...
Isn't that the one you gave to Precious smile?
Indeed
Precious Smile is quite generous
Such great material...
Young mistress, you couldn't even bear to wear it yourself
leaving two for her.
But she...gives it to servants!
Don't say nonsense!
Huanbi is Jiejie's close servant from back home
She normally does dress better than others
It's fine if she doesn't want to wear it
but Huanbi is only a servant.
Giving it to her...then what does she think of you?
It smells so fragrant
What took you so long?
It was easy to get the chestnut cake
but I saw that the imperial kitchen had some yuca powder
so I also brought some back.
I thought I'd make some pearl balls tonight
as a late-night snack for young mistress.
You're thoughtful
Since favoring Lingering An,
His Majesty has also relaxed a bit.
Before, he would spend 6-7 hours at a time
reading documents
without taking a break.
Listening to songs relaxes him
He should
You are sensible, unlike that moody Princess of Glory
Come
Don't be afraid. It's just a cat.
I heard Persia gave a cat as gift
which the emperor gave to 3rd prince.
This is the one
3rd prince is filial
He knows that Princess of Regularity likes cats
so he gave it to her.
But when Princess of Regularity brought it over the other day,
So she gave it to me
I gave it a name, Pine nut
Pretty name
You hold it?
I forgot. You're afraid of cats.
Empress shows care for me
You need not remember these little things
Come, sit
Actually, although I really like it,
I must be careful.
It is an animal after all
If I'm not careful and get bitten or scratched,
that would not be good.
Empress worries too much
Pine nut was raised by you
It's very docile
Really?
Even people are unpredictable, much less animals
It's easy to let your guard down around those who are docile and close
Today's the 7th
His Majesty invited all the dukes and inner palace
to enjoy the full moon at Chang Chun garden tonight.
Don't be late
Yes
Tonight's the 7th
I wish Your Majesties everlasting love,
fortune, and longevity.
We sisters forgot
It's a shame
I see that the grapes on your table are a tribute
Give them to me
Yes
Your Majesty, you have some yourself
What do you want mine?
I see that you're busy talking,
not eating,
so you might as well give them to me and not waste them.
Your Majesty likes to joke with me
Lately, His Majesty
only likes to joke with Lingering An.
To others,
it sounds like you're trying to steal her thunder.
I have little talent and even less learning
Niang Niang please advise me in more matters
I would like to toast Princess of Glory
Princess of Glory is magnanimous
I'm a bit drunk. I want to take a walk outside.
This is my first time here. I'm not familiar with the garden.
How about Auntie Jin Xi go with young mistress?
Your Majesty, I toast you
It feels so confined here
This Chang Chun garden
used to be the late emperor Kang Xi's favorite temporary residence.
After he passed away, it became more deserted.
Look, just ahead is Tonghua Terrace
Young mistress wants to walk around outside
It's too noisy near the banquet
Let's go look inside
Tonghua Terrace?
Such a unique, elegant name is rare in the palace
I heard that
that the Chinese parasol tree is the most loving, virtuous tree
so the late emperor dedicated this place to Princess Shu.
But it's a pity, that Princess Shu
During the late emperor's rule she was highly favored
But now she's a nun. It's really sad.
Why is it so deserted?
After His Majesty took the throne,
Empress Dowager thought Tonghua Terrace was too worn down.
People rarely come here
so it gradually became deserted.
No matter how beautiful the love and things were
they just lasted for only a short time
Tonghua Terrace is such an example
so was the love between the late emperor and Princess of Su
Yes
You stay here. I will go take a look.
Be careful!
Tonghua Terrace
Do you know what flower that is?
Who?!
Why does Precious Smile ask "who"
everytime you see me?
Seems that my appearance
is indeed not very memorable.
Duke loves to sneak up behind people
Of course it's alarming
It's Precious Smile who walked up before me
and didn't see me.
It is not I who likes to hide behind you
Tonghua Terrace is full of plants. I failed to see you.
But why didn't Duke say something earlier?
I thought you looked worried today
unlike in the past
so I dared not alarm you.
But I still ended up frightening Precious Smile
That was not my intention
I'm just a bit drunk. Thanks for Duke's concern.
There is a celebratory banquet in the palace
Why is Precious Smile out here?
Tonight is the July 7th (Chinese valentine's day)
the moon light is more attracting
Exactly
(Poem about July 7th) When autumn’s Golden Wind embraces Dew of Jade
All the love scenes on earth, however many, fade
If we just drink during such a beautiful night
What a waste
Just as you said
I was literary pursuits by a fluke for once
Precious Smile seems to really like the flowers on the terrace
Indeed
When I was young, I often saw them outside in the fields
They're called morning glory
I rarely see this flower in the palace
so they are even more unique.
This flower has another name - sunset
Indeed it shouldn't be in the palace
The palace does not plant flowers with such a short lifespan
Flowers also have short lifespans?
I thought only women did
They say this flower is lowly, just bloom in the corner
blooms at dusk, and falls in the next morning
no one enjoy it, so the saying goes
So it is called short lifespan?
But I think this flower is extraordinary
sunset
it is the beautiful sunset scenery
Do you think so
I just don't want to regard such a pure and beautiful flower
as short lifespan
Where is Precious Smile
Your majesty
young mistress was drunk, so she went to the side hall to change clothes
Smile Jiejie is usually weak-headed
can't compare with your majesty's great capacity for liquor
The imperial family's night
Precious and I come here to avoid the noisy world
it is not proper
I'm nearsightedness
I can only see the sunset
I heared that Lingering An
is introduced to his majesty by you
are you feeling sorrow because of her?
We are sisters in the palaces
you are joking
Actually it's a good thing to have someone share the favor
If Precious Smile monopolizes all the favor
and becomes the object of hatred in the six palaces,
I would really cry for you.
Many thanks Duke
Precious is exceptionally intelligent
My words are superfluous
But as a bystander,
I find that you seem to have walked into a puzzle.
So I wanted to say something
It's very kind of you to advise me
Imperial brother is the ruler of the country
On some things, he has no choice
I hope Precious will understand him
I'm actually very glad
to not be the emperor.
I need not be bothered by all these worries
Duke's name is known everywhere
I'm afraid you're the prince charming many girls dream about
I dare not be greedy
I only wish for one soulmate to spend my life with
don't want many beautiful concubines.
Easy said
Precious doesn't believe me?
I personally think that
to truly love someone
is to cherish each other
and not hurt each other in any way.
If Duke's words are true,
then the future 17th Fu'jin is very fortunate.
your suggestion is very commendable
Precious need not thank me
I just don't wish imperial brother to favor Precious too much
causing Precious to follow in my mother's footsteps.
only the candles and Buddha accompany her
It is rare for emperors to have true love
if they do
they will hide it in the dark
and others also can't accept it
Just like sunset, only blooms for one night
I've been out here too long, I must leave now
When I abruptly showed up last time,
it was not my intention.
The day of Princess Wenyi's birthday,
was also the day Mother entered the palace many years ago.
I was thinking of the past, and couldn't restrain myself in the moment
I lost my manners
I don't know what Duke is referring to
I don't even remember
Yes...I don't remember either...
Goodbye
What took you so long outside?
I don't have much alcohol tolerance. I went outside to get some fresh air.
I saw a type of flower called "sunset"
I was mesmerized
Sunset? What kind of flower is that?
I saw that the crape myrtles in the courtyard were blossoming well
I will order someone to bring you several pots
Now is the season for crape myrtles to bloom
Many thanks Your Majesty
Your Majesty is so good to Sister Smile
His Majesty treats everyone in the six palaces equally
He's also very good to Jiejie
Yes
Your majesty give each of us equal favor
Empress and all the concubines in the harem
are nourished by your favor
I'll drink a toast
Your Majesty, I have something to take care of. I would like to pardon myself.
What's so urgent?
Just now, the maid told me that Wenyi started throwing up her milk again
How could that happen?
Didn't she already get better?
Has the imperial doctor come to look at her?
The imperial doctor came several days ago
The doctor said she was born to be weak
and the weather is hot, so she got sick
She had already gotten better
I odn't know why she's throwing up again
Doesn't Jiejie find this odd?
How so?
Babies often throw up
but Princess Wenyi keeps going back and forth.
If it's due to hot weather,
Princess Wenyi is staying in Princess of Glory's Hall of Cool and Refreshing.
That place is the coolest
In the past, I never heard of Princess Wenyi
throwing up milk.
It indeed happened suddenly
Perhaps she will get better after some good care
Mothers always love their children
Let's hope that Precious Cao and Princess of Glory
can take good care of Wenyi.
Jiejie means...
For one's own glory and favor...
For a mother, isn't that too cruel?
I always thought people were kind by nature
but after all I've seen and heard in the palace,
nature can also be distorted.
I cannot rule out such a malicious intent
I heard the servants say
that wives in the previous court
would often use their infant children to fight for favor.
Mothers are naturally the warmest, gentlest people in the world
but in order to gain favor and glory in this palace,
they will not hesitate to use their children as weapons.
even their own children were used in such ways by themselves
no wonder many concubines hated other concubines' son
in order to get promoted
Jiejie need not lament about others
Jiejie has been favored for a long time
and should have had your own child by now.
Me?
I wish I had one when I don't
but if I have one, there will be many troubles
so let the fate decide
Lately I often hear a woman singing
with a voice like an oriole.
That should be Lingering An
Hearing her voice
makes me think of when Empress Chun Yuan was still here.
Niang Niang
Niang Niang, it's windy at night
Let's go inside
A barren woman...
who still cares about her health?
Niang Niang, don't be sad
I'm no longer sad
In my heart, I only feel hate
Niang Niang
I've never forgotten
how Princess of Glory force-fed me safflower poison back then.
After so many years,
the taste of that drug
is still in my mouth.
Niang Niang!
We will have an opportunity
Not only do we need an opportunity, we also need the right person
Niang Niang means...
The first time I saw her face,
I just knew
that she would definitely help me someday.
Don't cry, don't cry
Look
Your Majesty, the rattle drum you wanted
Princess still doesn't seem to be better
The imperial doctor is useless
I am useless
Your Majesty, you can't rush childrens' sickness
I saw that princess likes the water chestnut soup
how about preparing some more
and everyone can also have a try
Fine, I'm hungry, too.
I'll oder them to prepare
I saw that princess like it,
she's getting well
Thanks Empress' concern
also becouse of Princess of Glory's effort
she's working hard to look after the princess
Young mistress, princess hasn't got well
she spit out the milk againg
even the water chestnut soup has all been spit out
What's the matter
You have been treating her for two days without any effect
instead, she's getting worse
I...I really don't know
According to my common sense
infants usually regurgitate milk
when one or two months old
cause by the slender pylorus
but princess is already 1 year old now
useless
your majesty, don't be angry
you'd better let the imperial doctor check her carefully
In my opinion
princess suffers from indiestion
she probably eat something bad for her stomach
I want to check the food
that princess has had these days
Your majesty, I think the water chestnut soup has problem
To be careful
please let the food-taste Gonggong distinguish as well
Xiao Xiazi
Here
Your majesty, the water chestnut soup is non-poisonous
but there is some cassava powder in it
Cassava powder? What's that
Cassava is a kind of tribute from southeast Asia
its powder can be a material to make dessert
but its roots and leaves are poisonous, should be cleaned carefully
In your point view, it was poisoned by someone
Cassava is non-poisonous itself
but the infant's stomach is weak
it will irritate the infant's stomach and cause vomit
if continue to have it for a long time, the infant will die
Besides, the cassava powder and water chestnut powder are similar
in their colour and appearance
if they are mixed, it will be difficult to distinguish
Your majesty, princess had it every day
it must be the reason
How is the imperial kitchen doing its job?!
To even mix this up?!
The imperial kitchen is skillful at food, it can't be them
I think someone must have done it on purpose
How sinister
Trying to kill my daughter?
Your Majesty, Heavens please take pity on Wenyi
As her mother, I'm willing to accept any punishment
Quickly get up
What's the use in begging the heavens?
There is definitely someone behind this
deliberately giving you mother and daughter a hard time.
Your Majesty, please take pity on Precious Cao and her daughter
by thoroughly investigating this matter.
It will also eliminate such behavior in the palace
Then let's investigate it
Get the head of the imperial kitchen
to bring everyone who has been in touch with the cassava powder recently.
Then check which palaces have taken the powder
Don't miss a single one!
Niang Niang, drink your medicine
Why did it take so long to bring the medicine today?
I heard the imperial doctors say
that Princess Wenyi is always throwing up
so I asked some questions.
Do you think it's odd?
I don't know
I'd like to take a walk today
and visit the princess along the way.
Niang Niang has been secluded for many years, why go out now?
Secluded?
It's just a pity that while the tree prefers calm, the wind blows constantly
Servant checked
Only Precious Smile's palace
had someone pick up cassava powder four days ago,
saying they wanted to make pearl balls.
Aside from her, no one else
Four days ago, I wanted to eat water chestnut cake
so I asked Huanbi to pick some up.
When she returned, she did indeed bring some cassava powder
to make pearl balls for me.
Then, dare I ask Precious Smile...is the cassava powder still there?
I'm sure it hasn't been used up yet
Only people from Precious Smile's palace have picked it up?
No one else?
Yes
That doesn't prove Precious Smile did it
Replying to Your Majesty,
during the July 7th banquet Precious Smile went out by herself.
Servant seems to have seen Precious Smile walking towards Princess of Glory's
Hall of Cool and Refreshing.
Did you see it with your own eyes?
With my own eyes, absolutely
Servant saw it too
At the time, young mistress was also with Auntie Jin Xi
At the family feast
most of the servants in the Hall of Cool and Refreshing were serving by the side
the others were snatching a moment of leisure
very likely, someone has caught the chance
to poison the food
It seems that
Precious Smile, you're so cruelhearted
Maybe my inappropriate words and deeds
have offended Precious Smile unintentionally
but that day in the Hall of Policy
I was definitely unintentionally
didn't meant to cause misunderstand
between your majesty and you
But if you held the grudge because of this
you can just beat and scold me
don't harm my Wenyi
She's just a infant in the swaddling
Cao Jiejie misunderstood me
I never thought you offended me
As to the case in the Hall of Policy
there's no misunderstanding between his majesty and me
no need to mention grudges
Could it be that you think
you have done something bad for me
but I didn't even realize
Precious Cao, the case is still unclear
your weeping and wailing behavior
is undignified
Yes
I saw it clearly
by saying this
Empress is partial to Precious Smile
Princess of Glory, according to the ritual
you can't say such words to me
I was unintentional to offend you
but the princess has suffered so much
I think it is unfare to Precious Cao
Your majesty, please help her
even though you're concerning about Wenyi, you should respect Empress as well
after all, she is the master of the harem
Precious Smile, say what you want to say
I have never done such thing
and I won't
Have you been to the Hall of cool and refreshing that night
I have passed by the Hall of Cool and Refreshing
but I never walk in
Jinxi was with me, she can be my witness
Jinxi is your maid, her word can't be counted
Except for the imperial kitchen,
only your palace have cassava powder
besides, these maids have seen you
walk towards the hall of cool and refreshing
after that, princess got sick
I'm afraid it's not the word -- coincidence,
can explain
Though everything is pointing at me
I've never done this
Your Majesty, Empress, please clearly investigate
Since you say you didn't do it,
then after leaving the banquet that night
did you meet anyone?
who can prove you didn't enter the Hall of Cool and Refreshing?
Which also proves you have nothing to do with this
I...did not meet anyone
But I don't know if anyone else
saw me not enter the Hall of Cool and Refreshing.
Think carefully
If you think of anyone
who can prove you didn't enter the Hall of Cool of Refreshing,
tell me.
Then I will just have to ground you for the time being
Trust me, I will definitely get to the bottom of this
I will not falsely accuse anyone
Even you said so
Yes, I trust you
Then you will have to bear it for a while
Your Majesty
That night, Precious Smile was with me
Respects to Your Majesty and Empress
Didn't I say you can forgo the manners?
Sit down first
Thanks Your Majesty, Empress
Your body can't take the hot weather
Why did you come out here?
I heard the princess was not well, so I wanted to come visit
I saw something big happening inside
so I dared not come in right away.
But it's a good thing I came
Otherwise someone would be unjustly accused
Princess of Modesty, you say you were with Precious Smile that night
Is that true?
That night, I thought Precious Smile seemed a bit drunk
and was worried so I went to check on her with Jixiang.
Afterwards, we both went back to my palace
and chatted for a long time.
Jixiang
Yes
That night, Niang Niang and Precious Smile discussed Buddhist scriptures
They really hit it off
Then Precious Smile said it was getting late
and hurried back.
That means
Princess Wenyi's incident
has nothing to do with Precious Smile?
Princess of Modesty came just in the nick of time, like a much needed rain
Princess of Modesty has always stayed in her palace nursing her health, never leaving home
That night, why did you ignore the imperial doctors' advice
and go out at night?
Indeed, bedridden people should not go out
But on the day of the banquet,
I heard excellent music
and went outside as if in a rapture.
I wasn't expecting the good luck of meeting Precious Smile
Yes, I feel the same way
Oh? Then why didn't Precious Smile
mention meeting Princess of Modesty earlier?
I shouldn't have hidden this
When Princess of Modesty went out that day,
she didn't want anyone to know
to avoid worrying the Emperor and Empress.
So about our meeting that day
I didn't want to tell anyone.
Who knew this would involve the princess?
I know that the Emperor is wise, the Empress intelligent,
and will definitely uphold my innocence.
I didn't want to lose Princess of Modesty's trust,
so I kept my lips sealed.
What, Princess of Glory doesn't believe it?
I am not being mistrustful
I just think that
Princess of Modesty seems very partial to Precious Smile.
I've only met Precious Smile twice
The first time was also at Wenyi's birthday banquet
Why would I lie
to protect someone I don't know very well?
Get up
Sit
Have the imperial doctor take a good look later
Summer clothes are thin
Don't hurt yourself from kneeling
Precious Smile keeps her promises
It's reasonable for Princess of Glory to not believe me
When I was just outside the room,
I thought I heard the servant ladies say
that they saw Precious Smile
walking in the direction of Cool and Refreshing Hall that night.
Might as well make things clear now
to end the dispute once and for all.
Say again
Did you see, with your own yes, Precious Smile enter
the Cool and Refreshing Hall?
Servant did see Precious Smile
walk in the direction of Cool and Refreshing Hall.
As for whether she went inside, it seemed...
What seemed?! That's totally groundless!
What about you?
Servant...
Servant only saw Precious Smile walking with Auntie Jinxi
Your Majesty, what do you think?
Do as you see fit!
Just one thing
Don't go easy on this bad habit of chasing wind and clutching at shadows (making groundless accusations)!
Yes
Drag them out and give 80 face slaps each! As a warning to others!
Precious Smile, please wait
Is Precious Smile willing to walk with me?
I was just thinking the same
Many thanks Niang Niang for helping me today
I have my reasons for helping you
Niang Niang really believes I'm innocent?
That day,
I saw you walk out of Chang Chun Garden with a servant
and pass by my palace.
By calculating the time, I knew it wasn't you
I was in a hurry that day and didn't see Niang Niang
I hope Niang Niang will forgive me
These are all little things
Princess Wenyi is very cute
but she's suffering so much torment at such a young age.
Although Princess's body is weak,
she is the emperor's daughter and protected by the gods.
Precious Cao's child
originally couldn't be born.
She became pregnant at the wrong time
It was also a difficult birth. The fetal position was not right.
It nearly cost her life
But the emperor especially loves and dotes on this child
Children in this palace seem great
but they suffer way more ailments and disasters
than children outside.
Precious Smile, you were the target in all this
You must take good care of yourself
I can protect you once today
but not all the time.
Thanks Niang Niang for being thoroughly considerate
I will visit Niang Niang when I have time
No need
Besides, it would be more beneficial
if we don't see each other that much.
Yes
Precious Smile,
Niang Niang's body is weak and should go back early to rest.
Then I won't disturb you anymore
Niang Niang
How should this matter be handled?
Yes, I've already thought about it
How about letting some one be the scapegoat
and end this
Do you guarantee no problems?
Yes, I'm willing to guarantee
That's good. As long as I'm not exposed.
Crying all day and night, so annoying
Take her away!
Yes!
Then bring her back later
I understand
Thank you for watching! Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki