you had dared to ask
The people that your sister chose
She did something shameless
Who is shameless?
-What letter? -It's like this
yesterday I had Ruyi to the royal kitchen to fetch some evening snack, and she ran into Xiaolezi who served Third A Ge
sneaking on the long street. --- Third A Ge has been careful
he is not that kind of person
be careful is probably on surface. Chenqie beg the forgiveness of Niangniang
Niangniang is not good at educate your son
Third A Ge is young, and doesn't know a lot of things
must be seduced by a slut woman
Huangshang, Chenqie didn't do it, didn't do it
the person was chosen by the 17th Prince
what's good about this slut maid
Chenqie thought that Third A Ge is innocent in the involvement of the thing
but both physical evidence and eyewitness are here, the letter is the handwriting of Third A Ge
that must be that slut seduced him first
stop, don't argue more. --- Huangshang, don't wrong your own son!
Huangshang, Chenqie didn't seduce Third A Ge
you behaved improper, and seduced the royal son
Zhen award you an ending
I didn't do it, Huangshang
you had talked about what happened, and Zhen don't want to hear more
Su Peisheng,
take her down, and give her a white cloth
Huangshang, I'm wronged, Huangshang
stop
Hongshi has kneeing at Fengxiang Palace for most of the night
this thing is stopped here
Zhen don't want to here one gossip in the harem
you withdraw, Zhen have something to ask Xi Guifei
Ying Guiren was picked by Yu Fujin
whether someone told Ying Guiren to seduce my son for aiming at the crown?
why did Huangshang ask the question in this way?
Hongshi is the oldest, the struggle of whether set the older or younger as the heir is nonstop
destroying Hongshi's reputation is destroying Zhen's reputation
Yuyin would not dare absolutely, Huangshang
she wouldn't dare, how about the 17th Prince?
Chenqie dare to vouch for him
you are based on what?
everyone in this palace has been through the turmoil of the nine princes fighting for the crown under the late Emperor
the longing of the royal sons to the crown is fierce
the 17th Prince was one of the candidates the late Emperor considered
Huangshang is wise, Gui Junwant won't dare
Zhen are afraid that he won't dare to do anything to Zhen
so he let Yu Fujin
to put ideas on my son
Guo Junwant has been loyal to Huangshang all these years
loyal, who can dig up his heart to take a look?
even you and Jing Guifei thought that Zhen wronged Ying Guiren
Zhen have to protect the reputation of royal family
protect my son, and
not let anyone have an opportunity
Ying Guiren was wronged
for Qing dynasty, wronged one doesn't count
since Yuyin is your adopted sister, you have to recuse yourself from this case
a lot of things happened in the harem, you are probably tired
let Empress deal with the things, or
Jing Guifei can help
Huangshang put it this way
do Huangshang suspect Chenqie?
Empress is right. You have a royal son
you can't be helped not involved in this
these two slaps, one for you dared to go fater your royal father's woman
one for you dared to go after the Emperor's woman
Huang A Ma, it's all Erchen's fault
beg Huang A Ma's forgiveness
Zhen, of course, have to forgive you, not only because you are my eldest son
but because you are the descendent of Aixinjuelo
can't lose face for the royal family
Erchen know I did wrong
this wrong someone is taken for you
Zhen has executed Ying Guiren
she was innocent, of course, it was your fault
but you are my son
Zhen would not for a woman not to protect you
it was me who killed her
it was you who killed her
you don't know how high the sky is, how thick the earth, and you don't know the basic ethics and feudal order
Huang A Ma
stay here and repent your errors. if you do wrong again
Zhen can't protect you anymore
Sister
sister's place is so quiet that flower falling can be heard
it's rare that Sister's palace be this quiet
a person in the harem won't be favored for life
you won't be afraid if you see through it. losing favor
if you think the day is hare, it is hard
if you are calm and fearless, the day is calm and fearless
everything is in your heart, has nothing to do with anything else
when have time, go with me to burn an incense for Ying Guiren
alright
I'm to be blamed for this. original thought was to use this to against Empress
didn't think by pushing too hard that hurt you and Ying Guiren
Ying Guiren wronged, but Guo Junwant is under suspicion for no reason, that's really wrong
I never thought it through. Huangshang never likes Third A Ge
but he's on Third A Ge's side on this
and dealt a heavy hand on Ying Guiren and killed her
let Empress fight back and on the top of us
Huangshang can't lose face, and would protect royal family for certain
even his own son is not good
he is still his own son; furthermore, this is related to setting up heir
Huangshang naturally is more suspicious
I made a few kinds of dessert you like
I have no appetite
how come all of sudden you have no appetite?
maybe ate too much in the past
Jinxi, make a bowl of sour plum soup
this sour soup
haven't had it for a while, and eager to have
it's good that you want to eat; it is lucky
are you...?
you are really lucky. with this child, all your problems you face now will be solved
I'll go to tell Huangshang to relieve my regret of hurting you
my situation is not difficult to deal with. I worry about Yuyin and Guo Junwang
how is niangniang lately?
the doctor said that Niangniang's digestion is not good, so she looks tired
Niangniang feels wronged
this can't be blamed on her
no her fault. mine
Nucai won't dare
there was a reason that Zhen asked her the way the other day
Eertai and Maqi argued
Zhen heard the argument back and forth, and it was about setting up the heir
inside and outside the Harem
don't know how many people
laying their eyes on this dragon chair
if setting the heir publically, no one would have a peace any longer
Zhen have to find a good way to prepare if something happens
Huangshang is correct. --- Xi Guifei is pregnant now
Zhen don't want her feeling been wronged any longer. --- it is kind of strange,
several things recently, how come they were all against Xi Guifei?
seems strange
it is not that Zhen don't know
it looks calm on surface
a tangle of rotten dirt inside, in fact
Zhen thought about to clean it up but it is about women's stuff, and didn't seem worth it
secondly, Cunyuan's feeling exists
I let it go many times
it is okay if it is only about the harem
Zhen worry that
the Harem and the court is connected, and calculated together
Zhen have to be careful
you send Zhen's dessert to Yongshou Palace
let Xi Guifei know that Zhen care about her
Nucai go to do it now
today is the 15th, a big day,huangshang pays respect with incense, our Qing will be in prospers and the people in peace
Zhen haven't held Six A Ge for a long time
Six A Ge is taller, Huangshang truly cares
Six A Ge should grow taller and faster for Huangshang
Zhen care about A Ges and Princesses
and care about you
it is getting hotter day by day, don't eat raw and cold food, and
don't face wind with sweat. --- thanks for Emperor's concern
Zhen heard Xi Guifei coughed a few times, and felt concerned
Xi Guifei works hard. if you can't help her
and trouble her more instead, that would make
Zhen concern more
there are more people in the Harem
it is unavoidable there are more gossips
relieve some maids from both Han Junqi and Meng Junqi
have maids from Man Junqi to serve in rotation
yes, only the people serving Huangshang don't need to be cut
what Zhen dislike most is servants talktive
throw out those that like to make trouble first
now Zhungeer clan is watching us like tiger watches its prey
it means something for the front even it won't save much money in the Harem
you look out for yourselves
we remember Huangshang's instruction
I heard there are cuts in the Harem
this is Emperor embarrass Empress
what Huangshang thinks is most difficult to guess
it is hot now; it seems that you move around less
feel tired everyday, don't have much of spirit
I feel strange for this pregnancy, feel more like vomiting, and feel more unhappy
I didn't feel like this when I was pregnant with Longyue. --- in my opinion
have Wei Lin take a look. though you were pregnant before, let's play on the safe side
Jing Guifei is right. when Cunyuan Empress was pregnant, she felt a lot of discomfort
that woman gives birth is like go to the gate of Hell and come back
Cunyuan Empress was cared with such attention, yet ended up with the death of both mother and child
children in the harem are difficult to be born and raised; you hurt yourself recently, and you'd better rest well now
I'm a one that know how to steal rest, but still feel discomfort
the Empress killed the Empress
the Empress killed the Empress?
what did you say? even if you hate the Empress
you can't speak it loud
qjickly, tale princes and princesses away
you just said who killed whom?
the Empress killed the Empress. --- Empress?
what did you know?
it is not that I spoke some nonsense; this was the last sentence Lingrong said before she died
I thought she hated the Empress so much that she wanted me to kill the Empress for her
for her, if she hated so much, she could do it herself
no need to ask you before her death
I never thought about the sentence carefully until something Lingxi said that made me think about the key of the sentence
maybe there is another meaning
you seem have guessed the meaning long time ago
at the time, Emperor was still prince, Yihiu was ordinary woman so she was titled Ce Fujin and would be Fujin if she gave birth
of a son until Cunyuan Empress was called to the house to accompany the pregnant sister, and
and met Emperor who fell in love with her in the first sight
begged the mother to make her as Fujin
Emperor insisted upon it and Dowager couldn't deny his desire
Huangshang never saw Cunyuang Empress before that? --- never
since Huangshang and Dowager insisted, the only thing Yihiu could say was that older sister came to the house should be Fujin
Huangshang and Dowager were relieved
no long, Yihiu gave birth of a son; but the son wasn't healthy before birth, and died before he was three years old
then Cunyuan Empress was pregnant
Cunyuan was the favorite of Emperor. after her pregnancy, Emperor said to Yihiu
you're good at medicine, and are blood sister of Cunyuan, having her serve Cunyuan and looking at the prescriptions with doctors
after the pregnancy Cunyuan had so much discomforts
she had so much pain at the birth, and born a dead baby and died herself after
before she died she said to Huangshang that don't shift your anger to the doctors
and take good care of her only younger sister Yihiu
Cunyuan had treated everyone kindly in the House since she came; yet
yet heaven was not kind to her
even that child I had taken a peek
there were several black spots on that child
and had no breath once he was born
black spots? why did he have black spots?
did Huangshang know?
he did. the doctor said that it was because she was alarmed in pregnancy and not sufficient blood and Qi
because of the clan,Dowager was unwilling to have emperor to marry someone else, thus
Emperor agreed to put Yihiu as Fujin
you all know what happened after that
Yihiu cared extremely for her Fujin's position;
it was taken away suddenly by someone, didn't she have hatred toward her?
exactly. but we don't have evidence
after Cunyuan Empress's pregnancy, she served her closely
if we can bribe the eunuchs and maids of Empress,
maybe that is a way
take her power, take her favor, and lost her son, if she did it, she killed the Cunyuan Empress and her son
but we have no evidence. there must have somewhere
An Lingrong with Empress for very long, she thought everything carefully
she must've seen something; otherwise she wouldn't have said something like this
it could be that we are too paranoid
I like you hate her so much; but if we couldn't crash her in one blow
we have to endure whatever insults
why are you here?
alright. we'll go back soon
we have to think more carefully, no one can afford careless
what happened, mother?
mother saw your Xi Niangniang suffers so much with the pregnancy
can't eat well and sleep well, feels sick
I saw that other niangniangs are like this when they are pregnant
Longyue, do you know
when your Xi Niangniang was pregnant with you, she was suffered a lot
now the life is just getting better, and she got pregnant again
mother feel sad for her
then I will greet Xi Niangniang in the evening
good. Xi Niangniang will be happy when she sees Longyue
I also want Mother happy. Huang A Ma is with Xi Niangniang, I will be with Mother
Longyue is good. yet the more favors Xi Niangniang hets, the more harm could Xi Niangniang get; I want Longyue promise me
no matter when, you have to protect Xi Niangniang, not let Royal mother bullies her
Mother said this many times and I remember
what's the problem, doctor? she threw out whatever she ate, and didn't sleep well
don't be angry, Niangniang, my skill is not sufficient; if have Doctor Wen here, the baby could be saved
Yongshou Palace has asked Wen Shichu back
is there something with Xi Guifei's fetus?
there is no leak from Yongshou Palace, and I can't get anything. I asked the doctor and they said not a big problem now
Wen has be back that shows how much she cares about this fetus
March 18 is the birthday of the late Emperor. have you prepared? --- Huangshang is very filial
have ordered masters to read scriptures for 7 days and 7 nights, and hand copy the scriptures
and burn the scriptures on the day
Huangshang is a filial son, and sons of Huangshang are naturally filial
is the arrangement for Third A Ge ready?
according to Niangniang's instruction, Third A Ge has wrote a poem to Huangshang
with so many days' preparation, Huangshang must be very happy
the filial devotion of the princes are shown only in daily greetings
on the birthday of the late Emperor, Huangshang feels more culture and admiration, and would be moved more easily
, Third A Ge will be fine if he has done some preparation, right?
Third A Ge's style is not above others; remember to have masters to offer advices
Master Wang is a learned confusion scholar, Huangshang chose him for Third A Ge
that shows Huangshang has a lot of expectations for Third A Ge
hope so. Third A Ge is the oldest son of Huangshang, it is unavoidable that he has lots of expectations
only that the death of Ying Guiren would affect Third A Ge
Bengong will think of a way so that important ministers in the court will speak for Third A Ge
when he gets support from the court, Huangshang would feel ease to put him up as heir
everything is fine with Niangniang here
Doctor Wen is here
why you look so pale?
I wouldn't want to bother you if it is not that I couldn't find a way
I believe Wei Lin has tried his best
from your pulse, Wei Lin discovered early that Niangniang is weaker than others
so he used Huangqi and Baizhu, gentle herbs, to nurture you
it's pity. --- what
what Niangniang was pregnant first, Niangniang was anxious and sad
plus the timing of the pregnancy,
the deficit from two previous births was not made up, it was not a good time for another pregnancy
no matter how hard we try, the fetus can be kept for a while but can't be saved
tell me a truth,
how long can I keep this child?
Niangniang is pregnant for four months; this child
even I and Wei Lin try our best
he can't be kept for more than five months
five months?
then our mother-son relationship
has only less than one month left
your health is more important, Niangniang, you can have more child in future
this, can't tell anyone
as long as you and Wei Lin try hard to keep this child, keep it as long as possible
my prescriptions after my pregnancy, Wei Lin normally makes two copies
one keeps at the hospital, one I have
furthermore you have to prepare in advance
the drug to send this child away
maybe one day
this child can give me a big help
as long as not harm the health of Niangniang, I'll do anything you ask
I'm tired, and you go back
As long as you like it.
Yes.