~ Episode 74 ~
Seventeen,
tell me a true fact.
Did you and Concubine Xi have any illicit relationship?
For her,
you have been living out there in the blowing wind for 3 years.
is it because of her, you also want to steal my throne?
ehh?
all of the wrong-doings,
are my fault.
Imperial Brother, i have nothing.
We did not.
I am the Emperor.
naturally, you shouldn't have anything!
You don't deserve it!
Niang Niang,
The Emperor's eunuch Xiao Xiazi is here
Let him in
Yes
Servant greets Precious Consort Xi
Get up
The Emperor is waiting for Niang Niang at Jiu Zhou Qing Hall
Please go over there immediately
Alright
Your Majesty, Precious Consort Xi is here
Greetings and peace to the Emperor
Rise
You can go now.
Yes.
Your head is covered with sweat.
You've been in the Palace all these years...
This is first time I hit you after you have been in the Palace for all these years.
Your Majesty want to hit me, I will of course endure it.
What did I do wrong?
Let me understand what's wrong.
Will tell you.
When Yunli returned you were especially happy...
I was happy because of Yuyi (her sister)
Unlike me who has husband on my side every day.
She can only wait up with a single candle on her own each night.
I hoped when Prince Guo came back...
to rekindle their couple love.
Therefore,
I have already sent for her and her son.
Is it you waiting for Yunli or Yuyi (her sister) is?
You know the answer in your heart.
I am selfish.
I didn't want Prince Guo to come back.
Because of Prince Guo's return to the palace...
Your Majesty would doubt me as your wife.
The Palace will loose its peace.
I have doubt?!
I have no choice to avoid him.
From youth, Your Highness (my father) have especially loved the 17th Prince.
If not because of all the subject were against it back then,
today the person who sits on this throne in the Palace
would not be me.
Besides, in literature, riding or aerial shooting,
he was taught by Your Highness. (the previous Emperor)
He is better than me on everything.
Now that I let him lead the army
What if he had a different heart like my tenth brother.
I have to be careful
Emperor, Prince Guo is not capable of such...
You are not him.
How to you know what's in his heart and his thoughts?
Does he tell you everything ?
I knew long time ago
that he inappropriate feelings for you.
I do not dare
I am just guessing.
Prince Guo has always had the respect for Your Majesty.
For anyone who has the most respect,
once they have power in their hands, it is always possible that they will have a different heart.
Besides,
Your Highness (the previous Emperor) has wanted to hand over his power.
Hard to say that he might have wrong thoughts about the throne
The royal family has brotherhood
as well as the civil being
King wants me dead  I will have to die
Your Majesty
Emperor, Prince Guo is your younger brother.
That day
when my mother and I decided to go after the throne,
even #14 prince was part of it.
I've forgotten about having any brothers.
These few years...
I have treated him very well.
It is extra reward for him.
Your Majesty, please think carefully.
Prince Guo has done lots by leading the army and did not make any mistakes.
If Your Majesty really want to get rid of him,
I am afraid your integrity will be damaged.
You have never disppointted me.
So this time,
I am asking you to do it this time.
I must wipe out the 17th prince .
I'm giving you an opportunity...
Your actions will demonstrate
that you do not have selfish motives.
Its all arranged...
your meeting with him at the Lotus Flower Pavilion.
you take this and go there
I will be waiting for good news from you.
Let me change my outfit first.
You don't need to change clothes
My Huan Huan is always this pretty
If I were the 17th Prince,
I would be willing
to drink the poisonous wine you offer.
Little Xia Zi,
bring Xi Consort to the Lotus Flower Pavilion.
Yes.
After it is done,
Hong Yan will definately be the Crown Prince with no problem.
Because he has a
mother who I can trust but also is very capable.
Once Noble Conssort Xi has learn Prince was coming back,
She ask me to come get you and your son.
So the whole family can be reunion.
Big Sister is very good to us
Of course
Niang niang naturally hopes that Wangye...
and Fujin to have a harmonious marriage.
Her actions...
can be counted as giving me her blessings.
Yuan Che, you haven't seen your father for three years.
when you see him, remember to call him Father.
Yes.
He will surely be happy to see his Father
If only he would remember his wife and son.
Peace upon Your Majesty.
Wangye, it is Consort Xi who has arrived.
Oh? It was His Majesty who said to meet here.
His Majesty has not recovered from his hangover.
He ask for Consort Xi to provide some company first.
His Majesty will come after he has refreshed himself.
I'll have to trouble you then, Consort Xi.
Wangye, there's no need to be so courteous.
This is fine wine that has been bestowed by His Majesty.
Niang Niang, please accompany him.
I'll escort His Majesty over.
It's such a rare opportunity to drink with you, Wangye.
It's just like the old times. It's still summer.
You still like to dress like a royal wife.
Flower copper top  has been lonely for many years
Only the sun regularly visits
Consort Xi, do you still remember your words from the old days?
Yugao Flower is just a flower for a night
Just like something that neither be accepted by people
nor the world
Even though they are rejected by the general public
and the world
Things will still remain deep inside my heart
Will there eventually come a day when
people consider Yugao Flower as an eyesore,
and then strip all leaves of it？
Perhaps.
Even if you pluck the Yugao Flower
the things that remain inside of it
will never be removed
Wangye.
All these years,
you've worked hard at the borders.
Have you ever heard of this saying, Consort Xi?
May we all be blessed with longevity
Though far apart, we are still able to share the beauty of the moon together.
When I think of the moon that we share together
would illuminate on healthy people
It is worthy of my hard work
Before I work in palace,
I have been to Lingyun Peak
The mountain and the river,
It was all the same as in the past.
I'm afraid that in this life,
I will never get the chance to go back there again.
Have you ever thought of returning?
Wangye, would you believe me?
I've returned many times in my dreams.
It's as if everything is as it were in the past.
Nothing changed at all.
But when I awaken from my dream,
I'm just left with hurt feelings.
The best moments in my life...
are just in Ling Yun Feng.
Tonight is the 17th. The moon isn't even round anymore.
Do you still remember the marriage certificate?
I do.
There was a certificate,
but we never shared a wedding toast.
Then tonight...
allow me to be impudent this once.
The winds are strong tonight. Close the windows first.
Look at the picture on the window.
Is it especially current?
This is a pattern of He Huan Flower
The colour of golden red like this
Isn't it seem like we are in the wedding season?
Mother like this type of flower,
Dad once said when building this Tonghua Tai
that windows should all be decorated with this kind of flower
He Huan means gentle and forever
Wasn't Ninghui Tang you lived before
full of He Huan Flower?
It's just a pity
that no matter how much ather adores mother
he can never only be with her forever
Neither can I
I own Jingxian a big apology
As well as Yuyin
And even, you
Don't say such things. I understand it.
Maybe if we went back to the past,
we would all regret the choices we made then.
Perhaps if we change our paths,
we wouldn't even be trapped in this difficult position like today
What I regret most...
is going to Ganlu Temple...
to announce the edict and welcoming you back to the palace.
Huan Er, that is the single unforgivable mistake I made in this life.
Even though I always have feelings for you
but I have to restrain myself
Everything is predestined
I will not hold it against you.
The only one that I have been longing for throughout my entire life,
Not only can I not have her,
but also let two other ladies down
I am horrible
This is the place where the last emperor and Concort Shu kept their precious memories
Don't say such depressing things here.
But I'm afraid that if I don't say it now, I'll never get the chance to.
-Nonsense.-Isn't it?
Every time I see you, it's at a palace banquet.
Even getting close to you is so hard.
Where would we get the chance to speak these words?
- scene -
Over tens of years in one's life
already have passed by
I've never had the opportunity to tell you.
You're already a father, and you still speak without restraint?
I'm just afraid that I'll miss the chance again.
I'm sorry.
I refuse to hear such words.
What if I say
Wish you two can be together until death do you apart
We will have a harmonious husband and wife relationship forever
Look, I've finished drinking mine.
When it comes to cross-cupped wine,
I never had anything left in cup
I want to tell you,
In this lifetime of mine, to be able to have this moment...
I have no other regrets.
Ah Jin!
Why hasn't Wangye returned yet? I want to go take a look.
Wanye is drinking at Tong Hua Tai
-I'm going to take a look.-It might not be appropriate for you to go, Madam.
Don't stop me.
Huan Er.
Let me hug you once more.
If I'm no longer around,
Will you treat Yu Ying well
Of course.
If it were you,
you would do the same.
When Hongyan was young, he was very mischievous.
And yet, he was very sharp.
Unlike Ling Xi
who have been stable and lively since a young age
Their moves and sounds,
Their personalities are not like twins at all.
I want to go back to Ling Yun Feng
Yunli, what's wrong with you?
The cup of poisoned wine was clearly mine!
You switched the cups, didn't you?
A wine flask that's divided into a poisoned and un-poisoned section
I'm not unaware of the schemes in the palace.
I know what kind of person Brother is. He had you come alone in the night...
I felt that it was unusual.
When I asked you to close the window,
I switched the wine goblets.
Huan Er.
I refuse to make it difficult for you.
Spit the wine out!
I'll call the Imperial Physician.Yunli! Yunli!
Yunli.
Ever since I took my soldiers to save you,
Older Brother's threatening to kill
I long have been unable to run
If this drink was really from you
it won't even matter
That's because you are choosing to protect yourself.
Huan Er, from today on,
I cannot protect you anymore.
You must...
you must know how to protect yourself, alright?
No. I am the one who was supposed to die!
If I died, you'd still have a means to survive.
Imperial Brother wants me dead.
How can I still survive?
I don't want you to die!
Yunli!
The child, Hongyan, really resembles you.
You have your child.
You must live on well.
I beg of you, don't leave me.
I'm your wife. Take me away from this palace!I don't want to remain here!
I don't want to remain here!
I beg you to take me away from here!
With this sentiment of yours,
I have no regrets in this life.
Yunli.
In my heart...
you've always been my one and only...
wife.
I never told you...
Hongyan and Lingxi both are yours...
Niang Niang, you've come out?
Who's there?
If the Niang Niang came out, I will read the Royal Edict.
But if besides Niang Niang, there were someone else came out,
I was told to kill Niang Niang and the other person/people. No matter who the person is.
the person would be executed on the spot.
I'm fine.
I've come out.
Then...
Prince Guo...has passed away.
Please read the Royal Edict.
Gui Fei, please knee to receive the Royal Edict.
By royal edict of the Emperor,
The palace is full of misconduct  Your majesty feels there's no owner of the palaces
Assign Royal Xi as head of the 6 palaces
Position same as Queen
End of edict.
Niang Niang, this is a great news.
His Majesty knew that you'd be tired, Niang Niang.So he had me escort you back to your chambers.
Where's Wangye?
Inside.
-Wangye!-The flower has fallen.
Niang Niang!
Your Majesty.
Prince Guo has passed away suddenly.
The matter is concluded.
I have follow Your Majesty's order and sent  Prince's body back to the boarder in secret.
So the public would think Prince Quo had returned to the border
Ok and,
The weather is hot. It's not convenient to delay it for too long.
I remember that when I was young,
my Mother wasn't favored.
Father didn't like me either.
Among all the brothers, only the 13th and 17th...
were close to me.
That is precisely why...
Prince Guo's crime cannot be pardoned!
Has Your Majesty forgotten?
The letters that I secretly found in Prince Guo's residence...
were all filled with secret language between husband and wife.
He did deserve death.
But I cannot ignore our brotherly bond either.
I would like to give the prince a very big funeral.
Have his mourning carried out with lots of pomp.
In order to protect the peace at the boarder,
don't make it too big.
Your Majesty is definitely right.
I wonder if Gui Fei Ci was too surprised and  sad so she fell from the stairs.
The Doctor said her knee was injured quite seriously.  It would take a few days to heal before she can walk.
Sadness costs the scared.
It's really too hard on her.
Niang Niang has been sick for a few days now.  Your Majesty has not been here once.
What does that matter?
He has done what he set out to do?
Even my title has been bestowed.
Physician Wei said...
that your right knee was too seriously injured.
I'm afraid...
I'm afraid you won't be able to dance anymore.
Mother said...
that the Crane Dance is to be performed for the man you love.
Indeed, I don't need to dance anymore.
Niang Niang, it's time to drink your medicine.
Naturally, I should take my medicine.
I have promised him to live well.
Jin Xi
Tomorrow is his funeral procession.
-Yes.-I really want to send him off.
What did I do to deserve having him save me...
and give up his life for me?
I loved him my whole life.
I let him down my whole life too.
Now, he's died for me.
And I can't even have a good cry for him.
I want Father! I want Father!
You mustn't cry. You cannot cry!
His Majesty has granted special favour to allow the funeral ceremony.
His Majesty's edict stated that no sound of crying is to be heard!
His Majesty has done such a unrighteousness thing.
Naturally, he doesn't want people talking about it.
Asking us not to make a sound when crying.
You shouldn't say something like that. It is really not respectful.
Not respectful?
What should I be afraid of?
It's time. Move the coffin.
Mrs.
Dear, don't leave me behind!
Mrs. Mrs... Mrs. you...
Mrs. wake up. Mrs...
Mrs.
Mrs... Mrs...
- Niang Niang, Su Pei Sheng has ask to see you.- Niang Niang.
What's wrong?
Niang Niang, please overcome your grief.
Prince Guo's wife has followed his foot step and past aw
- Niang Niang!- Niang Niang, please take care.
His Majesty really respect her death for preserving her chastity.
Already order the proper funeral so she can be buried with Prince Guo.
What about Yuan Che? (their son)
His Majesty said his son is young  He'll be given to Sheng Jun Wang and his wife to raise
The prince died suddenly
Also been unable to tell anyone about the situation
He's been getting thinner in a few days
Tell him to contain his grief
There is one thing I like to you find out for me.
His Majesty,
Why did His Majesty wants Prince Guo dead all of a sudden?
It seems like it was because of some letters.
Letter? What letter?
Peace upon Consort Xi.
At the end of every letter he sent home,
this is what was written.
Jinxi,
every letter had it.
Prince Guo really cared about Niang Niang and that's the reason it resulted his death.
Yu Li and Yu Ying's letters
Only they can read it
Why would His Majesty have it
Xia Yi
The person Xie Yi brought named Zhan Gan Chu
He is definitely a competent person
He especially detect matters about the former dynasty for Emperor
Eliminate the opposition
So that's what it is
Jin Xi
I had already grown white hair
when I was only 27 years old
Concrot Xi
Now you are 37 years old
Let me help you cover your white hair
In case Emperor feels unhappy when he sees it
The reason why he would feel unpleasant is because he knows I am aging
Rather than he knows about my white hair
which is not grown due to him
Let me re-put dressing on your feet for you
Emperor is here
Your Majesty,
You may sit down
Your feet just got better
I heard that you have been to my place earlier this afternoon
Yes
I don't think it was a perfect time
since you were off to Consort Gui
It's my bad
Going out without informing you
How is your feet?
I am feeling better now
Why are you so careless while walking?
Was it Xiao Xia Zi's negligence?
It's all my fault
Wasn't it caused by heart breaking?
I am very scared
I never hurt anyone
Are you really concerned with Yun Li's death?
Recently, I heard that Emperor was extremely tired
and sleep deprived
To be honest, I dream about
what Yunli and me used to be back in old days
We are brothers from long ago, so I feel really sad
Then what about you?
I have been with you for a very long time
And you are still suspecting me?
It's not that I distrust you
But huanhuan, I think you...
have changed.-What about you?
Do you still care about me like you did before?
Hope we all haven't changed
I'm seeing off the Majesty.