The Legend of Zhen Huan
Episode 28
Isn't it fun?
Seems like Miss is in a good mood today
Being able to gain advantage from both sides
Actually
Miss need not to alert Consort Hua to find out about Lay Chun
We could've covered it at first
other people would have suspected me.
I'd rather be left alone. She deserves it for treading on forbidden ground.
Its understandable for Consort Hua to protect Lady Chen.
Why did you inform Consort Wan?
Consort Hua is having the time of her life, while Consort Wan is slowly catching up.
Even though I am on Consort Wan's side, I'm going with the flow.
Even though she knows that its too late to save Lady Chen,
but perhaps when Consort Wan dominates the palace one day,
she would not put me in a difficult spot just because of what i told her today.
Didn't Consort Wan suspect that it was Niang niang who pushed her?
Everyone can suspect who they want. But she does not have any evidence.
If she does, did you think I can still sit here peacefully?
Isn't that right? Its the fight of the century.
Instead of getting into trouble, its best that one finds an escape route.
Is it right?
Greetings your Majesty.
I needed to finish looking through the proposals before coming over.
Am I too late?
Its never too late as long as your heart is here.  I'll wait for you.
So I will come no matter how late it is.
Your majesty must be tired from working all day.
How did you not know that i will be coming?
Why did you prepare this?
I am constantly wishing Emperor you will come here.
So I always prepare it.
With this kind thoughts from you,
I would have missed you if I did not come.
It looks to me that you're in a good mood today.
Could there be any good news?
The war in the South east
your bother and nephew has accomplished a great achievement.
I have decided to grand your brother the title of First Class Duke.
Your father's title will be ascended
to Grand Mentor.
While your brother's previous title of First Class Baron
will be given to his second son, Nian Fu.
I will then grand your mother the title of Madam of Gao Ming.
What do you think?
Thank you your majesty.
I was thinking about Consort Wan's sadness over the death of Lady Chen.
To console her,
I will ascend her father's position.
Didn't you think that Consort Wan's father was disrespectful to you?
I have given him his punishment.
If you're against it, I will leave in the Conserate,
and only raised his title as officer. What do you think?
I dare not justify against your majesty's decision.
As long as Consort wan is happy.
Its great that you're so mature.
You've been holding on to the title of Consort for quite some time.
I'm planning to ascend your title after mid autumn.
All I wish is to accompany your majesty.
I care nothing about titles.
Greetings to your highness.
Raise.
Thank you, your highness.
Greetings to Consort Hua.
Raise.
Thank you Consort Hua.
What is with all of you today?
As close sisters,it is only natural for us to congratulate you after hearing his majesty's decision to ascend your title
Your highness has always lived in bliss.
Who knew that my days would come too.
Consort Hua, what do you mean by that?
We've congratulated you when you were granted the title of Fujin.
You are always in control, how smart of you.
No matter how smart I am, it can't be compared to your highness's intelligence.
Your highness knows his majesty best.
May I know what title will I be granted by his majesty?
Title above Consort is Imperial Consort, while Imperial Honored Consort is even higher.
It should be one of them.
Niang Niang, you are wrong.
There's the title of Empress above Imperial Hornored Consort.
Are you saying that you're
interested in my title of Empress?
Niang Niang, you are overthinking.
I happen to know that the title of Imperial Hornored Consort is equivalent to Empress.
Back when Imperial hornored Consort Dong-E was alive
Empress Bo Er Ji Jin did not even have the right to speak.
How knowledgable of you.
No matter how pretigious the title of Imperial Honored Consort is, it is equivalent to Empress.
Empress will always be empress.
Even with the Imperial Honored Consort, there can only be one mother of the nation.
Consort Dong-E was still not recognized even after being crowned Imperial Honored Consort.
It was never formal nor official.
With your intelligence, surely you understand where your place lies.
All I know is that, there will always be an outcry against justice.
My opinions stirred up such a fuss from your higness.
Others might have thought that your highness is frightened just
like Imperial Honored Consort Bo Er Ji Jin.
Its my duty as the empress to set the rules in the back palace.
You should learn form you so that you could perhaps use it in the future.
I will your highness's words in mind.
I will surely fulfill my duty once I get ascended.
So that empress could rest.
You've been in low spirits
ever since the passing of lady Chen.
I'm relived that you're finally
willing go out.
Sister Mei could have accompanied me, but she has not recovered yet.
Lady An is not feeling well either.
But Consort Jing would come over and talk to me.
Consort Jin is indeed a warm hearted person.
I gave you a white parrot, fearing that you might be bored. Do you like it?
Its really interesting, I really like it a lot.
Reporting to your majesty.
Officer Long Ko Do is here.
I will be taking my leave now.
Send him in.
Yes.
greetings your majesty.
Uncle Long Ko Do
rise.
Thank you, your majesty.
Have a seat.
Is there anything urgent
that you wish to see about?
I have found out that the Nian Gengyao mansion in capital city
is under a huge renovation.
The houses of others around it were also demolished for the sake of a garden.
His mansion as big as Prince's estate.
I've just rewarded him. Its normal that he renovates his home extravagantly.
Because Nian Gengyao's action, the people around him has lost their homes.
Many of them are left homeless.
Now that he is in capital city, back in Qing Hai
who knows, General Nian's house might get even bigger than prince's estate.
Your taking this too seriously.
Although Nain Geng Yao is arrogant,
he is a man who knows his place.
Your majesty,
Uncle and Nian Geng Yao have never gotten along.
Niang Geng Yao was born as a servant.
Even though you're my uncle,
there are a lot of things that I need to learn from you.
Perhaps its because of your presence,
that Nian Geng Yao would not dare to be overboard.
I will never forget,
your majesty's kindness.
I heard that Empress Dowager is not feeling well.
Has she gotten any better?
I would like to greet her highness.
You must be tired from travelling,
now that mother is sick
if not she could have a conversation with uncle.
Imperial doctors said that she needs to rest.
Perhaps now is not a suitable time to meet her.
How about paying her a visit when she gets better?
Your servant will take his leave now.
Look.
Your sewing is getting better.
These flowers that you sew are looking very realistic.
You're teasing me again.
I was never good at sewing in the past. I only started getting better at it when I entered the palace.
This belly band is full of a mother's love.
It is naturally the best.
Miss, Consort Jing,
Servants from the palace reported that the empress is having a severe headache and is feeling very comfortable.
Please proceed to the palace if you're free.
Who is serving her at the moment?
Consort Hua is with the emperor.
Lady Fucha just had a miscarriage, Lady Hui and Lady an are still ill.
Consort Qi and Lady Xin are serving her now.
Alright, I'm going now.
I shall go along with you.
Stay here if you're not feeling well.
Empress seldom feels uncomfortable, I will feel bad for not serving her.
I shall go with you.
alright then.
Your highness.
Please stay strong.
Please hang in there your higness.
Jian qiu
Is the imperial doctor here yet?
Not yet.
Why didn't you cal for the imperial doctor earlier?
Its not that I didn't, but the imperial doctors on duty are not around.
Why?
I've asked them earlier, besides the doctors taking care of
Empress Dowager, that can't be disturbed.
The rest were all taken by General Nian.
How did things turn out like this?
Heard that General Nian's is down with a serious illness,
he took all the imperial doctors with him this afternoon
to take care of his wife.
How could he act this way?
This is way too ridiculous.
How can the empress of the nation not have an imperial doctor?
How can they all be at the minister's mansion.
Your highness.
Send someone
to bring back those imperial doctors.
I did.
But General Nian says that his wife is in need of them.
He even said that the imperial doctors are not to return until his wife has recovered.
Did you inform the Emperor about this?
Her highness ordered to not alert his majesty.
Besides...no one would dare disturb him while he is at Consort Hua's place.
Why didn't you inform the emperor
when she is not feeling well?
I...
What are waiting for?
Go!
Don't go, its late. The emperor needs his rest.
Or else he'll be too tired tomorrow to handle his work.
But the imperial doctors must at least be called over.
Its normal for the imperial doctors to be Nian's mansion.
The gates are all closed now, I don't wish to create anymore problems.
The imperial doctors will be back by tomorrow morning.
Your highness.
Enough, that's it.
Madam,
empress was sick again last night.
She suffered through the night because of her headache.
So it is true.
I'll go over later
to greet her highness.
Brother is too much this time. How could he have taken all the imperial doctors?
What if there's a sudden order by the emperor?
Send my words out.
Tell them to send the imperial doctors who are done with their work back.
Yes.
Wait...
Wait.
Come and take a look at the emperor's breakfast with me.
The emperor likes pickles, put it in front.
Yes.
Wait.
Emperor only had a few bites of these buns yesterday, he must be bored of them. Put it further away.
Reporting to Madam
The eunuch from the Imperial Household is here.
What brings him here so early in the morning?
Bring them in.
Yes.
Greetings to Consort Hua.
Isn't this the attire of an Imperial Honored Consort?
Who ordered you to send them here?
Your servants are just carrying out orders from our superior.
Could it be from the Emperor?
Your servant does not know.
Who would dare to send out such an order other than the emperor?
Both of you have worked hard.
Please follow Eunuch Zhou to redeem your rewards.
Thank you Madam.
Yes.
This way please.
Congratulations Imperial Honored Consort.
Your majesty, I have issues to report to you.
Go ahead.
I heard that there was no imperial doctor attending to empress's headache last night.
She could not get any treatment last night due to the absence of Imperial doctors.
The empress is the mother of the nation, its the imperial doctor's fault,
for not treating Empress when she was ill.
Because of someone's selfish needs, there was no imperial doctor around.
This person should be punished for causing empress pain from not being treated on time.
Reporting to your majesty.
My wife was sick yesterday afternoon.
I was anxious and bought over the imperial doctors who were on duty.
I didn't expect that the empress would get a headache.
It is all my fault, but I was anxious back then.
Please spare me your majesty.
Rise.
Thank you your majesty.
I've always sent imperial doctors to treat
your injured hand too.
Now that your wife is sick,
its natural that you're anxious.
As his husband, you had to help her.
Is your wife's condition any better?
Thank you for your majesty's concern. She is feeling much better this morning.
I've sent all the imperial doctors back to palace.
You will have to be more rational in the future,
even if you are feeling anxious.
Yes.
It is necessary to have an imperial doctor on duty in the palace, in case anything sudden were to happen.
I was wrong.
I would dare not allow this to repeat again.
As an officer in court,
as a husband at home,
official matters are important,
so does family.
Just like General Nian,
as a wise officer in court,
as a dutiful husband at home.
Yes.
You were here in the morning before.
You're here again. Be careful not to tire yourself out.
Don't worry your highness.
I am fine.
I just want to accompany you.
I'm feeling better.
The imperial doctor has already checked on me.
Such a thing happened,
even the ministers are complaining about it.
It was said that not only was the emperor not angry
he even praised General Nian.
It is just an old ailment, nothing serious.
Has the emperor visited your highness?
He came over earlier in the morning and even left after I've taken my medication.
The emperor is so busy,
I don't wish to cause him any inconvenience.
Its obvious that the emperor is on Nian's side.
They have send the imperial honored consort clothes over.
Imperial Doctor Wen.
Greetings to Consort Wan
You must be really busy being the head imperial doctor in charge.
Thanks to his majesty's regards, I will definitely do my best.
I have something to ask you.
All the imperial doctors on duty were all called to General Nian's mansion.
Causing the palace to be void of imperial doctors.
How many of them are on duty usually?
The incident last night has empress's health involved.
We feel really guilty and awful about it.
I've asked the rest of my colleagues.
Last night, General Nian took Imperial Doctor Li and Zhang.
Imperial Doctor Chen and Zhao were still in the palace on duty.
Eunuch Jiang Fu-Hai came later.
Seeing them not around and thought that
Since Precious Fuca just had a miscarriage and While Imperial concubine Wan is pregnant.
It's a must that we have experienced doctors around.
So he told both doctors on duty to switch with Imperial Doctor Li and Imperial Doctor Zhang.
Nian Gengyao is in need of people.
Since both of them are experienced, of course he wouldn't let them both switch.
What about those not on duty?
Could they enter the palace once summoned?
Although the gates are closed at night, but it can be arranged.
It should be fine if there's an order from the Empress
Just that it involves a lot of work. It might bother others.
Understood
Thank you Doctor Wen.
Niang Niang is pregnant right now, I can't serve by your side.
How is everything?
Imperial Doctor Zhang is a reliable person.
Everything's fine.
I'm relieved to hear that..
i'll pay you a visit next time.
Madam asked about Ministry of Imperial Doctor.
Perhaps there's doubt in your mind?
I'm just guessing.
Empress is a through person
Could it be...
She's afraid to disturb the others due to her own illness.
That's why she's keeping it low profile?
If she wants to keep it low profiled
She wouldn't ask for Concubine's serving
Doesn't matter if she's a through person or if there's a hidden agenda.
Since we're taking the Empress's side.
We shall just go with the flow.
What book are you reading?
I saw this book of Zou Zhaun on the table.
It's really interesting
Which passage you're reading? Tell me about it.
Journey of Zheng Bo killing Duan
It's an old story. Why'd you like this passage?
Although it's an old story, but there's something that people could learn from it.
Madam Jiang's love for her youngest son makes her
intended to replace Lord Zhuang with Duke Duan. Lord Zhuang tolerance caused a outrage
That leads to the death Duke Duan
That's the best strategies as an Emperor.
I think Lord Zhuang's moves seems proper.
I've been receiving complaints about Nian Gengyao.
Saying that he's arrogant.
I know nothing about official matters
Just hat this passage seems fine
Now that you said it. I think the words are sharp
and worthy to read
There's a sentence that is very vivid
Which one?
Have a guess. Let's see if we have a heart connection.
You're always the favorite of mine
Arrival of the Royal Order.
Consort Hua takes the order.
Receiving order of Emperor
With god's wiliness, Emperor commands that
Consort Hua of Family Nian as the family pride with proper virtue
Granting the title of Imperial Consort
End
Did Enuch make a mistake?
Emperor granting me the title of Noble Consort?
Niang Niang, this Royal Order as handwritten by Emperor. There wouldn't be any mistakes for sure.
Congratulations to Noble Consort Hua.
But...but Imperial Household sent me an attire
of Imperial Noble Consort before this
That attire of Imperial Noble Consort belongs to Imperial Noble Consort Que-Hui of former Emperor.
Emperor is keeping it since there hasn't been any Imperial Noble Consort.
Now that Emperor wanted to make one for future use
But it was mistakenly sent here. Niang Niang please send it back to us.
Song-Zhi
Yes
Give it back to them.
Understood.
Niang Niang
You're the first and only Noble Consort in this Dynasty.
How prestigious! You need not worry about rankings
With the military influence of your family
and love of the Emperor
Everything seems in fine condition.
With the authority of the back palace in your hand.
Isn't it more formal and official
When you have a prince in the future?
Thanks for your words
Your servant takes his leave.
Congratulations to Imperial Consort.
All of you may take your leave.
There will be chances to congratulate me
once the ceremony is over.
Yes.
Madam.
The emperor needs to take care of the empress's needs.
And the dowager's reputation.
Its just a delusional dream of mine.
Sister.
I have some Boluchun tea, great for cooling your body down.
Have a cup then.
Consort Hua,
Great,
What a waste that I do not have a good father,
and brother to fight in the battle field.
Now that is slut is gaining all the advantages.
Sister need not be angry.
Now that Imperial Consort Hua is in power now,
I feel that she looks like the former Imperial Consort Wen-Xi.
Imperial Consort Wen-Xi?
She was the mother of Prince Dun.
Daughter of E-bilong.
Biological sister of Zhao Hao-Ren.
E-bilong is only powerful because of his master Oboi.
Even Emperor Kangxi could not tolerate him, not to mention Nian Gengyao.
I have heard of it too, Nian Geng Yao's domineering act.
But the emeperor is taking this too lightly.
He even praised General Nian.
It takes a lot of effort to remove the root of the problem.
The longer it takes, the cleaner it will be.
Peace is just around the corner.
But Sister seems to be
giving his majesty the cold shoulder lately.
How could I ingratiate the emperor?
Emperor just sees me as somone unimportant.
You will be looked down upon if you're disfavored.
You've been through it before.
Its obvious that Consort Hua is soley favored by the emperor.
All of us combined is nothing compared to yours.
You're emperor's favorite for sure.
Your highness must be teasing me.
Since emperor favors me,
I must do my best to serve his Majesty.
I'm glad to have you taking care of the emperor.
Since you are so love by the emperor, its time
you give him a little prince.
That's right.
But it will be really awful
if its just a princess.
Consort Qi's words sure are blunt.
If its a prince of high intelligence,
a celebration will most definitely be arranged. But if its a dumb headed prince,
it would not be in favor at all.
It might even disgust the emperor.
You.. Enough.
It doesn't matter if he's intelligent or dumb.
It all depends on how you educate the child. The most important thing right now
is to give birth to a healthy boy.  You should learn from Consort Hua,
look how blissful she is.  It doesn't matter if its a prince or princess
I liked both.
How nice would it be if it turned out to be like Princess Wen-Yi.Consort Qi, look, even Consort Wan
knows that its better than 3rd prince.  Consort Qi,
that's not what I meant.  What do you mean then?
Lady Fucha lost her baby the moment you're pregnant.
Are you trying to show off? Are you trying to
put 3rd prince in bad light after causing the death of Lady Fucha's baby?
Enough.
Since you're holding on to such a prestigious status,
and the mother of 3rd prince, why did you make a fuss with the rest?
How embarassing.  I have no intention
to argue with Consort Wan. I am the
mother of 3rd prince. How can I not take
his side?  You're his biological mother, I've watched him grow up too.
I know that
I am no longer attractive, and his majesty no longer favors me.
Its alright if I'm disfavored.
But 3rd prince is still his majesty's eldest son. You've been serving him all these years,
why would he dislike you? 3rd prince is his majesty's
only grown son after all.
can never catch up with it. But come to think of it,
now that Consort Wan is being favored and sharing the same
background as yours. Her child might be the same level as
3rd prince in the future.Didn't empress Shunz Zhi insist that
4th prince to be crowned prince back then? But don't worry, I will persuade emperor
for sure if he insist on grating the newborn.
Didn't empress Shun Zhi's prince died when he was till an infant?
Poor thing.
Perhaps not being born was a better option than death.
Oh bless me, how could I have spoke of such sinful words.
Greetings Consort Qi.
Madam,
What's the matter?  Pardon my words,
please don't stand under the Oleander tree.
The pollen and fluid of the Oleander tree are poisonous.
It'll be bad if madam accidentally consumes it. Really? Yes, thank goodness
that there are no Oleander tress in the area where Sister Wan is living. Or else it will be bad for
her since she is pregnant now.
How bad is it?  Oleander
is bad for pregnancy. Back in my home town, pregnant women stay away from it.
Miss,
its almost time to greet the empress.
Let's hurry along.  I will be taking my leave now.
Look how thick my waist is.
I've gained a lot of weight too.
Take a seat quickly. What's with all the weight?
Your baby is not even 4 months old.
Others may not see it, but I do know that this baby in my belly
is growing day by day.  Indeed, its summer already.
I remember Chun-Er,
liked Phoenxi flowers a lot.
I went to Bao Hua temple earlier on,
to pray for Lady Chun.
Its too bad that I'm pregnant,
or else I would have personally give her my blessings.
So that I could take revenge on her behalf. Now that you're pregnant, how can you say such words?
It will be bad if the baby hears it.
Your throat has not recovered.
It will be bad if you catch a cold on the way.
I'm alright.
I'm feeling better after talking to you.  Speaking of which,
I've been feeling unwell lately. Didn't Imperial doctor Zhang
prescribe you some Ramulus soup? Ramulus can help in smoothing your throat.
Its the best for calming down. I've been drinking it everyday.
Miss,
Consort Qi has send someone over.
Exactly.
Greetings to Consort Wan
and Lady An. Rise.
Yes madam. Consort Qi made some chestnut cake and had me send them over.
Please have a try Consort Wan. Thank madam on my behalf.
Your servant will be taking her leave now.
This came just in time.
Ling-Rong, have a try. The best snacks from the Qi Feng palace, I wonder how
would Consort Qi's snacks taste.
Wait. Don't eat this.
Why?
Chestnut Cake should taste sweet.  Why do I smell a tinge of bitterness?
Put it down.
This snack has Oleander
fluid in it.  This...  Oleander is poisonous.
It helps in removing stasis. But everyone know that your chest has been feeling stuffy lately.
Matching Oleander and Ramulus,
brings great effect for removing stasis. Its bad for your pregnancy.
The palace maid said that this was made by Consort Qi just now?
Yes. Consort Qi must have been jealous of you being favored and pregnant.
That's why she did this. I must let the emperor know about this.
Please be seated.
If the emperor knows about this, he will be mad at Consort Qi.
As the eldest son of the empress, her highness would protect 3rd prince.
Even though she cares nothing for Consort Qi. 3rd prince is also the eldest, once he takes the throne,
he'll definitely give you a hard time. How are you going to survive then?
I can't let go of this easily.
Bring these to Imperial Doctor Zhang.
I'll make my decision later. Take it away Liu-Zhu.
Have you send the snacks Consort Wan?
Yes, I could stay long enough
to see Consort Wan finish it.  Strange... the effect should have taken place by now.
Could I have added
too little of it?  Don't be anxious Madam, lets wait a little longer.
Greetings
Consort Qi Excused.  Madam, empress has summoned you
to the palace of great benevolence.  The empress should be taking her afternoon nap now.
What's the matter?  There must be something urgent for sure.
Greetings your highness.
Why is your highness not taking a nap? Even the palace maids are not around.
Kneel down.