What did those disgusting servants confess?
They admitted it. Apart from the murdering, they said more
and?
What else?
others are just some small cases
but there is one that I have to report
what is it?
Emperor,
the reason of xun yuan queen's death
is related to the queen...
how dare you?
I don't meant to
you tell me everything
yes
I've asked the doctor. Normally eating small amounts of Ba Jiao is fine
But pregnant women cannot ingest even a little
Medicines like Ba Jiao
can have aborting effects. Although the effects are not as obvious has Hong Hua
But if you cook the medicine, it can seep into food
After a long time, it can be very harmful. Also, the tea was switched to Tao Ren, which is also very harmful
Since it was mixed in, it was very hard to differentiate the taste
All of this was in Empress Chun Yuan's food and drink
Is this straight from the servants' mouth?
Jian Qiu didn't say anything, but Eunch Jiang
told us everything
Also, Empress Chun Yuan's stillborn fetus was purple with bruises. That is also clear evidence.
But wasn't that because the consort
used to make Chun Yuan worried and stressed all the time?
The doctors say that all that stress just hid these signs
So it was her. Yes.
Other than harming Empress Chun Yuan, there is much more.
I thought that they were sisters.
Blood sisters
She was always loving and gentle to Chun Yuan
Bring her here. We have been husband and wife for many years
I believe
that she tried to scheme for the throne
and kill royal children
But about Chun Yuan, I want to hear from her directly
Yes.
At this point, do you confess your guilt?
If you already believe it, what is the point of asking me?
I need to hear it from you directly
You think that I still want to see your face?
I have aged, it is no surprise that you do not want to see my face.
I just wonder if Jie Jie was still alive, if you would like her aged face as well.
I deeply regret
I should have let you see her aged face as well
Then you may not hate me so much
Beauty is the result of a pure heart
Even if Chun Yuan ages and becomes frail, she will still be superior to you a thousand fold
You gave me this jade bracelet to me when I first married into the palace. You even put it on me yourself.
We hoped to be like this bracelet. To see each other every day.
Yet today, you say you don't want to see me anymore because I've made mistakes
Back then, you would look at this bracelet and say to me
that if I bore sons, then I would be the official wife.
Yet when I did bear a son, you already married my sister and made her the official wife
And my son had to be the son of a consort instead
He had to be like me, the child of a consort instead of an official wife.
You know I didn't care of the difference statuses of a consort vs official
My mother didn't care either. Both my mother and I were born from consorts
But emperor, how could you understand?
The daughters of consorts are so miserable
Consort vs official determines your fate
My mother and I rarely got respect
Do you understand?
I do understand. And because I understand
when you married me, I treated you very well. Even when Chun Yuan became the official, I made you the second highest.
Yet you are never satisfied.
What should have been my official position was snatched away by another
The crown prince position was also snatched away
Even my husband's love and affection was given to her
I want to be satisfied, but I can't
Chun Yuan was your blood sister!
It was my mistake to let you marry into the family
Your mistake wasn't marrying me,
but rather marrying my Jie Jie, and only loving my Jie Jie
If you think you're smart  there's always someone smarter.
You are so wise, how can you not understand when it is your own issue
It was my mistake to so highly regard your sisterly affection
Are you afraid of bad karma?
You're not afraid that Chun Yuan and her stillborn will come haunt you?
If she wants to haunt me, let her!
That way I can stop imagining and hearing my child nonstop crying
When my child was ill, Jie Jie just became pregannt
You only cared that Jie Jie was pregnant. You didn't care about our child
He was only 3 years old. His whole body was hot with fever and died from lack of medical treatment
I held his body in my arms and walked in the rain the entire night
I wanted to ask the gods for help
If you want a life, take mine, not my son's
And then Jie Jie got pregnant. Her son took my son's life! How could I sit idly as her son becomes the Crown Prince
You're crazy
It was MY decision to marry Chun Yuan. It was MY choice to make her the official wife.
It was ME that had a child with her. Why didn't you hate me?
You think I didn't want to?
I wanted to hate you
But I couldn't do it
In your eyes, all you could see was Jie Jie.
How could you know that my love for you was no less that your love for Jie Jie
Emperor
You think that Jie Jie loved you a lot?
You think Noble Consort Xi loves you?
All women who love their husbands cannot stand watching their husband love and have children with others
I can't do it.
You think that I'm evil and jealous, but I'm the one that truly loves you
Thus, I did so much
You disgust me.
- music -
If it wasn't that I was in the position of Empress, having to protect myself
I would hope that you can remember some of my good traits
Don't you think I wish I wasn't jealous?
My instinctual loyalty to you is also the source of my pain
The Empress
Empress Wulanla,
Disobeyed God's will
Killed royal children and schemed for the throne, despite being the mother of the country
Is demoted to a citizen and is house arrested for eternity
Get my seal
Yes
Good Night Emperor
Why are you here Gu Gu
I know that there has been much chaos today. In order to relieve your stress, I have brought the Dowager's royal decree
My mother had a decree?
I do not dare to lie to you. If you do not believe me, you can look at the decree
It is in the Dowager's handwriting
We can read this later. First I want to get rid of this evil woman.
The Dowager's decree is regarding today's issue. Would the Emperor please kneel to receive the decree?
After my passing, if the Emperor wishes to get rid of the Empress, our Wu family cannot bear the shame.
The Emperor cannot get rid of the Empress.  This is indeed my mother's handwriting
Wife Ci'er Wulanala, of noble bearing and virtuous upbringing,
possesses all necessary women's virtues, is learned in the six practices, has displayed gentleness and excellence,
and is worthy of being the mother of the nation. Ordained by the Empress Dowager, I became Empress with all proper ceremonies.
The End.
That was the royal decree you wrote when you made me empress. Do you remember?
You are a filial son. You cannot disregard the Dowager's decree
The only reason I did not follow the Dowager to heaven, was to enforce this last decree
But her crime is unforgivable
I must get rid of her
Even Chun Yuan and the Dowager would be angered
With her last breath, the Dowager instructed me that if you still want to get rid of the Empress, I would ask you
What was Chun Yuan's last words when she was dying?
Chun Yuan was already very frail
her head rested on my knees and said
I cannot accompany you into old age
Even our child did not survive
I only have one sister. I hope you can look after her no matter what
Do not get rid of her
You promised her that you would never get rid of her sister
You must forgive the Empress so that Chun Yuan can rest in peace
You dislike the Empress. You do not even want to call her by her name. You call her by her last name
But Chun Yuan was also by the same last name
And the Dowager was by that name. Even you, the emperor, have blood from the Wu family.
It is the Dowager's decree that the Wu family cannot be removed as Empress
Seeing as I am feeling nostalgic
The Wu family woman is house arrested to this palace and can never leave until she dies.
Go get my decree that made her Empress
And the royal seals
We are never to meet again in this lifetime
I got it.
Can't you hear all this noise?
If the Emperor gets angry, look out for your lives!
Bo Ke has raised an army of 40,000
If Ye Ming Guan falls, then Beijing may not be safe either
I also know his ambition very well
All these years, there has been much trouble within the nation, that I haven't had time to take care of this matter
Today, even a small tribe dares to usurp me!
We just took care of Xi Bei. There was also another uprising. The treasury is much depleted
If Bo Ge attacks now, we will indeed have to scramble
I sent General Bo Er Dan
can't handle the heat. Every year many die from illness. We are truly unable to handle it
If we had to send another general
it would be a little difficult at the moment
It is easy to have soldiers, but difficult to find a good general.
I dare to say something disrespectful... If we could use 14th Prince...
No.
It is easy to free a tiger, but difficult to tame. Once he is free, if he decides to rebel, it will be a big trouble
We all don't want to anger the emperor. We don't know how to serve him.
Haven't you seen all the reports being sent to the Emperor these days?
How to serve? Serve as if you life depends on it.
Yong He Gong's servants came to ask if the Emperor wants to eat lunch there.
The Emperor ate little for breakfast
He hasn't even touched lunch. He's worked so hard, even his eyes are red.
then what's wrong with the Emperor?
What's wrong? Ask God
The person who takes my place in battle
should at least be a royal prince or lord
17th prince is a good choice
But his mother's status isn't very high. He's also not very politically active.
But you have considered many factors; I am in awe.
He's always loved studying. I will give him a promotion then.
As for the fighting general, you need to choose well.
Yes
You need to do this quietly. Give 2000 men to 17th prince.
Once the front lines are more settled, you can send him in.
Yes
Close the window, I don't want to hear the wind.
Yes.
Don't worry, Emperor, you are so powerful that you can have everything under control.
Take a look at this!
Zhun Ge Er wants the Qing Empire to pay him 300,000 taels
This Mo Ge is Zhun Ge Er's new Khan (King), young and full of energy, ambitious
By doing so, one, he is tested the Qing's power
Two, he wants to use this chance to go to war and go down into history as a good warrior that won lands
Mo Ge is testing Your Majesty, you cannot agree to his request
That goes without saying. He does not know his boundaries because he has strong armies and plentiful harvest
I cannot look over this matter
Your Majesty, Lord Zhang Ting Yu wishes an audience with you
Yes
I will take my leave first
I greet Your Majesty.
Get up.
Yue General has sent an urgent about that the enemy solders had food poisoning.
The heavens look after my Qing Empire
Zhun Mo Ge requests for an audience with Your Majesty
Why does he want to come to the capital?
The Khan has come to the capital at this time when his armies are strong and their harvest bountiful
Your Majesty, we must be wary of them
You send people to the Khan's and find out his motives and reasons
I remember Physician Wen left a prescription
Maybe it would be able to put into use
Yes
Older sister, we cannot let the 17th Brother go into war. His Majesty has always been jealous of his talent
This honour of going into war, the previous Prince has seen to its 'benefits'
His Majesty's temperamental you know it well, even I cannot say anything to this decision
But to stop this, there is only one way. And the only excuse is to say that one is useless
This way, His Majesty would be happy and 18th Brother (Wangye) with then be safe
Can't the Wangye not go?
The Court is in want of competent people.There are not many qinwangs that the Emperor can trust.
No wonder Yun Xi (her husband) is so fed up and raving at home. The country is on verge of war and he wants to bring armies
Only that he has written many reports to the King, but the King has replied none
Beile Shen (Yun Xi) is still young. Naturally, there'll still be plenty of opportunities for him to contribute.
Only 17th brother is appreciated by the King
Forget it.
Wangye is unlucky to be used by the King. I'm so worried for him.
Who knows his future?
Mo Ge is already near the capital but Your Majesty is not anxious to see him
I refuse to give him glory coming to the capital
Mo Ge comes to capital full of zest, Your Majesty's cold shoulders is the best remedy to cool him down.
2 days later is 7th day of 7th month, I will go Yuan Ming Yuan (famous garden) to see him
The relevant details get Lord Zhang to plan
Your Majesty, Mo Ge is outside, waiting for an audience with you
- Tell him to come in. - Yes.
Announcing Zhun Mo Ge coming.
Liking something for me means I like it and I will try anything to obtain it.
Khan is here to see your Majesty.
You came here to meet your Majesty, why are you not using our etiquette.
“Isn't it delightful to have friends coming from distant place?"
Today is July the 7th and you Majesty has invited close friend and family for the banquet.
Hearing Khan say proverb in Zhun Ge Er language,"Isn't it delightful to have friends coming from distant place?"
Jun Zi deal with things carefully without errors as well as treat people respectfully
All men between Four Seas should be all brothers!
- I haven't seen you for awhile.- You still look the same.
Khan seems to like the Analects of Confucius.
My 17th brother, Prince Guo of the Second Ran loves the poetry and literature the most.
Khan and him can learn from each other when you are free.
Han only pour liquor on floor when it comes to people dyingHow dare you curse me?
Khan has misunderstood. I didn't mean to curse you. I am using the highest regard to welcome you to our palace.
Khan is our special guest. The first glass of wine is to thank the god to bring in the special guest.
This is a little bit far fetched.
Khan don't blame yourself. The only interaction our nations have are only for trading
for many days their has been many deaths because of the war
Without a doubt, our relations became alienated Hopefully, your attendance to Da Qing today can improve our relations
Then there's no more wars;citizens can have peaceful life as well
How wise and eloquent are you, Xi Noble ConsortYou look nothing like the consorts who always keep indoors
Khan, I am flattered I am only stating the truth
what is know was taught to me by the emperer
How can I accept this praise from you Khan?
What she said is exactly what I meant
Cheers, Khan For the joy of meeting today
Ok. Wish Da Qing Emperor long live！
Sit
Present. Today is the 7 day of the 7 month.
I have a special item that I want to share with you together
I gained a Nine Jade Rings a few years ago. The name was given because lots of jade craftsmen sacrificed themselves
during plucking as well as worked diligently to make the ring
It is said that Zhong Yuan is full of intelligent people
May I ask you to do me a favor to unlock this Nine Jade Rings?
Present this to all the Da Chen, whoever unlock it can receive grand prize
Yes
Dancing time
Emperor said that whoever unlock this can be greatly rewarded. What do you think?
What do you think?
Sir,
-Please take a look, Da Ren,-No, I don't know
No no
Da Ren, what do you think?
-How do you feel about it? - The jade rings are turned out naturally, I can't undo this
Won't you take a closer look, please?
Emperor, nobody can unlock the rings
Show it to all Wang Ye
Yes
Go away, I feel dizzy
I don't know either
-Yun Xi-I usually don't like golden or jade jewelry
I have not a clue
Xi Noble Consort
-I can't solve it-So I guess "Da Qing is full of wise" is just a fake rumor
So its not true that the Qing Dynasty has many wise men
Long Yue
Yes
Dad, I have an idea, maybe that would work
Even the Court officials can't come up with a solution.How can a girl like you have a solution?
Your daughter is young and lacks knowledge. Even if I give the wrong solution, no one will laugh. Why don't you let me try?
Fine then.
Look, Imperial father! I've untangled it!
Longyue is the most favored in my heart.
You don't have to compliment me because everyone in Da Qing knows how to do it.They just too disdained to tell you
How could you...!, this Nine Jade Rings is priceless
To me,the jade rings is a very common item.Merely for a little piece of jewelry,you completely lose your tolerance.Are all Zhun
Ge Er people that cheap?
The jade rings are our nation's precious item.Now that you break it, how are you going to responsible for it?
Longyue.
The princess is young. Please don't be angry, Khan.Congratulations, Khan.
The Princess's friendly action, in fact, will bring your nation auspicious and harmonious air.
Jade stands for ominous things which would bring harm to civilians.Thus,princess actually helped break the unlucky jade
Of course, breaking the jade rings made Khan feel unhappy.
Xi Noble Consort is right
If hatred continues war in inevitable  Why not change for the better don't know of Ke Han agrees
Using ants to stop a predator?
What does Your Majesty think?
Your Majesty, this is the newly brewed orange wine. Your Majesty give it a taste.
Mr Zhang Ting Yu wanted to me tell you  that his part was a success
Ferocious beast has its power.
Mole crickets and ants (also means tiny individuals with no power) have its own brightness.
Khan, do you really know for sure who is going to win?
It looks as if mole crickets and ants (also means tiny individuals with no power) have been losing for several rounds.
Making concession in order to gain advantages. I believe Khan has studied books on the art of war, right?
Khan likes to think that way but I hope it is not just talking in random.
I am the son of the god. Every word carries weight.
Dragon gave birth to nine sons. There might be more than one son of the god.
We both have the same root, why do we try to hurt each other? Your nation belongs to me. Of course, I care about you.
I have just heard that some of your solders have had little food poisoning out there.
You are away from home, perhaps you don't have enough medication.
Several years ago, we also had similar food poisoning happened.
I do have some secret recipe. If Khan needs it, I am more than happy to send someone to find it for you.
Thank you, Your Majesty. Khan will find it myself.
That's fine. However, those doctors travel everywhere.
If I send people out to look for it, it might take as long as several months.
I wish Khan well.
I like to go and change, please.
- Niang Niang. I have good news.  - Su eunuch.
I have good news! Mr Yue Zhong Qi pretended to  confront with Zhun Ge Er secretly attacked his forage army
Without the forage, his army also infected with an epidemic  I kind of want to see how he's going to be superior
What a good news!
Your Majesty will be very happy when he learned the news. I will be there momentarily.
Yes.
Please wait!
Hail Ke Han
How have you been, Noble Consort Ci?
What do you mean, Khan? I have never met you before.
Why are you talking as if I have seen you before?
I have eyes of eagle and never forget anyone I ever met.
Noble Consort Ci, you are really brave.
You dare to have affair with Your Majesty's brother.
I have never make trouble for Khan.
Why would you think of harm my entire family?
Are you not afraid I told Your Majesty what I saw years ago?
About years ago,
Prince Guo of the Second Rank's 2nd wife is my sister who shares similar facial feature with me.
I have heard Prince and his 2nd wife travelled together and met Khan when you were hurt by a snake.
Now that friends met again, Prince and his 2nd wife were going to invite you for a drink.
You really are good at words.
The women like Noble Consort Ci who are beautiful and smart at the same time.
Your Emperor of Qing likes it, and I like it too.
Khan, you're drunk. I'll notify the Emperor to fix a potion to help you wake up.
That's not necessary. Do you really think I'm afraid of your Emperor?
He burned all the food for my army in secret and using the food poisoning to threaten me.
It is too contemptible.
How can Khan not know that in war nothing is too deceitful?
Disaster is caused by luck  Luck appeared with disaster,
Noble Consort Ci, do you believe that I have some lost
but at the same time I am going to have some gain?
As long as we can put an end to the war and have peace, it is gain for both Qing Dynasty and your nation.
I hope the thing I want, Your Emperor of Qing
will be willing to part with.
- scene -
I have confirm it for Your Majesty. It did happen.
You take your people and make sure you find the evidence.
I got it.
Your Majesty, Khan Mo Ge would like to see you for an important matter.
Khan said there is something he really like and hoping Your Majesty will grant it to him.