how has it be prepared for the memorial of Hui Fei's seven days?
it is ready
a service is carrying on at the Baohua Temple
I was thinking
a serve cannot comfort the soul of the Sister in heaven
you had ordered to kill Jingbai and Feiwen at the time
Chenqie don't think that's enough
Guaerjia shi instigated the discontent in the Harem
and her father staged troubles at the court
do the father and daughter want to push our family to the path of death?
Zhen know you don't like
yet the harem and the court connects in such way that touches one hair would move whole body
things cannot be rushed
your name is Yurao
Huangshang knew but still ask
a person of Rao means is enchantingly beautiful and charming
your beauty doesn't match your strong personality
a young woman should be gentle and soft
Zhen award you a name: Yuwan, what do you think?
the word, Wan, is alright; where is its origin from?
Huangshang award a name to the third sister, it can't be randomly picked
praise her beautiful shape, miss her charming gentleness
from Zhang Hua's Missing Forever, a sentence praising beauties
praise a beauty's enchantment, her eyes charmed the whole country
this poem is eulogy for a dead beauty
I am alive and well standing in front of Huangshang
Zhen just made an anology
Zhang hua's poem of Missing Forever was to commemorate his dead wife
Emperor,
you don't think to have Yurao as a wife, do you?
it's extremely distinctive between wife and concubines in the harem
wife is Empress, I have no intention to get a wife
Chenqie have less forture to be a wife, willingly serve huangshang with my life
but Yurao's temperament is proud and strong
not suit to be a concubine to serve
though you are concubine but you're Zhen's favor
and titled Guifei, under only one person
if your sister is like you, it wouldn't be bad
though the 17th Prince likes my second sister
she's still second wife
Chenqie have no heart to go after the position of Empress
but do you want to see all my sisters be concubines?
only awarded a name
.didn't expect that caused your sadness. it's Zhen's careless
the word, Wan, is not good. let's not talk about it
your sister is still young
if there is a good family, Zhen will pay attention
not talk about it now
Yurao saw the misfortune of the family when I was small
Huangshang asked why my personality was so strong
if Huangshang knew what I experienced and how I went to Ningguta with my parents
and how much we suffered, you'd have the answer
zhen like to hear
Emperor leaves.
Chenqie see Huangshang off
Huangshang didn't say other things and put this into my hand
said he'll take it back later
this pendant of mandarin duck
is carried by Huangshang everyday
thus, sister
I can't keep this
Huangshang treasures this pendant very much
maybe you look too much like Cunyuan Empress
Zhen Yurao is Zhen Yurao, I can be only unique, not a substitute
good
this is our Zhen's daughter
Huangshang, it's time for your nap
you won't be spirited in the afternoon otherwise
Huangshang, your jade pendant you carried all the time, how come it's not there?
Zhen awarded to Yurao
Third Miss? --- what then?
Nucai thought the third miss is really lucky
that jade pendant was the favorite piece of Cunyuan Empress
is this called lucky?
the time she's lucky is in future. put up the resting incense
Yes
I heard Huangshang punished the family of Guaerjia Shi because of her disrespect
that exposed her mother E Min
has been framed ministers, formed sect, and done some dirty business
behaved cruel and merciless, and etc. these years
in a month, house raided, imprisoned, and exiled
Huangshang is busy in the court and our ears are as busy
E Min had committed suicide in prison in desperation
in fact, Huangshang had to know some of the Guaerjia clan are not punished
only one thing in the court could affect many other things, it has to be cautious
do it slowly is a way
I thought the moves by Emperor seem to want to cut off their foundation
when it would see results if doing it slowly?
if don't count all crimes. how criminals be all captured and root of the cause be eliminated?
Guaerjia Wenyuan is arrogant, and her father is not better
Huangshang moved with thunderbolt, and they had no time to hit back
Empress niangniang, Empress niangniang
Empress Niang Niang!
Empress Niang Niang!  Don't run!
stop, stop
stop
Empress Niang Niang! Empress Niang!  Stop!
Chenqie Guaerjia Shi beg to see Emppress niangniang
stop
Guaerjia Shi
adult males all have their heads cut off
less than 14 years old, exile to western border area
wives and daughters become servants
Emperor, Emperor!
beg to forgive my family, Huangshang
Emperor!
Su Peisheng
Nucai is here
to tell Guaerjia Shi, consider she served me so many years
demote her as ordinary person, not death
Emperor,
please forgive my family, Huangshang, I live worse than die
Huangshang, you believed a slut
wronged your loyal minister
Zhen Huan, you slut
I won't forgive you if I become a ghost; come out, Zhen Huan
why you are still watching?
go handling it
Yes
Zhen Huan, slut, I won't forgive you if I'm a ghost
I want to become a horrific ghost
bury in a wilderness, and not tell Huangshang
so that get Huangshang's ear dirty
Zhen'll write another edict
exonerate your father's wrongs for many years, and restore his position
thanks Huangshang
don't give Chenqie's father higher position, he's really old now
then Zhen will give hjavascript:void(0);im
ceremonial position of fourth level, let him growing old peacefully
thanks Huangshang
know why she didn't have a good death?
Chenqie don't know
she's too useless. useless person in the Harem has no other way out except death
women in the Harem are difficult to dealing with. we have to be more careful
yes
Why didn't Sister interrogate more of Guaerjia?
let her accuse Empress was the chief plotter
there are people in the clan alive, and she wouldn't involve them
and she hated me in her bones
how could she accuse the one that can control me?
Wangye has collected the criminal evidence of the Guaerjia clan for years
they can finally be used now
the 17th Prince is your husband and helping his father-in-law is reasonable
you live outside, you and Wangye need to take care of the family
of course, don't worry, Sister
Wangye could make so much effort, it's because your effort at the Royal Household
is it easy to be with Meng Jingxian?
did she wrong you?
how could she?
her health is improving lately
but she still take medicine daily
Wangye pities her and she has everything
but they don't talk much
Wangye didn't have much feelings to her
not like you that knew Wangye for many years
Sister is mocking me
but Wangye treats me really well
Sister, I want to go out
Sanmei dresses so pretty, where are you going?
I don't know where she's going. a growing up girl has more ideas, I can't watch her closely
yesterday I heard from Wangye that Shen Beile went to see Dowager
and ran into our third sister
don't know why but both were blushed. and Dowager felt strange
when this happened?
what did you mean, Sister?
Shen Beile, since when?
about... I don't remember
don't you care his mother was from a low background?
he never looked down upon me
I remember someone used to say
I'd rather marry an ordinary man than enter a royal house
I don't know who said that
don't laugh at me, sister
Yunxi, he's different than Huangshang, he's good
if you really mean it
I can go to Huangshang, ask him to permit your marriage
only one thing, you can't sneak out to see him
so that become laughable when others know
alright. Sister Yuying, I'm leaving
Sister have decided?
you and I can tell the intention of Huangshang to Yurao
it's better to marry her now since the situation is still easy to deal with
I think back and forth that it's useless if just marrying an ordinary family
only marrying Huangshang's brother could stop Huangshang's idea
otherwise there would be a lot of troubles in future
that's good. fortunately Shen Beile and Third Sister are like each other
that save a lot of troubles
only not many concubines in the harem
the eyes of Huangshang are looking at Yurao all the time
have to find a way to have Huangshang looking somewhere else
don't worry, Sister. let me take up the task
Caiping, how many years have you been with Wangye?
five or six years
did Wangye treat you well? Wangye is my savior
did you know Wangye's situation in the court?
Huangshang has many brothers
but he cares few
some demoted, some imprisoned, don't know when Wangye would be the same situation
our Huangshang
not lenient even to blood brothers
Ce Fujing
come
we're outside, don't know the emotions of Huangshang
if there is someone closed to Huangshang
that comes from our house
that could make Huangshang happy
wouldn't our house have a layer of assurance?
Ce Fujin means...
Nubi can't carry such a big task
you can. our royal house including Qingliang Terrace
you are the most beautiful girl
in addition, you are so loyal to Wangye
you are the only one that can do this
Nubi...
if you still remember how Wangye treats you, you should think for our house
don't worry
Huangshang'll like you for certain
Emperor will definitely like you.
Nubi...
will obey the order of Ce Fujin
did Guifei niangniang know
someone exposed that the father of An Pin extorted 80 million taes of silver and several houses
Huangshang is really angry this time
I didn't know if Guiren didn't tell me
everyone in the harem gossips about this
Guifei looks at this bird how white its feathers are like snow
would An Bihuai see this bird made of silver?
guiren is good at making joke
three years clean county head, could make 100,000 tael of silver
let alone An Bihuai is a father-in-law of the Emperor, 80 million taels is nothing
his so-called father-in-law was named by himself, he cheated only idiot
Huangshang didn't view him that way
he's rid of official position, and put into prison
the daughter gets favor of Emperor is most important; it doesn't matter he's real father-in-law or not
Guiren is smart
had your father paying attention in secret that caught An Bihuai
otherwise An Pin is too pleased
if it's not for Niangniang's plan, it would still be useless even I had the evidence of An Bihuai
Huangshang is angry of the Guaerjia Clan, it's his misfortune that he ram into it
furthermore, his county head was due to Huangshang's favor to An Pin
this is like slapping on Huangshang's face and made Huangshang a laughing stuff
I heard that An Pin has been kneeing outside the Yangxin Palace,
crying for two days
Greetings to Niangniang
Su Gonggong
Huangshang asks to have dinner with Niangniang at the Yangxin palace
Niangniang, please
I know
Pinqie wouldn't bother more
farewell
why is Sister an doing this?
your health is more important
Sister won't deny my opportunity to beg forgiveness?
how could I?
I worry about that it's late in night and windy and cold
Sister is harmed in case
maybe
a mouse comes from somewhere and bites Sister
what to do if you get sick?
Sister is joking
how could there be mouse in yangxin Palace
yes, I forgot
these are in the prison only
I worried about wrong thing
I shouldn't worry about Sister An
but to worry...
Uncle An
Niangniang happy
Greetings to the Emperor.
Zhen's been waiting for you for a while
Chenqie saw Sister An kneeing outside, I felt pity and offered a few advices
how could she listen?
she has only her becoming nothing father right now in her heart. Zhen gave him a county head
offered a promotion path
he ravaged it that had me lost face
don't be angry, Huangshang
no matter how bad, An Bihuai is An Bihuai, it shouldn't be involved with Sister An
Huangshang let her get up
Zhen never wanted to punish her
it's herself wanting to knee there to take punishment for her father; most improper
Sister An is anxious to saving her father
Huangshang don't blame her
would Huangshang forgive An Bihuai? --- how could I?
Zhen won't shift my angry to her
but also won't forgive her father because of her
sister An hasn't drink and eat for two days
and has no sleep and rest
Huangshang didn't worry about her?
self harm of concubine is a big crime, and will cause harm to her family
she wouldn't dare
Emperor.
Sister An dresses plain
causes pity more than usual
yet regretable
what?
the pure and white are cleanest originally
shouldn't be intertwined with lust
involved with lust
dirties the nature of pure and white
it's late and cold. take An Pin back
zhen will imprison An Bihuai
you beg more, Zhen will kill him!
Emperor,
Emperor!
Chenqie beg Empress to save Chenqie's father
Bengong are afraid that I couldn't even I wanted to
if Niangniang are willing to lend a helping hand
Chenqie will serve Niangniang to my death
it's not Bengong didn't want to help you this tiem
I'm afraid that only you can help yourself
Niangniang, please state it clearly for me
Huangshang is kind, and care about children
you serve Huangshang for many years, and never got pregnant
Bengong has a secret prescription that is very effective
but the drug is risky and dangerous
if you get pregnant and favor of Huangshang
huangshang would extend his favor of you to the crows on your roof naturally
but Chenqie has been used the muscle resting pill
even I'm pregnant, I won't carry it to birth, I'm afraid
since your pregnancy would solve immediate trouble, it's not necessary to give birth
I heard from Yuying that Huangshang is interested in Yurao
if Xi Guifei pleas, it would be good if Huangshang allows the marriage
if not
how do you plan to do?
I'm a Beile that gets the least attention. I don't want anything
Yurao is the only thing I want
but you have to know
we can't fight anything over Huangshang no matter how we try
Huangshang can get a person, can he get the heart of someone?
even if I won't be successful, I have to try with all my heart
I had lost someone I loved, so I understand how you feel
I ask you one word only, are you really serious about Yurao?
my heart is like stone
can't be changed
I've know his feeling sometimes ago
it's worth the effort for how he feels about Yurao
don't worry
though we don't have 100% certainty for this
we have to try our best so that the sister won't be regretted for the rest of her life
now Dowager is in critical condition, we have to try this as early as possible
so that you won't have to wait for three years in case Dowager is passed away
I've done the thing Older Sister asked last time
the new concubine will enter the Harem this afternoon
what kind of person? --- Sister know her, Caiping
how could be her?
she's lucky. Huangshang has awarded her Ying Daying
Emperor,
the person from Jingshi house is here
the person from the 17 Prince's House is here?
yes, she's lived in Changchun Palace. --- how does she look?
this is the person picked by Yu Fujin, she is very good naturally
it's nice of the 17th Prince house
I'm busy at the court and hadn't found time to walk with you lately
Huangshang made up to me today?
you mock Zhen again
you showed up in front of Zhen intentionally?
intentional is unnecessary
such thing happens everyday
their feeling is deep that
why don't we fulfill their desire since we had gone through the experience before?
Xi Guifei, you are so smart that
you should've know how I feel about Yurao
Huangshang is smarter 100 times than Chenqie, how couldn't you know that king has desire, fairy has no dream
Zhen has a way to deal with that
even Huangshang has a way, shouldn't you ask how Yurao feels about it?
what benefit if she's forced?
Shen Beila is your blood brother
Huangshang doesn't approve that you and I are together
I'll keep begging if Huangshang is not allowed
if he's not allowed, I won't marry like the 17th brother
in a word, I'll never let you down
and won't marry anyone else
I know, before dust is settled, you have a lot of worries. I promise you one word
don't worry
I know
go to Ying Daying.
Huangshang, you forgot that
you had awarded Ying Daying as Changzai, she is having the award ceremony
okay. that won't be finished for a while
then, where are we going?
go to Yanxi Palace
Get ready to go to Yan Xi Palace.
Huangshang went away with a long face, what's going on?
I have to do it no matter what
Nubi worry that Huangshang is really angry that would harm Niangniang
Sister
look at you, didn't even know to wipe out your sweat, really like a child
are you happy to see Shen Baile today? ---happy
I'm happy to see him and talk with him
it's good you're happy
Oldest Sister wish you will always be happy like today
Oldest sister.
as long as you're happy
Sister will do anything for you
ten thousand peaces to Huangshang
rise
what you played is Qi Ao
have Yurao had a gentleman you admire and miss?
do you know Zhen as a gentleman like Yurao playing the Qin very much?
is Huangshang like Chennu because of my sister?
people say that Yurao has resemblance of Sister
you resemble her, yet not resemble her
you have heroine beauty that she doesn't have
on appearance, you resemble my late wife
really?
Chennu seem not resemble Empress
she is Empress, not my wife. my wife passed away long time ago
Chennu understand. Huangshang can have many empresses
but have only one wife
. you are smart. --- how about my sister?
your sister is Zhen's most important woman
you asked so many questions, do you want to be Zhen's woman?
Chennu admire Huangshang's wife
why?
though Huangshang's wife passed away long time ago, Huangshang still consider herself as wife only
and constantly thinks of her.
Huangshang said like Yurao, right?
Yes.
Chennu have a wish since I was little to become the wife of someone I love
not concubine, not most important woman, but the only wife that he loves most
it's pity Huangshang have wife already, and can't fulfill my wish
Chennu hope to realize my wish someday,
not admire huangshang's wife forever
Zhen said that you are smart, and very much like your sister
this is not smart, it is fact
if Huangshang like Chennu and keep Chennu In the Harem
what could Huangshang bring me? or abolish Empress and take me to Jingren Palace?
Empress is only Empress, not Huangshang's wife
forgive my talkative, Huangshang and your wife loved each other, right?
Chennu and Yunxi love each other. Chennu wouldn't dare to ask Huangshang allow me to be his formal wife
it's okay that I'll be his concubine as long as we can be together, I beg Huangshang
didn't you want only be his wife?
Empress is Huangshang's wife in title
but Huangshang doesn't view her as wife
though Chennu couldn't be wife in name for Yunxi
his heart has me only and my heart have him
Chennu know he won't marry anyone else, and Chennu is the only one he loves, am I not the wife in his heart?
you stand up
Chennu know Huangshagn like me; since like, Huangshang should fulfill my wish
besides Empress, Huangshang have so many women; I entered the harem not long and I saw Sister suffered so much twist and turns
though Huangshang thought Sister is the most important woman, she has to live extremely diligently and cautiously
Chennu don't want to live life like that in future
Huangshang's like is precious and Chennu won't dare to disappoint you
but love in the world is not only restricted between man and woman
Chennu beg Huangshang like me as a younger sister
this is the pendant Huangshang let me to keep, Chennu return it now
please allow Chennu and Yunxi's wish
this jade pendant, Zhen award to you
Huangshang, the lamp is dim, don't hurt your eyes
Nucai change a bright one for you
Emperor,
Zhen had my eyes on a woman
want to take her as concubine but she is not willing
what do you think?
Nucai don't know what kind of person this woman is
but Nucai thought that no matter how good this woman is, she can't compare to Cunyuan Empress
what do you mean?
Nucai thought, it doesn't matter whom Huangshang like
it is her luck to make Huangshang happy
for Cunyuan empress
you
seeing things too cruel
alright. one thing that Zhen want you to deal with for me
Xi Guifei marries her sister, can follow Princess Duoluo to prepare for dowry
Yunxi marries, promote Xi Taipin to Taifei; Dowager has been ill
having some happy things in the Harem
view it as warding off sickness for Dowager
Guifei marries younger sister, Emperor marries younger brother, such a rare happy occasion
Dowager will get better if she know such happy thing
Dowager, Dowager
Ai Jia am afraid that I won't last long
Don't say that, Dowager. doctors are waiting outside
Nubi have them in
Zhuxi
Ai Jia is muddle headed
but in my head
one idea is turning around
Aijia have been
protecting Yihiu the position of Empress
for the glory of Wulanala clan and Wuya clan
am I wrong?
Dowager, don't say that
At that time, what Yixiu
did to Chunyuan,
it was not that Aijia didn't know
but I couldn't find another way
if Yihiu died, Wulanala clan
would have no one to inherit the position of Empress
Aijia tried and suffered so much to become Dowager
I couldn't lose the effort I put in with all my life
therefore even I knew
Yihiu harmed concubines and children of Emperor
Aijia had to save her position of Empress
save her position of Empress
Dowager advised Empress many times
it was Empress who refused to repent
it is Empress that killed so many people
if she listened to Dowager and repent, it would be good
no matter how much Aijia didn't like her,
I have to care about the glory of the clan
these days
Aijia dreamt about Cunyuan every night
Aijia owe her
Dowager said
Cunyuan Empress was too soft
to be Empress in charge of the Harem
only Yihiu could keep the position of Empress
not fall into other's hand
Aijia also let Emperor down
let down those royal grandchildren who died wrongfully
yet now
Aijia can have Emperor listen to me one day
but not his whole life
my hearty and bloody efforts...
don't worry so much
give me brush and paper
Aijia, Aijia want to leave a testamentary edict
in case
Dowager, you want to pay more attention to your illness
you must remember
in case I'm not here
you safe keep this edict
if there is change in the position of Empress
use it to protect the Empress
yes, Nubi go get it
Nubi go get it
Emperor and the Noble Consort Xi leave.
Escort the Emperor.
Just then when I was with you,
Yunli and Yuying
Yunxi and Yurao
we are three couples made by heaven.
Sister Yurao is extremely grateful to Emperor
having you, Zhen like to fulfill Yurao's wish
Emperor! Emperor!
stop
Emperor!
Dowager niangniang
Dowager niangniang is not good