~ Episode 13 ~
Your Majesty slept with Precious Shen soundly yesterday.
how come you don't rest more?
I still need to worry about the court.
You didn't sleep well yesterday right?
First, because I was happy yesterday,
Second, also to order the Imperial Doctors
to keep an eye on Precious Shen's baby.
You've worked hard.
About Precious Shen...
What are your instructions?
I want put Precious Shen's rank up higher.
She is loved by you and also pregnant
to promote her would not be amiss
But there is no rule that when a concubine or lady is pregnant,
they must be promoted.
The main reason is that she is pregnant
That makes her precious
Of course,
Precious Smile is smart and intelligent and obeys by the rules,
Her friend Precious Shen behaves magnanimously
Do you intend to also promote Smile from 'Precious' to 'Pin'?
She deserves it.
Of course.
However, this would mean that
There will be 2 masters in Palace of Whole Blessings.
If she move to other palaces
it's inconvenient for Precious Shen since she's pregnant
How about waiting till the birth?
and let the two happy events come together
What you said sounds reasonable.
How about a gift first?
Gold and pearls are mere trinkets
temporarily I cannot promote her,
How about choosing a title for her first?
Your Majesty must have already had an idea.
I thought of a word -- 'Hui (virtuous)'
Virtuous and decent
It is suitable for Precious Shen
Precious Smile and Precious Shen are like sisters
Now they are on the same rank.
Jie Jie you are in luck
What great fortune?
all of a sudden, I almost can't go anywhere.
What a pain. I cannot do anything
so boring
there's still 9 months. But it is quick
I heard that in the 8th month of your pregnancy,
your mother can visit you.
A family reunion.
Really? That would be great!
I think that the one in your tummy
is suitable for me to be the godmother of.
Look, you are full of potential,
but you're still afraid no one will call you "mother"?
I don't even know if its a boy or a girl yet.
Boy or girl, both are great
But I want it to be a boy.
Then I will have someone to lean on..
His Majesty dotes you a lot now.
Whether it's a girl or boy, he'll love either
Maybe not until the end of your pregnancy
you'll be promoted
Stop making fun of me.
Oh yes, this morning,
I thought of something important
I wanted to tell you now.
What is more important than your baby currently?
This is very serious.
Princess of Glory is losing power, and she might create trouble again.
I'm afraid that you can't handle her alone.
Also, while I think
Our King is not someone who keeps on favouring only one person
I'm afraid that someone will take this chance to create mischief
You want to bring Ling Long here?
Correct.
Look at you. Last time you said Ling Long is evil,
now you think that she is kind.
You don't know. Being cruel has its own benefits.
I'm worried that you cannot do it yourself.
First bring her here.
Then when there is trouble,
we can try to solve it together.
I will speak to His Majesty about his as soon as possible.
His Majesty would most likely agree I think.
Now, you are the most favoured one
his Majesty must agree
But don't think and worry too much. Take care of yourself
Also take care of your baby too.
yes sister, what you said is true.
Older sister!
Finally you came.
Was it really hot on your way?
No it is alright.
Its so warm today, why are you standing here.
You're the most fearful of hot weather,
you made me worry.
oh yeah, sister mei just said one word,
and I was able to come.
How is she?
Everything is fine.
Now that your here, she is more happy.
Oh I forgot. On my way here,I heard from the eunuches, that
now sister mei has a baby,
His majesty listens to her words a lot.
When you see him you will know
Lets go greet the emporer first.
what ever you say.
Prince, you have been kneeling here for a whole day already
Let's go back already.
Su Gong Gong
Greeting Precious Smile, Greetings Promise An.
Su Gong Gong, who is that child?
That's the fourth prince. He wants to see His Majesty.
The 4th prince?
I've never heard about him before.
He has been raised in Yuan Ming Yuan.
His Majesty doesn't have time to see the 4th prince?
I'm afraid he won't have the time to see you and
Promise An either.
Young Mistress please go back.
How about,
let's just go back first.
What a pitiful child.
the prince might get sick.
please take care of him Gong Gong.
send him a lotus seed and lily porridge to clear the summer-heat
yes.
There is not much poeple in Yuan Ming Yuan.
Now that you have come, it will be more lively.
I can only come,
because of you and sister Shen remember me.
How is the Emperor and Princess of Glory?
Princess of Glory lives far away from his majesty's residence
so they rarely see each other
Greeting young mistresses.
Greeting Precious Smile,
may you have good health.
Granny Zhang, she is Precious Smile
Precious Smile
You may rise 4th prince.
You and I have never met
how do you know who I am?
I saw you once out of the Hall of Administrative
I feel Niangniang is very kind
so I know you
Niangniang also knows me
Juat as prince said
I also feel like you
And is destined,
to have trouble constantly on your mind.
This is Promise An
Greetings Niangniang An
You may rise 4th prince.
Sister
Walk around and see if you like it here.
Later I will accompany you
to see Precious Shen.
I shall take my leave.
Liuzhu follow mistress An
Yes
Precious Smile and I have some things to say to each other,
please move further away.
Yes.
You and Granny Zhang have a good relationship.
what do you have to say to me that even Granny Zhang can't hear?
Excuse me
but Niangniang always accompanies Imperial Father
you are most favoured
I just want to ask you a question
does Imperial Father dislike me?
Impossible. You Imperial Father is just too busy right now.
Then how come he leaves me here every year?
And never comes and visits me?
and rarely lets me greet him.
and do what I am supposed to do.
There is too much to do in the court. His Majesty is very busy.
and although you have always been in Yuan Ming Yuan,
and rarely sees the Emperor.
the care that his Majesty has given you is no less
than the 5th prince.
Don't you see that he rarely visits the 5th prince too?
But 5th prince has his mother, I don't.
My mother's position is low, so no one respects her.
Respect yourself, then you'll be respected
I don't know whether your mother's position is low
But parents always loves their children,
It doesn't matter how anyone else see you,
what really matters is how you see yourself
In several years, people will eventually come to respect you.
really?
if you don't believe me, then you wouldn't have asked me.
Thank you very much for your advice Precious Smile!
Just one thing,
you and I have only met for a moment,
why do you believe me?
Being a person that Imperial Father likes, you must be smart and not simple-minded.
Also, I heard
that you're not even afraid of Princess of Glory
I respect people who are daring.
Thanks for your compliments
I have something to tell you:
(CHINESE IDIOM) To be the respected one
(CHINESE IDIOM) rather than respect him
Is Imperial Father really that busy?
If he really is that busy
when I grow up, I will help Imperial Father.
You can't say this easily.
come, i'll take you to eat dessert.
okay!
Yan Qing Xi Jiu
It is cool and beautiful here
what a wonderful place
The music coming from above the lake
we can hear it clearly here
The palace's rules are strict
so kinsmen of the emperor can't be with concubines
except at important festival
I don't know any one of these people.
Do you know them sister?
That one is 5th prince, Prince of Hen with his side lady
"Prince Hen"
The first one seems so solemn
making me scared.
but he's very nice to his side lady
"Prince Dun"
That is the 10th prince
his mother is the late Empress' sister
his identity is so honourable, so he's solemn naturally
the 10th prince was disliked by the late emperor
so he has a bad temper
but he is very nice to his ladies
They all say that a brave man is a real man
but in my opinion a kind man is a real man
10th, I drink a toast to you and your lady
Thank your majesty
Sister, look at the Prince Dun
he is not polite to his majesty
why does his majesty want to win him over ?
His majesty ascended the throne not long
and doesn't want the situation to be turbulent
and get a accusation of not showing brotherly love.
17th must meet some fresh things and doesn't want to leave
it is so late
Your majesty, you know 17th brother
"Duke Shen"
He does whatever he likes
It's just a family feast
I know he's always absent, never mind
Oh, Precious Virtuous, your hair stick is so delicate
Is it from Empress Dowager
Yes
Empress Dowager knew Precious Virtuous was pregnant
so she specially sent someone to deliver it
the two immortals on the hair stick
stand for having many children and good luck
What is valued in this hair stick
is Empress Dowager worn it during she's bearing 14th prince
We can see, Empress Dowager is waiting for
the baby in Precious Virtuous' tummy
I also want to know
how pretty the AGe (prince) is
it may not be a prince
I'm looking forward to a princess
as lovely as Wenyi
Play with it
Princess of Modesty ( Duan Fei)
Lady Duan Fei is here.
I wish the King and his wife good health.
You may rise.
Thank you my King.
Your King has more family members.
Princess of Modesty doesn't meet any others all the time
So you may still keep the old vision.
The sun is so bright, but you still rushed here.
It's just a birthday feast for a little child
When it's not anything urgent.
Wenyi's first birthday is important
I should come here at least to congratulate the both of you.
As well, I have not seen Wenyi for a long time
You may take a seat then.
Thank you my King.
The last time we met.
Princess Wenyi was just 1 month old
Hurry, take princess to the lady
I have a heart too. I wish to hold the baby.
However, I don't have the strength to.
and I'm afraid I'd drop her.
Luckily, Here
This necklace is your marriage gift.
Wen Yi is still a child.
How can you gift her such an expensive gift?
You have a memory my King.
Unfortunately, over these many years' illness
Keeping it is of no use.
Wen Yi is so cute. Giving it to her is best.
Thank you very much my lady.
No need to thank me.
I want to go out for a walk.
If the King notices, just say I'll be back soon.
Let's rest for a bit. My legs are tired.
Me too.
Hey, look, there are some big fish in the pond.
Hold this for me.
How can you take your shoes off.
Don't worry. It's fine here.
What if others see you?
Your temper hasn't changed a bit.
As if you're still playing in the house.
Look, Lui Zhuo, there are so many fish!
Looks interesting.
Let's go down to play in the water okay?
The water is pretty cold.
Let's go down to play for a bit.
There should be no one here.
I just got these clothes made today.
If they got dirty, I'd feel sad inside.
Get dirty...
Let's see if your clothes get dirty or not!
You have to pay for my clothes!
Shh. Wait for me here. Hold my arm for a sec.
Be careful.
Young mistress! Young mistress! Young mistress!
Who are you?
Get away!
You became a drowned rat yourself. And you still blame others?
Who are you? How dare you be disrespectful?
Li Houzhu once said,(Li Houzhu: the final Southern Tang ruler )
"Beauty with white hands, she hold aloft the cyan glass to toast to me"
to praise the woman's fair-skinned
He said it really is true.
I think that is better to use the "Beauty with white and slender feet, she is wearing a cyan clothes."
Better able to express the feet of the white and slender.
Help me put on my shoes.
Here
Duke, please behave yourself!
Young Mistress.
Liuzhu, greet the Duke of Fruits
You've never met me, how do you know I'm the Duke of Fruits?
Other than the Duke of Fruits, who else in the palace
would always have a vertical flute by his side
and who else can be drinking the rose wine from Tibet's tribute
and who would dare be so ill-mannered in the palace?
Is the smell of wine on me that strong?
I beg your pardon
You're my brother's newest favourite?
This is Precious Smiles!
If I have offended you, please forgive me
Your Lord Duke is drunk
bring him back to sober up
Yes
His Majesty is waiting for me. Please excuse me
What is your name?
My lowly name is not fit to be heard by you
You are drunk, please go and rest
Today's matter cannot be known by anyone
Otherwise, I'll die without a place for my body to rest
My respects to Pin of Respects.
Hurry and rise
I saw that Meimei's alcohol tolerence wasn't very good
and wanted to take a look
But who knew that you already weren't inside
I felt that I was reaching my alcohol limit
so I came out for a walk
We see the same songs and dances every year
I'm rather bored of it
Just look on as shirking.
Is sister willing to
sit with me for a while in the side hall?
Niang Niang is so hospitable, of course I will
Your Majesty, I think
that although the songs and dances are magnificent,
they're a bit stiff.
Since this is a family feast, and everyone present is family,
why not do something more relaxing?
Do you have any ideas? Let's hear them.
All the sisters present are Your Majesty's company
and naturally have many talents.
Why not write down these talents and draw slips?
Whatever one draws,
she must come out and entertain the guests.
What does Your Majesty think?
This idea is interesting. Let's do as you say then.
Yes.
It's good that Meimei is kind
But in this palace,
being too kind is a bad thing
You must remember one thing
protecting oneself is the most important
Many thanks for Jiejie's advice
I am stupid
I hope Jiejie will give me more advice
You've met the 4th prince
He's intelligent and healthy
So why does the Emperor refuse to see him?
Have you ever wondered why?
I've been ignorant
In Palace, people always say "A high status son makes his mother become respected,"
but an unknow saying is "A high status mother makes her son become respected."
His Majesty dislikes 4th prince
because his birth mother was a lowly servant
from Rehe Palace (imperial resort).
This matter happened
when the Emperor was still a Duke
Once he had an argument with the 8th prince
and had too much to drink
He thus ended up spending the night with a palace maid
Who knew that this resulted in the 4th prince's birth
And this matter was found out by the 8th prince
who told the previous Emperor
This resulted in the Emperor
being berated for his careless and loose behaviour
It almost cost him his Dukedom
The palace maid was ugly
and of a lowly status
That's why the Emperor has never liked her
and left her in the Travelling Palace to give birth
This woman had a hard life
she even passed away during labour
leaving behind the 4th prince
And then the 4th prince was left to be raised in the Yuan Ming Gardens
What one cannot see cannot bother you
Thank you for your teachings
It's getting late, we should return to the feast
Your Majesty, I have already prepared everything
Since Hui Meimei is with child,
why don't I
draw the slips?
What? You came up with the idea
but you won't participate yourself?
I have no merits. I can only make bead strands.
It is hard for me to be elegant.
I've already thought about it
Sisters, no matter what you perform,
I will give you a bead strand as a token of my appreciation.
Your Majesty, what do you think?
Although you are lazy,I reluctantly let you cross the border.
Really interesting
I've long heard that every Niang Niang in the palace has her own talent
Today will be eye-opening
Then, how about Empress pick first?
You're the birthday girl's mother
You can pick for me
Thanks Empress for the honor
Empress, please share your beautiful calligraphy with us
and write the word "Shou" (longevity).
In front of so many people...you put me in a difficult spot.
Calligraphy is the Empress's unique talent
In my opinion, Precious Cao's lucky draw
makes this a breeze for the Empress.
Since it is so,
today is Princess Wen Yi's birthday.
Then I will write the word "longevity" as a present to her
I thank Empress on behalf of Wen Yi
Empress's handwriting is becoming better and better
Only more compact.
Your Majesties, please excuse me
I'm really not feeling well
I cannot stay for the fun
You are not feeling well. Quickly go back to lie down and rest.
I will visit you when I have time
Thanks Your Majesty
Niang Niang, although your health is important,
but leaving this early...
I'm afraid it will dampen His Majesty's spirits.
If I stayed there,
I'm afraid I would dampen the spirits of those who like to show off.
I really can't stand those fake people
out of sight, out of mind
This is for Precious Smile
Please dance Wild Goose Fly (implies girl's light and graceful body)
your majesty, Precious Smile
is light and graceful
It is suitable for her
Wild Goose Fly is created by Emperor Xuanzong of Tang's Princess of Plum
and lost for a long time
But the former Empress-- Empress of Origin loved dancing
sought this dance
and amended it
Once she danced, the world would be startled
so this dance is very popular at that time
But the Wild Goose Fly is the hardest dance to learn
if it was performed well, it will be a surprise
but if not, it will be awful
Sister Wan is young
how can she dance Wild Goose Fly
Precious Cao, you are constraining her
Precious Smile is clever
Besides, every girl can dance Wild Goose Fly
if not as good as Empress of Origin
it will be reasonable
we are sisters
we can understand
My dancing skill is poor
I'd better not do it
If she can't do it, why constraining her
Empress of Origin's movement
no one can compare with
Princess of Glory's words are provocable
if sister Smile doesn't dance
Precious Cao and Precious Virtuous will be disappointed
so does anyone else
if she does
and performed badly, it will be a shame for her
if performed well, it will be fine
but if copy Empress of Origin's dance
it will be a disrespect to the former Empress
Your majesty, I heard that
you got a Precious Smile
talented and beautiful. But she can't dance
I'm afraid
she's not as good as a geisha in my mansion
how can she serve your majesty
Those women who without talent are moral
dance Wild Goose Fly?
they are only goodlooking
So
she doesn't deserve the reputation of talented and beautiful
just serves with her appearance
and it seems that your majesty judge people with their appearance only
Wild Goose Fly is easy to learn but hard to perform well, you'd better not do it
perform another thing
Your majesty, Sister Smile is into the book
but not singing and dancing
how about composing a poem
to congratulate the Princess
Wild Goose Fly has not been performed in the palaces for a long time
I also want to watch it
Precious Smile, you just dance a piece
May I change my clothes first
Changing clothes is fine, but if she wants to pee...
Don't say drunken words in front of his Majesty
It's not that young mistress doesn't know the dance
It's just that to dance or not to dance, good or bad,
are both like riding a tiger.
What others want to see
is not the movements of the Wild Goose Fly dance,
but a startled bird.
Help me change
Your Majesty, I have finished changing
Your majesty
ordinary instruments are in poor tasts
Allow me to play the instrument
an Sister An to sing a song to accompany Precious Smile's dance.
I would be glad to
Get the Princess Dowager Shu's "Always Miss" qin
When the late Emperor's Princess Shu first came in the palaces
The late Emperor give her a zither named Always Miss
and a flute named Always Together as the taken of love
After the late emperor passed away,
Concubine Shu requested to leave the palace to practice Buddhism.
This zither and flute were left in the palace
Today, you are lucky.
(Lyrics from Goddess Luo Rhapsody)
She with a charming sprightly carriage,like a lightly flew frightened wild goose.
Her body curves soft, like a dragon playing soar up into the air.
Her face is bright, like a chrysanthemum in full bloom in the fall.
Her body is plump, like spring dense pine.
Aerial behavior like cloudlet gently hide the moon.
Flying Image like a breeze blow convoluted snowflakes.
From afar,
bright white like a rising sun in the sunglow.
Her movements cannot compare to those of Empress Chun Yuan's back in the day
Beautiful, but not creative
Respects are more important than creative
How many more surprises do you have that I don't know about?
It's just my little trick, your majesty don't laugh at me
Surly, the dance is so wonderful
comparable to the top dancer at my estate
10th brother, you don't understand
Precious Smile's dance is as great as the Princess of Plum's
Long ago, Princess of Plum dance the Wild Goose Fly
Xuan Zong called her Plum Spirit
Wild Goose Fly is originated from Princess of Plum
Today, I also watched a great classic
You haevn't ever seen Princess of Plum dance
how can you speak so definite
When it comes to riding and archery, of course I can't compare to 10th brother
but when it comes to history books,
I have read more than 10th brother.
We Manchurians rule the world through riding and archery
What's the use in reading so many stinking history books?
It's only because your birth mother is a Han
and taught you all these Han habits.
The Qing dynasty needs both people who are talented in literary and military capacities
My imperial brothers are my left and right arm
Both have their merits. Why compare which is better?
Your majesty, just as I said before
Precious Smile is indeed intelligent
She can dance what most people can't
I think her dance movements
must do justice to Empress of Origin's original dance?
I remember that when Empress of Origin created this dance,
even Princess of Glory hadn't entered the prince's estate yet.
Not to mention you, Precious Cao
How would you know what Empress of Origin's dance was like?
And how could you compare Precious Smile's dance
to it?
I was rash. I only heard of it.
I regret to not have seen Empress of Origin's dance
in person.
You danced for so long. Are you tired?
I'm not tired
I have never seen Empress of Origin's
exquisite grace in dancing the Wild Goose Fly.
it's my pity
The Wilde Goose Fly I just danced
imitate Princess of Plum's, how could my candle light
compare with Empress of Origin's moon light
17th brother! You're late. You must drink 3 cups of wine as penalty.
I just played music
to accompany my new sister-in-law's dance.
Imperial brother must, on behalf of new sister-in-law,
let me off the hook.
Only when Always Miss
accompany Always Together
could it be perfect
This is Precious Smile, Zhen Shi
This is Precious Hui, Shen Shi
The one singing
I am Promise An
Reward!
You! Sit next to me.
Thanks Your Majesty
17th brother finally came!
Here, sit
Princess of Glory, what's the matter with you?
It's such a joyous day. Why must you dampen the mood?
Thank you for watching! Please join us!
Presented by the Legend of Zhen Huan Team @ Viki