The weather is cold
The weather is cold.  The Imperial Household is sending the
winter clothes
Tell manager Jiang
that we don't want the clothes
Sure.  Ask him to send more flowers.
Yes  Jiang Zhong Min is grateful, so he knows to repay us.
wanted to get
The warm house needs more charcoal  You have to send flowers to here three times in a day  Yes
You must do it on your own
Don't worry
are the clothes I wanted done?
Are the clothes I wanted done? Yes
Go and get it.
The cloak according to your order
This is the color of sky
Yes, This is what I wanted
Finally you have the heart to make up  That's because
I didn't have somebody to cheer me up And do my job as a mother
Have you seen the light?
Yes thank you Sister for teaching me.
Good then, let's be quick
and I acted recklessly
I hope that,
Your Majesty can show mercy
Your Majesty can show mercy,
for the sake of our relationship.
Song-Zhi, hand this letter to Su Pei-Sheng
and ask him to send it to His Majesty.
You have suffered for His Majesty's sake.
It doesn't matter,
I don't want His Majesty,
to leave me alone here.
I heard that His Majesty did the same to Concubine Wan.
Serves her right.
I don't care so much, I just hope that His Majesty still cares for me.
Still not soft enough, needs to cook longer.
You are overdoing it a small fire will do. The chicken will not be tasty if you cook it for too long.
Look after this and then add more flavouring. Young Mistress does not look well. She needs more nutrition.
Huan Bi, help me to move this butterly
It smells good!
Yes, of course the cloak
smells nice. We put the scent into this cloak
Look after the charcoal fire and take care of the butterflies
Your Majesty,
Why do you sigh?
I am reading Consort Nian's appeal letter,
I was reminded of our past relationship,
I feel sad.
Both of you have been a couple
Your Majesty is a caring soul, remembering your love is understandable.
Wan Ping must have recovered
from losing her son.
If Your Majesty misses Consort Nian then do go visit.
I don't have the heart to see Concubine Wan,
moreover, Consort Nian.
Forget it.
I always hated using my beauty to please others,
But,I can only use it to attract him.
I heard Consort Nian wrote an appeal letter to His Majesty a few days ago.
His Majesty was moved,
but he has not decided just yet
She was hot previously
Sooner or later Consort Nian will be restored.
When that happens, everything will be tough.
It is snowing.
Yes
His majesty always stayed here.
This year the first snow fall is late.
Though late, it is a heavy one.
It means next year will be a good year.
Concubine Wan is not here?
Early this morning, she had sent Jin-Xi to inform that she is not well.
So I told her to rest for a few more days.
No wonder it seems there are less people.
Lady Cao is also not here because Princess Wen-yi is afraid of the cold.
Your Majesty, Lady Hui is not here either.
She is never late,
why is she late today?
It is possible that it is hard to travel in the snow
Greetings Your Majesty, Greetings, Empress
I am sorry I am late. I beg pardon from Your Majesty and Empress.
It is ok, please rise.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Why are you late today? Is anything the matter?
I was over at Yi Mei Garden and saw the blooming flowers
and therefore I am late.
Have the flowers bloom?
Yes, and they are very pretty.
Lady Hui, it is a waste to miss such a scene
why don't you accompany me to see it?
Yes, I will.
Your Majesty, don't leave us alone here.
Do bring us all along.
Move to the garden.
Your Ladyship, Lady Hui has brought His Majesty here.
I am so sorry that I
was not capable to protect the baby,
I sincerely
wish His Majesty,
to have a long life, I am willing to take only vegetarian food
if my wish comes true.
Huan Huan,
is that you?
I am sorry I can't meet Your Majesty.
Why aren't you looking at me?
Don't you want to see me anymore?
Your Majesty, please don't come any closer.
You told me this before.
Your Majesty still remembers it
But I dare not keep it in my mind.
Your hands are cold,
aren't you afraid of catching a cold?
I have prayed for Your Majesty sincerely.
But if I caused Your Majesty to worry about me, it is my fault.
I will leave first.
Look! Her body is full of butterflies!
She is using magic
It is winter, where did the butterflies come from?
Even butterflies are attracted to you.
I have no idea either.
If you fall sick because you have been praying for me,
it would cause me more heartache.
Your body smells very nice,
No wonder even the butterflies are attracted to you in winter.
You have intoxicated me too.
I have been washing my body
in order to pray for Your Majesty.
That's good,
Concubine Wan has kept to her room since her miscarriage
I have been worried for a few months
I have been praying for Your Majesty and Sister to get together
That the two of you can be
reconciled
Finally my wish has come true.
When did I have any conflict with Huan Huan?
Never
It is just that I am not well,
I can't serve Your Majesty
You should be happy now
We are all serving our masters
As servants, our lives will be good if our masters are happy
I have always spoken good things of Concubine Wan to His Majesty.
Save it,
As long as it is good for the Emperor, you will benefit too.
Moreover this time it is Lady Hui's efforts.
It is weird
Why is Lady Hui helping Concubine Wan but not herself?
Since she has been well, she has not gotten the same attention from His Majesty like in the past.
Stay outside.
It might be a small matter to make life difficult for Concubine Wan the other day
But you had to humiliate her.
Now Concubine Wan has gained the Emperor's favour again
Look at how it is today.
Once His Majesty had seen her, everyone ceases to exist.
Do you think we will have a good life after this?
Why are you worried?
Every woman in the palace has been favoured and has also lost favour
Moreover she is a Concubine while I am a Lady
You are a Consort.
There are two of us and one of her. Why do you need to be afraid?
Do you think we will win by having more people on our side?
I don't think Concubine Wan will be nice to us
But you are a Consort, to discipline the women in the palace is expected.
Moreover there is no evidence of the peach matter.
Concubine Wan can't do us any harm
Who knows?
Just accept fate.
Your Ladyship must be tired
Do rest earlier
Yes I am tired
But I do not feel like sleeping yet
Why is the charcoal so hot?
The charcoal did not change, but time changes everything.
Your mood is different therefore you feel that the charcoal is hotter
I used to think the words of His Majesty were the most important things.
But now
it cannot even hold a candle to this charcoal.
I once wished to have someone to love me
and never to part
but it is just my wishful thinking.
No matter, the fact is that His Majesty cares very much for you.
That's why
I know these are wishful thinking
His Majesty treats me such, he will also treat others the same.
i have no way
but to use schemes to get what I want
Your Ladyship has been sick for so long and has kept all these in her heart
Now that you have said it out loud and with no more vexation in your heart, you will not suffer anymore
Your Ladyship, they are going to lock the gates. Let's sleep now too.
I wonder if we can sleep peacefully.
Your Ladyship, His Majesty is here.
Don't let him in,
Tell his majesty that I have slept.
Yes.
Who are you?
Huan-Huan are you sleeping?
Why is Your Majesty here so late?
I am about to sleep.
Huan-Huan, are you better?
I want to see you so that I will not be worried.
I can't greet Your Majesty now.
So I can't keep Your Majesty company. I beg Your Majesty to forgive me.
Huan-Huan, let me go in and see you, just to see you.
If you are fine, I will be at ease then.
Your Majesty has to hold court early tomorrow morning so you should not sleep late.
I am almost sleeping.
If I were to get up, it might make my condition worse.
And I won't be able to get well sooner to serve Your Majesty.
Please spare a thought for me.
Then I'll go back.
Xiao Yun-Zi
Yes
Send His Majesty back
Goodbye Your Majesty.
Get me the water, we can sleep now.
Your Ladyship, it is snowing heavily outside.
His Majesty had come over, why did you not want to see him?
Even if His Majesty comes tomorrow, I still won't see him.
Your Majesty, it is late.
Which palace would you wish to go to retire for the night?
I think Lady An is not asleep yet.
Or perhaps you can go to the Empress or Lady Hui.
No, not going to any of them.
I am going back to the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
Yes
Go
House of Concentrating Glow
Yes, House of Concentrating Glow.
You had said you were asking me to stay the night in the palace because I had drunk too much
But it seems you have trouble sleeping and so you wanted someone to chat with you?
Stop bringing this up
I was chased away by everyone
Brother, you have a lot of wives
Yes
But when I wanted to go to the House of the Broken Jade
They all pushed me away
Concubine Wan said that she wasn't feeling well and so could not serve me.
She didn't even want to see me
Concubine Wan cares about you, I don't think she said anything wrong
I know, but...
It seems like the butterflies of Concubine Wan
Have flew into your heart.
I don't know how these butterflies came about
But no matter
It's fine as long as she is true to me.
You don't know how stubborn she is
She has been avoiding me for a few months
Simply because I refused to punish Consort Nian
She is petty little girl.
But it is because she is a petty little girl
That makes her charming.
Who says people who are not married wouldn't understand.
I have been with Your Majesty for so many years
Other than Empress Chun-Yuan
I have never heard Your Majesty talk about any girl like this
No matter how difficult the state affairs are
We will still have a way to solve it
But it is more energy consuming
To fight with a smart woman.
Therefore stupid but obedient women
are the cutest
But it is not definite that you will love cute women
You are really a good partner to chat with
Just take your time
Since you like Concubinet Wan
You can solve this in a short period of time
Since Concubine Wan has prejudices with you
Why don't you accommodate her
Su Pei-Sheng
Your Majesty
You're still awake?
Isn't it morning yet?
It is almost morning
It will be morning in four hours' time.
I am going to sleep
Extinguish two more candles
Yes
His Majesty is here
Greetings your Majesty
Please rise.
Thank you your Majesty
Your majesty just finished your court hearings
Is there any vexation?
I have something to discuss with you
Since you are all here, listen to me as well.
This morning the Dzungaria sent people to propose marriage
So that their lord can marry our princess
and pacify the residents of Dzungaria
It is common for the princess of our country to marry outsider
We just need to pick a suitable girl from the palace
And honor her as princess
But the problem is they want a princess from the main royal family, not the branch family
Dzungaria belongs to Qing dynasty, It is a small tribe at the boundry of our country
It is already an honor that our princess will marry them
Yet they want more and more and insist on a princess from the main royal family!
They are really too much!
Normally we only choose princesses from the branch family
The only exception was when the previous emperor married his own daughter to Dzungaria
That's why it is hard for me to reject
As this example existed
Your Majesty, although Wen-Yi is your biological daughter, she is too young to marry!
I won't be bothered by this
If she is not underage
You are clear about the condition in the government
I have just come to the throne for about three years
And conquered the northwest
Dzungaria used to be violent
We will have war again
If this thing can't be solved properly
We won't have enough supplies
If we have war now
It is really a bad idea
Your majesty is right
We have to look
at the big picture
Approving the proposal is the only way
It's just that my princess Wen-Yi is too young
I can't find a suitable person
Dzungaria only wants the princess from the main family
They didn't ask for your Majesty's biological daughters
Do you mean
The youngest daughter of the previous emperor, Princess Zhao-Gui is single
Still in puberty, she is the most suitable person.
But she is my youngest sister
Your Majesty has constantly sacrificed himself for the country
So your sister should do the same.
Moreover Princess Zhao-Gui's mother is only a Lady in the Previous Emperor's court.
Even if Your Majesty were to arrange a marriage for her in the future, you will only pick a officer from the governmen
It will not be as honorable as marrying Dzungaria.
Empress, you are right.
She is my only single sister.
I must plan for her
On further reflection
The Lord of Dzungaria is from a noble family.
As Zhao-Gui is our only choice
Then I will let Empress prepare everything.
She will marry Dzungaria ten days later.
Yes, I will do my best.
Since we are arranging her marriage
I will honor her as Princess Gu-Lun
So arrange the preparations according to this position
Yes
It is might be easy to say the Imperial Household can handled the dowry.
But there are difficult aspects too, we can't afford to make any mistake
Or it will embarrass the Qing dynasty.
Having too many people handling this may not be ideal, I think
Sister Cao is very meticulous
why don't we ask her to help the princess to prepare?
I really don't know anything about such matters
I am afraid I will let Your Majesty's and Sister's good intentions down.
You are suited to these tasks.
The rest will be handled by the Empress.
Yes.
I have to leave now
Goodbye, Your Majesty
You did not say anything for a while but in the end you suggested that Lady Cao should handle the dowry.
What are you thinking?
I did not say anything in the beginning because I don't approve of the marriage
But I can't change it either
I feel sad for Princess Zhao-Cui.
Yes, Dzungaria is a violent tribe.
It is fine if she can marry a good man.
But the Lord of Dzungaria is old, he is almost 60 years old.
Poor Princess is only in her puberty.
The Lord is old enough to be her grandfather.
But His Majesty needs her to marry Dzungaria
She can't avoid
this marriage.
Isn't Nian Gengyao a good warrior?
Why don't His Majesty let him go conquer Dzungaria?
Why do we have to send troops if the matter can be solved by a woman?
Nian Gengyao has great achievements in the military but if he loses, the price
would not be just a Princess.
If he wins,, he will have more power and might threaten His Majesty's position.
Therefore His Majesty has no other choice.
Did His Majesty look at you at all when he was here just now?
No, I am useless, I am unable to gain His Majesty's favour
It is not that you are useless, it is Concubine Wan who is too capable.
Without her, His Majesty was attentive to you.
But now she is back, His Majesty could not even remember you.
Sister has been away from His Majesty for a while so it is normal for him to look for her now.
What about the future?
Your days with His Majesty is not short either, do you still want him to care for you?
Yes, I await your Majesty's guidance.
Concubine Wan is still powerful when she was not the beloved of His Majesty
Do you still remember Lady Chun?
Being close to Concubine Wan and other consorts
is the long-term way
I understand.
Check
I lose.
Your Majesty has lost, so Your Majesty must stay here.
You have been chasing me away for days.
Finally you are letting me stay.
Since you like the House of Broken Jade so much, I will let you stay
You stay here Your Majesty. I will go over to Lady Hui's place for the night.
Your Majesty lost the game and so you have to stay but I need not stay.
I have not fully recovered from my illness
Since Your Majesty wishes to stay here, I will have to go somewhere else.
You are not well, you stay.
I am going back to the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
Goodbye, Your Majesty
Your Ladyship, it is the fourth day
you are still chasing away His Majesty
Not letting him stay. There are so many rumors as a result.
So what? I don't care about rumors.
But isn't Your Ladyship worried that His Majesty may be so upset he will not return?
Did you hear the story of the wife of Emperor Wu of Han?
Emperor Wu of Han loved Madam Li because of her beauty
And before Emperor Wu died, he wanted to see her for the last time
But she had covered her face.
She did not allowed him to see her even when he was dead.
It is because she had become ugly
She was the nightmare of every woman in the palace.
The best thing is the thing that you have lost and cannot recover easily.
Her Ladyship keeps chasing His Majesty away
so as to entice him further.
Yes, you are right.
This is just a scheme.
But you should not overdo it.
Or your effort will be in vain
Princess is so pitiable. It is so quiet.
No one has come to her wedding ceremony.
It is obvious her position is not important, His Majesty has never cared for his sister.
Morever marrying her to an outsider means they will never meet again.
His Majesty has only one sister and he can bear to do so.
Even if it is his biological daughter
His Majesty will have no choice.
I wonder who will be next?
Why did you not let me know you are here?
It shows I have no manners
I just sent Princess Zhao-Gui and her retinue away
I saw you sewing so seriously
I did not want to disturb you
I was just killing time
Is the Princess fine?
She cried very sadly
I did not want to part with her either.
So I came here.
What are you sewing?
I wanted to sew a sachet for Your Majesty
But I am slow, I have only just finished sewing the dragon,and have not decided what the color of the clouds should be.
Any colour will do
Your good intentions are more important.
Everything about Your Majesty must be perfect
Just like what you said, the sachet represents my good intentions.
So I cannot take this lightly
I like the light purple color of your clothes.
It matches the golden dragon.
Purple clouds and golden dragon
Indeed a really propitious sign.
When you finished sewing,
I will carry the sachet on me every day
Never let it out of my sight.
Alright?
Niang Niang
Is His Majesty staying at the House of Mental Cultivation today
or meeting Lady An?
Or is he staying at the House of Broken Jade?
Yes
Did't you say that woman has been rejecting His Majesty?
Yes, I heard that
But now it seems she has allowed him to stay.
She is acting and scheming to seduce His Majesty
Niang Niang, don't get angry, think of your health.
You have put in too much incense
Making you cough.
Is it a lot?
Why didn't I smell anything?
Why can't I smell anything?
Oh
His Majesty isn't here so the smell isn't here either.
Concubine Wan has recovered, she can serve His Majesty again.
I am happy to see that too.
Thank you, Empress
Your Majesty, Consort Nian is outside, she wants to greet you.
It is cold outside, tell her to go back.
She does not need to greet me.
Consort Nian knows Your Majesty does not want to see her so she just wish to come in and kowtow to you at a distance.
Let her come in and kowtow a greeting then.
It is almost at yearend, let her do this to fulfill her wish.
Then she does not need to come anymore.
Let her enter.
Yes
His Majesty calls Consort Nian to enter.
Greeting Your Majesty
Please rise.
Thank you, Your Majesty
I dare not ask Your Majesty for forgiveness but I have copied many scriptures when I was alone.
I have sent them to the temple for the monks to read
Hopefully it can bless Your Majesty.
I understand your good intentions. You can go back.
Yes
Concubine Wan is here too.
So many people
I will leave first.
The weather is cold. Continue with the copying of the scriptures when spring comes.
Yes
You look good in purple yesterday, why don't you let the Imperial Household make more purple clothes for you?
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Sister, you finally got what you wanted
I was really worried about you.
Sister is too kind.
If you worry about me, come visit me often then.
That's true.
When Concubine Wan is sick, His Majesty will look for you
Where would you have the time to visit your sister?
What are you looking at?
I was just thinking the year is ending soon.
If your Majesty can spend more time with Princess Wen-yi
she will be very happy
According to today's situation, although His Majesty did not pardon Consort Nian,
He did not punish her heavily either.
She still has the chance to come back
I knew that when I lost my baby
As long as Nian Genyao is in power, the Nian's family will not fall
No matter what Consort Nian does
His Majesty will not and dare not kill her.
It seems they are more powerful than His Majesty
His Majesty has no choice but to bear it.
I don't understand all this
But what is going on between you and Ling-Rong?
I feel that both of you are not as close as before
That's because we hardly meet now
If it is because of His Majesty, it is not worth it.
I saw that she seems to be trying to accommodate you today.
Is it worth it?
Ling-Rong is very good at sussing out the situation.
We will know the person's true nature after some time
If it is because of His Majesty, it is not worth it
But if it is for some other reason, you have to sort it out then.
The three of us came to the palace together, to be where we are today, it has not been easy.
If she has done anything wrong, if we can compromise, we should.
Luckily Sister still treats me as before.
The snow has stopped. I will go visit the Empress Dowager.
The road is slippery. Be careful.
Ji-Xi, let's go to the Imperial Garden for a walk.
Huan-Bi, you go back first.
I rarely meet both of you.
I was just thinking the snowy landscape is so pretty
it is sad to enjoy it alone.
It would be better to enjoy the scene with both of you.
I was about to go see Wen-yi but as I have not seen you for a while, i will remain.
How about Lady Fuca? I had promised to watch an opera with Consort Qi.
So I am not free.
If you are not free, that is fine but some people might think that you had committed some offensive crimes
then that would be bad.